<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Actions And Proceedings Therein</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235" level="3">Judgment And Execution</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23</section_number>
    <catch_line>Execution On Judgments Against Fiduciaries, Sheriffs, Etc.; Execution For Possession Of Rented Or Leased Dwelling</catch_line>
    <order_by>23</order_by>
    <text>
        Original executions issuing on judgments against executors, administrators, trustees and other fiduciary officers in their representative capacity, including any such original execution running against two or more parties, any one or more of whom are fiduciary officers as aforesaid in their representative capacity, or against sheriffs under section ten of chapter thirty-seven, or on special judgments entered under section twenty-four, shall be made returnable within sixty days after the date of the execution. Except as hereinafter provided, in all other cases, original executions shall be made returnable within twenty years after the date of the judgment. 
Executions for possession of premises rented or leased for dwelling purposes obtained in actions pursuant to chapter two hundred and thirty-nine shall not be issued later than three months following the date of judgment, except that any period during which execution was stayed by order of the court or by an agreement of the parties filed with the court shall be excluded from the computation of the period of limitation. Such executions shall be made returnable within three months after the date of issuance and shall state the date of issuance and the return date. No sheriff, constable, officer, or other person shall serve or levy upon any such execution for possession later than three months following the date of the issuance of the execution.
    </text>
</law>