<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Actions And Proceedings Therein</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="231" order_by="231" level="3">Pleading And Practice</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>85S</section_number>
    <catch_line>Physical Alteration Or Destruction Of Fine Art</catch_line>
    <order_by>85S</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The general court hereby finds and declares that the physical alteration or destruction of fine art, which is an expression of the artist’s personality, is detrimental to the artist’s reputation, and artists therefore have an interest in protecting their works of fine art against such alteration or destruction; and that there is also a public interest in preserving the integrity of cultural and artistic creations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No person, except an artist who owns or possesses a work of fine art which the artist has created, shall intentionally commit, or authorize the intentional commission of any physical defacement, mutilation, alteration, or destruction of a work of fine art. As used in this section, intentional physical defacement, mutilation, alteration, or destruction includes any such action taken deliberately or through gross negligence.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The artist shall retain the right to claim and receive credit under his own name or under a reasonable pseudonym or, for just and valid reason, to disclaim authorship of his work of fine art. Credit shall be determined in accord with the medium of expression and the nature and extent of the artist’s contribution to the work of fine art.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The artist or any bona fide union or other artists’ organization authorized in writing by the artist for such purpose may commence an action in the superior court department of the trial court of the commonwealth without having as prerequisites to a suit any need for: (1) damages, already incurred, (2) a showing of special damages, if any, or (3) general damages in any monetary amount to recover or obtain any of the following (i) injunctive relief or declaratory relief, (ii) actual damages, (iii) reasonable attorneys’ and expert witness fees and all other costs of the action, or (iv) any other relief which the court deems proper.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     In determining whether a work of fine art is of recognized quality, the court shall rely on the opinions of artist, art dealers, collectors of fine art, curators of art museums, restorers and conservators of fine art and other persons involved with the creation or marketing of fine art.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The provisions of this section shall, with respect to the artist, or if any artist is deceased, his heir, legatee, or personal representative, continue until the fiftieth anniversary of the death of such artist, continue in addition to any other rights and duties which may now or in the future be applicable, and except as provided in paragraph (1) of subdivision (h) may not be waived except by an instrument in writing expressly so providing which is signed by the artist and refers to specific works with identification and such waiver shall only apply to work so identified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     If the owner of a building wishes to remove a work of fine art which is a part of such building but which can be removed from the building without substantial harm to such fine art, the rights and duties created under this section shall apply unless the owner has diligently attempted without success to notify the artist, or, if the artist is deceased, his heir, legatee, or personal representative, in writing of his intended action affecting the work of fine art, or unless he did provide notice and that person failed within ninety days either to remove the work or to pay for its removal. If such work is removed at the expense of the artist, his heir, legatee, or personal representative, title to such fine art shall be deemed to be in such person.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>