<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Actions And Proceedings Therein</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="234A" order_by="234A" level="3">Office Of Jury Commissioner For The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>61</section_number>
    <catch_line>Violation Of Sec. 60; Harassment, Etc. Of Employee</catch_line>
    <order_by>61</order_by>
    <text>
        Any willful violation of section sixty of this chapter by an employer shall also constitute a violation of this section. A juror seeking a civil remedy against an employer shall have an election to proceed either under section sixty or under this section. An employer shall not deprive a juror-employee of his employment or any incidents or benefits thereof, nor shall an employer harass, threaten, or coerce an employee because the employee has received a juror summons, responds thereto, performs any obligation or election of juror service as a grand or trial juror, or exercises any right under any section of this chapter. An employer shall not impose compulsory work assignments upon any juror-employee nor shall the employer do any other intentional act which will substantially interfere with the availability, effectiveness, attentiveness, or peace of mind of the employee during the performance of his juror service. Any employer who violates this section shall be guilty of a crime and, upon conviction, may be punished by a fine of not more than five thousand dollars. Any employer who violates this section also shall be liable in tort to the juror-employee. The juror-employee may commence a civil action in the superior court for such damages and injunctive relief as may be appropriate. The court may award treble damages and reasonable attorney’s fees to the juror upon a finding of willful conduct by the employer. The legal counsel for the office of jury commissioner may submit an application for the issuance of a criminal complaint in any court of competent jurisdiction against an employer who has violated this section or section sixty.
    </text>
</law>