<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Actions And Proceedings Therein</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223" level="3">Commencement Of Actions, Service Of Process</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>37</section_number>
    <catch_line>Corporations; Persons Authorized To Be Served</catch_line>
    <order_by>37</order_by>
    <text>
        In an action against a county, city, town, parish or religious society, or against the proprietors of wharves, general fields or real estate lying in common, who are incorporated, service shall be made upon the treasurer thereof, or if no treasurer is found, upon one of the county commissioners, the city clerk or one of the aldermen, the town clerk or one of the selectmen, upon one of the assessors or standing committee of the parish or religious society, or upon one of the proprietors of such land or other estate, as the case may be. If there are no such officers as are mentioned in this section, service shall be made upon one of the inhabitants of the county, city or town, or upon one of the members of the corporation. 
In an action against a domestic corporation other than one mentioned in the preceding paragraph, service shall be made upon the president, treasurer, clerk, resident agent appointed pursuant to section 49 of chapter 156D, cashier, secretary, agent or other officer in charge of its business, or, if no such officer is found within the county, upon any member of the corporation. If an officer authorized to serve legal process makes a return on such process that, after diligent search, he can find no one upon whom he can lawfully make service as aforesaid, the court to which such process is returned may upon application issue an order of notice to such corporation, directing it to appear and answer within a designated period.
    </text>
</law>