<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Actions And Proceedings Therein</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="231" order_by="231" level="3">Pleading And Practice</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>60J</section_number>
    <catch_line>Negligence Actions For Serving Alcoholic Beverages To Minors Or Intoxicated Persons; Summary Judgments</catch_line>
    <order_by>60J</order_by>
    <text>
        Every action for negligence in the distribution, sale or serving of alcoholic beverages to a minor or to an intoxicated person shall be commenced in the superior court department and shall proceed according to the Massachusetts Rules of Civil Procedure unless otherwise provided for by this section. 
The plaintiff shall file, together with his complaint, or at such later time not to exceed ninety days thereafter, an affidavit setting forth sufficient facts to raise a legitimate question of liability appropriate for judicial inquiry. 
Any party may make a motion for summary judgment pursuant to Rule 56 of the Massachusetts Rules of Civil Procedure. Any such motion shall be heard and decided promptly after issue is joined as to any party, unless the court enlarges the time for discovery. Said enlarged time for discovery shall not exceed ninety days, except on further order of the court. 
On or within thirty days of filing a notice of appeal from summary judgment adverse to a plaintiff, the plaintiff shall file a bond in the amount of two thousand dollars for each adverse party on appeal secured by cash or its equivalent with the clerk of the appellate court in which the case is pending. Said bond shall be payable to the named adverse party or parties for costs assessed and attorney fees on appeal, if the appellant does not prevail on appeal. Upon motion filed by the plaintiff, and a determination by a single justice of the appellate court that the plaintiff is indigent, said justice may reduce or eliminate the amount of the bond. 
If a judgment is entered for a plaintiff, the court shall report its judgment to the alcoholic beverages control commission.
    </text>
</law>