<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="71" order_by="71" level="3">Public Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>38G.5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Specialist Teacher Endorsement In Transition Services;  Transition Of Students With Disabilities To Post School Activities</catch_line>
    <order_by>38G.5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 51, Sec. 1 effective June 7, 2012.]  As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meaning:--  "Board'', the board of elementary and secondary education established in chapter 15.  "Department'', the department of elementary and secondary education established in chapter 15.  "Transition services'', as defined in 20 USC 1401(34).  The board shall provide a specialist teacher endorsement in transition services which shall include both coursework and field experience for previously licensed special education teachers and rehabilitation counselors to develop the competence necessary to serve as transition coordinators to facilitate provision of a coordinated set of activities to adequately prepare students with disabilities to achieve successful transition to post-school activities, including further education, competitive employment and independent living. The requirements for the specialist teacher endorsement in transition services, as promulgated by the board, may also satisfy course requirements necessary to obtain a professional license. The board shall promulgate rules and regulations specifying the subject matter, knowledge, skills and competencies required for such endorsement, including requirements to incorporate renewal of the endorsement as part of the individual professional development plan required pursuant to section 38G. The rules and regulations shall also specify components necessary for preparation programs offering a specialist teacher endorsement in transition services, which shall be included in the department's process for approving preparation programs.
    </text>
</law>