<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2V</section_number>
    <catch_line>Dairy Equalization Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2V</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Dairy Equalization Fund. There shall be credited to such fund all monies payable pursuant to sections ten, eleven and twelve of chapter ninety-four A and any interest earned on monies within the fund. Amounts credited to said fund shall be made available by the state treasurer, without further appropriation, exclusively for the purposes of said chapter ninety-four A, only after receipt of notice certified by the commissioner of the department of food and agriculture that amounts are due pursuant to said chapter ninety-four A. Said commissioner shall file quarterly reports with the house and senate clerk and the house and senate committees on ways and means regarding the distribution of monies from the fund.
Chapter 29: Dairy Equalization Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Dairy Equalization Fund. There shall be credited to such fund all monies payable under sections 10, 11 and 12 of chapter 94A and any interest earned on monies within the fund. Amounts credited to said fund shall be made available by the state treasurer, without further appropriation, exclusively for the purposes of said chapter 94A, only after receipt of notice certified by the commissioner of the department of food and agriculture that amounts are due under said chapter 94A. Said commissioner shall file quarterly reports with the house and senate clerk and the house and senate committees on ways and means regarding the distribution of monies from the fund.
    </text>
</law>