<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>80G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Nurse Midwives;  Power To Order Tests And Therapeutics;  Issuance Of Written Prescriptions</catch_line>
    <order_by>80G</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until May 2, 2012. For text effective May 2, 2012, see below.]  A nurse authorized to practice as a certified nurse-midwife may order tests and therapeutics pursuant to guidelines mutually developed and agreed upon by the certified nurse-midwife and the supervising physician in accordance with regulations promulgated jointly by the board and the board of registration in medicine after consultation with the board of registration in pharmacy and issue written prescriptions subject to the provisions of paragraph (g) of section seven of chapter ninety-four C. Any prescription for medication made by a certified nurse-midwife shall include the name of the supervising physician.
Chapter 112: Nurse-midwives; authority to order and interpret tests and prescribe medications; clinical relationship with obstetrician-gynecologist; standards of care
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 24, Sec. 3 effective May 2, 2012. For text effective until May 2, 2012, see above.]  A nurse authorized to practice as a certified nurse-midwife, under section 80C, may order and interpret tests, therapeutics and prescribe medications in accordance with regulations promulgated by the board and the commissioner of public health under subsection (g) of section 7 of chapter 94C. Nurse-midwives shall practice within a health care system and have clinical relationships with obstetrician-gynecologists that provide for consultation, collaborative management or referral, as indicated by the health status of the patient. Nurse-midwifery care shall be consistent with the standards of care established by the American College of Nurse-Midwives.
    </text>
</law>