<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111J" order_by="111J" level="3">Alcohol And Drug Counselors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this section and in sections 2 to 8, inclusive, the following words shall, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, have the following meanings: 
“Approved continuing education”, continuing education approved by the department, including research and training programs, college and university courses, in-service training programs, seminars and conferences designed to maintain and enhance the skills of alcohol and drug counselors. 
“Approved program”, a program approved by the department for the education and training of alcohol and drug counselors. 
“Approved work experience”, supervised work experience, approved by the department, in alcohol and drug abuse treatment, intervention and prevention. 
“Department”, the department of public health. 
“Licensed alcohol and drug counselor I”, a person licensed by the department to conduct an independent practice of alcohol and drug counseling and to provide supervision to other alcohol and drug counselors. A licensed alcohol and drug counselor I shall have received a master’s or doctoral degree in behavioral sciences, including a supervised counseling practicum which meets the requirements established by the department or such equivalent educational credits as may be established by the department, shall have at least three years of approved work experience and shall have passed a licensing examination approved by the department. 
“Licensed alcohol and drug counselor II”, a person licensed by the department to practice alcohol and drug counseling under clinical supervision. A licensed alcohol and drug counselor II shall have completed an approved program of education, including a supervised counseling practicum which meets the requirements established by the department or such equivalent educational credits as may be established by the department, shall have at least three years of approved work experience and shall have passed a licensing examination approved by the department.
    </text>
</law>