<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6D" order_by="6D" level="3">Health Policy Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Payment By Acute Hospital, Ambulatory Surgical Center Or Surcharge Payor For Estimated Expenses Of Commission</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 15 effective July 1, 2016. See 2012, 224, Sec. 284.]  Each acute hospital, ambulatory surgical center and surcharge payor shall pay to the commonwealth an amount for the estimated expenses of the commission.  The assessed amount for hospitals and ambulatory surgical centers shall be not less than 33 per cent of the amount appropriated by the general court for the expenses of the commission minus amounts collected from: (i) filing fees; (ii) fees and charges generated by the commission; and (iii) federal matching revenues received for these expenses or received retroactively for expenses of predecessor agencies. Each acute hospital and ambulatory surgical center shall pay such assessed amount multiplied by the ratio of the hospital's or ambulatory surgical center's gross patient service revenues to the total of all such hospital's and ambulatory surgical center's gross patient services revenues. Each acute hospital and ambulatory surgical center shall make a preliminary payment to the commission on October 1 of each year in an amount equal to 1/2 of the previous year's total assessment. Thereafter, each hospital and ambulatory surgical center shall pay, within 30 days notice from the commission, the balance of the total assessment for the current year based upon its most current projected gross patient service revenue. The commission shall subsequently adjust the assessment for any variation in actual and estimated expenses of the commission and for changes in hospital or ambulatory surgical center gross patient service revenue. Such estimated and actual expenses shall include an amount equal to the cost of fringe benefits and indirect expenses, as established by the comptroller under section 5D of chapter 29. In the event of late payment by any such hospital or ambulatory surgical center, the treasurer shall advance the amount of due and unpaid funds to the commission prior to the receipt of such monies in anticipation of such revenues up to the amount authorized in the then current budget attributable to such assessments and the commission shall reimburse the treasurer for such advances upon receipt of such revenues. This section shall not apply to any state institution or to any acute hospital which is operated by a city or town.  The assessed amount for surcharge payors shall be not less than 33 per cent of the amount appropriated by the general court for the expenses of the commission minus amounts collected from (i) filing fees; (ii) fees and charges generated by the commission's publication or dissemination of reports and information; and (iii) federal matching revenues received for these expenses or received retroactively for expenses of predecessor agencies. The assessment on surcharge payors shall be calculated and collected in the same manner as the assessment authorized under section 68 of chapter 118E.
    </text>
</law>