<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="101" order_by="101" level="3">Transient Vendors, Hawkers And Pedlers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22</section_number>
    <catch_line>License; Certificate Of Police Chief; Fees; Special State Licenses;  Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>22</order_by>
    <text>
        The deputy director may grant a license to go about carrying for sale or barter, exposing therefor and selling or bartering any goods, wares or merchandise, the sale of which is not prohibited by section 16, to a person who is or has declared an intention to become a citizen of the United States and who files with the deputy director a completely executed application to be furnished by the deputy director and on which shall be a certificate which shall be signed by the chief of police of the city or town in which the applicant resides which shall state that to the best of his knowledge and belief the applicant therein named is of good repute as to morals and integrity. The deputy director may grant, as aforesaid, special licenses upon payment by the applicant to the deputy director of a fee, as determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section 3B of chapter 7 and the licensee may go about carrying for sale or barter, exposing therefor and selling or bartering in any city or town any meats, butter, cheese, fish, fruits, vegetables or other goods, wares or merchandise, the sale of which is not prohibited by statute. A hawker or peddler licensed under this section shall not be required to be licensed under section 17. A hawker or peddler licensed under this section shall be subject to such local rules and regulations as may be made in a city by the mayor and city council and in a town by the board of selectmen.
    </text>
</law>