<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>60A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>60A</order_by>
    <text>
        The following words as used in sections sixty A to sixty L, inclusive, unless the context otherwise requires, shall have the following meanings:— 
“Architect”, any person who engages in the practice of architecture as hereinafter defined. 
“Architect emeritus”, an honorary title issued to an architect who has retired from the active practice of architecture in the commonwealth 
“Board”, the board of registration of architects established by section forty-four A of chapter thirteen. 
“Certificate of registration”, the certificate of annual registration, issued by the board. 
“Good moral character”, such character as will enable a person to discharge the fiduciary duties of an architect to his client. Evidence of inability to discharge such duties shall include commission of an offense justifying discipline under section sixty G, the practice of architecture in violation of section sixty K, the practice of architecture without a license in violation of the laws of another jurisdiction, or conviction of a felony; provided, that the board may consider evidence of reform. 
“Practice of architecture”, performing or agreeing to perform or holding one’s self out as able to perform professional services in connection with the design, construction, enlargement or alteration of a building including consultations, investigations, evaluations, preliminary studies, aesthetic design, the preparation of plans, specifications and contract documents, the co-ordination of structural and mechanical design and site development, administration of construction contracts and any other similar service or combination of services in connection with the design and construction of buildings, regardless of whether one or all of these services are being performed and regardless of whether these services are performed in person or as the directing head of an office or organization performing them; provided, that the practice of architecture shall not include the practice of engineering as defined in this chapter, but a registered architect may perform such engineering work as is incidental to the practice of architecture. 
“Principal”, any person who has been or is the head of an organization practicing architecture.
    </text>
</law>