<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65" level="3">Taxation Of Legacies And Successions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Non Resident’S Estates; Payment Of Foreign Taxes; Procedure On Failure To File Proof Of Payment</catch_line>
    <order_by>24C</order_by>
    <text>
        The proof required by section twenty-four B may be in the form of a certificate issued by the official or body charged with the administration of the death tax laws of the domiciliary state. If such proof has not been filed within the time limited in section twenty-four B, and if within such time it does not appear that letters testamentary or of administration have been issued in the domiciliary state, the register of probate shall forthwith upon the expiration of such time notify by mail the official or body of the domiciliary state charged with the administration of the death tax laws thereof with respect to such estate, and shall state in such notice so far as is known to him (a) the name, date of death and last domicile of such decedent, (b) the name and address of each executor or administrator, (c) a summary of the values of the real estate, tangible personalty, and intangible personalty, wherever situated, belonging to such decedent at the time of his death, and (d) the fact that such executor or administrator has not filed theretofore the proof required in section twenty-four B. Such register shall attach to such notice a plain copy of the will and codicils of such decedent, if he died testate, or, if he died intestate, a list of his heirs and next of kin, so far as is known to such register. Within sixty days after the mailing of such notice the official or body charged with the administration of the death tax laws of the domiciliary state may file with such probate court in this commonwealth a petition for an accounting in such estate, and such official or body of the domiciliary state shall, for the purposes of this section, be a party interested for the purpose of petitioning such probate court for such accounting. If such petition be filed within said period of sixty days, such probate court shall decree such accounting, and upon such accounting being filed and approved shall decree either the payment of any such tax found to be due to the domiciliary state or subdivision thereof or the remission to a fiduciary appointed or to be appointed by the probate court, or other court charged with the administration of estates of decedents, of the domiciliary state, of the balance of the intangible personalty after the payment of creditors and expenses of administration in this commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>