<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118H" order_by="118H" level="3">Commonwealth Care Health Insurance Program</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Health Insurance Plans Procured By Board Of Connector</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) There shall be established a program for any resident with a household income that does not exceed 100 percent of the federal poverty level, in which the board of the connector shall procure health insurance plans that include, but are not limited to: (1) inpatient services; (2) outpatient services and preventative care by participating providers; (3) prescription drugs as provided under the MassHealth formulary; (4) medically necessary inpatient and outpatient mental health services and substance abuse services; and (5) medically necessary dental services, including preventative and restorative procedures.[ Subsection (b) effective until July 1, 2011. For text effective July 1, 2011, see below.]  (b) Enrollees with a household income that does not exceed 100 percent of the federal poverty level shall only be responsible for a copayment toward the purchase of each pharmaceutical product and for use of emergency room services in acute care hospitals for nonemergency conditions equal to that required of enrollees in the MassHealth program, as described in clause (5) of section 25 of chapter 118E. The board may waive copayments upon a finding of substantial financial or medical hardship. No other premium, deductible, or other cost sharing shall apply to enrollees under this program.[ Subsection (b) as amended by 2011, 68, Sec. 90 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221. For text effective until July 1, 2011, see above.]  (b) Enrollees with a household income that does not exceed 100 per cent of the federal poverty level shall only be responsible for copayments equal to those required of enrollees in the MassHealth program. The board may waive copayments upon a finding of substantial financial or medical hardship. No other premium, deductible, or other cost sharing shall apply to enrollees under this program.
    </text>
</law>