<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Determination Of Need</catch_line>
    <order_by>25C</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of law, except as provided in section twenty-five C1/2, no person or agency of the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof shall make substantial capital expenditures for construction of a health care facility or substantially change the service of such facility unless there is a determination by the department that there is need therefor. No such determination of need shall be required for any substantial capital expenditure for construction or any substantial change in service which shall be related solely to the conduct of research in the basic biomedical or applied medical research areas, and shall at no time result in any increase in the clinical bed capacity or outpatient load capacity of a health care facility, and shall at no time be included within or cause an increase in the gross patient service revenue of a facility for health care services, supplies, and accommodations, as such revenue shall be defined from time to time in accordance with section thirty-one of chapter six A. Any person undertaking any such expenditure related solely to such research which shall exceed or may reasonably be regarded as likely to exceed one hundred and fifty thousand dollars or any such change in service solely related to such research, shall give written notice thereof to the department and the division of health care finance and policy at least sixty days before undertaking such expenditure or change in service. Said notice shall state that such expenditure or change shall be related solely to the conduct of research in the basic biomedical or applied medical research areas, and shall at no time be included within or result in any increase in the clinical bed capacity or outpatient load capacity of a facility, and shall at no time cause an increase in the gross patient service revenue, as defined in accordance with said section thirty-one of said chapter six A, of a facility for health care services, supplies and accommodations. Notwithstanding the preceding three sentences, a determination of need shall be required for any such expenditure or change if the notice required by this section is not filed in accordance with the requirements of this section, or if the department finds, within sixty days after receipt of said notice, that such expenditure or change will not be related solely to research in the basic biomedical or applied medical research areas, or will result in an increase in the clinical bed capacity or outpatient load capacity of a facility, or will be included within or cause an increase in the gross patient service revenues of a facility. A research exemption granted under the provisions of this section shall not be deemed to be as evidence of need in any determination of need proceeding.  No person or agency of the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof shall provide an innovative service or use a new technology, as such terms are defined in section twenty-five B, in any location other than in a health care facility, as such term is defined in section twenty-five B, unless the person or agency first is issued a determination of need therefor by the department.  No person or agency of the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof shall acquire for location in other than a health care facility a unit of medical, diagnostic, or therapeutic equipment, other than equipment used to provide an innovative service or which is a new technology, as such terms are defined in section twenty-five B, with a fair market value in excess of one hundred and fifty thousand dollars unless the person or agency notifies the department of the person's or agency's intent to acquire such equipment and of the use that will be made of the equipment. Such notice shall be made in writing and shall be received by the department at least thirty days before contractual arrangements are entered into to acquire the equipment with respect to which notice is given. A determination by the department of need therefor shall be required for any such acquisition (i) if the notice required by this paragraph is not filed in accordance with the requirements of this paragraph, and (ii) if the requirements for exemption under subsection (a) of section twenty-five C1/2; provided, however, that in no event shall any person who acquires a unit of magnetic resonance imaging equipment for location other than in a health care facility refer or influence any referrals of patients to said equipment, unless said person is a physician directly providing services with that equipment; provided, however, that for the purposes of this section, no public advertisement shall be deemed a referral or an influence of referrals; and provided, further, that any person who has an ownership interest in said equipment, whether direct or indirect, shall disclose said interest to patients utilizing said equipment in a conspicuous manner.  Each person or agency operating a unit of equipment described in this section shall submit annually to the department information and data in connection with utilization and volume rates of said equipment on a form or forms prescribed by the department are not met.  Except as provided in section twenty-five C1/2, no person or agency of the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof shall acquire an existing health care facility unless the person or agency notifies the department of the person's or agency's intent to acquire such facility and of the services to be offered in the facility and its bed capacity. Such notice shall be made in writing and shall be received by the department at least thirty days before contractual arrangements are entered into to acquire the facility with respect to which the notice is given. A determination of need therefor shall be required for any such acquisition if the notice required by this paragraph is not filed in accordance with the requirements of this paragraph or if the department finds, within thirty days after receipt of notice in accordance with this paragraph, that the services or bed capacity of the facility will be changed in being acquired.  The department, in making any such determination, shall encourage appropriate allocation of private and public health care resources and the development of alternative or substitute methods of delivering health care services so that adequate health care services will be made reasonably available to every person within the commonwealth at the lowest reasonable aggregate cost and shall take into account the special needs and circumstances of HMOs. The department shall also recognize the special needs and circumstances of projects that (1) are essential to the conduct of research in basic biomedical or health care delivery areas or to the training of health care personnel, (2) are unlikely to result in any increase in the clinical bed capacity or outpatient load capacity of the facility, and (3) are unlikely to cause an increase in the total patient care charges of the facility to the public for health care services, supplies, and accommodations, as such charges shall be defined from time to time in accordance with section five of chapter four hundred and nine of the acts of nineteen hundred and seventy-six.  Applications for such determination shall be filed with the department, together with such other forms and information as shall be prescribed by, or acceptable to, the department. A duplicate copy of any application together with supporting documentation therefor, shall be a public record and kept on file in the department. The department may require a public hearing on any application. A reasonable fee, established by the department, shall be paid upon the filing of such application; provided, that in no event shall such fee exceed one-tenth of one per cent of the capital expenditures, if any, proposed by the applicant.  Except in the case of an emergency situation determined by the department as requiring immediate action to prevent further damage to the public health or to a health care facility, the department shall not act upon an application for such determination unless (a) the application has been on file with the department for at least thirty days, (b) the division of health care finance and policy, the state, and appropriate regional comprehensive health planning agencies and, in the case of long-term care facilities only, the department of elder affairs, have been provided copies of such application and supporting documents and given reasonable opportunity to comment thereon, and (c) a public hearing has been held thereon when requested by the applicant, the state or appropriate regional comprehensive health planning agency, or any ten taxpayers of the commonwealth. If, in any filing period, an individual application is filed which would implicitly decide any other application filed during such period, the department shall not act only upon an individual.  The department shall so approve or disapprove in whole or in part each such application for a determination of need within eight months after filing with the department; provided that the department may, on one occasion only, delay such action for up to two months after the applicant has provided information which the department reasonably has requested during such eight month period. Applications remanded to the department by the health facilities appeals board pursuant to the provisions of section twenty-five E shall be acted upon by the department within the same time limits provided in this section for the department to approve or disapprove applications for a determination of need. If an application has not been acted upon by the department within such time limits, the applicant may, within a reasonable period of time, bring an action in the nature of mandamus in the superior court to require the department to act upon the application.  Such determinations of need shall be based on the written record compiled by the department during its review of the application and on such criteria consistent with sections twenty-five B to twenty-five G, inclusive, as were in effect on the date of filing of the application. In compiling such record the department shall confine its requests for information from the applicant to matters which shall be within the normal capacity of the applicant to provide. In each case the action by the department on the application shall be in writing and shall set forth the reasons therefor; and every such action and the reasons therefor shall constitute a public record and be filed in the department.  The department shall stipulate the period during which a determination of need shall remain in effect, which in no event shall originally be longer than three years but which may be extended by the department for cause shown. Any such determination shall continue to be effective only upon the applicant (a) making reasonable progress toward completing the construction or substantial change in services for which need was determined to exist, (b) complying with all other provisions of law relating to the construction, licensure, and operation of health care facilities, and (c) complying with such further terms and conditions as the department reasonably shall require.  The department shall notify the secretary of elder affairs forthwith of the pendency of any proceeding, of any public hearing and of any action to be taken under this section on any application submitted by or on behalf of any long-term care facility.  No long term care facility located in an underbedded urban area shall be replaced or the license for said facility transferred outside an underbedded urban area. For the purposes of this paragraph, an underbedded urban area shall mean a city or town in which: (a) the per capita income is below the state average; or (b) the percentage of the population below one hundred percent of the federal poverty level is above the state average; or (c) the percentage of the population below two hundred percent of the federal poverty level is above the state average.
Chapter 111: Determination of need
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 71 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  (a) Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, except as provided in section 25 C1/2, a person or agency of the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof shall not make substantial capital expenditures for construction of a health care facility or substantially change the service of the facility unless there is a determination by the department that there is need for the construction or change. A determination of need shall not be required for any substantial capital expenditure for construction or any substantial change in service which shall be related solely to the conduct of research in the basic biomedical or applied medical research areas and shall at no time result in any increase in the clinical bed capacity or outpatient load capacity of a health care facility and shall not be included within or cause an increase in the gross patient service revenue of a facility for health care services, supplies and accommodations, as such revenue shall be defined under section 31 of chapter 6A. Any person undertaking an expenditure related solely to that research which shall exceed or may reasonably be regarded as likely to exceed $150,000 or any change in service solely related to the research, shall give written notice of the expenditure or change in service to the department the center for health information and analysis and the health policy commission, and the health policy commission at least 60 days before undertaking the expenditure or change in service. The notice shall state that the expenditure or change shall be related solely to the conduct of research in the basic biomedical or applied medical research areas and shall not be included within or result in any increase in the clinical bed capacity or outpatient load capacity of a facility and shall not cause an increase in the gross patient service revenue, as defined in under said section 31 of said chapter 6A, of a facility for health care services, supplies and accommodations; provided, however, that if it is subsequently determined that there was a violation of this section, the applicant may be punished by a fine of not more than 3 times the amount of the expenditure or value of the change of service.  (b) Notwithstanding subsection (a), a determination of need shall be required for any such expenditure or change if the notice required by this section is not filed in accordance with the requirements of this section or if the department finds, after receipt of the notice, that the expenditure or change will not be related solely to research in the basic biomedical or applied medical research areas, will result in an increase in the clinical bed capacity or outpatient load capacity of a facility or will be included within or cause an increase in the gross patient service revenues of a facility. A research exemption granted under this section shall not be deemed to be evidence of need in any determination of need proceeding.  (c) A person or agency of the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof shall not provide an innovative service or use a new technology in any location other than in a health care facility, unless the person or agency first is issued a determination of need for the innovative service or new technology by the department.  (d) A person or agency of the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof shall not acquire for location in other than a health care facility a unit of medical, diagnostic, or therapeutic equipment, other than equipment used to provide an innovative service or which is a new technology, as such terms are defined in section 25B, with a fair market value in excess of $250,000, to be adjusted in a similar fashion as section 25B1/2, unless the person or agency notifies the department of the person's or agency's intent to acquire the equipment and of the use that will be made of the equipment; provided, however, that maintenance or replacement of existing equipment defined as new technology shall not require a review. The notice shall be made in writing and shall be received by the department at least 30 days before contractual arrangements are entered into to acquire the equipment with respect to which notice is given. A determination by the department of need shall be required for any the acquisition (1) if the notice required by this paragraph is not filed in accordance with the requirements of this paragraph, and (2) if the requirements for exemption under subsection (a) of section 25C1/2 are not met; provided, however, that in no event shall any person who acquires a unit of new technology for location other than in a health care facility refer or influence any referrals of patients to the equipment, unless the person is a physician directly providing services with that equipment; provided, however, that for the purposes of this section, a public advertisement shall not be deemed a referral or an influence of referrals; and provided, further, that any person who has an ownership interest in the equipment, whether direct or indirect, shall disclose the interest to patients utilizing said equipment in a conspicuous manner.  (e) Each person or agency operating a unit of equipment described in this section shall submit annually to the department information and data in connection with utilization and volume rates of said equipment on a form or forms prescribed by the department.  (f) Except as provided in section 25 C1/2, a person or agency of the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof shall not acquire an existing health care facility unless the person or agency notifies the department of the person's or agency's intent to acquire the facility and of the services to be offered in the facility and its bed capacity. The notice shall be made in writing and shall be received by the department at least 3 0 days before contractual arrangements are entered into to acquire the facility with respect to which the notice is given. A determination of need shall be required for any such acquisition if the notice required by this subsection is not filed in accordance with the requirements of this subsection or if the department finds, within 3 0 days after receipt of notice under this subsection, that the services or bed capacity of the facility will be changed in being acquired.  (g) The department, in making any determination of need, shall be guided by the state health plan, shall encourage appropriate allocation of private and public health care resources and the development of alternative or substitute methods of delivering health care services so that adequate health care services will be made reasonably available to every person within the commonwealth at the lowest reasonable aggregate cost, shall take into account any comments from the center for health information and analysis, the health policy commission, and any other state agency or entity, and may impose reasonable terms and conditions as the department determines are necessary to achieve the purposes and intent of this section. The department may also recognize the special needs and circumstances of projects that: (1) are essential to the conduct of research in basic biomedical or health care delivery areas or to the training of health care personnel; (2) are unlikely to result in any increase in the clinical bed capacity or outpatient load capacity of the facility; and (3) are unlikely to cause an increase in the total patient care charges of the facility to the public for health care services, supplies, and accommodations, as such charges shall be defined from time to time in accordance with section 5 of chapter 409 of the acts of 1976.  (h) Applications for such determination shall be filed with the department, together with other forms and information as shall be prescribed by, or acceptable to, the department. A duplicate copy of any application together with supporting documentation for such application, shall be a public record and kept on file in the department. The department may require a public hearing on any application at its discretion or at the request of the attorney general. The attorney general may intervene in any hearing under this section. A reasonable fee, established by the department, shall be paid upon the filing of such application; provided, however, that in no event shall such fee exceed 0.2 per cent of the capital expenditures, if any, proposed by the applicant. The department may also require the applicant to provide an independent cost-analysis, conducted at the expense of the applicant, to demonstrate that the application is consistent with the commonwealth's efforts to meet the health care cost-containment goals established by the commission.  (i) Except in the case of an emergency situation determined by the department as requiring immediate action to prevent further damage to the public health or to a health care facility, the department shall not act upon an application for such determination unless: (1) the application has been on file with the department for at least 30 days; (2) the center for health care information and analysis, the health policy commission, the state and appropriate regional comprehensive health planning agencies and, in the case of long-term care facilities only, the department of elder affairs, or in the case of any facility providing inpatient services for the mentally ill or developmentally disabled, the departments of mental health or developmental services, respectively, have been provided copies of such application and supporting documents and given reasonable opportunity to comment on such application; and (3) a public hearing has been held on such application when requested by the applicant, the state or appropriate regional comprehensive health planning agency or any 10 taxpayers of the commonwealth. If, in any filing period, an individual application is filed which would implicitly decide any other application filed during such period, the department shall not act only upon an individual.  (j) The department shall so approve or disapprove in whole or in part each such application for a determination of need within 4 months after filing with the department; provided, however, that the department may, on 1 occasion only, delay the action for up to 2 months after the applicant has provided information which the department reasonably has requested during the 8 month period. Applications remanded to the department by the health facilities appeals board under section 25E shall be acted upon by the department within the same time limits provided in this section for the department to approve or disapprove applications for a determination of need. If an application has not been acted upon by the department within such time limits, the applicant may, within a reasonable period of time, bring an action in the nature of mandamus in the superior court to require the department to act upon the application.  (k) Determinations of need shall be based on the written record compiled by the department during its review of the application and on such criteria consistent with sections 25B to 25G, inclusive, as were in effect on the date of filing of the application. In compiling such record the department shall confine its requests for information from the applicant to matters which shall be within the normal capacity of the applicant to provide. In each case the action by the department on the application shall be in writing and shall set forth the reasons for such action; and every such action and the reasons for such action shall constitute a public record and be filed in the department.  (l) The department shall stipulate the period during which a determination of need shall remain in effect, which in no event shall originally be longer than 3 years but which may be extended by the department for cause shown. Any such determination shall continue to be effective only upon the applicant: (1) making reasonable progress toward completing the construction or substantial change in services for which need was determined to exist; (2) complying with all other laws relating to the construction, licensure and operation of health care facilities; and (3) complying with such further terms and conditions as the department reasonably shall require.  (m) The department shall notify the secretary of elder affairs forthwith of the pendency of any proceeding, of any public hearing and of any action to be taken under this section on any application submitted by or on behalf of any long-term care facility. In instances involving applications submitted on behalf of any facility providing inpatient services for the mentally ill or developmentally disabled, the department shall notify the appropriate commissioner.  (n) A long-term care facility located in an under-bedded urban area shall not be replaced or the license for said facility transferred outside an under-bedded urban area. For the purposes of this subsection, an under-bedded urban area shall mean a city or town in which: (1) the per capita income is below the state average; (2) the percentage of the population below 100 per cent of the federal poverty level is above the state average; or (3) the percentage of the population below 200 per cent of the federal poverty level is above the state average.
    </text>
</law>