<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>23A</order_by>
    <text>
        The following words as used in sections twenty-three A to twenty-three P, inclusive, unless the context otherwise requires, shall have the following meanings:— 
“Athletic trainer”, any person who is duly licensed in accordance with this section as an athletic trainer and who limits his practice to schools, teams or organizations with whom he is associated and who is under the direction of a physician or dentist duly registered in the commonwealth. 
“Athletic training”, the application of principles, methods and procedures of evaluation and treatment of athletic injuries, preconditioning, conditioning and reconditioning of the athlete through the use of appropriate preventative and supportive devices, temporary splinting and bracing, physical modalities of heat, cold, massage, water, electric stimulation, sound, exercise and exercise equipment under the discretion of a physician. Athletic training includes instruction to coaches, athletes, parents, medical personnel and communities in the area of care and prevention of athletic injuries. 
“Board”, the board on allied health professions, established under section eleven A of chapter thirteen. 
“Occupational therapy”, the application of principles, methods and procedures of evaluation, problem identification, treatment, education, and consultation which utilizes purposeful activity in order to maximize independence, prevent or correct disability, and maintain health. These services are used with individuals, throughout the life span, whose abilities to interact with their environment are limited by physical injury or illness, disabilities, poverty and cultural differences or the aging process. Occupational therapy includes but is not limited to: (1) administering and interpreting tests necessary for effective treatment planning; (2) developing daily living skills, perceptual motor skills, sensory integrative functioning, play skills and prevocational and vocational work capacities; (3) designing, fabricating or applying selected orthotic and prosthetic devices or selected adaptive equipment; (4) utilizing designated modalities, superficial heat and cold, and neuromuscular facilitation techniques to improve or enhance joint motion muscle function; (5) designing and applying specific therapeutic activities and exercises to enhance or monitor functional or motor performance and to reduce stress; and (6) adapting environments for the handicapped. These services are provided to individuals or groups through medical, health, educational, industrial or social systems. 
Occupational therapy shall also include delegating of selective forms of treatment to occupational therapy assistants and occupational therapy aides; provided, however, that the occupational therapist so delegating shall assume the responsibility for the care of the patient and the supervision of the occupational therapy assistant or the occupational therapy aide. 
“Occupational therapist”, a person who is duly licensed to practice occupational therapy in the commonwealth in accordance with section twenty-three B. 
“Occupational therapy assistant”, a person duly licensed in accordance with section twenty-three B and who assists in the practice of occupational therapy who works under the supervision of a duly licensed occupational therapist. 
“Physical therapy”, a health profession that utilizes the application of scientific principles for the identification, prevention, remediation and rehabilitation of acute or prolonged physical dysfunction thereby promoting optimal health and function. Physical therapy practice is evaluation, treatment and instruction related to neuromuscular, musculoskeletal, cardiovascular and respiratory functions. Such evaluation shall include but is not limited to performance and interpretation of tests as an aid to the diagnosis or planning of treatment programs. Such treatment shall include but is not limited to the use of therapeutic exercise, physical activities, mobilization, functional and endurance training, traction, bronchopulmonary hygiene postural drainage, temporary splinting and bracing, massage, heat, cold, water, radiant energy, electricity or sound. Such instruction shall include teaching both patient and family physical therapy procedures as part of a patient’s ongoing program. Physical therapy also shall include the delegating of selective forms of treatment to physical therapist assistants and physical therapy aides; provided, however, that the physical therapist so delegating shall assume the responsibility for the care of the patient and the supervision of the physical therapist assistant or physical therapy aide. 
Physical therapy shall also include the providing of consultation services for health, educational, and community agencies. 
“Physical therapist”, a person who is duly licensed to practice physical therapy in the commonwealth in accordance with section twenty-three B. 
“Physical therapist assistant”, a person duly licensed in accordance with section twenty-three B and who assists in the practice of physical therapy under the direction of a duly licensed physical therapist. 
“Recognized educational institution”, a degree-granting college or university recognized as such by the United States Office of Education of the Commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>