<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>19B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The board shall adopt, and may from time to time amend and repeal, regulations as it deems necessary for the implementation, administration, and enforcement of sections nineteen through nineteen J, inclusive. Said regulations shall be adopted, amended, or repealed pursuant to section two of chapter thirty A and all other provisions of chapter thirty A governing the adoption, amendment, and repeal of regulations. Said regulations shall include, without limitation, requirements for education, training, experience, and references and standards for professional conduct. Said standards shall be sufficiently stringent so that all waste site cleanup activity opinions rendered by all individuals meeting such standards and licensed by the board shall be rendered so that they protect public health, safety, welfare, and the environment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Without limiting the generality or applicability of the foregoing, by no later than January first, nineteen hundred and ninety-three, the board shall promulgate, in accordance with section two of chapter thirty A, and shall submit to the state secretary for publication in the Massachusetts Register, in accordance with sections five and six of chapter thirty A, regulations establishing standards for education, training, experience, and references that must be met by all individuals in order to thereafter be eligible to be licensed by the board as a hazardous waste site cleanup professional. By no later than January first, nineteen hundred and ninety-three, the board shall submit to the state secretary for publication in the Massachusetts Register, and the state secretary shall publish in the Massachusetts Register, in accordance with sections five and six of chapter thirty A, the notice required by section two of chapter thirty A and a draft of the regulations described in the preceding sentence.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>