<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2ZZZ</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commonwealth Transportation Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2ZZZ</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  (a) There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Commonwealth Transportation Fund, which shall be used exclusively for financing transportation-related purposes. There shall be credited to the fund all fees received by the registrar of motor vehicles pursuant to section 34 of chapter 90, all receipts paid into the treasury of the commonwealth and directed to be credited to the Commonwealth Transportation Fund pursuant to chapters 64A, 64E, 64F and any other applicable general or special law and all amounts appropriated into the fund by the general court. The fund shall be subject to appropriation and shall be used for transportation related expenses of the executive office of transportation or any successor agency or authority, including to pay or reimburse the General Fund for payment of debt service on bonds issued by, or otherwise payable pursuant to a lease or other contract assistance agreement by, the commonwealth for transportation purposes.  (b) Notwithstanding subsection (a), the crediting of receipts from the tax imposed pursuant to chapter 64A to the fund shall not affect the obligations of the commonwealth relating to notes issued pursuant to sections 9 to 10D, inclusive, of chapter 11 of the acts of 1997 and the pledge of receipts from the portion of the tax per gallon imposed pursuant to said chapter 64A equal to 10 cents per gallon, to secure the payment of such bonds under the circumstances described in the trust agreements relating to such notes is hereby ratified and confirmed in all respects and shall remain in full force and effect as long as any such notes issued as of July 1, 2009 remain outstanding in accordance with their terms and secured by funds in the fund.  (c) In addition to those revenues credited to the fund pursuant to subsection (a) there shall be credited to the fund all monies received by the commonwealth equal to .385 percent of the receipts from sales, as defined by chapter 64H, and .385 per cent of the sales price of purchases, as defined by chapter 64I, from that portion of the taxes imposed under said chapters 64H and 64I as excises upon the sale and use at retail of tangible property or of services, and upon the storage, use or other consumption of tangible property, or of services, including interest thereon or penalties, but not including any portion of the taxes that constitute special receipts within the meaning of subsection (b1/2) of section 10 of chapter 152 of the acts of 1997 or within the meaning of said subsection (b1/2); provided, however, that if in a fiscal year the amount credited to the fund under this subsection is less than $275,000,000, then the comptroller shall transfer an amount from the General Fund to make up the difference between the amount credited to the fund and $275,000,000, not later than September 1 of the following fiscal year.  (d) Not less than the following amounts shall annually be distributed from the fund to the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority and regional transit authorities:  (1) $160,000,000 to the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority or any fund controlled by the authority in each fiscal year; and  (2) $15,000,000 to regional transit authorities organized under chapter 161B or predecessor statutes in each fiscal year.
Chapter 29: Commonwealth Transportation Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  (a) There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Commonwealth Transportation Fund, which shall be used exclusively for financing transportation-related purposes. There shall be credited to the fund all fees received by the registrar of motor vehicles under section 34 of chapter 90, all receipts paid into the treasury of the commonwealth and directed to be credited to the Commonwealth Transportation Fund under chapters 64A, 64E, 64F and any other applicable general or special law and all amounts appropriated into the fund by the general court. The fund shall be subject to appropriation and shall be used for transportation related expenses of the executive office of transportation or any successor agency or authority, including to pay or reimburse the General Fund for payment of debt service on bonds issued by, or otherwise payable under a lease or other contract assistance agreement by, the commonwealth for transportation purposes.  (b) Notwithstanding subsection (a), the crediting of receipts from the tax imposed under chapter 64A to the fund shall not affect the obligations of the commonwealth relating to notes issued under sections 9 to 10D, inclusive, of chapter 11 of the acts of 1997 and the pledge of receipts from the portion of the tax per gallon imposed under said chapter 64A equal to 10 cents per gallon, to secure the payment of such bonds under the circumstances described in the trust agreements relating to such notes is hereby ratified and confirmed in all respects and shall remain in full force and effect as long as any such notes issued as of July 1, 2009 remain outstanding under their terms and secured by funds in the fund.  (c) In addition to those revenues credited to the fund under subsection (a) there shall be credited to the fund all monies received by the commonwealth equal to .385 percent of the receipts from sales, as defined by chapter 64H, and .385 per cent of the sales price of purchases, as defined by chapter 64I, from that portion of the taxes imposed under said chapters 64H and 64I as excises upon the sale and use at retail of tangible property or of services, and upon the storage, use or other consumption of tangible property, or of services, including interest thereon or penalties, but not including any portion of the taxes that constitute special receipts within the meaning of subsection (b1/2) of section 10 of chapter 152 of the acts of 1997 or within the meaning of said subsection (b1/2); provided, however, that if in a fiscal year the amount credited to the fund under this subsection is less than $275,000,000, then the comptroller shall transfer an amount from the General Fund to make up the difference between the amount credited to the fund and $275,000,000, not later than September 1 of the following fiscal year.  (d) Not less than the following amounts shall annually be distributed from the fund to the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority and regional transit authorities:  (1) $160,000,000 to the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority or any fund controlled by the authority in each fiscal year; and  (2) $15,000,000 to regional transit authorities organized under chapter 161B or predecessor statutes in each fiscal year.
    </text>
</law>