<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23A" order_by="23A" level="3">Department Of Economic Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Financial Assistance Program For Tourist Promotion Agencies</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     geographical size and population served by such agency;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     amount of matching funds from nongovernmental sources;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Assurance that the funded proposal will be in addition to the work currently being done by the agency and that the agency will maintain a continued effort of the funded program;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     demonstrated effectiveness of agency;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     integration of agency’s tourism promotion plans with other private and public agency plans.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the agency shall have made application to tourism for such grant, and shall have set forth the program proposed to be undertaken for the purpose of encouraging and stimulation tourist, convention, visitor and vacation business. The application shall further state, with evidence satisfactory to tourism, the amount of nongovernmental funds held by or committed or subscribed to the agency for application to the proposals herein described and the amount of the grant for which application is made;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     tourism, after review of the application, shall be satisfied that the program of the agency appears to be in accord with the purpose of this section, and shall authorize the making of a grant to such agency;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the maximum received by a private nonprofit agency shall be no greater than the amount received by that agency from nongovernmental sources.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>