<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="100A" order_by="100A" level="3">Motor Vehicle Damage Repair Shops</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 1, 2012. For text effective November 1, 2012, see below.]  As used in this chapter, the following words, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, shall have the following meanings:  "Deputy director'', the deputy director of standards in the office of consumer affairs and business regulation.  "Registered motor vehicle repair shop'', a motor vehicle repair shop which has a current valid certificate of registration issued hereunder.  "Motor vehicle repair'', the business or act of repairing damaged motor vehicles in the commonwealth for compensation.  "Motor vehicle repair shop'', any person or entity which, for compensation, or with the intention or expectation of receiving the same, repairs or undertakes to repair in the commonwealth a damaged motor vehicle as defined in section thirty-four A of chapter ninety.  "Person'', individuals, associations, partnerships and corporations, and the officers, directors and employees of a corporation.  "Unregistered motor vehicle repair shop'', a motor vehicle repair shop which does not have a current valid certificate of registration issued hereunder, which has had its registration revoked or suspended, or which has surrendered its certificate of registration hereunder.
Chapter 100A: Definitions
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 208, Sec. 1 effective November 1, 2012. For text effective until November 1, 2012, see above.]  As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:--  "Deputy director'', the deputy director of the division of standards within the office of standards of consumer affairs and business regulation.  "Motor vehicle glass repair'', the business or act of repairing or replacing damaged or undamaged glass in motor vehicles for compensation.  "Motor vehicle glass repair shop'', a person or entity which, for compensation or with the intention or expectation of receiving the same, repairs or replaces or undertakes to repair or replace motor vehicle glass.  "Motor vehicle repair'', the business or act of repairing damaged motor vehicles for compensation, excluding motor vehicle glass repair.  "Motor vehicle repair shop'', a person or entity which, for compensation, or with the intention or expectation of receiving the same, repairs or undertakes to repair in the commonwealth a damaged motor vehicle as defined in section 34A of chapter 90, excluding motor vehicle glass repair.  "Person'', an individual, association, partnership or corporation and the officers, directors and employees of a corporation.  "Registered motor vehicle glass repair shop'', a motor vehicle glass repair shop which has a current valid certificate of registration for motor vehicle glass repair issued under this chapter.  "Registered motor vehicle repair shop'', a motor vehicle repair shop which has a current valid certificate of registration for motor vehicle repair issued under this chapter.  "Unregistered motor vehicle glass repair shop'', a motor vehicle glass repair shop that does not have a current valid certificate of registration issued under this chapter, which has had its registration revoked or suspended or which has surrendered its certificate of registration under this chapter.  "Unregistered motor vehicle repair shop'', a motor vehicle repair shop that does not have a current valid certificate of registration issued under this chapter, which has had its registration revoked or suspended or which has surrendered its certificate of registration under this chapter.
    </text>
</law>