<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="121A" order_by="121A" level="3">Urban Redevelopment Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Contracts With Cities Or Towns Relative To Public And Private Ways, Sidewalks, Parks And Other Public Improvements; Contracts For Sale, Lease Or Exchange Of Real Estate</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        Any such corporation, in accordance with the provisions of section six, may enter into a contract with the city or town in which its project has been authorized, or with the appropriate board or officer of such city or town, and any such city or town or such board or officer may enter into a contract with such a corporation, by which such city, town, board or officer obligates itself or himself to do any or all of the following things: (a) lay out and construct, alter, relocate, change the grade of, make specific repairs upon or discontinue, public ways and construct sidewalks, adjacent to or through a project, if such action is found to be required by the common necessity and convenience; (b) cause parks, playgrounds or schools, or water, sewer or drainage facilities, or any other public improvements which it is otherwise authorized to undertake, to be laid out, constructed or furnished adjacent to or in connection with a project; (c) cause private ways, sidewalks, footpaths, ways for vehicular travel, playgrounds, or water, sewer or drainage facilities and similar improvements, to be constructed or furnished within the site of a project for the particular use of a project or of those dwelling therein. 
If any city or town or a corporation wholly owned or controlled by such city or town has acquired or is about to acquire real estate by purchase or eminent domain for purposes of urban redevelopment or similar purposes, such city or town, or such corporation, may enter into a contract with a corporation organized under section three for the purchase, sale, lease or exchange of real estate held by either of the parties to such contract, in order to more effectively carry out the provisions of this chapter. 
A contract under this section between a city or town or a corporation wholly owned or controlled by a city or town, and a corporation organized under section three, shall not be subject to any provision of law relating to publication or to advertising for bids. The construction of a project under this chapter shall be subject to the provisions of sections twenty-six to twenty-seven D, inclusive, of chapter one hundred and forty-nine.
    </text>
</law>