<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="3">Department Of Transitional Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>30</section_number>
    <catch_line>Overpayments Of Assistance; Repayment Agreement; Assignment Of Income</catch_line>
    <order_by>30</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     This section shall apply to the collection of overpayments of financial assistance paid by the department to persons receiving benefits under any program of such assistance administered by the department. An overpayment obligation is one established by a judgment or order of a court, by an administrative hearing decision of the department, or by voluntary agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     At the time of the assignment, the obligor shall inform the department of the name and address of his employer, and shall notify the employer of the existence of the assignment. The department shall then notify the employer whether the assignment is in effect under subsection (c). When the obligor changes employers, the obligor shall notify the department, within three days after beginning the new employment, and shall notify the employer of the assignment. The department shall then transfer the assignment to the subsequent employer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Such assignment shall take effect immediately when the obligor is found in violation or contempt of an order, judgment, hearing decision or agreement. Such assignment shall also take effect immediately in all other cases, unless the court or the department finds good cause exists to order that the assignment be suspended and makes written findings in support of suspension. If the department suspends such assignment, the department shall inform the obligor that under the provisions of subsection (d), such assignment, even if suspended, will take effect without further hearing if an arrearage accrues as described in subparagraph (1) or (2).
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     when a total arrearage equaling the amount owed for a sixty-day period has accrued; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     in cases where payment is to be made once per month, thirty days after the payment is missed; or,
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     at the request of the obligor at any time prior to the accrual of an arrearage described in subparagraph (1) or (2).
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     When the department determines that an arrearage has accrued it shall immediately send the notice of assignment to the obligor’s employer and shall send a notice to the obligor.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The assignment shall begin on the first payment of income that occurs more than three days after an employer receives notice of the assignment and shall continue until the obligor ceases employment or the employer is notified by the department that the assignment should be terminated.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     An employer shall send the amount required by the assignment to the department within three days after the day the obligor is paid.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     An employer may deduct from said earnings a sum not exceeding one dollar per pay period per obligor as reimbursement for costs incurred in processing any assignment, and may submit to the department a single check covering all employees whose income is assigned along with a statement enumerating each employee’s obligation and amount paid.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     If any employer fails to comply with an order of income assignment executed pursuant to this section the court may summon the employer to appear in court and show cause why the employer should not be held in civil contempt for failure to obey said order. Said employer shall also be liable to the department in a civil action, action for contempt, or other appropriate proceeding for the full amount of the income assigned and a civil penalty of five hundred dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     If the obligor ceases employment, the employer shall notify the department of the employee’s departure and any subsequent employer, if known, prior to the time that the next payment to the department is due. Any subsequent employer of the obligor shall, upon notice of an income assignment, comply with the provisions of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The obligor may also request a hearing, under the same procedure and with the same notice, if the obligor contends that the total arrears owing is incorrect. If the court or hearing officer determines at the hearing that the total amount of arrears calculated is erroneous, the amount calculated shall be adjusted to correct the amount.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Each obligor making payments to the department under this section shall be sent a notice describing: the obligor’s duty to report changes in address or employment under subsection (b), the suspended income assignment under subsection (c), the obligor’s right to a hearing under subsection (e), and the obligor’s right to access to the information compiled on this case at the time when the obligation was established, and once each year thereafter.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>