<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="25A" order_by="25A" level="3">Division Of Energy Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Contracts For Procurement Of Energy Management Services</catch_line>
    <order_by>11C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A state agency or building authority may, in the manner provided by this section, contract for the procurement of energy management services. Such contracts may include terms of not more than 20 years. The state agency or building authority shall solicit competitive sealed proposals through a request for proposals. At least 1 week prior to soliciting proposals for a contract under this section, the agency or authority shall notify the commissioner in writing, in such form and including such information as the commissioner shall prescribe by regulation, of the intent to solicit proposals. Such notification shall, at a minimum, include a complete copy of the request for proposals. An acknowledgment of receipt, in such form and including such information as the commissioner shall prescribe by regulation, shall be issued to the state agency or building authority upon successful compliance with the requirements of this paragraph.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A local governmental body may, in the manner provided in this subsection, contract for the procurement of energy management services. Unless no other manner of description suffices, and the local governmental body so determines in writing, setting forth the basis for the determination, all requirements shall be written in a manner which describes the requirements to be met without having the effect of exclusively requiring a proprietary supply or service, or a procurement from a sole source.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The state agency, building authority or local governmental body may cancel a request for proposals or may reject in whole or in part any and all proposals when the state agency, building authority or local governmental body determines that cancellation or rejection serves the best interests of the state agency, building authority or local governmental body. The state agency, building authority or local governmental body shall state in writing the reason for a cancellation or rejection. The state agency, building authority or local governmental body shall promptly publish in the central register notice of the offeror awarded the contract. The state agency, building authority or local governmental body shall, within 30 days, file a copy of the contract with the commissioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The commissioner shall enforce the requirements of this section and regulations adopted hereunder as they relate to local governmental bodies and shall have all the necessary powers to require compliance. The commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall enforce all such regulations as they relate to state agencies and building authorities, except quasi-public agencies. An order of the commissioner under this subsection shall be effective and may be enforced according to its terms, and enforcement thereof shall not be suspended or stayed by the entry of an appeal therefrom. The superior court for Suffolk county shall have jurisdiction over appeals of orders of the commissioner under this subsection, and shall also have jurisdiction upon application of the commissioner to enforce all orders of the commissioner under this subsection. The burden of proof shall be upon the appealing party to show that an order of the commissioner is invalid. An aggrieved person shall not be required to seek an order from the commissioner as a condition precedent to seeking any other remedy.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>