<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118E" order_by="118E" level="3">Division Of Medical Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Medical Care Advisory Committee; Member; Staff; Report From Office Of Medicaid</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a medical care advisory committee which shall advise the executive office about health and medical care services. The committee shall have the opportunity to participate in policy development and program administration. The secretary of health and human services shall appoint members to the advisory committee on a rotating and continuous basis in such numbers and for such terms as the secretary of health and human services deems appropriate; provided that the committee shall include board-certified physicians and other representatives of the health professions who are familiar with the medical needs of low-income population groups and with the resources available and required for their care, members of consumers’ groups, including medical assistance recipients, and the commissioner of the department of public welfare. 
The executive office shall provide the committee with such staff and technical assistance as is necessary to enable the committee to make effective recommendations, and such financial arrangements as are necessary to make possible the participation of recipient members. 
The office of Medicaid shall make a report to the committee on health care financing and to house and senate committees on ways and means no later than October 1 of each year on the previous state fiscal year’s activities of the medical care advisory committee. The report shall include, but not be limited to, the names and titles of committee members, dates of committee meetings, agendas and minutes or notes from such meetings, and any correspondence, memorandum, recommendations or other product of the committee’s work.
    </text>
</law>