<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24L</section_number>
    <catch_line>Serious Bodily Injury By Motor Vehicle While Under Influence Of Intoxicating Substance; Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>24L</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Whoever, upon any way or in any place to which the public has a right of access, or upon any way or in any place to which members of the public have access as invitees or licensees, operates a motor vehicle with a percentage, by weight, of alcohol in their blood of eight one-hundredths or greater, or while under the influence of intoxicating liquor, or marihuana, narcotic drugs, depressants, or stimulant substances, all as defined in section one of chapter ninety-four C, or the vapors of glue, and so operates a motor vehicle recklessly or negligently so that the lives or safety of the public might be endangered, and by any such operation so described causes serious bodily injury, shall be punished by imprisonment in the state prison for not less than two and one-half years nor more than ten years and by a fine of not more than five thousand dollars, or by imprisonment in a jail or house of correction for not less than six months nor more than two and one-half years and by a fine of not more than five thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Whoever, upon any way or in any place to which the public has a right of access or upon any way or in any place to which members of the public have access as invitees or licensees, operates a motor vehicle with a percentage, by weight, of alcohol in their blood of eight one-hundredths or greater, or while under the influence of intoxicating liquor, or of marihuana, narcotic drugs, depressants or stimulant substances, all as defined in section one of chapter ninety-four C, or vapors of glue, and by any such operation causes serious bodily injury, shall be punished by imprisonment in a jail or house of correction for not more than two and one-half years, or by a fine of not less than three thousand dollars, or both.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     For the purposes of this section “serious bodily injury” shall mean bodily injury which creates a substantial risk of death or which involves either total disability or the loss or substantial impairment of some bodily function for a substantial period of time.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The registrar shall revoke the license or right to operate of a person convicted of a violation of subdivision (1) or (2) for a period of two years after the date of conviction. No appeal, motion for new trial or exception shall operate to stay the revocation of the license or the right to operate; provided, however, such license shall be restored or such right to operate shall be reinstated if the prosecution of such person ultimately terminates in favor of the defendant.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>