<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32" order_by="32" level="3">Retirement Systems And Pensions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assignment Of Retirement Allowances For Payment Of Certain Subscriber Premiums, Income Taxes Or Support Orders; Deduction For Payment Of Premiums For Coverage Under Chapter 32 B</catch_line>
    <order_by>19A</order_by>
    <text>
        [First paragraph applicable as provided by 2009, 21, Sec. 26.] 
Any employee of the commonwealth, a city, town, district or other member unit of a retirement system who is retired under this chapter shall, upon the request of the retiring authority paying such pension or retirement allowance, or otherwise may, by assignment made in writing authorize the retiring authority paying such pension or retirement allowance to withhold each month such amount as he may designate for the payment of subscriber premiums applicable to any hospitalization, medical or surgical insurance in effect with a nonprofit hospital and medical service corporation or insurance company at the time of his retirement. In the event that the amount of a retiree’s pension check is insufficient to accommodate the entire deduction and upon notice from the retirement board, the employer for whom the retiree last worked and from whom he is retired shall bill the retiree for the employee share of the premiums. 
Any member retired under this chapter may by assignment made in writing authorize the retirement board paying such pension or retirement allowance to withhold each month such amount as he may designate for the payment of income taxes levied under the Internal Revenue Code of the United States and the amount designated shall be transmitted and paid quarterly by the treasurer-custodian of any system to the government of the United States. 
Any member retired under this chapter may by assignment made in writing authorize the retirement board paying such pension or retirement allowance to withhold each month such amount as he may designate for the payment of a child support order, issued under chapter 208, 209, 209A, 209C or 273, or received, entered, or registered pursuant to chapter 209D, and the amount designated shall be transmitted and paid monthly by the treasurer or custodian of any system to the IV-D agency. Nothing in this section shall preclude the IV-D agency from executing an order to withhold income from a member’s retirement allowance, pursuant to section 12 of chapter 119A. 
A retirement board in the case of a retiree may deduct the per cent contribution of health insurance premiums for all retired members receiving group life insurance, group accidental death and dismemberment insurance, group general or blanket hospital, surgical, medical, dental or other health insurance coverage under chapter 32B from the respective retiree pension check. In the event that the amount of a retiree’s pension check is insufficient to accommodate the entire deduction and upon notice from the retirement board, the employer for whom the retiree last worked and from whom he is retired shall bill the retiree for the employee share of the premiums.
    </text>
</law>