<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="78" order_by="78" level="3">Libraries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Library Media Services; Comprehensive Statewide Program; Funds;  Standards</catch_line>
    <order_by>19E</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     for the establishment of the Boston public library as a statewide reference and referral center for Massachusetts libraries;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     for the establishment and development of cooperation and coordination among libraries, including the authority to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     provide coordination and administration of cooperative statewide programs of services and statewide coordination of regional programs;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     provide for identification, maintenance, development and preservation of critical research collections;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     provide statewide access to specialized information resources, research collections and specialized reference and information services;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     participate in interstate library services if such participation will increase the availability of library services;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     provide statewide delivery services;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     provide statewide interlibrary loan services;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     provide education, training and technical advisory services; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     provide funding for grants for projects that demonstrate innovative uses of technology, interlibrary cooperation or shared services delivery to improve information delivery to library users.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     the type of institution;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     the size of the resident population;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     the availability of library media services to the institutional population;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     the qualifications of personnel for staffing of a library media center;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     the institution’s commitment to annual budgetary support for library media services.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     the establishment and development of library media services and centers for persons whose native language is not English. The board shall establish standards for such services and centers;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     the development of library media services for the elderly, the unemployed, the poor, the functionally illiterate, and those persons who have cultural, social, or educational disadvantages that prevent them from using library media centers and services designed for persons without said disadvantages;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     the establishment and development of library media services for persons who are visually impaired, mentally, physically, or emotionally handicapped.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>