<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132B" order_by="132B" level="3">Massachusetts Pesticide Control Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Registration</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        Pesticides, including pesticides that are federally registered may be registered by the subcommittee of the pesticide board for use in the commonwealth. 
Each applicant for the registration of a pesticide shall annually file with the subcommittee an application providing thereon such information as said subcommittee shall require. Said subcommittee may require of applicants for pesticide registrations any information that it deems necessary to determine whether, or how, the pesticide should be registered. 
An applicant desiring to register or reregister a pesticide shall pay such registration fee, not to exceed twenty-five dollars, as said subcommittee may by regulation require. All pesticide registrations shall be for a period not to exceed one year. 
In the event that any person files with said subcommittee an application to reregister a pesticide which is registered on the date of application for reregistration and pays the appropriate fee therewith, such registration shall be deemed to be in effect until the earlier of the following two events shall occur, ninety days have elapsed after the registration was scheduled to expire, or the subcommittee notifies the applicant for reregistration that the registration has been renewed, modified or denied. 
If said subcommittee determines that a pesticide, when used in accordance with its directions for use, warnings and cautions and for the uses for which it is registered, or for one or more such uses, or in accordance with a widespread and commonly recognized practice, will not generally cause unreasonable adverse effects on the environment, it may classify the pesticide, or the particular use or uses of the pesticide to which the determination applies, as being for general use. 
If said subcommittee determines that a pesticide, when used in accordance with its directions for use, warnings and cautions and for the use for which it is registered, or for one or more of such uses, or in accordance with a widespread and commonly recognized practice, may cause, without additional restrictions, unreasonable adverse effects on the environment, including injury to the applicator, it may classify the pesticide or the particular use or uses to which the determination applies, for restricted use. 
Said subcommittee shall register a pesticide if it determines that its composition is such as to warrant the proposed claims for it; its labeling and other material required to be submitted comply with the requirements of this chapter; it will perform its intended function without unreasonable adverse effects on the environment; and when used in accordance with widespread and commonly recognized practice it will not generally cause unreasonable adverse effects on the environment. 
As part of the registration of a pesticide, said subcommittee may require that the pesticide be colored or discolored if such requirement is necessary for the protection of health or the environment, may classify for restricted use any pesticide or pesticide use classified for general use under FIFRA, and may include in the registration such conditions of use as it deems necessary. 
If at any time it appears that a pesticide registration does not comply with the provisions of FIFRA, this chapter, or rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, or when used as registered, or a pesticide may cause unreasonable adverse effects on the environment, or a registered pesticide is an imminent hazard, the subcommittee as established in section three A, may, forthwith by an order suspend the registration of such pesticide. Notification of such order shall be sent to the applicant and shall be a public record.
    </text>
</law>