<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22B.5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions Applicable To Secs. 22 C To 22 F</catch_line>
    <order_by>22B.5</order_by>
    <text>
          For the purposes of sections 22C to 22F, inclusive, unless a contrary intention clearly appears, the following words shall have the following meanings:  "Comparable low bid or offer'', a responsive and responsible bid or offer which is not more than 10 per cent greater than the lowest bid or offer submitted for goods or services.  "Essential'', necessary in order that a state agency or state authority may perform its mission, there being no substitute, to avoid irreparable, harm to the agency or authority programs.  "Person'', an individual, partnership, firm, association, corporation or other entity or a subsidiary thereof.  "Secretary'', the secretary of administration and finance.  "State agency'', awarding authorities of the commonwealth including, but not limited to, executive offices, agencies, departments, commissions and public institutions of higher education.[ Definition of "State authority'' effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  "State authority'' shall include, but not be limited to: the Bay State Skills Corporation, Centers of Excellence, Community Economic Development Assistance Corporation, Community Development Finance Corporation, government land bank, Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority, Massachusetts Business Development Corporation, Massachusetts Capital Resource Company, Massachusetts Convention Center Authority, Massachusetts Corporation for Educational Telecommunications, Massachusetts Educational Loan Authority, Massachusetts Health and Educational Facilities Authority, Massachusetts Higher Education Assistance Corporation, Massachusetts Housing Finance Agency, Massachusetts Industrial Finance Agency, Massachusetts Industrial Service Program, Massachusetts Legal Assistance Corporation, Massachusetts Port Authority, Massachusetts Product Development Corporation, Massachusetts Technology Development Corporation, Massachusetts Technology Park Corporation, Massachusetts Department of Transportation, Massachusetts Water Resource Authority, Nantucket Land Bank, New England Loan Marketing Corporation, Pension Reserves Investment Management Board, State College Building Authority, Southeastern Massachusetts University Building Authority, Thrift Institutions Fund for Economic Development, University of Lowell Building Authority, University of Massachusetts Building Authority, Victim and Witness Assistance Board, and the Woods Hole, Martha's Vineyard and Nantucket Steamship Authority.[ Definition of "State authority'' as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 58 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  "State authority'', as defined in section 1 of chapter 29.
    </text>
</law>