<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>178K</section_number>
    <catch_line>Sex Offender Registry Board; Member Qualifications; Guidelines To Assess Risk Of Reoffense; Notification</catch_line>
    <order_by>178K</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     There shall be, in the executive office of public safety and security, a sex offender registry board which shall consist of seven members who shall be appointed by the governor for terms of six years, with the exception of the chairman, and who shall devote their full time during business hours to their official duties. The board shall include one person with experience and knowledge in the field of criminal justice who shall act as chairman; at least two licensed psychologists or psychiatrists with special expertise in the assessment and evaluation of sex offenders and who have knowledge of the forensic mental health system; at least one licensed psychologist or psychiatrist with special expertise in the assessment and evaluation of sex offenders, including juvenile sex offenders and who has knowledge of the forensic mental health system; at least two persons who have at least five years of training and experience in probation, parole or corrections; and at least one person who has expertise or experience with victims of sexual abuse. Members shall be compensated at a reasonable rate subject to approval of the secretary of administration and finance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     criminal history factors indicative of a high risk of reoffense and degree of dangerousness posed to the public, including:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     whether the sex offender has a mental abnormality;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     whether the sex offender’s conduct is characterized by repetitive and compulsive behavior;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     whether the sex offender was an adult who committed a sex offense on a child;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     the age of the sex offender at the time of the commission of the first sex offense;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     whether the sex offender has been adjudicated to be a sexually dangerous person pursuant to section 14 of chapter 123A or is a person released from civil commitment pursuant to section 9 of said chapter 123A; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     whether the sex offender served the maximum term of incarceration;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     other criminal history factors to be considered in determining risk and degree of dangerousness, including:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     the relationship between the sex offender and the victim;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     whether the offense involved the use of a weapon, violence or infliction of bodily injury;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     the number, date and nature of prior offenses;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     conditions of release that minimize risk of reoffense and degree of dangerousness posed to the public, including whether the sex offender is under probation or parole supervision, whether such sex offender is receiving counseling, therapy or treatment and whether such sex offender is residing in a home situation that provides guidance and supervision, including sex offender-specific treatment in a community-based residential program;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     physical conditions that minimize risk of reoffense including, but not limited to, debilitating illness;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     whether the sex offender was a juvenile when he committed the offense, his response to treatment and subsequent criminal history;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     whether psychological or psychiatric profiles indicate a risk of recidivism;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     the sex offender’s history of alcohol or substance abuse;
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     the sex offender’s participation in sex offender treatment and counseling while incarcerated or while on probation or parole and his response to such treatment or counseling;
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     recent behavior, including behavior while incarcerated or while supervised on probation or parole;
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     recent threats against persons or expressions of intent to commit additional offenses;
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     review of any victim impact statement; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     review of any materials submitted by the sex offender, his attorney or others on behalf of such offender.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The guidelines shall provide for three levels of notification depending on the degree of risk of reoffense and the degree of dangerousness posed to the public by the sex offender or for relief from the obligation to register:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Where the board determines that the risk of reoffense is low and the degree of dangerousness posed to the public is not such that a public safety interest is served by public availability, it shall give a level 1 designation to the sex offender. In such case, the board shall transmit the registration data and designation to the police departments in the municipalities where such sex offender lives and works and attends an institution of higher learning or, if in custody, intends to live and work and attend an institution of higher learning upon release and where the offense was committed and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The police shall not disseminate information to the general public identifying the sex offender where the board has classified the individual as a level 1 sex offender. The police and the board may, however, release such information identifying such sex offender to the department of correction, any county correctional facility, the department of youth services, the department of children and families, the parole board, the department of probation and the department of mental health, all city and town police departments and the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Where the board determines that the risk of reoffense is moderate and the degree of dangerousness posed to the public is such that a public safety interest is served by public availability of registration information, it shall give a level 2 designation to the sex offender. In such case, the board shall transmit the registration data and designation to the police departments in the municipalities where the sex offender lives, has a secondary address and works and attends an institution of higher learning or, if in custody, intends to live and work and attend an institution of higher learning upon release and where the offense was committed and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The public shall have access to the information regarding a level 2 offender in accordance with the provisions of sections 178I and 178J. The sex offender shall be required to register and to verify registration information pursuant to section 178F1/2.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Where the board determines that the risk of reoffense is high and the degree of dangerousness posed to the public is such that a substantial public safety interest is served by active dissemination, it shall give a level 3 designation to the sex offender. In such case, the board shall transmit the registration data and designation to the police departments in the municipalities where the sex offender lives, has a secondary address and works and attends an institution of higher learning or, if in custody, intends to live and work and attend an institution of higher learning upon release and where the offense was committed and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. A level 3 community notification plan shall require the police department to notify organizations in the community which are likely to encounter such sex offender and individual members of the public who are likely to encounter such sex offender. The sex offender shall be required to register and to verify registration information pursuant to sections 178F1/2. Neighboring police districts shall share sex offender registration information of level 3 offenders and may inform the residents of their municipality of a sex offender they are likely to encounter who resides in an adjacent city or town. The police or the board shall actively disseminate in such time and manner as such police department or board deems reasonably necessary the following information:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     the name of the sex offender;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     the offender’s home address and any secondary address;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     the offender’s work address;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     the offense for which the offender was convicted or adjudicated and the date of the conviction or adjudication;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     the sex offender’s age, sex, race, height, weight, eye and hair color; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     a photograph of the sex offender, if available; provided, that such active dissemination may include publication of such information on the internet by the police department at such time and in such manner as the police or the board deem reasonably necessary; and provided further, that the police or the board shall not release information identifying the victim by name, address or relation to the sex offender. All notices to the community shall include a warning regarding the criminal penalties for use of sex offender registry information to commit a crime or to engage in illegal discrimination or harassment of an offender and the punishment for threatening to commit a crime under section 4 of chapter 275.
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     the name and address of the institution of higher learning that the sex offender is attending.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The board may, upon making specific written findings that the circumstances of the offense in conjunction with the offender’s criminal history do not indicate a risk of reoffense or a danger to the public and the reasons therefor, relieve such sex offender of any further obligation to register, shall remove such sex offender’s registration information from the registry and shall so notify the police departments where said sex offender lives and works or if in custody intends to live and work upon release, and where the offense was committed and the Federal Bureau of Investigation. In making such determination the board shall consider factors, including but not limited to, the presence or absence of any physical harm caused by the offense and whether the offense involved consensual conduct between adults. The burden of proof shall be on the offender to prove he comes within the provisions of this subsection. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply if a sex offender has been determined to be a sexually violent predator; has been convicted of two or more sex offenses defined as sex offenses pursuant to the Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children and Sexually Violent Offender Registration Act, 42 U.S.C. section 14071, committed on different occasions; or has been convicted of a sexually violent offense. The provisions of this subsection shall also not apply if a sex offender has been convicted of a sex offense involving a child or a sexually violent offense, and such offender has not already registered pursuant to this chapter for at least ten years, or if the sex offender is otherwise subject to lifetime or minimum registration requirements as determined by the board pursuant to section 178D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     No sex offender classified as a level 3 offender shall knowingly and willingly establish living conditions within, move to, or transfer to any convalescent or nursing home, infirmary maintained in a town, rest home, charitable home for the aged or intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded which meets the requirements of the department of public health under section 71 of chapter 111. Any sex offender who violates this paragraph shall, for a first conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 30 days in a jail or house of correction; for a second conviction, be punished by imprisonment for not more than 21/2 years in a jail or house of correction nor more than 5 years in a state prison or by a fine of not more than $1,000, or by both such fine and imprisonment; and for a third and subsequent conviction, be punished by imprisonment in a state prison for not less than 5 years; provided, however, that the sentence imposed for such third or subsequent conviction shall not be reduced to less than 5 years, nor suspended, nor shall any person sentenced herein be eligible for probation, parole, work release or furlough, or receive any deduction from his sentence for good conduct until he shall have served 5 years. Prosecutions commenced hereunder shall neither be continued without a finding nor placed on file.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The sex offender registry board shall make a determination regarding the level of risk of reoffense and the degree of dangerousness posed to the public of each sex offender listed in said sex offender registry and shall give immediate priority to those offenders who have been convicted of a sex offense involving a child or convicted or adjudicated as a delinquent juvenile or as a youthful offender by reason of a sexually violent offense or of a sex offense of indecent assault and battery upon a mentally retarded person pursuant to section 13F of chapter 265, and who have not been sentenced to incarceration for at least 90 days, followed, in order of priority, by those sex offenders who (1) have been released from incarceration within the past 12 months, (2) are currently on parole or probation supervision, and (3) are scheduled to be released from incarceration within six months. All agencies shall cooperate in providing files to the sex offender registry board and any information the sex offender registry board deems useful in providing notice under sections 178C to 178P, inclusive, and in assessing the risk of reoffense and the degree of dangerousness posed to the public by the sex offender. All agencies from which registration data, including data within the control of providers under contract to such agencies, is requested by the sex offender registry board shall make such data available to said board immediately upon request. Failure to comply in good faith with such a request within 30 days shall be punishable by a fine of not more than $1,000 per day.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>