<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="57" order_by="57" level="3">Congressional, Councillor And Senatorial Districts, And Apportionment Of Representatives</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Division Of State Into Senatorial Districts</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 3, 2011. For text effective November 3, 2011, see below.]  For the purposes of choosing senators, and of electing members of state committees of political parties as provided in section 1 of chapter 52, until the next apportionment, the commonwealth is divided, conformably with the constitution, into the following 40 senatorial districts:  Berkshire, Hampshire, and Franklin--Consisting of the cities and towns in the county of Berkshire; the towns of Chesterfield, Cummington, Goshen, Huntington, Middlefield, Plainfield, Westhampton, Williamsburg and Worthington in the county of Hampshire; and the towns of Ashfield, Charlemont, Conway, Hawley, Heath, Monroe, and Rowe in the county of Franklin.  Bristol and Norfolk--Consisting of the city of Attleboro, ward 3, precinct B, ward 4, precincts A and B, ward 5, precincts A and B, ward 6, precincts A and B, and the towns of Mansfield, Norton, Rehoboth, and Seekonk in the county of Bristol; the towns of Dover, Foxborough, Medfield, Sharon, precincts 1, 4, and 5, and Walpole in the county of Norfolk.  First Bristol and Plymouth--Consisting of the city of Fall River and the towns of Freetown, Somerset, Swansea, and Westport in the county of Bristol; the towns of Lakeville and Rochester in the county of Plymouth.  Second Bristol and Plymouth--Consisting of the city of New Bedford and the towns of Acushnet, Dartmouth, and Fairhaven in the county of Bristol; and the town of Mattapoisett in the county of Plymouth.  Cape and Islands--Consisting of the towns of Barnstable, precincts 1 to 9, inclusive, and 13, Brewster, Chatham, Dennis, Eastham, Harwich, Mashpee, Orleans, Provincetown, Truro, Wellfleet, and Yarmouth in the county of Barnstable; the towns of Aquinnah, Chilmark, Edgartown, Gosnold, Oak Bluffs, Tisbury, and West Tisbury in the county of Dukes; the town of Nantucket in the county of Nantucket.  First Essex--Consisting of the cities of Haverhill and Newburyport and the towns of Amesbury, Merrimac, Methuen, North Andover, precincts 1, 4, 6, and 8, and Salisbury in the county of Essex.  Second Essex--Consisting of the cities of Beverly, Peabody and Salem and the towns of Danvers and Topsfield in the county of Essex.  First Essex and Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Gloucester and the towns of Boxford, Essex, Georgetown, Groveland, Hamilton, Ipswich, Manchester-by-the-Sea, Middleton, Newbury, North Andover, precincts 2, 3, 5, and 7, Rockport, Rowley, Wenham, and West Newbury in the county of Essex; and the towns of North Reading and Wilmington in the county of Middlesex.  Second Essex and Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Lawrence and the town of Andover in the county of Essex; and the towns of Dracut and Tewksbury in the county of Middlesex.  Third Essex and Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Lynn and the towns of Marblehead, Nahant, Saugus, precincts 1, 3 to 5, inclusive, 7 to 9, inclusive, and Swampscott in the county of Essex; the city of Melrose, ward 6 and ward 7, in the county of Middlesex.  Hampden--Consisting of the cities of Chicopee, ward 2, precincts A to D, inclusive, ward 4, precincts A to C, inclusive, ward 5, precincts A and B, and Springfield, ward 1, ward 3, ward 4, ward 5, precincts A and B, ward 6 and the towns of Agawam and West Springfield.  First Hampden and Hampshire--Consisting of the city of Springfield, ward 2, ward 5, precincts C to H, inclusive, wards 7 and 8 and the towns of East Longmeadow, Hampden, Longmeadow, Ludlow, and Wilbraham in the county of Hampden; the towns of Belchertown, precincts B and C, and Granby in the county of Hampshire.  Second Hampden and Hampshire--Consisting of the cities of Chicopee, ward 1, precincts A and B, ward 3, precincts A to C, inclusive, ward 6, precincts A and B, ward 7, precincts A and B, ward 8, precincts A and B, ward 9, precincts A and B, Holyoke, and Westfield and the towns of Blandford, Chester, Granville, Montgomery, Russell, Southwick, and Tolland, in the county of Hampden; and the towns of Easthampton and Southampton in the county of Hampshire.  Hampshire and Franklin--Consisting of the city of Northampton and the towns of Amherst, Belchertown, precincts A and D, Hadley, Hatfield, Pelham and South Hadley in the county of Hampshire; the towns of Bernardston, Buckland, Colrain, Deerfield, Erving, Gill, Greenfield, Leverett, Leyden, Montague, New Salem, Northfield, Shelburne, Shutesbury, Sunderland, Wendell and Whatley in the county of Franklin.  First Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Lowell and the towns of Dunstable, Groton, Pepperell, Tyngsborough, and Westford in the county of Middlesex.  Second Middlesex--Consisting of the cities of Medford, Somerville, ward 1, precincts 2 and 3, ward 2, precincts 2 and 3, and wards 3 to 7, inclusive, Woburn, ward 2, and the town of Winchester in the county of Middlesex.  Third Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Waltham and the towns of Bedford, Carlisle, Chelmsford, Concord, Lexington, precincts 3, 8 and 9, Lincoln, Sudbury, precincts 1 and 4, and Weston.  Fourth Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Woburn, ward 1, wards 3 to 7, inclusive, and the towns of Arlington, Billerica, Burlington, and Lexington, precincts 1 and 2 and 4 to 7, inclusive, in the county of Middlesex.  Middlesex and Essex--Consisting of the cities of Malden and Melrose, wards 1 to 5, inclusive, and the towns of Reading, Stoneham, and Wakefield in the county of Middlesex; and the town of Lynnfield in the county of Essex.  First Middlesex and Norfolk--Consisting of the city of Newton in the county of Middlesex; the towns of Brookline and Wellesley, precincts A and C to E, inclusive, in the county of Norfolk.  Second Middlesex and Norfolk--Consisting of the towns of Ashland, Framingham, Holliston, Hopkinton, and Natick, precincts 1 to 5, inclusive and 8, in the county of Middlesex; and the towns of Franklin, precincts 1 and 5 to 8, inclusive, and Medway in the county of Norfolk.  Middlesex, Suffolk, and Essex--Consisting of the cities of Cambridge, ward 3, precinct 2, ward 6, ward 7, ward 8, precincts 1 and 2, ward 9, precinct 1, ward 10, precinct 2, Everett, and Somerville ward 1, precinct 1, and ward 2, precinct 1, all in the county of Middlesex; the city of Boston, ward 2, ward 21, precincts 4, 6, and 7, ward 22, precincts 1, 2, and 5; the cities of Chelsea and Revere ward 6, all in the county of Suffolk; the town of Saugus, precincts 2, 6, and 10, all in the county of Essex.  Middlesex and Worcester--Consisting of the city of Marlborough and the towns of Acton, Ayer, Boxborough, Hudson, Littleton, Maynard, Shirley, Stow, and Sudbury, precincts 2, 3, and 5, all in the county of Middlesex; the towns of Harvard, Northborough, precinct 3, Southborough, and Westborough, all in the county of Worcester.  Norfolk, Bristol, and Plymouth--Consisting of the towns of Avon, Braintree, precincts 1, 3, 4, and 5, Canton, Milton, Randolph, Sharon, precincts 2 and 3, and Stoughton, all in the county of Norfolk; the town of Easton, precincts 3 to 6, inclusive, in the county of Bristol; and the towns of East Bridgewater, precinct 4, and West Bridgewater, all in the county of Plymouth.  Norfolk, Bristol, and Middlesex--Consisting of the towns of Franklin, precincts 2 to 4, inclusive, Millis, Needham, Norfolk, Plainville, Wellesley, precincts B, F, and G, and Wrentham, all in the county of Norfolk; the city of Attleboro, ward 1, ward 2, and ward 3, precinct A, and the town of North Attleboro, all in the county of Bristol; and the towns of Natick, precincts 6, 7, 9, and 10, Sherborn, and Wayland, all in the county of Middlesex.  Norfolk and Plymouth--Consisting of the city of Quincy and the towns of Braintree, precincts 2 and 6 to 12, inclusive, and Holbrook, all in the county of Norfolk; the towns of Abington and Rockland, all in the county of Plymouth.  Plymouth and Barnstable--Consisting of the towns of Kingston, Pembroke, Plymouth, and Plympton, all in the county of Plymouth; the towns of Barnstable, precincts 10 to 12, inclusive, Bourne, Falmouth, and Sandwich, all in the county of Barnstable.  First Plymouth and Bristol--Consisting of the towns of Bridgewater, Carver, Marion, Middleborough, and Wareham, all in the county of Plymouth; the towns of Berkley, Dighton, and Raynham, and the city of Taunton, all in the county of Bristol.  Second Plymouth and Bristol--Consisting of the city of Brockton, the towns of East Bridgewater, precincts 1 to 3, inclusive, Halifax, Hanover, Hanson, and Whitman, all in the county of Plymouth; and the town of Easton, precincts 1 and 2, in the county of Bristol.  Plymouth and Norfolk--Consisting of the towns of Duxbury, Hingham, Hull, Marshfield, Norwell, and Scituate, all in the county of Plymouth; the towns of Cohasset and Weymouth, all in the county of Norfolk.  First Suffolk--Consisting of the city of Boston, ward 1, precinct 15, ward 6, ward 7, ward 13, ward 14, precincts 1, 2, 4, 5, and 12 to 14, inclusive, ward 15, ward 16, ward 17, ward 18, precincts 1 to 6, inclusive, and 21, all in the county of Suffolk.  Second Suffolk--Consisting of the city of Boston, ward 3, precincts 7 and 8, ward 4, precincts 1 to 6, inclusive, 8, and 9, ward 5, precincts 1, 4 to 8, inclusive, and 11, ward 8, ward 9, ward 10, ward 11, ward 12, ward 14, precincts 3, 6 to 11, inclusive, and ward 19, precincts 1 to 9, inclusive, all in the county of Suffolk.  First Suffolk and Middlesex--Consisting of the cities of Boston, ward 1, precincts 1 to 14, inclusive, ward 3, precincts 1 to 6, inclusive, and ward 5, precinct 3, Revere, wards 1 to 5, inclusive, and the town of Winthrop, all in the county of Suffolk; the city of Cambridge, wards 1 and 2, ward 3, precincts 1 and 3, wards 4 and 5, and ward 8, precinct 3, all in the county of Middlesex.  Second Suffolk and Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Boston, ward 4, precincts 7 and 10, ward 5, precincts 2, 9, and 10, ward 21, precincts 1 to 3, inclusive, and 5, and 8 to 16, inclusive, ward 22, precincts 3 and 4, and 6 to 13, inclusive, all in the county of Suffolk; the city of Cambridge, ward 9, precincts 2 and 3, ward 10, precincts 1 and 3, and ward 11, and the towns of Belmont and Watertown, all in the county of Middlesex.  Suffolk and Norfolk--Consisting of the city of Boston, ward 18, precincts 7 to 20, inclusive, 22, and 23, ward 19, precincts 10 to 13, inclusive, and ward 20, all in the county of Suffolk; the towns of Dedham, Norwood, and Westwood, all in the county of Norfolk.  First Worcester--Consisting of the towns of Berlin, Boylston, Clinton, precincts 3 and 4; Holden, Northborough, precincts 1, 2, and 4; Paxton, Princeton, West Boylston, and the city of Worcester, wards 1 to 4, inclusive, 9 and 10, all in the county of Worcester.  Second Worcester--Consisting of the towns of Auburn, Grafton, Leicester, Millbury, Shrewsbury, Upton, and the city of Worcester, wards 5 to 8, inclusive, all in the county of Worcester.  Worcester, Hampden, Hampshire, and Franklin--Consisting of the towns of Ashburnham, Athol, Barre, Brookfield, Charlton, East Brookfield, Hardwick, Hubbardston, New Braintree, North Brookfield, Oakham, Petersham, Phillipston, Royalston, Rutland, Spencer, Sturbridge, Templeton, Warren, West Brookfield, and Winchendon, all in the county of Worcester; the towns of Brimfield, Holland, Monson, Palmer, and Wales, all in the county of Hampden; the town of Ware, in the county of Hampshire; and the towns of Orange and Warwick in the county of Franklin.  Worcester and Middlesex--Consisting of the cities of Fitchburg, Gardner and Leominster and the towns of Bolton, Clinton, precincts 1 and 2, Lancaster, Lunenburg, Sterling, and Westminster, all in the county of Worcester; the towns of Townsend and Ashby in the county of Middlesex.  Worcester and Norfolk--Consisting of the towns of Blackstone, Douglas, Dudley, Hopedale, Mendon, Milford, Millville, Northbridge, Oxford, Southbridge, Sutton, Uxbridge, and Webster, all in the county of Worcester; and the town of Bellingham in the county of Norfolk.
Chapter 57: Division of state into senatorial districts
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 152, Sec. 1 effective November 3, 2011. For text effective until November 3, 2011, see above.]  For the purposes of choosing senators, and of electing members of state committees of political parties as provided in section 1 of chapter 52, until the next apportionment, the commonwealth shall be divided, conformably with the constitution, into the following 40 senatorial districts:  Berkshire, Hampshire, Franklin and Hampden--Consisting of the cities and towns in the county of Berkshire; the towns of Chesterfield, Cummington, Goshen, Huntington, Middlefield, Plainfield, Westhampton, Williamsburg and Worthington in the county of Hampshire; and the towns of Ashfield, Buckland, Charlemont, Conway, Hawley, Heath, Monroe, Rowe and Shelburne in the county of Franklin; and the towns of Blandford and Chester in the county of Hampden.  Bristol and Norfolk--Consisting of the city of Attleboro, ward 3, precinct B, ward 4, precincts A and B, ward 5, precincts A and B, ward 6, precincts A and B, and the towns of Mansfield, Norton, Rehoboth and Seekonk in the county of Bristol; and the towns of Foxborough, Medfield, Sharon, precincts 1, 4 and 5, and Walpole in the county of Norfolk.  First Bristol and Plymouth--Consisting of the city of Fall River and the towns of Freetown, Somerset, Swansea and Westport in the county of Bristol; and the towns of Lakeville and Rochester in the county of Plymouth.  Second Bristol and Plymouth--Consisting of the city of New Bedford and the towns of Acushnet, Dartmouth and Fairhaven in the county of Bristol; and the town of Mattapoisett in the county of Plymouth.  Cape and Islands--Consisting of the towns of Barnstable, Brewster, Chatham, Dennis, Eastham, Harwich, Mashpee, Orleans, Provincetown, Truro, Wellfleet and Yarmouth in the county of Barnstable; the towns of Aquinnah, Chilmark, Edgartown, Gosnold, Oak Bluffs, Tisbury and West Tisbury in the county of Dukes; and the town of Nantucket in the county of Nantucket.  First Essex--Consisting of the cities of Haverhill and Newburyport and the towns of Amesbury, Merrimac, Methuen, North Andover, precincts 1 to 4, inclusive, and Salisbury in the county of Essex.  Second Essex--Consisting of the cities of Beverly, Peabody and Salem and the towns of Danvers and Topsfield in the county of Essex.  Third Essex--Consisting of the city of Lynn and the towns of Lynnfield, Marblehead, Nahant, Saugus and Swampscott in the county of Essex.  First Essex and Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Gloucester and the towns of Boxford, Essex, Georgetown, Groveland, Hamilton, Ipswich, Manchester-by-the-Sea, Middleton, Newbury, North Andover, precincts 5 to 8, inclusive, Rockport, Rowley, Wenham and West Newbury in the county of Essex; and the towns of North Reading and Wilmington in the county of Middlesex.  Second Essex and Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Lawrence and the town of Andover in the county of Essex; and the towns of Dracut and Tewksbury in the county of Middlesex.  Hampden--Consisting of the cities of Chicopee, ward 2, precincts A and B, ward 3, precincts A and B, ward 4, precincts A and B, and Springfield, ward 1, ward 2 precincts A to F, inclusive, and H, ward 3, ward 4, precincts A to E, inclusive, G and H, ward 5, precincts A to C, inclusive, and E, ward 6, precincts A and C, and E to G, inclusive, ward 8, precincts B to H, inclusive, and the town of West Springfield in the county of Hampden.  First Hampden and Hampshire--Consisting of the cities of Chicopee, ward 1, precincts A and B, ward 5, precincts A and B, ward 6, precincts A and B, ward 8, precinct B and ward 9, precinct B and Springfield, ward 2, precinct G, ward 4, precinct F, ward 5, precincts D, F, G and H, ward 6, precincts B, D and H, ward 7 and ward 8, precinct A and the towns of East Longmeadow, Hampden, Longmeadow, Ludlow and Wilbraham in the county of Hampden; and the towns of Belchertown and Granby in the county of Hampshire.  Second Hampden and Hampshire--Consisting of the cities of Chicopee, ward 7, precincts A and B, ward 8, precinct A, ward 9, precinct A, Holyoke and Westfield and the towns of Agawam, Granville, Montgomery, Russell, Southwick and Tolland, in the county of Hampden; and the towns of Easthampton and Southampton in the county of Hampshire.  Hampshire, Franklin and Worcester--Consisting of the city of Northampton and the towns of Amherst, Hadley, Hatfield, Pelham and South Hadley in the county of Hampshire; the towns of Bernardston, Colrain, Deerfield, Erving, Gill, Greenfield, Leverett, Leyden, Montague, New Salem, Northfield, Orange, Shutesbury, Sunderland, Warwick, Wendell and Whatley in the county of Franklin; and the town of Royalston in the county of Worcester.  First Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Lowell and the towns of Dunstable, Groton, Pepperell, Tyngsborough and Westford in the county of Middlesex.  Second Middlesex--Consisting of the cities of Cambridge, wards 9 to 11, inclusive, Medford and Somerville, and the town of Winchester, precincts 4 to 7, inclusive, in the county of Middlesex.  Third Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Waltham and the towns of Bedford, Carlisle, Chelmsford, Concord, Lexington, precincts 3, 8 and 9, Lincoln, Sudbury, precincts 1, 4 and 5, and Weston in the county of Middlesex.  Fourth Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Woburn and the towns of Arlington, Billerica, Burlington and Lexington, precincts 1 and 2 and 4 to 7, inclusive, in the county of Middlesex.  Fifth Middlesex--Consisting of the cities of Malden and Melrose, and the towns of Reading, Stoneham, Wakefield and Winchester, precincts 1 to 3, inclusive, and 8, in the county of Middlesex.  First Middlesex and Norfolk--Consisting of the city of Newton in the county of Middlesex; and the towns of Brookline and Wellesley, precincts A, C to E, inclusive, and H in the county of Norfolk.  Second Middlesex and Norfolk--Consisting of the towns of Ashland, Framingham, Holliston, Hopkinton and Natick, precincts 1 to 5, inclusive, and 8, in the county of Middlesex; and the towns of Franklin, precincts 5, 6, and 8, and Medway in the county of Norfolk.  Middlesex and Suffolk--Consisting of the cities of Cambridge, ward 1, ward 2, precinct 1, ward 3, ward 4, precinct 2 and ward 6 to 8, inclusive, and Everett, all in the county of Middlesex; and the city of Boston, ward 2, ward 3, precinct 5, ward 21, precincts 4, 6 and 7, ward 22, precincts 1, 2 and 5; and the city of Chelsea, all in the county of Suffolk.  Middlesex and Worcester--Consisting of the city of Marlborough and the towns of Acton, Ayer, Boxborough, Hudson, Littleton, Maynard, Shirley, Stow and Sudbury, precincts 2 and 3 all in the county of Middlesex; and the towns of Harvard, Northborough, precinct 3, Southborough and Westborough, all in the county of Worcester.  Norfolk, Bristol and Plymouth--Consisting of the towns of Avon, Braintree, precincts 1, 1A, 2 and 2A, Canton, Milton, Randolph, Sharon, precincts 2 and 3, and Stoughton, all in the county of Norfolk; the town of Easton, precincts 3 to 6, inclusive, in the county of Bristol; and the towns of East Bridgewater, precinct 4, and West Bridgewater in the county of Plymouth.  Norfolk, Bristol and Middlesex--Consisting of the towns of Franklin, precincts 1 to 4, inclusive, and precinct 7, Millis, Needham, precincts A to C, inclusive, I and J, Norfolk, Plainville, Wellesley, precincts B, F, and G and Wrentham, in the county of Norfolk; the city of Attleboro, ward 1, ward 2 and ward 3, precinct A, and the town of North Attleborough in the county of Bristol; and the towns of Natick, precincts 6, 7, 9 and 10, Sherborn and Wayland in the county of Middlesex.  Norfolk and Plymouth--Consisting of the city of Quincy and the towns of Braintree, precincts 3, 3A, 4, 4A, 5, 5A, 6 and 6A and Holbrook in the county of Norfolk; the towns of Abington and Rockland in the county of Plymouth.  Norfolk and Suffolk--Consisting of the city of Boston, ward 18, precincts 9, 10, 16 to 20, inclusive, and 23, ward 19, precincts 10 to 13, inclusive, and ward 20 in the county of Suffolk; and the towns of Dover, Dedham, Needham, precincts D to H, inclusive, Norwood and Westwood in the county of Norfolk.  Plymouth and Barnstable--Consisting of the towns of Kingston, Pembroke and Plymouth in the county of Plymouth; and the towns of Bourne, Falmouth and Sandwich in the county of Barnstable.  First Plymouth and Bristol--Consisting of the towns of Bridgewater, Carver, Marion, Middleborough and Wareham in the county of Plymouth; and the towns of Berkley, Dighton and Raynham, and the city of Taunton, all in the county of Bristol.  Second Plymouth and Bristol--Consisting of the city of Brockton and the towns of East Bridgewater, precincts 1 to 3, inclusive, Halifax, Hanover, Hanson, Plympton and Whitman, all in the county of Plymouth; and the town of Easton, precincts 1 and 2, in the county of Bristol.  Plymouth and Norfolk--Consisting of the towns of Duxbury, Hingham, Hull, Marshfield, Norwell and Scituate in the county of Plymouth; and the towns of Cohasset and Weymouth in the county of Norfolk.  First Suffolk--Consisting of the city of Boston, ward 1, precinct 15, ward 6, ward 7, ward 13, precincts 3 and 5 to 10, inclusive, ward 14, precincts 2, 4, 5 and 12 to 14, inclusive, ward 15, ward 16, ward 17, ward 18, precincts 1 to 6, inclusive, 13, 15 and 21 in the county of Suffolk.  Second Suffolk--Consisting of the city of Boston, ward 3, precinct 7, ward 4, precincts 1, 3 and 4, ward 8, ward 9, ward 10, ward 11, ward 12, ward 13, precincts 1, 2 and 4, ward 14, precincts 1, 3, 6 to 11, inclusive, ward 18, precincts 7, 8, 11, 12, 14 and 22 and ward 19, precincts 1 to 9, inclusive, in the county of Suffolk.  First Suffolk and Middlesex--Consisting of the cities of Boston, ward 1, precincts 1 to 14, inclusive, ward 3, precincts 1 to 4, inclusive, 6 and 8, and ward 5, precinct 1, 3 to 5, inclusive, and 11, Revere and the town of Winthrop, all in the county of Suffolk; and the city of Cambridge, ward 2, precincts 2 and 3, ward 4, precincts 1 and 3, and ward 5, all in the county of Middlesex.  Second Suffolk and Middlesex--Consisting of the city of Boston, ward 4, precincts 2 and 5 to 10, inclusive, ward 5, precincts 2 and 6 to 10, inclusive, ward 21, precincts 1 to 3, inclusive, 5 and 8 to 16, inclusive, ward 22, precincts 3 and 4 and 6 to 13, inclusive, in the county of Suffolk; and the towns of Belmont and Watertown in the county of Middlesex.  First Worcester--Consisting of the towns of Boylston, Clinton, precincts 3 and 4, Holden, Northborough, precincts 1, 2 and 4, Princeton and West Boylston, and the city of Worcester, wards 1 to 4, inclusive, ward 8, precincts 2 to 4, inclusive, and wards 9 and 10 in the county of Worcester.  Second Worcester--Consisting of the towns of Auburn, Grafton, Leicester, Millbury, Northbridge, precincts 2 and 4, Shrewsbury and Upton and the city of Worcester, wards 5 to 7, inclusive, and ward 8, precincts 1 and 5 in the county of Worcester.  Worcester, Hampden, Hampshire and Middlesex--Consisting of the towns of Ashburnham, Athol, Barre, Brookfield, Charlton, East Brookfield, Hardwick, Hubbardston, New Braintree, North Brookfield, Oakham, Paxton, Petersham, Phillipston, Rutland, Spencer, Sturbridge, Templeton, Warren, West Brookfield and Winchendon in the county of Worcester; the towns of Brimfield, Holland, Monson, Palmer and Wales in the county of Hampden; the town of Ware in the county of Hampshire; and the town of Ashby in the county of Middlesex.  Worcester and Middlesex--Consisting of the cities of Fitchburg, Gardner and Leominster and the towns of Berlin, Bolton, Clinton, precincts 1 and 2, Lancaster, Lunenburg, Sterling and Westminster in the county of Worcester; and the town of Townsend in the county of Middlesex.  Worcester and Norfolk--Consisting of the towns of Blackstone, Douglas, Dudley, Hopedale, Mendon, Milford, Millville, Northbridge, precincts 1 and 3, Oxford, Southbridge, Sutton, Uxbridge and Webster in the county of Worcester; and the town of Bellingham in the county of Norfolk.
    </text>
</law>