<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Operating Budget;  Expenditures From Trust And Bond Funds;  Reconciliation Of Reports Of Budget Director And Comptroller</catch_line>
    <order_by>6C</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  In addition to information required by section six to be included in the budget submitted by the governor, said budget shall also include the following information:  (a) a description of and the amount of expenditure by state agencies from trust funds and bond funds anticipated for the subsequent fiscal year; and  (b) a narrative description accompanied by appropriate fiscal statements which shall reconcile the amounts for state revenues and expenditures for the previous fiscal year as presented by the budget director in the governor's budget with the amounts of state revenues and expenditures for the previous fiscal year as presented by the comptroller in the annual financial report of the commonwealth. Such description shall include a statement concerning the net consolidated surplus or deficit in the budgetary funds which are subject to direct appropriation.
Chapter 29: Operating budget; expenditures from trust and bond funds; reconciliation of reports of budget director and comptroller
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  In addition to information required by section 6 to be included in the budget submitted by the governor, said budget shall also include the following information:  (a) a description of and the amount of expenditure by state agencies from trust funds and bond funds anticipated for the subsequent fiscal year; and  (b) a narrative description accompanied by appropriate fiscal statements which shall reconcile the amounts for state revenues and expenditures for the previous fiscal year as presented by the budget director in the governor's budget with the amounts of state revenues and expenditures for the previous fiscal year as presented by the comptroller in the annual financial report of the commonwealth. Such description shall include a statement concerning the net consolidated surplus or deficit in the budgetary funds which are subject to direct appropriation.
    </text>
</law>