<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90B" order_by="90B" level="3">Motorboats, Other Vessels And Recreational Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Operation Of A Vessel Under The Influence Of A Controlled Substance Causing Death; Penalties; Probation, Parole Or Furlough; License Revocation</catch_line>
    <order_by>8B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Whoever operates a vessel on the waters of the commonwealth with a percentage, by weight, of alcohol in their blood of eight one-hundredths or greater, or while under the influence of intoxicating liquor, or of marihuana, narcotic drugs, depressants, or stimulant substances, all as defined in chapter ninety-four C, or the vapors of glue, and so operates said vessel recklessly or negligently so that the lives or safety of the public might be endangered, and by any such operation so described causes the death of another person, shall be guilty of homicide by a vessel while under the influence of an intoxicating substance, and shall be punished by imprisonment in the state prison for not less than two and one-half years nor more than fifteen years and a fine of not more than five thousand dollars, or by imprisonment in a jail or house of correction for not less than one year nor more than two and one-half years and a fine of not more than five thousand dollars. The sentence imposed upon such person shall not be reduced to less than one year, nor suspended, nor shall any person convicted under this paragraph be eligible for probation, parole, or furlough or receive any deduction from his sentence until such person has served at least one year of such sentence; provided, however, that the commissioner of correction may, on the recommendation of the warden, superintendent, or other person in charge of a correctional institution, or the administrator of a county correctional institution, grant to an offender committed under this paragraph a temporary release in the custody of an officer of such institution for the following purposes only: to attend the funeral of a relative; to visit a critically ill relative; to obtain emergency medical or psychiatric services unavailable at said institution; or to engage in employment pursuant to a work release program. Prosecutions commenced under this section shall neither be continued without a finding nor placed on file.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Whoever operates a vessel on the waters of the commonwealth with a percentage, by weight, of alcohol in their blood of eight one-hundredths or greater, or while under the influence of intoxicating liquor, or of marihuana, narcotic drugs, depressants or stimulant substances, all as defined in chapter ninety-four C, or the vapors of glue, or whoever operates a vessel recklessly or negligent so that the lives or safety of the public might be endangered and by any such operation causes the death of another person, shall be guilty of homicide by a vessel and shall be punished by imprisonment in a jail or house of correction for not less than thirty days nor more than two and one-half years, or by a fine of not less than three hundred nor more than three thousand dollars, or both.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The registrar shall revoke the license or right to operate and the director shall revoke the certificate of number of a person convicted of a violation of this section for a period of ten years after the date of conviction for a first offense. The registrar shall revoke the license or the right to operate and the director shall revoke the certificate of a person convicted for a subsequent violation of this section for the life of such person. No appeal, motion for a new trial or exceptions shall operate to stay the revocation of the license, right to operate, or certificate provided, however, such license, right to operate and certificate of number shall be restored if the prosecution of such person ultimately terminates in favor of the defendant.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>