<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="110H" order_by="110H" level="3">Registration And Protection Of Trademarks</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assignment Of Marks And Registration; Recording</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A mark and its registration hereunder shall be assignable with the good will of the business in which the mark is used, or with that part of the good will of the business connected with the use of and symbolized by the mark. Assignment shall be by instruments in writing duly executed and may be recorded with the secretary upon the payment of the recording fee payable to the secretary who, upon recording of the assignment, shall issue in the name of the assignee a new certificate for the remainder of the term of the registration or of the last renewal thereof. An assignment of any registration under this chapter shall be void as against any subsequent purchaser for valuable consideration without notice, unless it is recorded with the secretary within 3 months after the date thereof or before the subsequent purchase.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A registrant or applicant effecting a change of the name of the person to whom the mark was issued or for whom an application was filed may record a certificate of change of name of the registrant or applicant with the secretary upon the payment of the recording fee. The secretary may issue in the name of the assignee a certificate of registration of an assigned application. The secretary may issue in the name of the assignee, a new certificate or registration for the remainder of the term of the registration or last renewal thereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Other instruments which relate to a mark registered or application pending pursuant to this chapter, such as, by way of example, licenses, security interests or mortgages, may be recorded in the discretion of the secretary, provided that the instrument is in writing and duly executed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Acknowledgement shall be prima facie evidence of the execution of an assignment or other instrument and, when recorded by the secretary, the record shall be prima facie evidence of execution.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A photocopy of any instrument referred to in subsection (a), (b) or (c), shall be accepted for recording if it is certified by any of the parties thereto, or their successors, to be a true and correct copy of the original.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>