<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="3">Department Of Food And Agriculture</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32</section_number>
    <catch_line>Agricultural Inspection And Infrastructure Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>32</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 239, Sec. 7 effective August 7, 2012.]  There shall be established and set upon the books of the commonwealth an Agricultural Inspection and Infrastructure Trust Fund, consisting of: (i) fee revenues from apiary inspections under sections 32 and 35 of chapter 128, poultry inspections under section 124 of chapter 94, registration of animal rescue and shelter operations under section 39A of chapter 129 and registration of pesticide companies; (ii) interest or investment earnings on such monies; and (iii) all other monies credited or transferred to the fund by law.  The commissioner shall be the trustee of the fund and may expend monies in the fund without further appropriation for programs and costs related to the following: (1) sections 32 to 38, inclusive, and sections 64 and 65 inclusive of chapter 128; (2) the integrated pest management program established in chapter 132B and in chapter 85 of the acts of 2000; (3) spay and neuter programs and animal rescue and shelter programs established under section 139A of chapter 140; (4) poultry testing programs established in 330 CMR 5.00 seq; and (5) the Agricultural Innovation Center.  Any unexpended balance in the fund at the end of the fiscal year, not to exceed $200,000, shall not revert to the General Fund but shall remain available for expenditure in subsequent fiscal years. No expenditure made from the fund shall cause the fund to become deficient at any point during a fiscal year.
    </text>
</law>