<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="3">The General Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assistant Sergeant At Arms;  Appointment, Duties, Compensation And Removal</catch_line>
    <order_by>16</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  In case of the disability or necessary absence of the sergeant-at-arms and of the sergeant-at-arms of the house of representatives, the sergeant-at-arms may appoint, with the approval of the presiding officers of the two branches of the general court or, during its recess, of the governor, an assistant sergeant-at-arms to perform the duties of the sergeant-at-arms during such disability or absence. His compensation shall be paid by the sergeant-at-arms, who shall be responsible for his fidelity and good conduct in office; but for misconduct or other sufficient cause he may be removed by the general court or, during its recess, by the governor and council.
Chapter 3: Assistant sergeant-at-arms; appointment, duties, compensation and removal
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 3 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  In case of the disability or necessary absence of the sergeant-at-arms of the general court and of the sergeant-at-arms of the house of representatives, the sergeant-at-arms may appoint, with the approval of the presiding officers of the 2 branches of the general court, an assistant sergeant-at-arms to perform the duties of the sergeant-at-arms during such disability or absence. The compensation of the assistant sergeant-at-arms shall be paid by the sergeant-at-arms, who shall be responsible for the assistant's fidelity and good conduct in office; but for misconduct or other sufficient cause the assistant may be removed by the general court
    </text>
</law>