<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148" level="3">Fire Prevention</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        In this chapter the following words, unless a different meaning is required by the context or is specifically prescribed, shall have the following meanings:— 
“Department”, the department of fire services. 
“Division”, the division of fire safety of the department of fire services. 
“Head of the fire department”, the chief executive officer of the fire department in a city, town, fire district or the Massachusetts military reservation fire department having such an officer, otherwise the fire commissioner, board of fire commissioners or fire engineers, or commissioner of public safety; and, in towns not having a fire department, the chief engineer, if any, otherwise the chairman of the board of selectmen. 
“Local licensing authority”, in towns, including those towns which have adopted a town management form of government, the board of selectmen; in Boston, the board of street commissioners; in cities having adopted one of the plans of government provided in chapter forty-three, the city council, or the licensing board or commission in such cities wherein such a board or commission is authorized by statute or ordinance to grant licenses under this chapter; in other cities, the board of aldermen, or the licensing board or commission in cities wherein such a board or commission is authorized by statute or ordinance to grant licenses under this chapter; provided, that in any town having over twenty thousand inhabitants, an unpaid licensing board of three members may be appointed or designated by the board of selectmen to act as the licensing authority in issuing licenses for garages for not more than two automobiles or motor vehicles. In case the board of aldermen or city council constitute such authority, any hearing required by this chapter may be held before a committee thereof. 
“Marshal”, the state fire marshal or his designee. 
“Board”, the board of fire prevention regulations established under section four of chapter twenty-two D. 
“Building”, a combination of any materials, whether portable or fixed, having a roof, to form a structure for the shelter of persons, animals or property. For the purpose of this definition “roof” shall include an awning or any similar covering, whether or not permanent in nature. The word “building” shall be construed where the context allows as though followed by the words “or part or parts thereof”. 
“Structure”, a combination of materials assembled at a fixed location to give support or shelter, such as a building, framework, retaining wall, tent, reviewing stand, platform, bin, fence, sign, flagpole, mast for radio antenna or the like. The word “structure” shall be construed, where the context allows, as though followed by the words “or part or parts thereof”.
    </text>
</law>