<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="55C" order_by="55C" level="3">Limited Public Financing Of Campaignsfor Statewide Elective Office</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Minimum Financing Available; Primary Election</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        Any candidate for statewide elective office certified by the state secretary under section 2 as qualifying for the ballot and having opposition in primary election shall be eligible to receive limited public financing of his primary election campaign, to the extent provided by section 5, on determination and certification by the director that the candidate (a) has filed a request for public financing with the director together with the bond required by section 8; (b) has filed with the director a statement under subsection (a) of section 1A agreeing to abide by the expenditure limits provided thereby; and (c) has received qualifying contributions as defined by section 1 in at least the following minimum amounts for the following statewide elective offices: 
Governor  $75,000 
Lieutenant Governor  15,000 
Attorney General  37,500 
Secretary  15,000 
Treasurer and Receiver General  15,000 
Auditor  15,000 
Only amounts appearing in statements of qualifying contributions filed with the director, in such form as he shall prescribe, shall be considered in determining whether any such minimum amount has been met. Determination and certification of the eligibility of candidates shall be made by the director on the eighth Tuesday before the primary and shall be based solely upon information contained in such statements as have been filed by candidates. Candidates for governor seeking public financing shall file the statement on or before the Friday that is 11 days preceding said eighth Tuesday and other candidates seeking public financing shall file said statements on or before the Friday next preceding said eighth Tuesday.
    </text>
</law>