<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="82" order_by="82" level="3">The Laying Out, Alteration, Relocation And Discontinuance Of Public Ways, And Specific Repairs Thereon</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>40B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Designation Of Location Of Underground Facilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>40B</order_by>
    <text>
        Within 72 hours, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays, from the time the initial notice is received by the system or at such time as the company and the excavator agree, such company shall respond to the initial notice or subsequent notice by designating the location of the underground facilities within 15 feet in any direction of the premarking so that the existing facilities are to be found within a safety zone. Such safety zone shall be so designated by the use of standard color-coded markings. The providing of such designation by the company shall constitute prima facie evidence of an exercise of reasonable precaution by the company as required by this section; provided, however, that in the event that the excavator has given notice as aforesaid at a location at which because of the length of excavation the company cannot reasonably designate the entire location of its facilities within such 72 hour period, then such excavator shall identify for the company that portion of the excavation which is to be first made and the company shall designate the location of its facilities in such portion within 72 hours and shall designate the location of its facilities in the remaining portion of the location within a reasonable time thereafter. When an emergency notification has been given to the system, the company shall make every attempt to designate its facilities as promptly as possible.
    </text>
</law>