<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="3">Department Of Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Council On Alcoholism</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be an advisory council on alcoholism consisting of the attorney general, the commissioner of public health, the commissioner of mental health, the commissioner of corrections, the commissioner of rehabilitation, the commissioner of education, the commissioner of youth services, the commissioner of probation, the commissioner of public safety, the commissioner of public welfare, the commissioner of elder affairs, the commissioner of children and families, the registrar of motor vehicles, the chairman of the alcoholic beverages control commission, the president of the Massachusetts chiefs of police association, or their designees, all of whom shall serve ex officiis, and twelve persons experienced in the field of alcoholism treatment and prevention to be appointed by the governor, of whom at least two shall be women and at least four shall be rehabilitated alcoholics. Upon the expiration of the term of any appointive member, a successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of three years. The term of all appointive members shall be three years and no such member shall be appointed to serve more than two consecutive terms. 
The governor shall annually designate the chairman of the council from among its members. The council shall meet at least four times each year, and shall convene special meetings at the call of the chairman, a majority of the members of the council, the commissioner of public health, or the director of the division of alcoholism. The director of the division of alcoholism shall serve as the executive secretary of the council and shall attend all meetings. The council shall make an annual report to the governor, and shall file a copy of said report with the state secretary, the clerk of the senate and the clerk of the house of representatives. Members of the council shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for their expenses actually and necessarily incurred in the discharge of their duties. 
Said advisory council shall (a) assist the commissioner of public health and the director of the division of alcoholism in coordinating the efforts of all public and private agencies within the commonwealth concerned with the prevention of alcoholism and the treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics and intoxicated persons, (b) advise the said commissioner and said director on policy and priorities of need in the commonwealth for comprehensive treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics, and (c) review the annual plans, the proposed annual budget and the programs and services of the division and make recommendations to the commissioner, including approval, modification, or disapproval in regard thereto. 
The chairman of the advisory council shall appoint a five member executive committee which shall meet annually with the commissioner and director, or shall meet at the request of the commissioner, director or chairman for the purpose of reviewing existing programs and implementing new programs designed to meet the future needs which arise as a result of the administration of chapter one hundred and eleven B.
    </text>
</law>