<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="52" order_by="52" level="3">Political Committees</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Committees; Election; Organization; Terms; Vacancies</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        Each political party shall, in the manner herein provided, elect a state committee from among its members who either have enrolled on or before the ninetieth day prior to the last day for filing nomination papers for state committees with the state secretary, or are newly registered voters in their city or town enrolled in that political party and have not been enrolled in another political party during the year preceding such last day for filing nomination papers. Each state committee shall consist of one man and one woman from each senatorial district, who shall be residents thereof, to be elected at the presidential primaries by plurality vote of the members of the party in the district, and such number of members as may be appointed by the state committee as hereinafter provided. Members of said committee elected at the presidential primaries from senatorial districts shall hold office for a period of four years from the thirtieth day next following their election; provided that members of said committee elected in nineteen hundred and seventy-six shall hold office for a period beginning May fifteenth, nineteen hundred and seventy-six and ending on the thirtieth day following the day on which presidential primaries are next held. Members appointed by the state committee shall hold office for two years from the date of their appointment; provided, however, that in no event shall the terms of office of such members extend beyond the term of office of members who were elected at the presidential primaries. 
The members of the state committee elected at the presidential primaries shall, within ten days after the thirtieth day next following their election, meet and organize for the purpose of choosing a secretary, treasurer, and such other officers, other than a chairman, as they may decide to elect; provided, however, that such members shall, within ten days after the November general election at which a president is elected, meet and choose a chairman. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law to the contrary, a chairman shall serve in his respective position until his successor has been chosen; provided, however, that in the event that a state committee requires that its chairman be a member and any such elected chairman ceases to be a member, the committee shall choose a temporary chairman who shall serve until a permanent chairman is chosen following the November election as aforesaid. Such committee may, at any time after its organization, add to its membership. 
The secretary of the state committee shall file with the state secretary, and send to each city and town committee, within ten days after such permanent organization, a list of the members of the state committee and of its officers, and, within ten days after each addition to its membership made subsequently to its permanent organization, a list of the members so added. 
A vacancy in the office of chairman, secretary or treasurer of the state committee or in the membership thereof shall be filled by said committee, and a statement of any such change shall be filed as in the case of the officers first chosen.
    </text>
</law>