<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="30" order_by="30" level="3">General Provisions Relative To State Departments, Commissions, Officers And Employees</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>46</section_number>
    <catch_line>Administration Of Classification And Pay Plans</catch_line>
    <order_by>46</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The following shall be the salary schedule for the pay plan of the commonwealth:— GENERAL SALARY SCHEDULEEffective July 6, 1986(Weekly Rates on Total Cash Basis)
        </section>
        <section prefix="1A">
    	     Any employee serving a minimum of twelve years as deputy income tax assessor in the income tax division of the department of corporations and taxation shall automatically be promoted to the position of income tax assessor.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1B">
    	     Any employee in the income tax division of the department of corporations and taxation, appointed with the advice and consent of the governor and council under section four of chapter fourteen of the General Laws, and having charge of a district office or of the subdivisions of partnership, abatements, auditing, assessing, fiduciary, corporation information and miscellaneous, administration, correspondence, domicile, files, special investigation and any other subdivision within said income tax division serving in such position on January first, nineteen hundred and fifty-one, and any employee so appointed who shall after said date succeed to and be the appointee in charge of said district offices or of said subdivisions on account of the promotion, resignation, retirement or death of the then serving incumbent, shall be promoted to and hold the position of assistant income tax director.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     For purposes of salary increments provided for in the general salary schedule, a year of service shall be a period of fifty-two weeks of work. Increments shall commence on the first day of the payroll period in which such increments fall; provided, however, that if an employee is off the payroll for one or more days, such increment shall be postponed in accordance with the rules and regulations of the division of personnel administration. Notwithstanding the contrary provisions of any rule or law, the service of an employee of the commonwealth, who has been elected to a state office and who is on leave of absence while performing the duties of such elected office, shall be considered as service for salary increments in the job group from which he received a leave of absence.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2A">
    	     For the purpose of determining the date of initial employment, the period of service under an interim appointment, as defined in chapter thirty-one, shall be included as creditable service for such employee who subsequently receives a permanent, temporary or provisional appointment to a position of the same title.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Daily rates of all employees shall be computed on the basis of their assigned Job Groups.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Every regular step-rate increase in the salary of any office or employee of the commonwealth under the salary schedule set forth in this section shall be initiated by the division of personnel administration, in accordance with said salary schedule, and shall take effect in accordance with the said schedule upon certification of such increase by the personnel administrator to the comptroller and the appointing authority concerned.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The said administrator may, with the approval of the commissioner of administration, permit the recruitment of employees at a rate above the minimum, but not exceeding the maximum, of the job group salary range for the class concerned; provided, however, that the said administrator shall have first determined, upon request of the appointing authority, that an emergency exists due to inability to fill positions. Any such permit shall remain in effect until rescinded by the said administrator, but shall not be in effect longer than one year unless renewed in like manner and with like approval. Whenever the said administrator shall permit such recruitment, all employees in the same class being paid a rate or rates below such rate of recruitment shall be advanced to the said recruitment rate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5A">
    	     In accordance with regulations established by the personnel administrator with the approval of the commissioner of administration, designating certain classes as professional classes, an appointing authority may, in the initial appointment of a person to a position in such class, recruit such person at a rate above the minimum and within the grade to which the position is allocated, upon certification by said appointing authority to the administrator that the person to be employed has served satisfactorily in a comparable position for a period of time equivalent to the period required by the general salary schedule had such service been entirely in the service of the commonwealth, and, in the case of an office in or position with any department, agency, board, commission or institution within any of the executive offices established by chapters six A and seven, upon the prior written approval of the secretary having charge of such executive office. For the purpose of such regulations, professional classes shall include, but shall not be limited to, classes including positions for registered nurses and persons employed in medical or technical positions in hospitals and clinics, including the administration thereof, persons employed for the instruction of students and engineers and chemists. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the recruitment of personnel under the provisions of section fourteen of chapter seventy-five. No person may be recruited under this section if he has held a personal services contract with or been in the service of the commonwealth within a twelve-month period immediately prior to the date of proposed recruitment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5B">
    	     The said administrator shall, with the approval of the commissioner of administration, designate certain classes of nonmanagerial positions as professional data processing positions, as defined in paragraph (9) of section forty-five, and he shall submit, in writing, to the budget director and the house and senate committees on ways and means a list of classes so designated. Appointments to such positions shall not be subject to the provisions of section nine A, section forty-five, and chapter thirty-one. The salaries of such positions shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration on or before June first after recommendation by the personnel administrator, who shall make such recommendation annually on or before May first after having conducted an analysis of salaries for the same or similar types of positions paid by other governments and by private employers with which the commonwealth competes in securing qualified applicants for such positions. Any person transferred or promoted to any such position from a position in which he had rights or tenure under section nine A, chapter thirty-one, or any other general or special law, shall, upon termination of his services in such professional data processing position, if he so requests, be restored to the position from which he was transferred or promoted, or to a position equivalent thereto in salary grade in the same agency, without impairment of his tenure, seniority, retirement and other rights to which uninterrupted service in such position would have entitled him; provided, however, that if his service in such professional data processing position shall have been terminated for cause, his right to be so restored shall be determined by the civil service commission in accordance with the standards applied by the said commission in administering chapter thirty-one.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     When in accordance with sections forty-five to fifty, inclusive, the office of any officer or the position of any employee shall be initially allocated to a job group in the salary schedule, or shall be reallocated to a higher job group, or when in accordance with the said sections any officer or employee shall be transferred or promoted to another position in a different job group, any such officer or employee, for subsequent step-rate increases, shall be credited with the number of years of service which shall correspond to his rate in the job group for such office or position. Any officer or employee reinstated or reemployed, if reinstated or reemployed within three years following his separation from the payroll, shall be credited with the number of years of service which shall correspond to his rate in the job group to which his office or position at the time of such separation shall then have been allocated; but in no event shall he be paid at a rate lower than that which he shall have been receiving at the time of such separation. Such credit for any employee reinstated or reemployed after three or more years following such separation shall be determined in accordance with rules of the personnel administrator.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Whenever an employee receives a promotion to a position in a higher job group, his rate shall be the next higher rate in said higher job group, or the second next higher rate therein if such new salary rate would result in an increase of salary smaller in amount than the salary increment for such higher job group; however, if a teacher or supervisor employed in any school or college within any department of the commonwealth is transferred from a position, in which the regular service is rendered from September first to June thirtieth, to a position in which the regular service is rendered for the entire year, he shall be reallocated in the salary schedule from the rate in the salary schedule in effect immediately prior to such transfer to the corresponding step-in-range in the job group which includes the class to which he has been transferred.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     An employee who is demoted to a position in a lower job group shall receive the salary to which his period of service would entitle him if his service had been rendered in such position in the lower job group, but not less than the employee would have been entitled to had his service been continuously in such position in the lower job group.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     No increase in salary shall be effective for any position before the effective date of the appropriation act which includes an appropriation made for the purpose of, and sufficient to cover, the cost of such increase.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     Rates of compensation in the salary schedule are for work hours as provided in section thirty A of chapter one hundred and forty-nine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     An employee serving on a part time basis as certified by the appointing authority shall be entitled to the provisions of this chapter in the proportion that his service bears to full time service.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law to the contrary, no employee shall receive compensation from any agency, department, commission, board or other undertaking of the commonwealth if said employee is also a non-elected employee of a county and would receive compensation from such county in excess of twenty thousand dollars or, in the case of court officers of the trial court of the commonwealth employed by courts located in Dukes and Nantucket counties, in excess of twenty-seven thousand dollars. Any employee covered by the provisions of this paragraph shall have thirty days prior to separation from the payroll of the commonwealth within which to resign from the employ of each county.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>