<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="3">The General Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15</section_number>
    <catch_line>Sergeant At Arms;  Appointment, Tenure, Salary</catch_line>
    <order_by>15</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The general court shall choose a sergeant-at-arms who shall hold office until removed or until another is chosen. He may be removed by the general court or, during its recess, may be suspended by the governor and council. If a vacancy or suspension occurs during such recess, the governor and council may appoint a person to perform the duties of the office until a new election. He shall receive such salary as may be established by the committees on rules of the two branches of the general court acting concurrently.  The house of representatives may choose a sergeant-at-arms of the house of representatives who shall perform such duties as may be prescribed by the committee on rules of the house, and in case of the disability or necessary absence of the sergeant-at-arms of the general court he shall perform the duties of said sergeant-at-arms during such disability or absence. He shall receive such salary as may be established by the committee on rules of the house.
Chapter 3: Sergeant-at-arms; appointment, tenure and salary
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 3 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The general court shall choose a sergeant-at-arms who shall hold office until removed or until another is chosen. The sergeant-at-arms may be removed by the general court. The sergeant-at-arms shall receive such salary as may be established by the committees on rules of the 2 branches of the general court acting concurrently.  The house of representatives may choose a sergeant-at-arms of the house of representatives who shall perform such duties as may be prescribed by the committee on rules of the house, and in case of the disability or necessary absence of the sergeant-at-arms of the general court, the sergeant-at-arms of the house of representatives shall perform the duties of the sergeant-at-arms during such disability or absence. The sergeant-at-arms of the house of representatives shall receive such salary as may be established by the committee on rules of the house.
    </text>
</law>