<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>39A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Plan For Development Of Airports And Air Navigation Facilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>39A</order_by>
    <text>
        The commission shall prepare and revise from time to time a plan for the development of airports and air navigation facilities in the commonwealth. Such plan shall specify, in terms of general location and type of development, the projects considered by the commission to be necessary to provide a system of airports adequate to anticipate and meet the needs of civil aeronautics within the commonwealth. In formulating and revising such plan the commission shall consider the probable technological developments in the science of aeronautics, the protection and safety of persons operating aircraft, the needs of the national defense program, air commerce and private flying in order that locations of such airports and air navigation facilities will provide the greatest safety, security and utility. In carrying out this section the commission may make such surveys, studies and investigations as it may deem necessary or desirable. 
The commission may, subject to appropriation, construct, establish and maintain air navigational facilities within the commonwealth for the convenience and safety of persons operating, using or traveling by aircraft, and for the safety of the general public. The commission on behalf of the commonwealth may take by eminent domain under chapter seventy-nine or eighty A, or acquire by purchase, gift or otherwise, such property as may be necessary to fulfill the requirements of this section.
    </text>
</law>