<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118E" order_by="118E" level="3">Division Of Medical Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31</section_number>
    <catch_line>Adjustment Or Recovery Of Payments</catch_line>
    <order_by>31</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     This subsection shall apply to estates of individuals dying prior to April first, nineteen hundred and ninety-five. There shall be no adjustment or recovery of medical assistance correctly paid except as follows:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Recovery from the Permanently Institutionalized: From the estate of an individual, regardless of age, who was an inpatient in a nursing facility or other medical institution when he or she received such assistance. Recovery of such assistance shall be limited to assistance provided on or after March twenty-second, nineteen hundred and ninety-one.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Recovery from Persons Age 65 and Over: From the estate of an individual who was sixty-five years of age or older when such individual received such assistance. Any recovery may be made only after the death of the surviving spouse, if any, and only at a time when such individual has no surviving child who is under age twenty-one or is blind or permanently and totally disabled. The division shall waive recovery where it would result in undue hardship, as defined by the division in its regulations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     This subsection shall apply to estates of individuals dying on or after April first, nineteen hundred and ninety-five. There shall be no adjustments or recovery of medical assistance correctly paid except as follows:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Recovery from the Permanently Institutionalized: From the estate of an individual, regardless of age, who was an inpatient in a nursing facility or other medical institution when he or she received such assistance. Recovery of such assistance shall be limited to assistance provided on or after March twenty-second, nineteen hundred and ninety-one.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Recovery from Persons Age 65 and Over: From the estate of an individual who was sixty-five years of age or older when he or she received such assistance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Recovery from Persons Age 55 and Over for Post-October 1, 1993 Medicaid: From the estate of an individual who was fifty-five years of age or older when he or she received such assistance, where such assistance was for services provided on or after October first, nineteen hundred and ninety-three.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     For purposes of this section, “estate” shall mean all real and personal property and other assets includable in the decedent’s probate estate under the General Laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The division is also authorized during an individual’s lifetime to recover all assistance correctly provided on or after April 1, 1995, if property against which the division has a lien or encumbrance under section 34 is sold. No lien or encumbrance shall be valid against any bona fide purchaser for value or take priority against any subsequent mortgagee for value unless and until it is recorded in the registry of deeds where the property lies.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>