<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="25C" order_by="25C" level="3">Department Of Telecommunications And Cable</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Voiceover Internet Protocol Service And Internet Protocol Enabled Service; Regulation Prohibited</catch_line>
    <order_by>6A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meanings, unless the context clearly requires otherwise:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Except as set forth in subsections (c) to (f), inclusive, and notwithstanding any other general or special law to the contrary, no department, agency, commission or political subdivision of the commonwealth, shall enact, adopt or enforce, either directly or indirectly, any law, rule, regulation, ordinance, standard, order or other provision having the force or effect of law that regulates or has the effect of regulating, the entry, rates, terms or conditions of VoIP Service or IP enabled service.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Subsection (b) shall not be construed to affect the authority of the attorney general to apply and enforce chapter 93A or other consumer protection laws of general applicability.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Subsection (b) shall not be construed to affect, mandate or prohibit the assessment of nondiscriminatory enhanced 911 fees or telecommunications relay service fees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Subsection (b) shall not be construed to modify or affect the rights or obligations of any carrier under sections 47 USC 251 or 47 USC 252.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Subsection (b) shall not be construed to affect or modify any obligations for the provision of video service by any party under applicable law.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>