<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138" level="3">Alcoholic Liquors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing Of Railroad Or Car And Airline Corporations; Vessel Owners And Operators; Shipping Companies And Ship Chandlers</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        A railroad or car corporation operating any line of railroad or furnishing refreshments upon railroad cars within the commonwealth may sell, in any dining, club, buffet or lounge car, alcoholic beverages to be drunk in the cars, if the commission sees fit to issue a license to the railroad or car corporation. The fee for each license under this section shall be $500 and for each certified copy thereof $50. An airline corporation operating within the commonwealth may sell in any aircraft alcoholic beverages to be consumed thereon, if duly licensed by the commission. The annual license fee for each airline corporation shall be $500 and for each certified copy thereof $50. The commission may also issue licenses to sell alcoholic beverages to the owner or operator of any vessel or shipping company carrying passengers and operating out of any port of the commonwealth. Sales of alcoholic beverages by licensees under this section shall be made only under regulations as the commission may prescribe. The annual license fee for each vessel shall be $500. Retail sales by ship chandlers of all alcoholic beverages not to be drunk on the premises, may be authorized by the commission, but the sales shall not be for purposes other than provisioning a vessel or shipping company using any port of the commonwealth. The fee for a license to a ship chandler for the sales shall be not less than $500 nor more than $1,000. No other license shall be required under this chapter for sales as authorized under this section.
    </text>
</law>