<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18B" order_by="18B" level="3">Department Of Social Services</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Area Directors; Appointment; Qualifications; Duties; Plans;  Budgets; Social Worker Qualifications</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        The commissioner, with the advice of the area board, shall appoint an area director in each area, and, subject to appropriation, such other employees as the commissioner may deem necessary. 
Each area director shall be qualified by training and experience to perform the duties of the office and shall at the time of appointment have received a masters or higher degree in a field related to human service and shall have had not less than five years of professional administrative experience in the delivery of human services or a related field or said area director shall have had experience in a field related to human services for a period of years required to obtain a master’s degree, and shall have had, in addition thereto, not less than five years of professional administrative experience in the delivery of human services or a related field. The area director shall be placed in grade 29 of the classification and pay schedule of the commonwealth, and shall devote full time to the duties of the office. 
The area director shall perform such duties as are described in this chapter and such other duties as may be assigned by the commissioner. 
The area director shall, in consultation with the area board, prepare and submit to the commissioner an annual plan for the operation and development of its program. Such plan shall provide, as far as practicable, a comprehensive area program in social services as required by departmental standards. 
The area director shall also prepare and submit to the commissioner the proposed annual budget for the area for programs to be supported at the area level. The commissioner shall make such revisions as shall be necessary and shall include said area budgets as part of the departmental budget requests submitted annually under sections 27 and 28 of chapter 29. A copy of the area budget as included with said departmental requests shall be forwarded by the commissioner to each area director for the information of the area board. 
The area director, subject to the overall supervision of the commissioner, shall supervise all employees within the area and shall be responsible for the administration of the area budget and the implementation of the area plan. 
A social worker shall have a bachelor’s degree at the time of appointment. A supervisory social worker shall have a master’s degree in social work or a related field at the time of appointment.
    </text>
</law>