<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="31" order_by="31" level="3">Civil Service</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notice Of Examinations For Original Appointments; Posting</catch_line>
    <order_by>18</order_by>
    <text>
        The administrator shall prepare notices of all examinations for original appointment to the official service and shall send such notices to the clerks of those cities and towns where persons are domiciled who may be eligible to apply to take such examinations. The clerks shall cause a minimum of five such notices to be posted in the city and town halls and in other conspicuous places for at least three weeks prior to the final day for the filing of applications for the examination or, if no such final day for filing is indicated, as directed by the administrator. The clerks of such cities and towns shall submit an annual report to the administrator certifying that all such notices have been posted pursuant to the requirements of this section. The administrator shall determine when such annual report shall be submitted and the specific information it shall contain concerning the time and place of posting of notices. 
The administrator, on the basis of his assessment of local conditions, may require posting in addition to that required by this section or may modify the requirements of this section in some other manner. The administrator shall distribute to high schools in the commonwealth notices of examinations for original appointment to entry level positions in state service and service in political subdivisions of the commonwealth for which persons in their senior year of high school are eligible. The administrator shall cause to be posted copies of all notices required by this section in a conspicuous place at the office of the division for not less than three weeks prior to the final day for the filing of applications for the examination or, if no such final day for filing is indicated, for so long as he shall continue to accept applications for the examination. 
Each notice required by this section shall state the duties, compensation, and title of and required qualifications for the position for which the examination is to be held, the time, place and manner of applying for admission to the examination, the entrance requirements, if any, and any other information which the administrator determines should be included because of its relevancy and usefulness.
    </text>
</law>