<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="63" order_by="63" level="3">Taxation Of Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>38X</section_number>
    <catch_line>Credit Against Taxes Imposed On Persons Filming Motion Picture For Employment Of Persons Within Commonwealth In Connection With Filming Or Production</catch_line>
    <order_by>38X</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A taxpayer engaged in the making of a motion picture shall be allowed a credit against the taxes imposed by this chapter for the employment of persons within the commonwealth in connection with the filming or production of 1 or more motion pictures in the commonwealth within any consecutive 12 month period. The credit shall be equal to 25 per cent of the total aggregate payroll paid by a motion picture production company that constitutes Massachusetts source income, when total production costs incurred in the commonwealth equal or exceed $50,000 during the taxable year. For purposes of this subsection, the term “total aggregate payroll” shall not include the salary of any employee whose salary is equal to or greater than $1,000,000.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A taxpayer shall be allowed an additional credit against the taxes imposed by this chapter equal to 25 per cent of all Massachusetts production expenses, not including the payroll expenses used to claim a credit pursuant to subsection (b), where the motion picture is also eligible for a credit pursuant to subsection (b) and either Massachusetts production expenses exceed 50 per cent of the total production expenses for a motion picture or at least 50 per cent of the total principal photography days of the film take place in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The tax credit shall be taken against the taxes imposed under this chapter and shall, at the election of the taxpayer, be refundable to the extent provided for in section 32E. Any amount of the tax credit that exceeds the tax due for a taxable year may be carried forward by the taxpayer to any of the 5 subsequent taxable years.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     An owner, transferee or assignee desiring to make a transfer, sale or assignment shall submit to the commissioner a statement which describes the amount of tax credit for which the transfer, sale or assignment of tax credit is eligible. The owner, transferee or assignee shall provide to the commissioner such information as the commissioner may require for the proper allocation of the credit. The commissioner shall provide to the taxpayer a certificate of eligibility to transfer, sell or assign the tax credits. The commissioner shall not issue a certificate to a taxpayer that has an outstanding tax obligation with the commonwealth in connection with any motion picture for any prior taxable year. A tax credit shall not be transferred, sold or assigned without a certificate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The commissioner, in consultation with the secretary, shall promulgate regulations necessary for the administration of this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, aggregate salary and compensation amounts including all per diems, housing and other allowances, paid to, or for the services of, an individual shall not qualify for the credit under this section or for the credit under subsection (l) of section 6 of chapter 62 to the extent that such amounts exceed $2,000,000.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>