<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2O</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of Bonds And Notes Payable From Commonwealth Transportation Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2O</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  When authorized by a vote taken by the yeas and nays of two-thirds of each house of the general court present and voting thereon, including any authorization in effect as of July 1, 2009, the state treasurer, upon the request of the governor, may issue bonds of the commonwealth as hereinafter provided. Any such bonds shall be special obligations of the commonwealth payable solely from monies credited to the Commonwealth Transportation Fund established pursuant to section 2ZZZ; provided, however, that notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, including without limitation section 60A, such bonds shall not be general obligations of the commonwealth. Bonds may be issued in such manner and on such terms and conditions as the state treasurer may determine in accordance with this paragraph and, to the extent not inconsistent with this paragraph, provisions of the General Laws for the issuance of bonds of the commonwealth. Bonds may be secured by a trust agreement entered into by the state treasurer, with the concurrence of the secretary of administration and finance and the secretary of transportation, on behalf of the commonwealth, which trust agreement may pledge or assign all or any part of monies credited to the Commonwealth Transportation Fund and rights to receive the same, whether existing or coming into existence and whether held or thereafter acquired, and the proceeds thereof. The state treasurer may, with the concurrence of the secretary of administration and finance and the secretary of transportation, enter into additional security, insurance or other forms of credit enhancement which may be secured on a parity or subordinate basis with the bonds. A pledge in any such trust agreement or credit enhancement agreement shall be valid and binding from the time such pledge shall be made without any physical delivery or further act, and the lien of such pledge shall be valid and binding against all parties having claims of any kind in tort, contract or otherwise, irrespective of whether such parties have notice thereof. Any such pledge shall be perfected by filing of the trust agreement or credit enhancement agreement in the records of the state treasurer, and no filing need be made under chapter 106. Any such trust agreement or credit enhancement agreement may establish provisions defining defaults and establishing remedies and other matters relating to the rights and security of the holders of the bonds or other secured parties as determined by the state treasurer, including provisions relating to the establishment of reserves, the issuance of additional or refunding bonds, whether or not secured on a parity basis, the application of receipts, monies or funds pledged pursuant to such agreement, and other matters deemed necessary or desirable by the state treasurer for the security of such bonds, and may also regulate the custody, investment and application of monies. Any such bonds shall be deemed to be investment securities under chapter 106, shall be securities in which any public officer, fiduciary, insurance company, financial institution or investment company may properly invest funds and shall be securities which may be deposited with any public custodian for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds is authorized by law. Any such bonds, the transfer thereof and the income therefrom, including profit on the sale thereof, shall at all times be exempt from taxation by and within the commonwealth.  The provisions hereof relating to bonds shall also be applicable to the issuance of notes insofar as such provisions may be appropriate therefor.  In order to increase the marketability of any such bonds or notes issued by the commonwealth and in consideration of the acceptance of payment for any such bonds or notes, the commonwealth covenants with the purchasers and all subsequent holders and transferees of any such bonds or notes that while any such bond or note shall remain outstanding, and so long as the principal of or interest on any such bond or note shall remain unpaid: (i) no pledged funds shall be diverted from the Commonwealth Transportation Fund; (ii) in any fiscal year of the commonwealth and until an appropriation has been made which is sufficient to pay the principal, including sinking fund payments, of and interest on all such bonds and notes of the commonwealth and to provide for or maintain any reserves, additional security, insurance or other forms of credit enhancement required or provided for in any trust agreement securing any such bonds or notes, no pledged funds shall be applied to any other use; and (iii) so long as such revenues are necessary, as determined by the state treasurer in accordance with any applicable trust agreement or credit enhancement agreement, for the purposes for which they have been pledged, and notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law to the contrary, the rates of the fees collected pursuant to sections 33 and 34 of chapter 90 and of the excises imposed in chapters 64A, 64E and 64F shall not be reduced below the amount in effect at the time of issuance of any such bond or note.
Chapter 29: Issuance of bonds and notes payable from Commonwealth Transportation Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  When authorized by a vote taken by the yeas and nays of two-thirds of each house of the general court present and voting on such authorization, including any authorization in effect as of July 1, 2009, the state treasurer, upon the request of the governor, may issue bonds of the commonwealth as hereinafter provided. Any such bonds shall be special obligations of the commonwealth payable solely from monies credited to the Commonwealth Transportation Fund established in section 2ZZZ; provided, however, that notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, including without limitation section 60A, such bonds shall not be general obligations of the commonwealth. Bonds may be issued in such manner and on such terms and conditions as the state treasurer may determine in accordance with this paragraph and, to the extent not inconsistent with this paragraph, the General Laws for the issuance of bonds of the commonwealth. Bonds may be secured by a trust agreement entered into by the state treasurer, with the concurrence of the secretary of administration and finance and the secretary of transportation, on behalf of the commonwealth, which trust agreement may pledge or assign all or any part of monies credited to the Commonwealth Transportation Fund and rights to receive the same, whether existing or coming into existence and whether held or thereafter acquired, and the proceeds thereof. The state treasurer may, with the concurrence of the secretary of administration and finance and the secretary of transportation, enter into additional security, insurance or other forms of credit enhancement which may be secured on a parity or subordinate basis with the bonds. A pledge in any such trust agreement or credit enhancement agreement shall be valid and binding from the time such pledge shall be made without any physical delivery or further act, and the lien of such pledge shall be valid and binding against all parties having claims of any kind in tort, contract or otherwise, whether such parties have notice thereof or not. Any such pledge shall be perfected by filing of the trust agreement or credit enhancement agreement in the records of the state treasurer and no filing need be made under chapter 106. Any such trust agreement or credit enhancement agreement may establish provisions defining defaults and establishing remedies and other matters relating to the rights and security of the holders of the bonds or other secured parties as determined by the state treasurer, including provisions relating to the establishment of reserves, the issuance of additional or refunding bonds, whether or not secured on a parity basis, the application of receipts, monies or funds pledged pursuant to such agreement, the regulation of the custody, investment and application of monies and such other matters deemed necessary or desirable by the state treasurer for the security of such bonds. Any such bonds shall be deemed to be investment securities under chapter 106, securities in which any public officer, fiduciary, insurance company, financial institution or investment company may properly invest funds and securities which may be deposited with any public custodian for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds is authorized by law. Any such bonds, the transfer of such bonds and the income from such bonds, including profit on the sale of such bonds, shall at all times be exempt from taxation by and within the commonwealth.[ Second paragraph as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 does not take effect. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The provisions of this section relating to bonds shall also be applicable to the issuance of notes insofar as such provisions may be appropriate for such bonds.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2012, 239, Sec. 7 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 239, Sec. 60. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The provisions of this section relating to bonds shall also be applicable to the issuance of notes insofar as such provisions may be appropriate for such notes.  In order to increase the marketability of any such bonds or notes issued by the commonwealth and in consideration of the acceptance of payment for any such bonds or notes, the commonwealth covenants with the purchasers and all subsequent holders and transferees of any such bonds or notes that while any such bond or note shall remain outstanding, and so long as the principal of or interest on any such bond or note shall remain unpaid: (i) no pledged funds shall be diverted from the Commonwealth Transportation Fund; (ii) in any fiscal year of the commonwealth and until an appropriation has been made which is sufficient to pay the principal, including sinking fund payments, of and interest on all such bonds and notes of the commonwealth and to provide for or maintain any reserves, additional security, insurance or other forms of credit enhancement required or provided for in any trust agreement securing any such bonds or notes, no pledged funds shall be applied to any other use; and (iii) so long as such revenues are necessary, as determined by the state treasurer in accordance with any applicable trust agreement or credit enhancement agreement, for the purposes for which they have been pledged, and notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the rates of the fees collected under sections 33 and 34 of chapter 90 and of the excises imposed in chapters 64A, 64E and 64F shall not be reduced below the amount in effect at the time of issuance of any such bond or note.
    </text>
</law>