<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6A" order_by="6A" level="3">Executive Offices</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18L</section_number>
    <catch_line>Silver Alert Community Response System</catch_line>
    <order_by>18L</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     There is hereby created, subject to available funds, a silver alert community response system. The silver alert system shall be used, when appropriate, to alert public safety departments and private safety departments, when an adult with serious memory impairment such as Alzheimer’s disease or other dementia is reported to a police department as a missing person. The silver alert system shall direct and focus law enforcement and other key response resources in a cost-effective way within a geographic area consistent with the missing person’s last known location and in accordance with the best available research data related to activities of persons with Alzheimer’s disease or other dementia.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The executive office of public safety, in conjunction with the department of state police, shall, subject to available funds, develop and implement the silver alert system. The secretary shall adopt rules and regulations, as necessary, to ensure proper implementation of the silver alert system.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     All first responders, EMS first responders, 911 operators and other appropriate personnel as determined by the secretary shall be trained on the silver alert system application and protocols. Re-training shall be included in the in-service training curriculum for such personnel. Training shall include information relative to drivers whose memory impairments may put them at high risk for accidents or becoming lost while driving.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The secretary shall develop a plan to ensure that the silver alert system shall utilize a localized reverse 911 emergency phone system.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>