<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Boating Safety Advisory Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be within the office of law enforcement a boating safety advisory board. The board shall consist of 5 members to be appointed by the governor, 2 of whom shall be representatives of the boating public, each of whom shall hold a certificate of number issued pursuant to section 3 of chapter 90B; 1 of whom may represent the harbormaster’s association; and 2 of whom shall represent the recreational boating business, 1 of whom shall operate a boat dealership. Each member shall serve for a term of 3 years. The chair of the board shall be appointed from among the 5 members, annually by the governor and, in the absence of same, shall be designated by the director. Board members shall be appointed or reappointed for terms of 3 years. 
The boating safety advisory board shall meet at least quarterly and 3 members in attendance shall constitute a quorum. The chiefs of enforcement of the coastal enforcement bureau and the inland enforcement bureau established under section 6 of chapter 21, or their designees, shall attend all meetings of the board and shall provide such information as the board shall request. 
The board shall review the budgetary recommendations of the director and the secretary of energy and environmental affairs concerning the expenditure of federal funds allocated to the division for recreational boating safety each fiscal year prior to the submission of such recommendations to the secretary or the governor, as the case may be. In the event the board disapproves of any such recommendation it may file a report noting its objection and such report shall be transmitted to the governor and to the house and senate committees on ways and means.
    </text>
</law>