<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="71B" order_by="71B" level="3">Children With Special Needs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bureau Of Transitional Planning;  Transitional Advisory Committee;  Establishment</catch_line>
    <order_by>12B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  There shall be within the executive office of human services a bureau of transitional planning. There is also hereby established within the executive office of human services a committee, to be known as the transitional advisory committee, which shall meet on a regular and periodic basis for the purpose of reviewing and approving transitional plans for disabled persons whose entitlement to services under special education programs has terminated or will terminate within two years. The committee shall consist of the secretary of the executive office of human services who shall be chairman, or his designee, and one representative from each of the following agencies: the department of labor and workforce development, the department of mental health, the department of developmental services, the department of children and families, the department of transitional assistance, the department of public health, the Massachusetts rehabilitation commission, the Massachusetts office of deafness, the Massachusetts commission for the blind and the department of education. Said representatives shall be designated by the executive secretary, commissioner or department head whose agency they shall represent. The committee shall adopt rules and procedures governing its proceedings. Members of the committee shall not be compensated for service on said committee.
Chapter 71B: Bureau of transitional planning; transitional advisory committee; establishment
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 110 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  There shall be within the executive office of human services a bureau of transitional planning. There is also hereby established within the executive office of human services a committee, to be known as the transitional advisory committee, which shall meet on a regular and periodic basis for the purpose of reviewing and approving transitional plans for disabled persons whose entitlement to services under special education programs has terminated or will terminate within two years. The committee shall consist of the secretary of the executive office of human services who shall be chairman, or his designee, and one representative from each of the following agencies: the executive office of labor and workforce development, the department of mental health, the department of developmental services, the department of children and families, the department of transitional assistance, the department of public health, the Massachusetts rehabilitation commission, the Massachusetts office of deafness, the Massachusetts commission for the blind and the department of education. Said representatives shall be designated by the executive secretary, commissioner or department head whose agency they shall represent. The committee shall adopt rules and procedures governing its proceedings. Members of the committee shall not be compensated for service on said committee.
    </text>
</law>