<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>60C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Submission Of Evidence Of Education And Experience; Examinations;  Exemption From Written Examination; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>60C</order_by>
    <text>
        Every person applying to the board for registration shall submit with his application to the board evidence of graduation from a recognized high school or its equivalent. The applicant shall also submit satisfactory evidence of graduation from an accredited school of architecture and of such practical experience in architectural work as the board may by regulation prescribe. In lieu of evidence of graduation from an accredited school of architecture, the applicant may submit satisfactory evidence of such other academic experience, practical experience, or both, as the board may by regulation prescribe. The board shall thereupon examine the applicant in writing, on such technical and professional subjects as are prescribed by it including, but not limited to, the requirements of section thirteen A of chapter twenty-two and the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto pertaining to accessible design standards. A written examination may be supplemented by such oral examination as the board may determine. The board may exempt from said written examination a holder of a certificate of qualification issued by the National Council of Architectural Registration Boards. 
The board may adopt as its own rules and regulations governing academic and practical experience those guidelines published from time to time by the National Council of Architectural Registration Boards. The board may also adopt the examinations and recommended grading procedures of the National Council of Architectural Registration Boards.
    </text>
</law>