<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>39</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bonds, Etc., Held By Commonwealth;  Exchanges</catch_line>
    <order_by>39</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  When the commonwealth holds any bond, note or certificate of indebtedness payable to bearer and issued by a county, city, town or district or any domestic corporation, such county, city, town, district or corporation shall, at the request of the state treasurer, issue in exchange therefor a bond, note or certificate of the same effect, payable to the commonwealth by name. The commonwealth shall pay the expense involved in making such exchange. Any county, city, town, district or corporation neglecting or refusing to comply with this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than fifty dollars.
Chapter 29: Bonds, etc., held by commonwealth; exchanges
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  When the commonwealth holds any bond, note or certificate of indebtedness payable to bearer and issued by a county, city, town or district or any domestic corporation, such county, city, town, district or corporation shall, at the request of the state treasurer, issue in exchange therefor a bond, note or certificate of the same effect, payable to the commonwealth by name. The commonwealth shall pay the expense involved in making such exchange. Any county, city, town, district or corporation neglecting or refusing to comply with this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than $50.
    </text>
</law>