<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>106</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Certification Of Community Health Workers; Membership;  Term; Removal And Vacancies</catch_line>
    <order_by>106</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section added by 2010, 322, Sec. 2 effective January 1, 2012. See 2010, 322, Sec. 4.] 
There shall be a board of certification of community health workers, called the board in sections 106 to 108, inclusive. The board shall consist of 11 members who shall be residents of the commonwealth, 1 of whom shall be the commissioner of public health or the designee thereof, who shall serve as chair of the board, and 10 of whom shall be appointed by the governor. Of the appointed members of the board, 6 shall be appointed to ensure representation of all 6 geographic regions of the executive office of health and human services and shall include not fewer than 4 community health workers selected from recommendations offered by the Massachusetts Association of Community Health Workers; 1 shall represent a community health worker training organization; 1 shall represent the Massachusetts Public Health Association; 1 shall represent the Massachusetts Association of Health Plans; 1 shall represent the Massachusetts League of Community Health Centers; 1 shall represent a community-based community health worker employer; and 1 shall represent the public, subject to section 9B of chapter 13, and shall be familiar with community health worker services. Board members initially appointed to the board as community health workers shall be persons who are eligible for board certification as community health workers and shall obtain such certification within a time frame specified in regulations adopted by the board. 
The term of office of each appointed member of the board shall be 3 years, except that of the initially appointed members of the board of which 3 members shall be appointed for terms of 1 year, 3 members for terms of 2 years, and 3 members for terms of 3 years, at least 1 of which is a community health worker. No member shall be appointed to more than 2 consecutive full terms; provided, however, a member appointed for less than a full term may serve 2 full terms and a former member shall again be eligible for appointment after a lapse of 1 or more years. Upon the expiration of his term of office, a member of the board shall continue to serve until the appointment of a successor. Any member of the board may be removed by the governor for neglect of duty, misconduct, malfeasance or misfeasance in office after being given a written statement of the charges against him and sufficient opportunity to be heard thereon. Upon the death, resignation or removal for cause of any member of the board, the governor shall fill the vacancy for the remainder of that member’s term.
    </text>
</law>