<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>277B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Foreign Goods Or Services; Marking; Advertisement; Penalty</catch_line>
    <order_by>277B</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall sell, or offer or expose for sale any machinery, hardware, ladders, shoes or other footwear, fabrics, suits or other wearing apparel, sporting goods or equipment, radios or parts thereof, or scallops, which have been imported from a foreign country, without notifying each person purchasing or intending to purchase the same that it has been imported, by displaying in a conspicuous place, in letters at least as large as the figures indicating the price of the goods to be sold, a sign marked “Imported Goods”. If the goods have an individual price marking, then in like manner, they shall also be marked with the words “Imported Goods” or the country of origin indicated. 
No person shall advertise for sale such goods unless such advertisement also contains the words “Imported Goods”. The word “person” as used in this paragraph shall not be deemed to include a person owning or publishing a newspaper, owning or operating a radio or television station, or other person, furnishing an advertising medium for the sale of such goods. 
No person shall sell, or advertise, offer or expose for sale any passenger tickets for ocean cruises unless such tickets, or such advertisement, contain a statement indicating the flag of registry of the vessel. 
Whoever violates any provision of this section shall, for the first offense, be punished by a fine of not less than fifty dollars nor more than one hundred dollars, and, for each subsequent offense, by a fine of not less than fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for one month, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
    </text>
</law>