<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23" level="3">Executive Office Of Labor And Workforce Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Apprenticeship Council;  Members;  Terms;  Expenses;  Meetings</catch_line>
    <order_by>11E</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  There shall be in the department of workforce development an apprenticeship council, to consist of 8 members, 6 of whom shall be appointed by the director of workforce development with the approval of the governor, 1 of whom shall be the director of workforce development or his successor, ex officio, and 1 of whom shall be the associate commissioner of career and technical education or his successor, in the department of education, ex officio. Of the appointive members, 3 of whom shall be persons who, on account of previous vocation, employment, occupation or affiliation, may be classified as representatives of labor and 3 of whom shall be persons who, on account of previous vocation, employment, occupation or affiliation, may be classified as representatives of management. The terms of office of the representatives of labor and management initially appointed shall expire as designated by the director at the time of making the appointments, 1 representative each of labor and management shall be appointed for a term of 1 year, 1 representative each of labor and management shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, and 1 representative each of labor and management shall be appointed for a term of 3 years. Thereafter, each member representing labor and management shall be appointed for a term of 3 years. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term of his predecessor shall be appointed for the remainder of the term. Each member of the council not otherwise compensated by the commonwealth may be reimbursed for transportation and other necessary expenses. The council shall not meet more than 15 days in a year.[ First paragraph as amended by 2011, 3, Secs. 46 to 48 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  There shall be in the department of labor standards an apprenticeship council, to consist of 8 members, 6 of whom shall be appointed by the secretary of labor and workforce development with the approval of the governor, 1 of whom shall be the director of the department of labor standards or his successor, ex officio, and 1 of whom shall be the associate commissioner of career and technical education or his successor, in the department of education, ex officio. Of the appointive members, 3 of whom shall be persons who, on account of previous vocation, employment, occupation or affiliation, may be classified as representatives of labor and 3 of whom shall be persons who, on account of previous vocation, employment, occupation or affiliation, may be classified as representatives of management. The terms of office of the representatives of labor and management initially appointed shall expire as designated by the director at the time of making the appointments, 1 representative each of labor and management shall be appointed for a term of 1 year, 1 representative each of labor and management shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, and 1 representative each of labor and management shall be appointed for a term of 3 years. Thereafter, each member representing labor and management shall be appointed for a term of 3 years. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term of his predecessor shall be appointed for the remainder of the term. Each member of the council not otherwise compensated by the commonwealth may be reimbursed for transportation and other necessary expenses. The council shall not meet more than 15 days in a year.  The council shall meet at the call of the director and shall aid the director in formulating policies for the effective administration of this chapter. The council shall suggest standards for apprentice programs and apprentice agreements, which shall in no case be lower than those prescribed by this chapter. The council shall suggest such rules and regulations as it deems necessary to carry out the intent and purposes of this chapter, and shall perform such other functions as the director may direct.
    </text>
</law>