<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>172J</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commissioner Of Banks To Obtain Criminal Record Information Of Applicants For Licensure Pursuant To Chapter 255 F; Restriction On Use</catch_line>
    <order_by>172J</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until May 4, 2012. For text effective May 4, 2012, see below.] 
Notwithstanding section 172 or any other general or special law to the contrary, the commissioner of banks may obtain all available criminal offender record information as found in the court activity record information from the criminal history systems board of all applicants for licensure pursuant to chapter 255F. Information obtained under this section shall not be disseminated for any purpose other than to provide mortgage protection for home owners. 
Chapter 6: Commissioner of banks to obtain criminal record information of applicants for licensure pursuant to chapter 255F; restriction on use [Text of section as amended by 2010, 256, Sec. 31 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102. For text effective until May 4, 2012, see above.] 
Notwithstanding section 172 or any other general or special law to the contrary, the commissioner of banks may obtain all available criminal offender record information as found in the court activity record information from the department of all applicants for licensure pursuant to chapter 255F. Information obtained under this section shall not be disseminated for any purpose other than to provide mortgage protection for home owners.
    </text>
</law>