<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146" level="3">Inspection Of Boilers, Air Tanks, Etc. Licenses Of Engineers, Firemen, And Operators Of Hoisting Machinery</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
          The following words as used in this chapter, unless a contrary meaning is specifically prescribed or the context otherwise requires, shall have the following meanings:  "Board'', the board of boiler rules appointed under section ten of chapter twenty-two.  "Boiler'', A closed pressure vessel in which water is heated, steam is generated, steam is superheated or any combination thereof, under pressure or vacuum for use externally to itself by the direct application of heat from the combustion of fuel, or from electricity or nuclear energy. The term "Boiler'' shall include fired units for heating or vaporizing liquids other than water where these units are separate from processing systems and are complete within themselves.  "Chief'', the chief of inspections of the department of public safety.  "Commissioner'', the commissioner of public safety.  "Department'', the department of public safety.[ Definition of "District engineering inspector'' inserted following definition of "Department'' by 2011, 68, Sec. 96 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221.]  "District engineering inspector'', an inspector of the division.  "Division'', the division of inspection of the department of public safety.  "Inspector'', a district engineering inspector of the division of inspection of the department of public safety, or an inspector of an insurance company authorized to insure steam boilers in the commonwealth.  "Pressure Vessel'', A vessel in which the pressure is obtained from an external source or by the application of heat from an indirect source or from a direct source, other than a vessel defined as a "Boiler'' in this section.
    </text>
</law>