<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>150</section_number>
    <catch_line>Lists Of Dogs;  Refusal To Answer Person Listing Dogs;  False Answers</catch_line>
    <order_by>150</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  Persons authorized or directed by section four of chapter fifty-one or by any special law to make lists of residents three years of age or older shall make a list of all dogs owned by the inhabitants at the time of making lists required under such section and return the same in duplicate to the city or town clerk, or, in Boston, to the police commissioner on or before April first. An owner or keeper of a dog who refuses to answer or answers falsely to persons directed or authorized to make a list of the owners of dogs shall be punished by a fine of not less than ten dollars which, except in Suffolk county, shall be paid into the county treasury.
Chapter 140: Lists of dogs; refusal to answer person listing dogs; false answers
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 21 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  Persons authorized or directed by section 4 of chapter 51 or by a special law, to make lists of residents 3 years of age or older shall make a list of all dogs owned by the inhabitants at the time of making such lists and shall annually return the same, in duplicate, to the city or town clerk or to the police commissioner in the city of Boston. An owner or keeper of a dog who refuses to answer or answers falsely to a person directed or authorized to make such a list shall be punished by a fine of not less than $20 which shall be paid to the city or town.
    </text>
</law>