<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111F" order_by="111F" level="3">Hazardous Substances Disclosure By Employers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Material Safety Data Sheets; Preparation; Revision</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        The manufacturer of any toxic or hazardous substance shall prepare and provide direct purchasers of said toxic or hazardous substances with an MSDS which, to the best of the manufacturer’s knowledge, is current, accurate, and complete, based on information then reasonably available to the manufacturer. 
Any person other than a manufacturer who sells a mixture of toxic hazardous substance as defined in this chapter shall provide its direct purchasers of the mixture at the time of sale with a copy of the most recent MSDS or equivalent information. 
Any person who produces a mixture may, for the purposes of this section, prepare and use a mixture MSDS, subject to the provisions of section ten. 
A manufacturer who is responsible for preparing and transmitting an MSDS under the provisions of this section shall revise said MSDS, on a timely basis, as appropriate to the importance of any new information which would affect the contents of the existing MSDS, and in any event within one year of such information becoming available to the manufacturer. 
Any employer who receives, compiles, or prepares new information which would serve to update the MSDS for any toxic or hazardous substance present in his workplace, and who has filed a copy of said MSDS with DEP and the municipal coordinator pursuant to section sixteen of this chapter, shall file an updated MSDS containing said new information on a semi-annual basis, and shall concurrently update his own copy of said MSDS.
    </text>
</law>