<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>148</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>148</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in sections one hundred and forty-nine to one hundred and sixty-two, inclusive of this chapter, section one of chapter one hundred and fifty-six A, section forty-seven D of chapter one hundred and seventy-five, section sixty B of chapter two hundred and thirty-one, the following words shall, unless the context requires otherwise, have the following meanings:— 
“Acupuncture”, the practice of medicine based on Traditional Oriental Medical Theories; primarily the insertion of metal needles through the skin at certain points on the body, with or without the application of electric current, and with or without the application of heat to the needles, skin, or both, in an attempt to relieve pain or improve body function. Electroacupuncture, whether utilizing electrodes on the surface of the skin or current applied to inserted needles will be considered the practice of acupuncture. 
“Board”, the board of registration in medicine, established under the provisions of section ten of chapter thirteen. 
“Committee”, the committee on acupuncture of the board of registration in medicine, established under the provisions of section one hundred and forty-nine. 
“Acupuncturist”, a person licensed under the provisions of sections one hundred and forty-nine to one hundred and sixty-two, inclusive, to practice acupuncture. 
“Acupuncture intern”, an acupuncture student engaged in practical training including needle insertion on human subjects in an acupuncture internship program approved by the committee on acupuncture.
    </text>
</law>