<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="5" order_by="5" level="2">Militia</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="33" order_by="33" level="3">Militia</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>126</section_number>
    <catch_line>Armory Commission; Powers And Duties In Respect To Location And Rejuvenation Of Armories; Method Of Acquiring Land</catch_line>
    <order_by>126</order_by>
    <text>
        The armory commission shall rebuild, remodel or repair state armories or air installations injured or destroyed by fire, and may reconstruct, remodel, enlarge or otherwise improve existing state armories, or air installations if it deems the needs of the service so require, and shall construct additional armories or air installations until the armed forces of the commonwealth shall be provided with adequate quarters. 
It shall designate the location of armories and air installations so to be constructed and shall thereupon, in behalf of the commonwealth, take by eminent domain under chapter seventy-nine, or acquire by purchase or otherwise, suitable lots of land in the respective cities or towns designated, and shall erect, furnish and equip thereon armories or air installations sufficient for one or more units of the armed forces of the commonwealth as it deems necessary, but no land shall be acquired and no buildings erected, reconstructed, remodeled or enlarged until the site and plans thereof, and the total amount to be authorized therefor, have been approved by the governor and council. 
It may, in behalf of the commonwealth, and with the approval of the governor and council, take by eminent domain under chapter seventy-nine, or acquire by purchase or lease, land suitable for ranges for target practice for the armed forces of the commonwealth and upon such land may, with the approval of the governor and council, erect such buildings and construct such facilities as may be needed. 
Land acquired by purchase under this section shall be paid for by the commonwealth upon the execution of such a release or conveyance as shall be prescribed by the attorney general. 
It may, in behalf of the commonwealth, and with the approval of the governor and council, dispose of an armory or air installation, whenever it deems that the continued existence of such armory or air installation no longer suitably or efficiently serves the purposes of the armed forces of the commonwealth either due to obsolescence or changes in the defense requirements.
    </text>
</law>