<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>198</section_number>
    <catch_line>Apprentice Hearing Instrument Specialists</catch_line>
    <order_by>198</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The board shall establish the requirements for registration of apprentice hearing instrument specialists and shall promulgate the rules and regulations consistent with law as may be necessary. A person registered as an apprentice by the board may engage in the dispensing of hearing aids without first having met the requirements under subsection (f) of section 197. The board shall promulgate rules and regulations to establish an apprentice training program which may include a board approved home study course. The board shall register as an apprentice and issue a certificate of registration to an applicant who has shown to the satisfaction of the board that the applicant: (1) is at least 18 years of age; (2) has a high school diploma or its equivalent; (3) is registered in a board approved training program; (4) has an identified supervisor who is a person registered in good standing in the commonwealth as a hearing instrument specialist or licensed as an audiologist and who has agreed to perform supervisory functions as described in subsection (c); and (5) has paid the board a fee which shall be set by the secretary of administration and finance. The certificate of registration for an apprentice shall include the name of the hearing instrument specialist who is supervising the apprentice and such supervisor shall execute an acknowledgment of responsibility for all acts of the apprentice in connection with hearing aid dispensing.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Upon completion of the training program, the apprentice shall take the board approved examination. Following three failed examinations, an apprentice shall only be reexamined at the discretion of the board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     An apprentice shall perform the functions of a hearing instrument specialist in accordance with board rules only under the supervision of a registered hearing instrument specialist or licensed audiologist. Such supervision shall be direct, on site and full-time, or the equivalent part time, for a minimum of 30 days after the initial hiring of the apprentice.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The board shall develop standards and regulations governing dispensing practices related to home visits. An apprentice engaging in hearing aid dispensing, after the initial period of direct supervision, shall be subject to all standards of dispensing and related penalties and fines pertaining to hearing instrument specialists.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     An apprentice registration shall expire 18 months from the date of its issuance except that, on recommendation of the board, the registration may be reissued for 18 months only.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>