<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>60H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Charges Against Architect; Hearing; Notice; Revocation, Suspension Or Annulment Of Certificate; Notice To Secretary Of State; Re Issue Of Certificate</catch_line>
    <order_by>60H</order_by>
    <text>
        Charges against an architect involving any matter coming within the jurisdiction of the board shall be in writing and shall be filed with the board. Such charges, at the discretion of the board, shall be heard within thirty days after being so filed. The accused architect shall have the right at such hearing to appear personally, with or without counsel, to cross-examine witnesses against him and to produce evidence and witnesses in his defence. The board shall set the time and place for such hearing and shall cause a copy of the charges, together with a notice of the time and place fixed for the hearing, to be sent by registered mail to the accused architect, at his latest place of residence or business known to the board, at least ten days before such date. If after such hearing the board finds the accused architect guilty of the charges, or any of them, it shall issue an order revoking, suspending or annulling the certificate of registration of the accused architect, or reprimanding, censuring or otherwise disciplining him. If the board finds him not guilty it shall enter an order dismissing the charges. If such order be that a certificate of registration be revoked, suspended or annulled, the board shall in writing so notify the state secretary and the clerk of the city or town in the commonwealth wherein such architect has his principal place of business. The board may re-issue a certificate of registration to any person whose certificate of registration has been revoked. Application for the re-issuance of a certificate of registration shall be made in such manner as the board may direct, and shall be accompanied by a fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven.
    </text>
</law>