<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>21B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing Of Private Trade School;  Suspension And Revocation Of License</catch_line>
    <order_by>21B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until August 1, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 106, Sec. 4. See 2012, 106, Sec. 9.]  No person shall operate or maintain a private trade school unless he is licensed so to do by the commissioner of education as hereinafter provided. Said commissioner shall not issue a license to operate or maintain such a school unless and until he shall have approved as to such school the proposed standards adopted and methods of instruction to be followed, the equipment and housing provided, the training and experience of the teachers to be employed, the form and contents of the student enrolment agreement or contract and the method of collecting tuition, nor and unless and until such schools shall have filed in the office of said commissioner its current advertising, if any. All advertising used by any such school subsequent to the receipt of a license hereunder shall from time to time be filed in the office of said commissioner. Said commissioner may, after reasonable notice and a hearing, suspend or revoke such license and shall have the same powers to require by summons the attendance and testimony of witnesses, the production of books, papers and documents, and to administer oaths, as are conferred upon city councils and other bodies by section eight of chapter two hundred and thirty-three. Sections nine and ten of said chapter shall apply to witnesses summoned as aforesaid. Every such license shall run for two years from date of issuance and the fee for an original license and for each renewal thereof shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven. Said commissioner may adopt and from time to time alter and amend rules and regulations, in conformity with this section, governing such schools and the licensing thereof. Each person operating a private trade school shall make an annual report to said commissioner in such form as he may prescribe.
    </text>
</law>