<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="55C" order_by="55C" level="3">Limited Public Financing Of Campaignsfor Statewide Elective Office</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Limited Public Financing Eligibility</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        The director shall determine and certify to the state treasurer those candidates for statewide elective office that are eligible for limited public financing as provided in sections 4 and 6 and shall determine and certify to the state treasurer the amounts due to each eligible candidate as provided in sections 5 and 7. 
The director shall prescribe and make available forms on which statements of qualifying contributions shall be filed by candidates, which statements shall contain the name and address of each individual making a contribution, the amount of the contribution and date of deposit, the cumulative total of all contributions made by that individual during the calendar year in which elections are held for statewide elective office and the next preceding calendar year and shall contain such other information and shall be organized in such a manner as the director may reasonably require to expedite the determinations required to be made by the director by this chapter. The director shall notify candidates of any amounts determined by the director to be due from candidates under section nine and shall direct that such amounts be paid to the state election campaign fund. On or before January 30 of any year next following a year in which elections are held for statewide elective office the director shall prepare and submit a report relating to the matters entrusted to him under this chapter to the clerk of the senate and to the commission established by section 3 of chapter 55 and shall make copies of such report available to any person upon payment of the reasonable cost of copying or reproduction.
    </text>
</law>