<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="121D" order_by="121D" level="3">Affordable Housing Trust Fund</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Committee; Members</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be established an advisory committee to the fund, which shall make policy recommendations to the agency and to the department of housing and community development regarding the fund’s program and funding activities.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The committee shall be comprised of the following 15 members: the director of the Department of Housing and Community Development or his designee; the executive director of the Massachusetts Housing Partnership Fund or his designee; the executive director of the Community Economic Development Assistance Corporation or his designee; two municipal officials appointed by the Massachusetts Municipal Association, one of whom shall be from a city and one of whom shall be from a town; one lender experienced in the financing of affordable housing and one for-profit developer of affordable housing, each appointed by the agency; an executive director of a local housing authority appointed by the Massachusetts chapter of the National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials; and a representative appointed by each of the following organizations: the Citizens’ Housing and Planning Association, Inc., the Massachusetts Affordable Housing Alliance, the Massachusetts Association of Community Development Corporations, the Massachusetts Nonprofit Housing Association, the Massachusetts Housing and Shelter Alliance and the Greater Boston Interfaith Organization. Committee members shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing authorities.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Chapter 268A shall apply to committee members as special state employees, but the fund may purchase from, sell to, borrow from, loan to, contract with or otherwise deal with any person in which any committee member is in any way interested or involved, if such interest or involvement is disclosed in advance to the members of the committee and recorded in the minutes of the committee meeting. No committee member having such an interest or involvement may participate in any action of the committee relating to such person. Employment by the commonwealth or service in any agency thereof shall not be deemed to be such an interest or involvement.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>