<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Civil Service Commission; Members; Chairman; Appointment;  Tenure; Political Party Restriction; Compensation</catch_line>
    <order_by>4I</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be within the executive office for administration and finance, but not under its supervision or control, a commission to be known as the civil service commission, consisting of five members, one of whom because of vocation, employment, occupation or affiliation, can be classified as a bona fide representative of labor and 2 of whom shall have prior experience serving as a town administrator, city manager, selectman or city councilor. 
Upon the expiration of the term of office of a commissioner of the civil service commission, his successor shall be appointed by the governor for five years; provided, however, that if such successor is not appointed within sixty days of the expiration of the term of office of a commissioner, the said commissioner shall be deemed to be reappointed to a full term. Not more than three of such members of said commission shall be members of the same political party, and, of the members of said commission who are enrolled as members of a political party on the voting list used at the primaries, not more than a majority of such members shall be of the same political party. The governor shall, from time to time, designate one of the members as chairman. The positions of chairman and each other member of the commission shall be classified in accordance with section forty-five of chapter thirty and the salaries shall be determined in accordance with section forty-six C of said chapter thirty. The commissioners shall receive their travel and other necessary expenses incurred in attending meetings. 
Meetings of the commission shall be held at such time and location as it may determine and the commission shall meet upon the request of the personnel administrator. The commission shall in its rules of practice and procedure provide for the conduct of hearings throughout the commonwealth when it would best serve the interested parties. 
Said commission or any member thereof, or the personnel administrator, may require in connection with the activities authorized by law any official or employee of the human resources division to give full information and to provide all papers and records relating to any official act performed by him.
    </text>
</law>