<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35RR</section_number>
    <catch_line>Health Information Technology Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35RR</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 68, Sec. 21 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Health Information Technology Trust Fund, in this section called the fund. There shall be credited to the fund revenues from federal reimbursements under the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act, Title XIII of Division A and Title IV of Division B of Pub. L. No. 111-5, and any other federal reimbursements, grants, premiums, gifts or other contributions from any source received for or in support of the health care provider incentive payment program and for the promotion of electronic health record adoption and health information exchange in the commonwealth. The secretary of health and human services shall be the fund's trustee and shall expend the fund, without further appropriation, for incentive payments to eligible Massachusetts Medicaid health care providers for the adoption, implementation, upgrade or meaningful use of certified electronic health record technology and to support the planning, implementation and operating costs of administering these payments. The secretary may certify for payment amounts in anticipation of federal revenues collected for the corresponding quarter during the previous fiscal year. For the purpose of accommodating timing discrepancies between the receipt of revenues and related expenditures, the secretary may incur expenses, after written approval from the secretary of administration and finance, and the comptroller shall certify for payment, amounts not to exceed the most recent revenue estimate as certified by the MassHealth director, as reported in the state accounting system.
    </text>
</law>