<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>127J</section_number>
    <catch_line>Petition By Receiver To Apply For Financial Assistance; Notice And Hearing; Financial Assistance; Lien</catch_line>
    <order_by>127J</order_by>
    <text>
        A receiver may petition the court for leave to apply for financial assistance from the commonwealth to supplement funds otherwise available from rents, if he deems that the rents are insufficient to effectuate the necessary repairs or rehabilitation. Seven days’ notice of a hearing on said petition shall be given to the respondent as well as any mortgagees or lien holders of record. The court, after hearing, may, by decree, authorize the receiver to apply for such financial assistance, if it finds such assistance is necessary, that it is in a reasonable amount and that the sum required to repair and rehabilitate the premises is not so excessive as to constitute an imprudent and unreasonable expenditure to accomplish the purpose. 
Application for financial assistance shall be made to the department of public health in such manner and on such forms as may be prescribed by said department. 
Said department may expend for such assistance such sums as may be appropriated therefor. 
The receiver shall return any unused portion of any sums received by him to the commonwealth. The balance owed by the receiver to the commonwealth shall, together with interest thereon at the rate of six per cent per annum, constitute a debt due the commonwealth, upon the rendering of an account therefor to the owner of record, and shall be recoverable from such owner in an action of contract. Any such debt, including interest thereon, shall constitute a lien on the property involved, if a notice of such lien is recorded on behalf of the commonwealth in the proper registry of deeds within ninety days after the debt becomes due. 
Any proceeding under this section may be advanced for speedy trial.
    </text>
</law>