<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="3">Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bureau Of Pipefitters, Refrigeration Technicians And Sprinkler Fitters</catch_line>
    <order_by>10A</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be in the department of public safety a bureau to be known as the bureau of pipefitters, refrigeration technicians and sprinkler fitters. The bureau shall consist of eleven members, one of whom shall be the commissioner of public safety or his designee; and ten of whom shall be appointed by the governor, one of whom shall be a representative of the public, one of whom shall be a member of Air Conditioning and Refrigeration Contractors of Boston, who has been in business not less than ten years as a refrigeration contractor, one of whom shall be a refrigeration technician with a minimum of ten years experience, one of whom shall be a member of the New England Mechanical Contractors Association, Inc., one of whom shall be a member of the Massachusetts Building and Construction Trades Council, one of whom shall be a pipefitter with a minimum of ten years experience, one of whom shall be a fire protection sprinkler system contractor who has been in business not less than ten years as such contractor, one of whom shall be a sprinkler fitter with a minimum of ten years experience, one of whom shall be a mechanical engineer, and one of whom shall represent a user. Said members shall be designated in groups of two in their initial appointments to serve for one, two, three, and four years, respectively. Upon the expiration of the term of office of a member, his successor shall be appointed in the manner aforesaid for four years. The commissioner of public safety or his designee shall be designated the chairman. 
Each appointive member of the bureau shall be paid fifty dollars for each day while engaged in the actual performance of his duties as such; provided, however, that such payment shall not exceed seven hundred and fifty dollars in the aggregate in any fiscal year; and provided further, that such member shall also receive from the commonwealth all expenses necessarily incurred by him in connection with his official duties. 
There shall be an executive secretary of the bureau, who shall assist the members in their responsibilities. Such clerical, technical and other assistants required by the bureau shall be assigned by the commissioner.
    </text>
</law>