<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>173</section_number>
    <catch_line>Regulations For Program Research; Monitoring; Access Restricted</catch_line>
    <order_by>173</order_by>
    <text>
        [First paragraph effective until May 4, 2012. For text effective May 4, 2012, see below.] 
The board shall promulgate regulations to govern the use of criminal offender record information for purposes of program research. Such regulations shall require preservation of the anonymity of the individuals to whom such information relates, shall require the completion of nondisclosure agreements by all participants in such programs, and shall impose such additional requirements and conditions as the board finds to be necessary to assure the protection of privacy and security interests. 
[First paragraph as amended by 2010, 256, Secs. 33 and 34 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102. For text effective until May 4, 2012, see above.] 
The commissioner may approve research programs to obtain criminal offender record information; provided, however, that said research programs shall not publish any information that either identifies or tends to identify the subject of the criminal offender record information, and the commissioner shall promulgate regulations to govern the use of criminal offender record information for purposes of program research. Such regulations shall require preservation of the anonymity of the individuals to whom such information relates, shall require the completion of nondisclosure agreements by all participants in such programs, and shall impose such additional requirements and conditions as the commissioner finds to be necessary to assure the protection of privacy and security interests. 
[Second paragraph effective until May 4, 2012. For text effective May 4, 2012, see below.] 
The board may monitor any such programs to assure their effectiveness. The board may, if it determines that a program’s continuance threatens privacy or security interests, prohibit access on behalf of any such program to criminal offender record information. 
[Second paragraph as amended by 2010, 256, Sec. 34 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102. For text effective until May 4, 2012, see above.] 
The commissioner may monitor any such programs to assure their effectiveness. The commissioner may, if it determines that a program’s continuance threatens privacy or security interests, prohibit access on behalf of any such program to criminal offender record information.
    </text>
</law>