<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Access To Records;  Copies Of Reports, Notices And Other Documents;  Production Of Books And Documents</catch_line>
    <order_by>4E</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The commissioner shall have access to all records, as defined in section forty-two of chapter thirty, in the custody of all agencies within the executive office for administration and finance, except where such access is prohibited by law. Such agencies shall furnish him with copies of all reports, notices and other documents which they are required by law to submit to the governor, the general court or any other agency, and with all other information requested by the commissioner for the purpose of discharging the duties of his office.  In making any examination or investigation authorized under this chapter, the commissioner may require the production of books, papers, contracts and documents in the custody of any agency other than those within said executive office, which relate to any matter within the scope of such examination or investigation.
Chapter 7: Production of agency records in connection with investigations
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 39 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  In addition to any powers provided in chapter 6A, in making any examination or investigation authorized under this chapter, the secretary may require the production of books, papers, contracts and documents in the custody of any agency other than those within the executive office of administration and finance, which relate to any matter within the scope of such examination or investigation.
    </text>
</law>