<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138" level="3">Alcoholic Liquors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>21</section_number>
    <catch_line>Liability Of Manufacturer, Winegrower, Farmer Brewer, Wholesaler, Importer And Licensee For Excise; Fines; Administration Of Tax</catch_line>
    <order_by>21</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For each barrel of thirty-one gallons, or fractional part of a barrel, aforesaid, of malt beverages, at the rate of three dollars and thirty cents per barrel aforesaid;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     For each wine gallon, or fractional part thereof, of cider containing more than three per cent but not more than six per cent of alcohol by weight at sixty degrees Fahrenheit, at the rate of three cents per wine gallon;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     For each wine gallon, or fractional part thereof, of still wine, other than cider containing more than three per cent but not more than six per cent of alcohol as aforesaid, including vermouth, at the rate of fifty-five cents per wine gallon;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     For each wine gallon, or fractional part thereof, of champagne and all other sparkling wines, at the rate of seventy cents per wine gallon;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     For each wine gallon, or fractional part thereof, of all other alcoholic beverages containing fifteen per cent or less of alcohol by volume at sixty degrees Fahrenheit, at the rate of one dollar and ten cents per wine gallon;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     For each wine gallon, or fractional part thereof, of all other alcoholic beverages containing more than fifteen per cent but not more than fifty per cent of alcohol by volume at sixty degrees Fahrenheit, at the rate of four dollars and five cents per wine gallon;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     For each proof gallon, or fractional part thereof, of all other alcoholic beverages containing more than fifty per cent of alcohol by volume at sixty degrees Fahrenheit, or alcohol at the rate of four dollars and five cents per proof gallon. The words “proof gallon” when used in this section with reference to an alcoholic beverage, shall be held to be a gallon of the alcoholic beverage which contains one half its volume of alcohol of a specific gravity of seven thousand nine hundred and thirty-nine ten thousandths (.7939) at sixty degrees Fahrenheit. Every person subject to this section shall keep a true and accurate account of all alcoholic beverages or alcohol sold by him other than malt beverages imported into the commonwealth by him, and a like account of all malt beverages imported into the commonwealth by him. The excise imposed by this section shall be paid to the commissioner of revenue at the time provided for filing the return required by section sixteen of chapter sixty-two C. The state tax commission by rule or regulation shall provide for the waiver of payment of the excise in respect to any alcoholic beverages or alcohol if it appears that an excise has already been paid under the provisions of this section in respect thereto; provided, however, that alcoholic beverages or alcohol manufactured within or imported into the commonwealth and exported therefrom shall be exempt from such excise. Alcohol for the purpose of this section shall not include alcohol sold for scientific, chemical, mechanical, manufacturing, industrial, culinary, pharmaceutical or medical purposes in containers greater in capacity than one wine gallon, and shall not include absolute alcohol, so-called, sold for such purposes in any containers. The taxes imposed by this section shall also be applicable to sales of alcoholic beverages, upon which an excise has not already been paid under the provisions of this section, made by railroad or car corporations or the owner or operator of any vessel or shipping company licensed to sell alcoholic beverages under the provisions of section thirteen.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Sixteen and seven-tenths per cent shall be credited to the Commonwealth’s Pension Liability Fund for the accumulation of assets in advance of the payment of retirement allowances and used solely for the purposes of offsetting the anticipated future cost of funding the contributory retirement systems of the state employees and teachers as defined in section one of chapter thirty-two.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The balance shall be credited to the General Fund.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>