<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118E" order_by="118E" level="3">Division Of Medical Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>21A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Medical Assistance Eligibility Of An Institutionalized Spouse</catch_line>
    <order_by>21A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     In determining the eligibility for medical assistance of an institutionalized spouse, the division shall comply with all the requirements set forth in 42 U.S.C. 1396r-5, including, but not limited to, the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Upon a determination of eligibility for medical assistance of an institutionalized spouse, the division shall send notification to both spouses.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The notice shall include, but shall not be limited to, the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     the type and amount of all countable assets;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     the amount of the community spouse monthly income allowance, as defined in 42 U.S.C. 1396 r-5(d)(2);
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     the amount of any family allowances described in 42 U.S.C. 1396 r-5(d)(1)(C);
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     the minimum monthly maintenance needs allowance of the community spouse, as defined in 42 U.S.C. 1396r-5(d)(3);
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     the community spouse resource allowance and its method of computation; provided, however, that the division shall establish the maximum community spouse resource allowance permissible under 42 U.S.C. s.1396r-5(f)(2);
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     the right to a fair hearing concerning ownership or availability of income or resources, and the determination of the community spouse monthly income allowance or community spouse resource allowance, and the right to a decision within ninety days of a timely request for a fair hearing;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     a citation to this section and to any applicable regulation of the division of medical assistance; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="viii">
    	     the following language:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The notice shall include, but shall not be limited to, the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     the type and amount of all countable assets;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     the right to a fair hearing concerning ownership or availability of income or resources, and the determination of the community spouse monthly income allowance or community spouse resource allowance at the time Medicaid eligibility is determined, and the right to a decision within ninety days of a timely request for a fair hearing;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     a citation to this section of the General Laws and to any applicable regulation of the division of medical assistance; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     the following language:
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In making determinations under this section, the division shall revise the community spouse resource allowance as permitted or required by federal law. Either spouse shall have the right to request a fair hearing at which, if it is shown that the income of the community spouse is less than the minimum monthly maintenance needs allowance of the community spouse, the referee shall revise the community spouse resource allowance, using methods permitted or required by federal law, to a level sufficient to generate the shortfall in income. The division shall calculate interest income on the investment of the community spouse resource allowance using the rates reported in the Bank Rate Monitor Index on the date of the hearing.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>