<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32</section_number>
    <catch_line>Time For Presentment For Payment Of Checks Issued By The State Treasurer;  Place For Payment Of Checks Not Timely Presented;  Refunds</catch_line>
    <order_by>32</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  Any check issued by the state treasurer or by any agent or agency of the commonwealth, other than checks issued in payment of obligations of the state board of retirement, the teachers' retirement board and the MassHealth program, which is not presented for payment within 1 year after its issue date, shall be payable only at the office of the state treasurer. Any check issued on behalf of the MassHealth program, which is not presented for payment within 180 days after its issue date, shall be payable only at the office of the state treasurer. On such date, the comptroller also shall refund to the unemployment compensation fund and to each applicable account of monies separately accounted for by the comptroller as other than commonwealth monies, such amounts which in the opinion of the state treasurer represent all monies of such unemployment compensation fund or such account which have remained in the unclaimed check fund for at least one year. All checks issued in payment of obligations of the state board of retirement and the teachers' retirement board shall be payable only in accordance with the provisions of subdivision (3) of section eleven of chapter thirty-two.
Chapter 29: Time for presentment for payment of checks issued by the state treasurer; place for payment of checks not timely presented; transfer of unclaimed funds; refunds
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 61 effective July 1, 2012 until January 1, 2013. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Any check issued by the state treasurer or by any agent or agency of the commonwealth, other than checks issued in payment of obligations of the state board of retirement, the teachers' retirement board and the MassHealth program, which is not presented for payment within 1 year after its issue date, shall be payable only at the office of the state treasurer. Any check issued on behalf of the MassHealth program, which is not presented for payment within 180 days after its issue date, shall be payable only at the office of the state treasurer. Annually, on June 30, the comptroller shall transfer to the Unclaimed Property Fund, established in section 9 of chapter 200A, all funds that are identified by the state treasurer as funds of the commonwealth that have remained in the unclaimed check fund for not less than 1 year. On such date, the comptroller also shall refund to the unemployment compensation fund and to each applicable account of monies separately accounted for by the comptroller as other than commonwealth monies, such amounts which in the opinion of the state treasurer represent all monies of such unemployment compensation fund or such account which have remained in the unclaimed check fund for at least one year. All checks issued in payment of obligations of the state board of retirement and the teachers' retirement board shall be payable only in accordance with the provisions of subdivision (3) of section eleven of chapter thirty-two.
Chapter 29: Time for presentment for payment of checks issued by the state treasurer; place for payment of checks not timely presented; transfer of unclaimed funds; refunds
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Any check issued by the state treasurer or by any agent or agency of the commonwealth, other than checks issued in payment of obligations of the state board of retirement, the teachers' retirement board and the MassHealth program, which is not presented for payment within 1 year after its issue date, shall be payable only at the office of the state treasurer. Any check issued on behalf of the MassHealth program, which is not presented for payment within 180 days after its issue date, shall be payable only at the office of the state treasurer. Annually, on June 30, the comptroller shall transfer to the Unclaimed Property Fund, established in section 9 of chapter 200A, all funds that are identified by the state treasurer as funds of the commonwealth that have remained in the unclaimed check fund for not less than 1 year. On such date, the comptroller also shall refund to the unemployment compensation fund and to each applicable account of monies separately accounted for by the comptroller as other than commonwealth monies, such amounts which in the opinion of the state treasurer represent all monies of such unemployment compensation fund or such account which have remained in the unclaimed check fund for at least one year. All checks issued in payment of obligations of the state board of retirement and the teachers' retirement board shall be payable only under subdivision (3) of section 11 of chapter 32.
    </text>
</law>