<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="15D" order_by="15D" level="3">Department Of Early Education And Care</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3A</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Advisory Council On Early Education And Care; Membership;  Reimbursement Of Expenses; Terms; Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>3A</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a state advisory council on early education and care, the members of which shall represent a reasonable geographic balance and shall reflect the diversity of the commonwealth in race, ethnicity, gender and sexual orientation. Members of the advisory council shall, at minimum, include 1 person from each of the following organizations, or their successor organizations, if applicable: Child Development and Education, Inc., the Massachusetts Head Start Association; the Massachusetts Association for the Education of Young Children; the Massachusetts Association of Early Childhood Teacher Educators; the Massachusetts Association of School Committees; the Massachusetts Association of School Superintendents; the Massachusetts Elementary School Principals Association; the Massachusetts Association of Regional Schools; the Massachusetts Teachers Association; the American Federation of Teachers Massachusetts; the Massachusetts Business Alliance for Education; the Massachusetts Association of Community Partnerships for Children, Inc.; Strategies for Children/Early Education for All; the Child Care Resource and Referral Network; the Massachusetts Association of Day Care Agencies; the Massachusetts Independent Child Care Organization; Associated Early Care and Education; BostNET; the YMCAs of Massachusetts; the United Way of Massachusetts Bay; the Massachusetts After-School Partnership; Parents Alliance for Catholic Education; Together for Kids Coalition; Horizons for Homeless Children; the Massachusetts Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics; the Federation of Children With Special Needs; the Bureau of Jewish Education; the Boston Institute for the Development of Infants and Parents; the Massachusetts Early Intervention Consortium; and a family child care provider chosen by the commissioner. 
The council shall be further composed of 8 members, 3 of whom shall be appointed by the speaker of the house, 1 of whom shall be appointed by the minority leader of the house of representatives, 3 of whom shall be appointed by the president of the senate, and 1 of whom shall be appointed by the minority leader of the senate. Additional advisory members may also be recommended by the commissioner and appointed by the board. All appointees shall have a special expertise or interest in high quality early childhood education and care and shall represent a mix of representatives of the early childhood community, the civic, labor, and business communities, academics, parents, teachers, social service providers, and health care providers. 
Members shall not, by virtue of their membership, be considered state employees under chapter 268A. The members of the council shall serve without compensation but may be reimbursed, subject to appropriation, for expenses necessarily and reasonably incurred in the performance of their responsibilities. Members shall be appointed for a term of 3 years. No member shall serve for more than 2 consecutive terms. The council shall meet not fewer than 4 times annually. 
The commissioner shall consult with the advisory council on the development of the 5-year master plan for early education and care required under section 4, and the adoption of the educationally sound kindergarten readiness assessment instrument required under sections 3 and 13. The advisory council may review and offer comments on any rules or regulations before promulgation by the board, and may, from time to time, make recommendations to the board that it considers appropriate for changes and improvements in early education and care programs and services.
    </text>
</law>