<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commercial Shooting Preserves; Permits; Licenses</catch_line>
    <order_by>31</order_by>
    <text>
        The director is authorized to issue permits for the operation of commercial shooting preserves. Any person desiring to operate a commercial shooting preserve shall make application therefor on forms to be furnished by the director. The director may, upon receipt of a fee, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration and finance under the provisions of section three B of chapter seven of the General Laws, issue to such applicant a commercial shooting preserve permit. A commercial shooting preserve shall consist of a single parcel of land containing not less than one hundred acres nor more than five hundred acres. A permit to operate a commercial shooting preserve shall, notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, entitle the holder and his guests to kill and take on such preserve, by shooting or falconry only, such native or non-native game birds as shall be determined by the director. Every person hunting on such commercial shooting preserve or participating in a shoot held on a commercial shooting preserve permit shall possess a valid resident or nonresident hunting or sporting license or a resident or nonresident commercial shooting preserve license, good only on commercial shooting preserves; provided, however, that a person purchasing a resident or nonresident commercial shooting preserve license shall be exempt from the provisions of section fourteen; provided, further, that such exemption shall be applicable only to one who purchases a resident or nonresident commercial shooting preserve on no more than four separate occasions in any calendar year. Tags and posters, if used, shall be supplied by the director at a cost to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration and finance under the provision of said section three B of said chapter seven. The director may, with the approval of the fisheries and wildlife board, establish rules and regulations relating to commercial shooting preserves including but not limited to species of game birds hunted, liberation requirements, posting, period of operation, record keeping and classes of preserves, and may in like manner alter, amend, or repeal the same. Any permit issued under this section may be revoked by the director for violation of any provision of this section or any rule or regulation established hereunder.
    </text>
</law>