<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="85" order_by="85" level="3">Regulations And By Laws Relative To Ways And Bridges</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Signs On State Highways Indicating Availability Of Certain Services</catch_line>
    <order_by>2D</order_by>
    <text>
        The department may, upon application by an interested person or persons and upon payment of an appropriate fee to be established by the department, erect on state highways, signs indicating the availability of gas, food and lodging and telephone or other services convenient to the public. Said signs shall be erected at such locations and shall be of such size and color and contain such wording or symbol as the department deems proper for the public convenience, and such signs shall be maintained by the department. Any sign erected under this section shall not constitute a billboard or other advertising device, as defined in section thirty of chapter ninety-three. The department may make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. 
Any fees collected under this section shall be paid over to the state treasurer and credited to the Highway Fund. 
Notwithstanding the provisions of section five of chapter thirty A, no rule, regulation, change of regulation, or condition of the public works commission promulgated pursuant to the provisions of this section shall take effect except as hereinafter provided. 
A copy of every such rule, regulation or condition shall be filed with the clerks of the senate and the house of representatives and shall be forthwith referred by them to the joint committee on transportation. 
Said committee shall file a written report with the clerks of the senate and house of representatives within sixty days after the filing of the copy thereof with said clerks stating whether said rules, regulations and conditions are consistent with the statutory provisions under which they were promulgated. 
Said rules, regulations and conditions shall take effect unless disapproved by a majority vote of both branches of the general court sixty days after the filing of the copy thereof with the clerks of the senate and house of representatives unless the general court has prorogued within said sixty days. 
If the general court prorogues within sixty days of the filing with the clerks of the senate and house of representatives of such rules, regulations and conditions, said clerks shall refer the same to said committee in the next session of the general court. Said committee shall report as hereinbefore provided, within sixty days of the first day of such session and such rules, regulations and conditions shall take effect sixty days after such first day of such session unless disapproved by a majority vote of both branches of the general court within such sixty days. 
The clerks of the senate and house of representatives shall notify the commission of the action taken thereon by the general court.
    </text>
</law>