<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32B" order_by="32B" level="3">Contributory Group General Or Blanket Insurance For Persons In The Service Of Counties, Cities, Towns And Districts, And Their Dependents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18</section_number>
    <catch_line>Medicare Extension Plans;  Mandatory Transfer Of Retirees</catch_line>
    <order_by>18</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. Repealed by 2011, 68, Sec. 53. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221.]  In a governmental unit which has accepted the provisions of section ten and which accepts the provisions of this section, all retirees, their spouses and dependents insured or eligible to be insured under this chapter, if enrolled in medicare part A at no cost to the retiree, spouse or dependents or eligible for coverage thereunder at no cost to the retiree, spouse or dependents, shall be required to transfer to a medicare extension plan offered by the governmental unit under section eleven C or section sixteen; provided, that benefits under said plan and medicare part A and part B together shall be of comparable actuarial value to those under the retiree's existing coverage; provided, further, that retirees or spouse, who has a dependent who is not enrolled or eligible to be enrolled in Medicare part A at no cost shall not be required to transfer to a Medicare extension plan if a transfer requires the retiree or spouse to continue the existing family coverage for the dependent in a plan other than a Medicare extension plan offered by the governmental unit. Each retiree shall provide the governmental unit, in such form as the governmental unit shall prescribe, such information as is necessary to transfer to a medicare extension plan. If a retiree does not submit the information required, he shall no longer be eligible for his existing health coverage. The governmental unit may from time to time request from any retiree, a retiree's spouse and dependents, proof certified by the federal government of their eligibility or ineligibility for medicare part A and part B coverage. The governmental unit shall pay any medicare part B premium penalty assessed by the federal government on said retirees, spouses and dependents as a result of enrollment in medicare part B at the time of transfer into the medicare health benefits supplement plan.  This section shall take effect in a county, except Worcester county, city, town or district upon its acceptance in the following manner:-- In a county by vote of the county commissioners; in a city having a Plan D or Plan E charter by a majority vote of its city council; in any other city by vote of its city council, approved by the mayor; in a district, except as hereinafter provided, by vote of the registered voters of the district at a district meeting; in a regional school district by vote of the regional district school committee; and in a town either by vote of the town at a town meeting or, by a majority of affirmative votes cast in answer to the following question which shall be printed upon the official ballot to be used at an election of said town:-- "Shall the town require that all retirees, their spouses and dependents who are enrolled in Medicare Part A at no cost to a retiree, their spouse or dependents, or eligible for coverage thereunder at no cost to a retiree, their spouse or dependents, be required to enroll in a medicare health benefits supplement plan offered by the town?''.
    </text>
</law>