<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35OO</section_number>
    <catch_line>Off Highway Vehicle Program Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35OO</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth an Off-Highway Vehicle Program Fund. Notwithstanding the provisions relative to the distribution of fines, penalties and forfeitures in section 10G of chapter 21A to the contrary, there shall be credited to the fund all of the fees collected pursuant to section 22 of chapter 90B, 75 per cent of all fines, costs, forfeitures, expenses and interest imposed pursuant to section 21 and sections 24 to 32, inclusive, of said chapter 90B and pursuant to the fourth paragraph of section 10H of chapter 21A, any revenue from appropriations or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited to the fund, any appropriation or grant explicitly made to the fund and any income derived from the investment of amounts credited to the fund. The remaining 25 per cent of the fines, costs, forfeitures, expenses and interest imposed pursuant to said section 21 and said sections 24 to 32, inclusive of said chapter 90B and pursuant to the fourth paragraph of section 10H of chapter 21A shall be distributed equally among the division, departments or offices involved or to the division, department or office if a single law enforcement agency was involved.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The secretary of energy and environmental affairs, as trustee, shall administer the fund. All amounts credited to the fund may be expended, without further appropriation, for use by the office of environmental law enforcement, the department of conservation and recreation, the department of fish and game and the department of environmental protection for the following purposes: (i) the enforcement of statutes, regulations and policies applicable to off-highway vehicles; (ii) the acquisition of land for use as commonwealth-approved trails and facilities for off-highway vehicles or for the development, maintenance, repair or restoration of commonwealth-approved trails and facilities; (iii) grants made by the department of conservation and recreation to municipalities and other public entities for the purposes of clauses (i) and (ii); (iv) the development and administration of safety, training and education programs relative to off-highway vehicles; and (v) other off-highway program activities, including all direct and indirect costs of personnel or contractors of the office of environmental law enforcement, the department of conservation and recreation, the department of fish and game and the department of environmental protection; provided, however, that the secretary of energy and environmental affairs shall report annually, not later than January 15, to the house and senate committees on ways and means and the joint committees on environment, natural resources and agriculture, transportation and public safety and homeland security relative to the source and amount of funds deposited into the fund, the amount distributed to each department and the purpose and recipient of expenditures from the fund.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Monies deposited into the fund that are unexpended at the end of the fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund and shall be available for expenditure in the subsequent fiscal year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Not less than 25 per cent of the monies deposited in the fund shall be expended on a fiscal year basis for the activities identified in clause (ii) of subsection (b) or for grants made pursuant to clause (iii) of subsection (b) to fund the activities identified in clause (ii) of subsection (b). Monies that are deposited in the fund that are unexpended at the end of the fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund and shall be available for expenditure in the subsequent fiscal year.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>