<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Counties And County Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="34B" order_by="34B" level="3">Abolition Of County Government</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Registries Of Deeds Of Abolished Counties; Employees, Functions And Proceedings Transferred To Commonwealth</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law to the contrary, this section shall facilitate the orderly transfer of the employees, proceedings, rules and regulations, property and legal obligations of the registry of deeds functions of an abolished county’s government to the commonwealth, as hereby defined as of the transfer date, and for the Berkshire and Suffolk county registries of deeds on July 1, 1999:
        </section>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     The functions of the registries of deeds, hereinafter called the transferor agencies, shall be transferred to the office of the secretary of state, which is hereinafter referred to as the transferee agency.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     All employees of the transferor agencies, including those who immediately prior to the transfer date hold permanent appointment in positions classified under chapter 31 or have tenure in their positions by reason of section 9A of chapter 30 or do not hold such tenure, are hereby transferred to said transferee agency, without interruption of service within the meaning of said section 9A or said chapter 31, and without reduction in compensation or salary grade. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law to the contrary, all such employees of the transferor agency shall continue to retain their right to collectively bargain pursuant to chapter 150E, and shall be considered employees for the purposes of said chapter 150E. Employees shall be transferred without change in union representation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="C">
    	     All petitions, requests, investigations and other proceedings approximately and duly brought before said transferor agencies, or duly begun by said transferor agencies and pending before said transferor agencies prior to the transfer date, shall continue unabated and remain in force, but shall be assumed and completed by said transferee agency.
        </section>
        <section prefix="D">
    	     All orders, rules and regulations duly made and all approvals duly granted by said transferor agencies which are in force immediately prior to the transfer date, shall continue in force and the provisions thereof shall thereafter be enforced, until superseded, revised, rescinded or canceled in accordance with law by said transferee agency.
        </section>
        <section prefix="E">
    	     All books, papers, records, documents, and equipment which immediately prior to the transfer date are in the custody of said transferor agencies shall be transferred to said transferee agency.
        </section>
        <section prefix="F">
    	     All duly existing contracts, leases and obligations of said transferor agencies, shall continue in effect and shall be assumed by said transferee agency. No existing right or remedy of any character shall be lost, or affected by the provisions of this chapter.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>