<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Investigations And Enforcement Bureau</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) There shall be within the commission an investigations and enforcement bureau which shall be the primary enforcement agent for regulatory matters under this chapter. The bureau shall perform such functions as the chair may determine in relation to enforcement, including the investigation of all licensees under this chapter. The bureau shall be under the supervision and control of the deputy director of investigations and enforcement. The deputy director shall be the executive and administrative head of the bureau and shall be responsible for administering and enforcing the laws relative to the bureau and to each administrative unit of the bureau. The duties of the deputy director as provided in this chapter and in any other general or special law shall be exercised and discharged subject to the direction, control and supervision of the chair.  (b) The bureau shall be a law enforcement agency and its employees shall have such law enforcement powers as necessary to effectuate the purposes of this chapter, including the power to receive intelligence on an applicant or licensee under this chapter and to investigate any suspected violations of this chapter.  (c) Officers and employees of the gaming enforcement unit of the state police assigned to the commission under section 70 of chapter 22C shall work with employees of the bureau, under the direction of the deputy director, to investigate violations of this chapter by a licensee or to investigate any activity taking place on the premises of a gaming establishment. Officers assigned to work with the bureau shall record their time and submit total hours to the deputy director and the commission shall reimburse the state police.  (d) The bureau shall notify the division of gaming enforcement in the department of the attorney general of criminal violations by a gaming licensee. The bureau and the division shall cooperate on the regulatory and criminal enforcement of this chapter and may determine whether to proceed with civil or criminal sanctions, or both, against a gaming licensee.  (e) To further effectuate the purposes of this chapter with respect to the investigation and enforcement of gaming establishments and licensees, the bureau may obtain or provide pertinent information regarding applicants or licensees from or to law enforcement entities or gaming authorities and other domestic, federal or foreign jurisdictions, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and may transmit such information to each other electronically.  (f) The gaming enforcement unit within the department of state police shall have exclusive police jurisdiction over any criminal activity relating to the operation of a gaming establishment or relating to games or gaming that occur inside a gaming establishment; provided, however, that the state police shall have concurrent jurisdiction with the law enforcement agency of the host community on all other policing matters. The commission, in consultation with the colonel of the state police, shall facilitate the execution of a memorandum of understanding with the law enforcement agency of the host community that shall include, but not be limited to, procedures involving: (i) assignment of police officers of the host community to the gaming enforcement unit of the state police; (ii) first responder calls from the gaming establishment; (iii) emergencies occurring within the gaming establishment, including the gaming area; and (iv) criminal investigations involving employees or patrons of a gaming establishment.  (g) Investigators and employees of the gaming liquor enforcement unit of the alcoholic beverages control commission assigned to the commission under section 72A of chapter 10 shall work with employees of the bureau, under the direction of the deputy director, to enforce, regulate and control the distribution of alcoholic beverages in a gaming establishment. Investigators assigned to work with the bureau shall record their time and submit their total hours to the deputy director and the commission shall reimburse the alcoholic beverages control commission.
    </text>
</law>