<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Office Of Law Enforcement; Director; Deputies; Environmental Police Officers; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>10A</order_by>
    <text>
        The office of law enforcement shall be in the executive office of environmental affairs and shall be under the administrative supervision of a director who shall be called the director of law enforcement. The director shall be qualified by training, experience and executive ability and shall not be subject to chapter 31. The secretary shall appoint the director and may remove him. The director shall appoint and may remove with the approval of the secretary such deputy directors of enforcement and chiefs of enforcement as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the office; provided, however, that the chief of enforcement of the boating and recreation vehicle safety enforcement bureau shall be appointed and may be removed by the director with the approval of the boating and recreational vehicle safety advisory board established pursuant to section 11 of chapter 21A. Such positions shall not be subject to chapter 31. The deputy directors of enforcement, assisted by law enforcement coordinators, shall perform such enforcement and administrative duties as assigned by the director. 
The director may with the approval of the secretary designate employees of the commonwealth and the United States as deputy environmental police officers. 
The director may promulgate rules and regulations necessary for implementation of sections 10A to 10H, inclusive; provided, however, that no rule or regulation promulgated under this section shall take effect before the thirtieth day next following the date on which a copy of such rule or regulation has been filed with the joint committee on natural resources and agriculture.
    </text>
</law>