<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="121B" order_by="121B" level="3">Housing And Urban Renewal</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31</section_number>
    <catch_line>Submission Of Plans For Low Rent Housing Project To Department;  Application; Hearing; Disposition</catch_line>
    <order_by>31</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Projects involving the purchase or acquisition of the right to use completed dwelling units which have been recently constructed, reconstructed or remodeled, whether condominium units, individual buildings part of a larger development, or a portion of the units in a multi-family development, shall be approved by the department only after it makes the following determinations: (i) the number of units involved, other than units specifically to be used for elderly persons of low income, does not exceed one hundred in any one building or development; and (ii) the housing authority has made adequate arrangements for the maintenance and operation of the units, either through use of its own personnel or by contract with a private real estate management organization acceptable to the local housing authority with the approval of the department.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Projects involving the construction of new buildings by a housing authority shall be approved by the department following due notice and a public hearing in the town or city involved held to consider testimony relating to the determinations required to be made. The department shall approve such a project only if it makes the following determinations: (i) the proposed project does not include in excess of one hundred dwelling units in any one site; (ii) the total combined number of units of the proposed project and any low rent housing project which is in existence or has been approved or is before the department for approval and is located adjacent to or within one-eighth of a mile of the site of the proposed project shall not exceed one hundred, other than those to be used specifically for elderly persons of low income. This provision shall not apply to sites for projects approved or being approved under the preceding paragraph (a); (iii) the design and layout of the proposed project is appropriate to the neighborhood in which it is to be located; and (iv) an adequate supply of dwelling units for families of low income is not then available in the private market, and the housing authority, after reasonable effort, has been unable to obtain such units either through reconstruction, remodeling, or repair of existing buildings or by the purchase of completed dwelling units. The provisions of this clause shall not apply to any project which shall be certified by the department to be a project designed specifically for elderly persons of low income. A project shall be deemed to be designed specifically for elderly persons of low income if a majority of the dwelling units in said project are designed specifically for elderly persons of low income and if not more than one hundred dwelling units in said project are designed for families of low income.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>