<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>57</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Gaming Control Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>57</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Massachusetts Gaming Control Fund. The commission shall be the trustee of the fund and shall expend monies to finance operational activities of the commission. The fund shall be credited any appropriations, bond proceeds or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited thereto, the proceeds of the assessments levied under section 56, initial application fees for licenses issued under this chapter and such additional funds as are subject to the direction and control of the commission. All available monies in the fund that are unexpended at the end of each fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund and shall be available for expenditure in the subsequent fiscal year. Any funds unexpended in any fiscal year for the purposes of which such assessments were made shall be credited against the assessment to be made in the following fiscal year and the assessment in the following fiscal year shall be reduced by any such unexpended amount. The commission shall record all expenditures made by subsidiary on the Massachusetts management and accounting reporting system according to regulations established by the state comptroller.  (b) The commission shall, for the purposes of compliance with state finance law, operate as a state agency as defined in section 1 of chapter 29 and shall be subject to the provisions applicable to agencies under the control of the governor including, but not limited to, chapters 7, 7A, 10 and 29; provided, however, that the comptroller may identify any additional instructions or actions necessary for the commission to manage fiscal operations in the state accounting system and meet statewide and other governmental accounting and audit standards. Unless otherwise exempted by law or the applicable central service agency, the commission shall participate in any other available commonwealth central services including, but not limited, to the state payroll system under section 31 of said chapter 29 and may purchase other goods and services provided by state agencies in accordance with comptroller provisions. The comptroller may chargeback the commission for the transition and ongoing costs for participation in the state accounting and payroll systems and may retain and expend such costs without further appropriation for the purposes of this section. The commission shall be subject to section 5D of chapter 29 and subsection (f) of section 6B of chapter 29.  The commission shall annually submit a finance plan to the secretary of administration and finance, the chairs of the house and senate committees on ways and means and the chairs of the joint committee on economic development and emerging technologies.
    </text>
</law>