<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20</section_number>
    <catch_line>Joint Powers Agreements; Definitions; Approval; Administration</catch_line>
    <order_by>20</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     In order to facilitate intergovernmental action on natural resource and environmental issues and thereby to advance the objectives set forth in Article XCVII of the Articles of Amendment to the Constitution of the Commonwealth, any two or more public agencies, for any region they may elect, may apply to the secretary of environmental affairs to enter into an agreement for the joint exercise of certain of their powers and duties. The proposed joint powers agreement shall specify:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the purpose and nature of the arrangement;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the work to be performed, and the division or sharing of responsibility among public agencies;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the estimated costs and the methods of financing;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the method of administration; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the duration of the proposed agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A joint powers agreement established pursuant to the provisions of this section may be administered by a board comprised of at least one member representing each participating public agency. In order to enable a combination of public agencies to act together, the board shall coordinate the activities of such participating agencies, but only to the extent of the powers otherwise granted by law to one or more of the participating public agencies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Nothing in this section shall be construed to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     amend, repeal or otherwise alter the authority or jurisdiction of, or establish, any public agency;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     confer any management authority over funds, land, or natural resources beyond the authority exercised by the participating agencies;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     authorize appropriated funds to be expended for the purposes of this section, or to be transferred or have the effect of being transferred from one appropriation account to another, except as otherwise authorized by law;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     amend, repeal or otherwise alter the authority of the department of environmental protection to undertake or order actions pursuant to chapter twenty-one E, nor otherwise to require said department to participate in a joint powers agreement if the commissioner thereof determines that such participation would conflict with the purposes of said chapter twenty-one E; nor
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     create liability on the part of any public agency for the act or omission of another public agency.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>