<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90B" order_by="90B" level="3">Motorboats, Other Vessels And Recreational Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24</section_number>
    <catch_line>Lights;  Reflectors;  Excessive Noise;  Noxious Fumes</catch_line>
    <order_by>24</order_by>
    <text>
          Each snow vehicle and each recreation vehicle shall be equipped with one or more headlights, a red rear light, a red rear reflector, and adequate muffler, and such safety equipment as may be required by the director. Each such vehicle shall be capable of decelerating in a reasonable manner. Any sled or trailer attached to any such vehicle shall also be equipped with a red rear reflector. All such equipment shall conform to such specifications as the registrar of motor vehicles shall prescribe; provided, however, that the requirements for lighting, as set forth in this paragraph, shall not apply to category Y - all terrain vehicles, so-called; and provided, further, that said registrar in such specifications shall define said category Y - all terrain vehicles in a manner which shall be consistent with the American National Standards Institute Standard ANSI/SVIA I - 1990.[ Second paragraph effective until January 2, 2013. For text effective January 2, 2013, see below.]  No snow vehicle or recreation vehicle shall be operated which emits noxious fumes or makes unusual or excessive noise. No snow vehicle or recreation vehicle manufactured on or after January 1, 1998, shall be sold, offered for sale or operated that produces a sound pressure level of more than 96 decibels when measured from a distance of 20 inches using test procedures established by the Society of Automotive Engineers under Standard J1287 JUL98 or with such other test procedures for measurement of sound pressure levels as the registrar may adopt. No snow vehicle or recreation vehicle manufactured prior to January 1, 1998, shall be offered for sale or operated that produces a sound pressure level of more than 101 decibels when measured from a distance of 20 inches using test procedures established by the Society of Automotive Engineers under Standard J1287 JUL98 or with such other test procedures for measurement of sound pressure levels as the registrar may adopt.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2012, 296, Sec. 3 effective January 2, 2013. For text effective until January 2, 2013, see above.]  No snow vehicle or recreation vehicle shall be operated which emits noxious fumes or makes unusual or excessive noise. No snow vehicle or recreation vehicle manufactured on or after January 1, 1998, shall be operated that produces a sound pressure level of more than 96 decibels when measured from a distance of 20 inches using test procedures established by the Society of Automotive Engineers under Standard J1287 JUL98. No snow vehicle or recreation vehicle manufactured before January 1, 1998, shall be operated that produces a sound pressure level of more than 101 decibels when measured from a distance of 20 inches using test procedures established by the Society of Automotive Engineers under said Standard J1287 JUL98. This paragraph shall not apply to a snow vehicle or recreation vehicle being operated on a privately-owned track or closed course as permitted by local municipal authority; provided, however, that a snow vehicle or recreation vehicle manufactured before January 28, 1985, and substantially maintained in its original or restored condition shall meet the sound and emission specifications in place at the time of its manufacture.
    </text>
</law>