<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>116F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Harbormaster Training Council</catch_line>
    <order_by>116F</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a harbormaster training council within the executive office of public safety. The council shall consist of 11 members, 1 of whom shall be a member of the state police marine unit with knowledge of marine law enforcement and operations who shall be appointed by the colonel of state police; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the environmental police with knowledge of marine law enforcement and operations who shall be appointed by the secretary of energy and environmental affairs; 1 of whom shall be an employee of the executive office of public safety who shall be appointed by the secretary of public safety to serve ex officio; 1 of whom shall be an employee of United States First Coast Guard District to be appointed by the district commander who shall serve ex officio; and 7 of whom shall be harbormasters appointed by the governor, 2 of whom shall be from the coastal communities north of Boston, 2 of whom shall be from coastal communities south of Boston, 2 of whom shall be from coastal communities from Cape Cod and the Islands and 1 of whom shall be from the city of Boston. Members appointed by the governor shall serve for 2-year terms and their successors shall be appointed in like manner. Members of the council shall serve without compensation. 
The council shall set policies and standards for training harbormasters and assistant harbormasters in accordance with applicable laws and regulations including sections 19 to 21, inclusive, of chapter 102. 
The expenses of the council shall be funded solely from the Harbormaster Training Trust Fund established in section 35KK of chapter 10.
    </text>
</law>