<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>42B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Primary Candidate Accounts</catch_line>
    <order_by>42B</order_by>
    <text>
        On or before the eighth, sixth, fourth and second Tuesday before the primary election in any year in which elections for statewide elective office are held the state treasurer shall without further appropriation distribute from each primary candidate account the amounts then certified by the director of campaign and political finance to be due to each eligible candidate. All distributions shall be made by direct deposit to the depository account designated by such candidates under section 19 of chapter 55. Immediately following the second Tuesday before the primary election all primary candidate accounts established under section 43 shall be closed and any balances remaining shall be allocated to the general election account and shall be available for distribution as herein provided. 
On or before the fourth and second Tuesday before the state election in any year in which elections are held for statewide elective office, the state treasurer shall without further appropriation distribute from each state election candidate account the amounts then certified by the director of campaign and political finance to be due to each eligible candidate. All distributions shall be made by direct deposit to the depository accounts designated by such candidates under section 19 of chapter 55. Immediately following the second Tuesday before the state election all state election candidate accounts established under section 43 shall be closed and any balances remaining shall be redeposited as provided in section 41 pending the next year in which statewide elections are held.
    </text>
</law>