<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Boards Subsequently Mentioned To Serve In Division; Offices; Compensation</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Subsection (a) effective until January 1, 2012. For text effective January 1, 2012, see below.]  (a) The following boards of registration shall serve in the department of public health: the board of registration in medicine; the board of registration in nursing; the board of registration in pharmacy; the board of registration of physician assistants; the board of registration of perfusionists; the board of registration of nursing home administrators, the board of registration in dentistry, the board of registration of genetic counselors and the board of registration of respiratory therapists.[ Subsection (a) as amended by 2010, 322, Sec. 1 effective January 1, 2012. See 2010, 322, Sec. 4. For text effective until January 1, 2012, see above.]  (a) The following boards of registration shall serve in the department of public health: the board of registration in medicine; the board of registration in nursing; the board of registration in pharmacy; the board of registration of physician assistants; the board of registration of perfusionists; the board of registration of nursing home administrators, the board of registration in dentistry, the board of registration of genetic counselors, the board of certification of community health workers and the board of registration of respiratory therapists.[ Subsection (b) effective until May 20, 2012. For text effective May 20, 2012, see below.]  (b) All other boards of registration and examination mentioned in this chapter, as well as the state racing commission established by section 48 of chapter 6, shall serve in the division of professional licensure.[ Subsection (b) as amended by 2011, 194, Sec. 11 effective May 20, 2012. See 2011, 194, Sec. 110. For text effective until May 20, 2012, see above.]  (b) All other boards of registration and examination mentioned in this chapter shall serve in the division of professional licensure.  (c) Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, all of the board members of the department of public health or the division of registration shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties.
    </text>
</law>