<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>85</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration Of Speech Language Pathology And Audiology;  Membership; Appointment; Election Of Officers; Expenses</catch_line>
    <order_by>85</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board of registration for speech-language pathology and audiology, in this section and in sections eighty-six and eighty-seven hereinafter called the board, consisting of five members appointed by the governor. Members of the board shall be citizens of the United States and residents of the commonwealth. One member of the board shall be a representative of the public, subject to the provisions of section nine B, two members shall be certified speech-language pathologists who have had at least three years experience practicing speech-language pathology in the commonwealth immediately preceding appointment, and two members shall be certified audiologists who have had at least three years experience practicing audiology in the commonwealth immediately preceding appointment. Appointments shall be for a period of three years except for the initial appointments of which one shall be for one year, two shall be for two years and two shall be for three years. No member shall be appointed for more than two consecutive terms. In the event of a vacancy in the office of a member of the board other than by expiration of a term, the governor shall appoint a person to fill the vacancy for the unexpired term. The governor shall make the appointments of the speech-language pathologists and audiologists from a list of not less than ten names submitted by the Massachusetts Speech and Hearing Association, Inc. 
The board shall elect annually by majority vote a chairperson and a secretary. Three members of the board shall constitute a quorum to do business, provided that at least one speech-language pathologist and one audiologist are present. The board shall meet quarterly or more frequently upon the call of the chairperson of the board. 
Members shall receive no compensation for their services but shall be entitled to reasonable travel and other expenses provided that the expenses of the members of the board, the cost of personnel providing services to the board and all other expenses associated with the operation of the board are generated by licensure fees.
    </text>
</law>