<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32A" order_by="32A" level="3">Contributory Group General Or Blanket Insurance For Persons In The Service Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Insurance And Medicare Benefits Of State Employees</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        Each employee shall be automatically insured for five thousand dollars of group life insurance and five thousand dollars of group accidental death and dismemberment insurance and group general or blanket insurance providing hospital, surgical, medical, dental and other health insurance benefits provided under said policy or policies, commencing on the date he first becomes eligible or on the effective date of such coverage or coverages, including dependent benefits, whichever last occurs; provided, that any employee desiring not to be so insured shall, on an appropriate form prescribed by the commission, give written notice to the commission that he is not to be insured for such coverages, including dependent benefits, provided under such policy or policies. Such notice shall be mailed to the office of the commission at least thirty days prior to the effective date the employee becomes eligible or insured. If an employee fails to give such notice or, if an employee desires to terminate said insurance, he may withdraw, and such insurance benefits shall cease to be effective on the date to which the premium has been paid. In determining said date, payroll deductions or direct payments on behalf of the employee shall continue to be made until the expiration of fifteen days from the receipt of notice of withdrawal by the commission. 
When an employee insured under this section becomes eligible for health insurance coverage, as provided in section ten C, he may terminate by notice, as aforesaid, his hospital, surgical, medical, dental and other health benefits provided herein and retain his five thousand dollars of group life insurance and five thousand dollars of group accidental death and dismemberment insurance. 
Every policy whether original or renewal shall, in the case of employees who immediately prior to the effective date of such original or new policy were covered by group insurance benefits under this chapter, provide protection by continuing uninterrupted coverage without regard to waiting periods for benefits.
    </text>
</law>