<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138" level="3">Alcoholic Liquors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Pub Brewery Licenses; Hearings; Records; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>19D</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The commission shall issue a pub brewery license to an applicant who is a citizen or permanent legal resident of the commonwealth and to applying partnerships and to applying corporations organized under the laws of the commonwealth or organized under the laws of any other state and admitted to do business in the commonwealth and to applying limited liability companies or limited liability partnerships organized under the laws of the commonwealth unless:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     such person does not comply with application procedures required by the commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the commission determines that such applicant is not of responsible character;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     a church or school located within 500 feet of the brewery premises has objected to the issuance of such license in accordance with the provisions of section 16C and the commission finds that the pub brewery premises are detrimental to the spiritual activities of such church;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the commission determines that the applicant retains or owns an interest, directly or indirectly, in the business of a licensee under section 15 or a business which would be licensed under said section 15 if it were located within the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the commission determines that the applicant retains or owns an interest, directly or indirectly, in a business license under section 18 or a business which would be licensed under said section 18 if it were located within the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     the commission determines that the applicant retains or owns an interest, directly or indirectly, in any activity or in any business directly or indirectly engaged in the business of manufacturing any alcoholic beverages either within or outside of the commonwealth, except any interest, directly or indirectly, in a pub brewery license under this section or any business which would be licensed as a pub brewery under this section if it were located within the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     the commission determines that the applicant retains or owns an interest, directly or indirectly, in the business of a holder of a certificate issued under section 18B;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     the applicant has not furnished the requisite license fee or bond; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     the commission determines that the co-partners, corporate officials or stockholders of the applicant do not meet the requirements of clauses (2), (4), (5), (6), (7) and (8), or that the manager or agent intended to conduct the pub brewery business on the applicant’s behalf does not meet such requirements, or that such co-partners, officials, stockholders, agents or managers remain undisclosed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commission may, on its own motion, and shall, upon the written request of an applicant who has been refused a pub brewery license or has been refused transfer or renewal of such a license, hold an adjudicatory hearing, notice of which shall be mailed to the applicant at the address provided in his application. Such hearing shall be conducted before the commission or a member thereof. The commission shall present its reasons for refusing to issue, transfer or renew such license. The applicant may appear in person or by counsel, cross-examine witnesses for the commission and present evidence. Such hearing shall be stenographically or sound recorded. The commission shall decide within 30 days of the completion of the hearing whether to issue the pub brewery license or grant the transfer or renewal. If the commission refuses to grant the license, transfer or renewal following the hearing, notice thereof in writing shall be mailed to the applicant. In all such cases, the commission shall keep on file a statement in the form of an opinion of its reasons for such refusal and shall furnish a copy thereof to the applicant.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     An applicant who has appeared before the commission at any such hearing and who has been refused a pub brewery license or the transfer or renewal thereof may appeal such refusal to the superior court of the county wherein the applicant resides or has his principal place of business within the commonwealth or to the superior court for Suffolk county.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Every applicant for an original pub brewery license or for a transfer thereof shall, within seven days after filing an application with the commission, send written notice of his application by registered mail, return receipt requested, to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     each school which offers instruction and training to children of compulsory school age in accordance with sections 1 and 4 of chapter 71 and which is located within a radius of 500 feet from the premises on which the pub brewery is to be operated; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     each church, as defined in section 16C, which is located within a radius of 500 feet of such premises.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     such school or church had actual notice of the application and of the right to object under said section 16C prior to the issuance or transfer; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     such school or church did not complain as soon as possible after actual notification of the application and of the right to object. Any pub brewer aggrieved by the cancellation of his license by said commission or any school or church aggrieved by the refusal of the commission to cancel such license may appeal such decision as provided herein.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A pub brewer may operate a pub brewery under such conditions as the commission may prescribe by regulation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A pub brewer may import into the commonwealth malt, cereal grains, fermentable sugars and hops but may not so import malt beverages or alcohol.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     A pub brewer may sell malt beverages or malt beverage products produced by the pub brewery or produced for the pub brewery and sold under the pub brewery name:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     at wholesale to any person holding a valid wholesalers’ and importers’ license under section 18;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     at wholesale to churches and religious societies, educational institutions, incorporated hospitals, homes for the aged, manufactures of food products and manufacturers of drugs and chemicals as authorized by and subject to the provisions of section 28;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     at wholesale to any person in any state or territory in which the importation and sale of malt beverages is not prohibited by law; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     at wholesale to any person in a foreign country.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     A pub brewer may be licensed as a keeper of a pub brewery by the local licensing authorities subject to the prior approval of the commission to sell all alcoholic beverages or only wines and malt beverages, as the case may be, for consumption on the pub brewery premises in accordance with the pertinent provisions of section 12 and such rules and regulations as the commission may prescribe. A pub brewer licensed under section 12 may not sell at retail to consumers for off premises consumption malt beverages or malt beverage products not produced by the pub brewery on the pub brewery premises or produced for the pub brewery and sold under the pub brewery brand name. All retail sales shall be made on the pub brewery premises. A pub brewer may sell at retail by the bottle, not to exceed two gallons, to consumers for consumption off the pub brewery premises, malt beverages or malt beverage products produced by the pub brewery and sold under the pub brewery brand name in accordance with such rules and regulations as the commission may prescribe.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     All malt beverages produced by the pub brewery or produced for the pub brewery and sold under the pub brewery brand name and sold by a licensee hereunder shall be sold and delivered in such manner and under such conditions and with such labels or other marks to identify the producer as the commission may prescribe.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     In no event shall less than 50 per cent of the malt beverages or malt beverage products sold under paragraphs (g) and (h) be produced on the pub brewery premises in any one calendar year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     Every pub brewer licensed under this section shall keep such records as the commission may prescribe and shall file with the commission whenever and as often as it may require duplicate copies of such records. The commission shall at all times, through its designated officers or agents, have access to all books, records or other documents of every licensed pub brewer relating to the licensee’s pub brewery business.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     The annual license fee for each pub brewer in respect of each pub brewery shall be computed based on the malt beverage barrelage produced by the pub brewery as follows:
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     Every applicant for a pub brewery license shall, at the time of filing of an application, pay the minimum license fee. Persons holding pub brewery licenses shall report to the commission annually at the end of each year covered by the license the amount of malt beverages produced during such year together with copies of all excise filings due and payments made pursuant to the provisions of section 21. If the fee paid is less than the fee due for the total amount of such malt beverages produced, the licensee shall pay forthwith the amount of the excess fee under this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>