<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Procurement Of Goods Or Services From Bidders Or Offerors On Restricted Purchase List</catch_line>
    <order_by>22H</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Except as otherwise provided in this section, a state agency, a state authority, the house of representatives or the state senate may not procure goods or services from any person listed on the restricted purchase list maintained by the secretary, or who is determined through affidavit or through other reliable methods to meet the criteria for so being listed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A state agency, a state authority, the house of representatives or the state senate may procure goods or services from a person who is on or who is so determined to meet the criteria of the restricted purchase list only after certifying in writing to the secretary or, in the case of a state authority, to the chief operating officer that:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the procurement is essential; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     compliance with paragraph (a) would eliminate the only bid or offer, or would result in inadequate competition.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In any solicitation, a state agency, a state authority, the house of representatives or the senate shall provide ample notice of the requirements of this section. Prior to reviewing responses to bid documents for any procurements, or, if there are none, prior to entering into any contractual arrangement, the awarding authority shall obtain from such person seeking a contract a statement, under the pains and penalties of perjury, from an authorized representative of such person seeking a contract, on a form to be provided by the awarding authority, declaring the nature and extent to which said person is engaging in activities which would subject said person to inclusion on the restricted purchase list.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     In any procurement that includes bidders or offerors who are on or meet the criteria of the restricted purchase list, the awarding authority may award the contract to a person who is on or who meets the criteria of the restricted purchase list only if there is no comparable low bid or offer by a person who is not on the restricted purchase list.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A person with operations in Burma (Myanmar) for the sole purpose of reporting the news, or solely for the purpose of providing goods or services for the provision of international telecommunications shall not be subject to the provisions of sections twenty-two G to twenty-two M, inclusive.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>