<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7C" order_by="7C" level="3">Capital Asset Management And Maintenance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>30</section_number>
    <catch_line>Evaluation Of Energy Consumption Of Buildings And Their Major Energy Using Systems</catch_line>
    <order_by>30</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 165, Sec. 82 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  The director of facilities management shall make provision, as part of development of an inventory of buildings owned or otherwise occupied by state agencies or building authorities pursuant to section 24, for evaluation of the energy consumption of each building and its major energy using systems. The director may, with the approval of the commissioner and subject to appropriation or allocation, hire consultants for the purpose of performing energy audits designed to determine the need for energy conservation projects.  The director shall recommend to the commissioner standards and guidelines governing energy conservation maintenance and operating procedures.  The director shall in conjunction with the commissioner of energy resources set priorities and energy efficiency standards for all state buildings and conduct energy audits of said buildings. The bureau may contract with professional consulting firms to perform the energy audits.  All energy conservation projects within the jurisdiction of the division) of capital asset management and maintenance as defined by section 4, including projects funded out of any lump-sum energy conservation fund or account, shall be fully subject to this chapter except that alternative energy property program projects authorized pursuant to section 11 of chapter 25A shall not be subject to sections 11 and 12, sections 13 to 28, inclusive, or this section.
    </text>
</law>