<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21D" order_by="21D" level="3">Massachusetts Hazardous Waste Facility Siting Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Technical Assistance Grants</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        The local assessment committee of a host community and the chief executive officers of abutting communities may request technical assistance grants from the council. If a local assessment committee of a host community or the chief executive officer of an abutting community requests a technical assistance grant on or before the date that the secretary has defined the scope of the environmental impact report part of the preliminary project impact report, the council shall act on said request within thirty days after the secretary has so defined the scope and shall award, subject to funds appropriated therefor, such amounts as in its discretion shall be appropriate, upon consultation with the department of housing and community development. All technical assistance grants awarded to the chief executive officers of abutting communities and to the local assessment committee of a host community which has requested such a grant after the secretary has defined the scope of the environmental impact report part of the preliminary project impact report shall be awarded in such amounts and form, subject to funds appropriated therefor, as the council in its discretion shall deem to be appropriate. 
The local assessment committee of a host community and the chief executive officers of abutting communities may expend these funds, and such other funds as a city or town may appropriate therefor, to pay the costs incurred by said communities for participation in the hazardous waste facility site process established by this chapter.
    </text>
</law>