<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6A" order_by="6A" level="3">Executive Offices</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Support To Individuals With Disabilities And Their Families</catch_line>
    <order_by>16F</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     “Community services”, services that are available to the general population.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     coordination and facilitation of support services;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     counseling and information;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     facilitation of self-help groups;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     home adaptations;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     assistive technology devices and services and support services to facilitate full communication and language access;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     financial assistance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     assistance in caregiving including: respite, day care, after school care and personal care or personal care surrogacy, when necessary;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     adaptive equipment and clothing;
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     medical services;
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     transportation, including vehicle modification;
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     recreation and leisure activities;
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     life planning;
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     special dietary supplements and medical equipment and maintenance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="14">
    	     mental health treatment; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="15">
    	     advocacy training.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Each department, after substantial consultation with individuals with disabilities and their families, the departments’ statewide or regional advisory councils subject to appropriation, shall annually prepare an individual and family support plan that shall explain how the department intends to provide flexible supports to families and individuals. The plans shall be submitted to the governor, the secretary of health and human services, the joint committee on human services and elderly affairs and the house and senate committees on ways and means. Each department shall set forth its own plan, subject to appropriation, for coordinating, enhancing and expanding individual and family supports during the fiscal year. Each department shall seek creative and innovative ways, within its existing authority and mandate for serving individuals with disabilities and chronic illnesses, to provide flexible supports. The plan shall include, but not be limited to, the following goals:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     to develop interagency collaboration and public and private partnerships in order to: increase access to services; coordinate resources and referrals; pool funds to better support those with multiple disabilities; and provide technical assistance, training and outreach to consumers, specialized providers and community service providers about the philosophy and goals of individual and family support plans and progress toward those goals;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     to create opportunities for individuals with disabilities and their families for oversight of, and input into, the direction and development of policies and programs involving support services funded by the departments’ local, regional and central offices and their vendor agencies;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     to specify long and short-term objectives and strategies for implementing accessible and flexible supports for individuals with disabilities or chronic illnesses and their families and to review progress toward long and short-term objectives specified in the previous plan. Long-term strategies should span multiple years and the range of years shall parallel the department’s usual short and long-term planning patterns;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     to identify family support resources that shall be used to achieve goals and objectives specified in the plan and to analyze the current flexibility of departmental funding mechanisms in order to identify any adjustments needed to more adequately provide family supports for those families prioritized for funding within the guidelines of each department mandate;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     to enable the full participation of individuals with disabilities or chronic illnesses and their families in community life in a way that maintains respect and sensitivity to choices made by all cultures;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     to expand the capacity of community services to include persons with disabilities or chronic illnesses by training and educating community service providers; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     to empower consumers and ensure their active leadership and advocacy through opportunities for education, leadership development and training.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>