<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32B" order_by="32B" level="3">Contributory Group General Or Blanket Insurance For Persons In The Service Of Counties, Cities, Towns And Districts, And Their Dependents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Purchase Of Insurance By Public Authority Following Acceptance Of Chapter</catch_line>
    <order_by>10A</order_by>
    <text>
        The appropriate public authority shall provide for the purchase of insurance, or include the cost thereof, for dental expenses under those sections of this chapter which provide for the purchase of hospital, surgical, medical, dental and other health insurance benefits but only upon the acceptance of this section in the following manner:—in a city having a Plan D or Plan E charter by majority vote of its city council; in any other city by vote of its city council, approved by the mayor; in a district, except as hereinafter provided, by vote of the registered voters of the district at a district meeting; in a regional school district by vote of the regional district school committee; in a veterans’ services district by vote of the district board; in a health district established under section twenty-seven A of chapter one hundred and eleven by vote of the joint committee; and in a town by vote of the board of selectmen or, by vote of the town at a town meeting or, by submission for acceptance to the registered voters in the form of the following question which shall be printed upon the official ballot to be used at an election:—“Shall certain provisions of chapter thirty-two B of the General Laws, authorizing any county, except Worcester county, city or town or district to provide dental benefits as part of group general or blanket insurance providing hospital, surgical, medical, and other health insurance benefits for certain persons in the service of such county, town or district and their dependents, be accepted by this town?” If a majority of the voters voting on the question shall vote in the affirmative, the chapter shall take effect in such town. 
Any town which is a member of the Cape Cod municipal health group which does not provide dental benefits under this chapter may provide that any general, group or blanket insurance policy it purchases makes dental benefits available to employees at said employees’ expense. 
Notwithstanding the provisions of any general law to the contrary, acceptance of this section shall not be revoked or rescinded. This section shall not apply to Worcester county nor its employees, and they shall be eligible for coverage under the provisions of chapter thirty-two A. This action shall be a transferral and not a revocation or rescission.
    </text>
</law>