<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="143" order_by="143" level="3">Inspection And Regulation Of, And Licenses For, Buildings, Elevators And Cinematographs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Inspector Of Buildings Or Building Commissioner; Local Inspectors;  Employment And Designation; Qualifications; City Or Town Without Local Inspectors</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        The chief administrative officer of each city or town shall employ and designate an inspector of buildings or building commissioner as well as such other local inspectors as are reasonably necessary to assist the inspector of buildings or building commissioner to administer and enforce the state building code as well as section thirteen A of chapter twenty-two and the rules and regulations made under the authority thereof. The building commissioner or inspector of buildings shall be the administrative chief in a city or town responsible for administering and enforcing the state building code as well as section thirteen A of chapter twenty-two and the rules and regulations made under the authority thereof. Any additional persons employed by a city or town to assist the building commissioner or inspector of buildings in the performance of his duties shall be called local inspectors. The local inspector shall also be responsible for enforcing the state building code as well as section thirteen A of chapter twenty-two and the rules and regulations made under the authority thereof. The inspector of buildings or building commissioner shall report directly and be solely responsible to the person or public body that appointed him. Two or more cities or towns may combine and share expenses in the appointment of any building commissioner or inspector of buildings and local inspectors. If the board of selectmen of two or more towns so vote, such towns may enter into an agreement with the county commissioners of the county wherein such towns are located relative to the appointment and compensation of a building commissioner or inspector of buildings and local inspectors. The county commissioners shall apportion the budget approved for the building commissioner or inspector of buildings and local inspectors in accordance with said agreement. Said apportionment shall forthwith be certified by said commissioners to the board of selectmen of each member town and the amounts so certified shall be appropriated and paid to the county treasurer in accordance with provisions of said agreement. 
Each inspector of buildings or building commissioner shall have had at least five years of experience in the supervision of building construction or design or in the alternative a four year undergraduate degree in a field related to building construction or design or any combination of education and experience which would confer equivalent knowledge and ability, as determined by the board. In addition, such person shall have had a general knowledge of the quality and strength of building materials; a general knowledge of the accepted requirements for building construction, fire prevention, light, ventilation, safe exits and the requirements of section thirteen A of chapter twenty-two and the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto pertaining to accessible design standards; and a general knowledge of other equipment and materials essential for safety, comfort, and convenience of the occupants of a building or structure. 
Each local inspector shall have had at least five years of experience in the supervision of building construction or design or in the alternative a two year associate degree in a field related to building construction or design or any combination of education and experience which would confer equivalent knowledge and ability, as determined by the board. In addition, such persons shall have a general knowledge of the quality and strength of building materials; a general knowledge of the accepted requirements for building construction, fire prevention, light, ventilation and safe exits; and a general knowledge of other equipment and materials essential for safety, comfort, and convenience of the occupants of a building or structure, and the energy requirements imposed by clause (p) of section 94. 
In the event that a city or town shall be without a local inspector, the board may, with the approval of the commissioner, direct an inspector to temporarily fulfill the duties of the local inspector for a period not to exceed thirty days. In such an event the inspector shall have all the powers of a local inspector. Each city or town shall reimburse the commonwealth for the actual cost of such services provided. 
The clerk of each city and town shall annually, not later than April first, transmit to the board in writing the name and official address of each inspector of buildings or building commissioner and each local inspector in such city or town. 
Every inspector of buildings, building commissioner or local inspector shall be certified by the board of building regulations and standards in accordance with regulations promulgated by said board.
    </text>
</law>