<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2FFF</section_number>
    <catch_line>Dam Safety Trust</catch_line>
    <order_by>2FFF</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth an expendable trust to be known as the Dam Safety Trust. There shall be credited to the trust all receipts and revenues generated through agreements executed between the department of environmental management and public or private entities for dam safety purposes, and all fines, costs, expenses, and interest imposed pursuant to sections 44 to 48A, inclusive, of chapter 253. The amounts credited to the trust shall be available for expenditure subject to appropriation, by the department of environmental management up to an amount of $250,000 each fiscal year for the costs associated with the operations of the office of dam safety within the department, but such expenditures shall be solely for the purposes stated in this section and no funds shall be transferred from the trust to any other fund. The comptroller may assess the trust for fringe and overhead costs pursuant to section 5D and 6B. If the amount credited to the trust exceeds $250,000, the excess amount shall be deposited into the General Fund. No expenditure made from the fund shall cause the fund to become deficient at any point during fiscal year.
Chapter 29: Dam Safety Trust
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth an expendable trust to be known as the Dam Safety Trust. There shall be credited to the trust all receipts and revenues generated through agreements executed between the department of conservation and recreation and public or private entities for dam safety purposes, and all fines, costs, expenses, and interest imposed under sections 44 to 48A, inclusive, of chapter 253. The amounts credited to the trust shall be available for expenditure subject to appropriation, by the department of conservation and recreation up to an amount of $250,000 each fiscal year for the costs associated with the operations of the office of dam safety within the department, but such expenditures shall be solely for the purposes stated in this section and no funds shall be transferred from the trust to any other fund. The comptroller may assess the trust for fringe and overhead costs under section 5D and section 6B. If the amount credited to the trust exceeds $250,000, the excess amount shall be deposited into the General Fund. No expenditure made from the fund shall cause the fund to become deficient at any point during the fiscal year.
    </text>
</law>