<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>151B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Emergency Treatment Of Dogs Or Cats Injured On Ways;  Payment To Veterinarians</catch_line>
    <order_by>151B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  Any veterinarian registered under the provisions of section fifty-five or fifty-six A of chapter one hundred and twelve who renders emergency care or treatment to, or disposes of, a dog or cat that is injured on any way, shall receive payment from the owner of such dog or cat, if known, or if not known, from the dog fund of the county in which the injury occurred, in an amount not to exceed twenty dollars for such care, treatment or disposal; provided, however, such emergency care, treatment or disposal shall be for the purpose of maintaining life, stabilizing the animal or alleviating suffering until the owner or keeper of such dog or cat is identified or for a period of twenty-four hours, whichever is sooner. Any veterinarian who renders such emergency care or treatment to, or disposes of, such dog or cat shall notify the dog officer in the city or town and, upon notification, such dog officer shall assume control of such dog or cat.
Chapter 140: Emergency treatment of dogs or cats injured on ways; payment to veterinarians
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 21 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  A veterinarian registered under section 55 or 56A of chapter 112 who renders emergency care or treatment to, or who euthanizes, a dog or cat that is injured on any way shall receive payment from the owner of such dog or cat, if known, or, if not known, from the city or town in which the injury occurred in an amount not to exceed $250 for such care, treatment or euthanization; provided, however, such emergency care, treatment or euthanization shall be rendered for the purpose of maintaining life, stabilizing the animal or alleviating suffering until the owner or keeper of the dog or cat is identified or for 24 hours, whichever is sooner. A veterinarian who renders such emergency care or treatment to a dog or cat or euthanizes a dog or cat shall notify the municipal animal control officer and the animal control officer shall assume control of the dog or cat or the remains of the dog or cat.
    </text>
</law>