<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>182A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Schooner Ernestina Commission</catch_line>
    <order_by>182A</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a commission to be known as the Schooner Ernestina commission, to consist of nine persons to be appointed by the governor, one of whom shall be the commissioner of environmental management or his designee, one of whom shall be the director of the office of travel and tourism or his designee, one of whom shall be the commissioner of the department of education or his designee, one of whom shall be a resident of New Bedford, one of whom shall be a member of the Ernestina/Morrissey Historical Association, the four remaining persons shall be any person whose expertise would be an asset to the commission and the Schooner Ernestina or have particular expertise in the Cape Verdean history as it relates to said schooner, or history of said ship as the Effie M. Morrissey. Of the initial appointment, three shall be for a term of one year, three shall be for a term of two years and three shall be for a term of three years. Thereafter, all appointments shall be for terms of three years. Said commission shall annually thereafter elect from among their members a chairman and a vice-chairman. The members of said commission shall serve without compensation. Said commission shall meet a minimum of four times annually and shall additionally meet as often as necessary to transact the business of the vessel. It is the responsibility of the commission to establish all policies relative to the operation of the vessel.
    </text>
</law>