<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="3">The General Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>38A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bills Reported Favorably By Joint Or Ways And Means Committees;  Fiscal Notes;  Cost Limitation</catch_line>
    <order_by>38A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Joint committees of the general court and the committees on ways and means of either branch thereof when reporting favorably on bills referred to them shall include therewith a fiscal note prepared in accordance with the provisions of section three A of chapter twenty-nine showing the estimated cost or fiscal effect of the proposed legislation, if such cost of said legislation exceeds one hundred thousand dollars. Such fiscal notes shall be printed in the daily calendars of each branch whenever said bills appear thereon.
Chapter 3: Bills reported favorably by joint or ways and means committees; fiscal notes; cost limitation
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 6 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Joint committees of the general court, the house and senate committees on ways and means and the house and senate committees on bonding, capital expenditures and state assets when reporting favorably on bills referred to them shall include with that report a fiscal note prepared under section 3A of chapter 29 showing the estimated cost or fiscal effect of the proposed legislation, if the cost of the legislation exceeds $100,000. Such fiscal notes shall be printed in the daily calendars of each branch whenever said bills appear on the calendar and shall be made available on the official website of the general court.
    </text>
</law>