<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87AA</section_number>
    <catch_line>Operation Of Registered Shops; Fee; Employment Of Unregistered Persons; Change Of Location; Shops In State Institutions; Supervisors</catch_line>
    <order_by>87AA</order_by>
    <text>
        The board may authorize one or more registered hairdressers, manicurists or aestheticians or any person employing one or more registered hairdressers, manicurists, or aestheticians, upon payment to the board of a beauty shop, manicure shop or aesthetic shop registration fee as provided in section eighty-seven CC, to operate a registered beauty shop, manicure shop or an aesthetic shop, and such person may thereafter operate such beauty shop, manicure shop or aesthetic shop upon payment annually of a beauty shop, manicure shop or aesthetic shop registration renewal fee as provided in said section eighty-seven CC; provided, that, in the case of a beauty shop or manicure shop conducted solely by a hairdresser or manicurist owning the same, the beauty shop or manicure shop registration fee and beauty shop or manicure shop renewal fee shall each be as provided in said section eighty-seven CC. 
The owner of such beauty shop, manicure shop or aesthetic shop shall not employ for hire or allow any hairdresser, operator, demonstrator, manicurist or aesthetician to work in such beauty shop, manicure shop or aesthetic shop unless registered in accordance with sections eighty-seven T to eighty-seven JJ, inclusive. 
Certificates of registration issued hereunder shall be valid only for the location named therein, and shall not be transferable. Upon change of location of a registered shop, a new certificate of registration shall be issued to such shop upon payment of the fee provided in section eighty-seven CC. 
The board may register beauty shops operated in state institutions for the sole purpose of crediting the operators employed therein with the practical experience so obtained and thereby enabling them to qualify for the hairdressers’ examination. 
Each registered beauty shop qualified under this section, or under any other previous provision of law, and which employs operators, shall employ one hairdresser to supervise no more than each three operators employed therein.
    </text>
</law>