<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>196</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>196</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this section and sections 197 to 200, inclusive, the following words shall have the following meanings, unless the context clearly requires otherwise: 
“Apprentice”, a person registered as an apprentice hearing instrument specialist, engaged in dispensing hearing aids under the supervision of a Massachusetts registered hearing instrument specialist or audiologist and studying to become a hearing instrument specialist. 
“Assistive listening device and system”, an amplification system specifically designed to improve the signal to noise ratio for the user that is used to reduce interference from the noise in the background and to enhance hearing level at a distance by picking up sound from as close to the source as possible and sending it directly to the ear of the user. 
“Audiologist”, a person licensed as an audiologist in the commonwealth. 
“Board”, the board of registration of hearing instrument specialists. 
“Dispensing hearing instruments”, (a) the selection and adaptation of suitable hearing aids, the making of ear molds or ear impressions, or both, and providing appropriate initial and follow-up counseling and training in hearing aid use through utilization of results of audiological or hearing tests and hearing aid evaluations, or both; and (b) all acts pertaining to the selling, renting, leasing, pricing, delivery, servicing, repairing and warranty of hearing aids. 
“Hearing aid”, a wearable aid or device, not including surgical implants, which is inserted directly into the ear or worn with an ear mold and air conduction receiver or bone oscillator attachment and any part, attachment or accessory but excluding batteries, cords and accessories thereto, designed for or offered for the purpose of aiding or compensating for hearing loss. 
“Hearing instrument specialist”, a person licensed as a hearing instrument specialist in the commonwealth. 
“Register”, “registered”, “registrant” and “registration” shall be used interchangeably with the words “license”, “licensed”, “licensee” and “licensure”. 
“Sale” or “sell”, to transfer title to a hearing aid or the right of possession of a hearing aid by sales contract, lease, bailment, loan or other means, excluding wholesale transactions of dealers and distributors and excluding transfer of a title to a used hearing aid for purposes of donation to a hearing aid bank for distribution.
    </text>
</law>