<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6A" order_by="6A" level="3">Executive Offices</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Executive Office Of Education</catch_line>
    <order_by>14A</order_by>
    <text>
          EXECUTIVE OFFICE OF EDUCATION  EXECUTIVE OFFICE OF EDUCATION  (a) There shall be an executive office of education, which shall include the departments of early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and higher education.  (b) The executive office of education shall be under the supervision and control of a secretary of education, in this section called the secretary. The secretary shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the governor, shall receive such salary as the governor determines, and shall devote full time to the duties of her office.[ Subsection (c) effective until June 19, 2012. For text effective June 19, 2012, see below.]  (c) The secretary shall have the following duties and powers: (1) analyze the present and future goals, needs, and requirements of public education in the commonwealth; (2) pursuant to chapters 15A, 15D, 69, and 75, review and approve mission statements and 5-year master plans encompassing each sector of the public education system, including early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and public higher education. These mission statements and master plans shall take into account the secretary's analysis of goals, needs, and requirements and shall be designed to achieve a well coordinated system of education from early childhood through the university level and beyond; (3) approve the appointments of the commissioners of early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and higher education; (4) make recommendations to the secretary of administration and finance and the governor concerning the funding of education in the commonwealth and assist in preparing budget proposals to be put before the legislature on behalf of the boards and departments of early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and higher education; (5) serve as the governor's advisor on educational issues and represent the interests of education in the governor's cabinet; and (6) serve as an ex officio voting member of the boards of early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and higher education and the board of trustees of the University of Massachusetts, and facilitate coordination and communication between and among those boards.[ Subsection (c) as amended by 2012, 118, Secs. 3 and 4 effective June 19, 2012. For text effective until June 19, 2012, see above.]  (c) The secretary shall have the following duties and powers: (1) analyze the present and future goals, needs, and requirements of public education in the commonwealth; (2) pursuant to chapters 15A, 15D, 69, and 75, review and approve mission statements and 5-year master plans encompassing each sector of the public education system, including early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and public higher education. These mission statements and master plans shall take into account the secretary's analysis of goals, needs, and requirements and shall be designed to achieve a well coordinated system of education from early childhood through the university level and beyond; (3) approve the appointments of the commissioners of early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and higher education; (4) make recommendations to the secretary of administration and finance and the governor concerning the funding of education in the commonwealth and assist in preparing budget proposals to be put before the legislature on behalf of the boards and departments of early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and higher education; (5) serve as the governor's advisor on educational issues and represent the interests of education in the governor's cabinet; (6) serve as an ex officio voting member of the boards of early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and higher education and the board of trustees of the University of Massachusetts, and facilitate coordination and communication between and among those boards; and (7) manage all information technology resources within the departments listed in subsection (a) including, but not limited to, all resources necessary to implement a longitudinal data system to coordinate the collection and analysis of educational data from prekindergarten programs through higher education and oversee the departments' compliance with all standards and policies of the information technology division.  (d) The secretary may, subject to appropriation, appoint such other employees as she deems necessary to carry out her duties and responsibilities, shall be provided with adequate offices, and may expend sums for other necessary expenses of the executive office.  (e) Nothing in this section shall be construed as conferring any powers upon the secretary with respect to the boards or departments of early education and care, elementary and secondary education, and higher education except as set forth in this section or as otherwise expressly provided by law.
    </text>
</law>