<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18C" order_by="18C" level="3">Office Of The Child Advocate</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Access To Facilities And Records;  Release Of Information</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. For text effective July 1, 2011, see below.]  The child advocate or his designee shall have access at any and all reasonable times to any facility, residence, program, or portion thereof, that is operated, licensed or funded by an executive agency, and to all relevant records, reports, materials and employees in order to better understand the needs of children in the custody of the commonwealth or who are receiving services from an executive agency. The child advocate shall be bound by any limitations on the use or release of information imposed by law upon the party furnishing such information, except as provided in subsection (e) of section 12.
Chapter 18C: Access to facilities and records; release of information
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 68, Sec. 28 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221. For text effective until July 1, 2011, see above.]  The child advocate or his designee shall have access at any and all reasonable times to any facility, residence, program, or portion thereof, that is operated, licensed or funded by an executive agency, and shall have unrestricted access to all electronic information systems records, reports, materials and employees in order to better understand the needs of children in the custody of the commonwealth or who are receiving services from an executive agency. The child advocate shall be bound by any limitations on the use or release of information imposed by law upon the party furnishing such information, except as provided in subsection (e) of section 12.
    </text>
</law>