<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148" level="3">Fire Prevention</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificate As Oil Burner Technician; Minimum Age; Application;  Fee; Examination; Duration Of Certificate; Electrical Work</catch_line>
    <order_by>10D</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person who has attained eighteen years of age may make application to the department for a certificate as an oil burner technician. Application for such certification shall not be made more often than once in thirty days. A fee shall accompany each application, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven for the filing thereof. The application shall be in such form and contain such information as the commissioner may require. Within one month after the date of receipt of his application the applicant shall be examined as to his experience and ability to alter, repair and install oil burning equipment, and, if found by an examiner to be qualified, he shall forthwith be issued a certificate. Said certificate shall be valid throughout the commonwealth until the date of birth of the licensee occurring more than twelve months but not more than twenty-four months after the effective date of such license and may be renewed within two years after its expiration without examination upon the payment of a renewal fee as determined pursuant to the aforementioned chapter seven provision. If any such license or the renewal thereof expires in an even year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the licensee’s date of birth occurring in an even year. If any such license or renewal thereof expires in an odd year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the licensee’s date of birth occurring in an odd year. A license issued to a person born on February twenty-ninth shall, for the purposes of this section, expire on March first. Licenses not renewed at the expiration date shall become void, and shall after one year be reinstated only by reexamination of the licensee. A notice of the date of expiration of a license shall, at least thirty days prior to such date, be sent to the licensee. 
A person holding a certificate as an oil burner technician may connect or disconnect for the purpose of repair or replacement, any device or control required by rules and regulations of the board to be a part of an oil burner installation, or being an integral part of the oil burning equipment, at the connection on such device, control or part to be repaired or replaced, notwithstanding any contrary provision of chapter one hundred and forty-one. Any person licensed as an electrician under said chapter one hundred and forty-one may do any electrical work in connection with the alteration, repair or installation of oil burning equipment without being certified as an oil burner technician.
    </text>
</law>