<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>201</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>201</order_by>
    <text>
        The following words and phrases as used in this section and in sections 202 to 210, inclusive, shall, unless context otherwise requires, have the following meanings: 
“Board”, the board of registration of dietitians and nutritionists established in section 11D of chapter 13. 
“Licensed dietitian/nutritionist” or “LDN”, a person licensed under sections 202 to 210 of this chapter. The terms “licensed dietitian” and “licensed nutritionist” may be used interchangeably. 
“Field of dietetics and nutrition”, the integration and application of scientific principles of food, nutrition, biochemistry, physiology, food management, behavioral and social sciences to achieve and maintain the health of people. The field includes assessing the nutritional needs of individuals and groups of individuals based upon appropriate biochemical, anthropometric, physical, demographic, clinical, and dietary data to determine nutrient needs including enteral and parenteral nutrition; developing, evaluating and monitoring nutrition care plans that establish priorities, goals and objectives for meeting nutrient needs for individuals and groups; and advising and assisting individuals or groups of individuals on appropriate nutritional intake as part of preventive or restorative health care. Dietetics and nutrition also includes integrating information from the nutrition assessment with information on food and other sources of nutrient and meal preparation consistent with cultural background and socioeconomic status. 
“Registered dietitian”, a person registered by the commission of dietetic registration of the American Dietetic Association who practices the field of dietetics and nutrition. 
“Nutritionist”, a person concerned with food science and human nutrition, who adapts and applies food and nutrient information to the solution of food problems, the control of disease and the promotion of health, performs nutritional research, instructs groups and individuals about nutritional research, instructs groups and individuals about nutritional requirements and assists individuals about nutritional requirements, and assists individuals in developing patterns to meet their nutritional needs.
    </text>
</law>