<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>49B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions Of Terms Used In Secs. 49 B To 49 R</catch_line>
    <order_by>49B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     “Judgment”, any judgment which has become final upon a claim for damages suffered by a claimant arising out of the ownership, operation, maintenance or use of any aircraft, including damages for care and loss of services, because of bodily injury to or death of any person or injury to or destruction of property, including the loss of use thereof, or upon an agreement of settlement for such damages.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     “Non-resident’s operating privilege”, the privilege conferred upon a non-resident by the commonwealth pertaining to the operation by him of an aircraft, or the use of an aircraft owned by him therein.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     “Operator”, any person who is exercising actual physical control of an aircraft.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     “Owner”, any of the following persons who may be legally responsible for the operation of an aircraft:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     A person who holds the legal title to an aircraft.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A lessee of an aircraft.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A conditional vendee, a trustee under a trust receipt and a mortgagor or other person holding an aircraft subject to a security interest.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     “Passenger”, any person in, on or boarding an aircraft for the purpose of riding therein, or alighting therefrom following a flight or attempted flight therein.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     “Registration”, a certificate of registration of aircraft engaged in air navigation or of operators thereof, issued by the commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     “Notice”, notice in writing served upon a person by either:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Actual delivery or offer of delivery to such person by any disinterested person; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Registered mail addressed to the person at the last address known to the commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     “State”, any state, the District of Columbia, any territory or possession of the United States and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     “Claimant”, any person having a claim for damages as the result of an accident within the commonwealth involving an aircraft.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>