<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23" level="3">Executive Office Of Labor And Workforce Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Executive Office Of Labor And Workforce Development Created;  Adoption Of Regulations;  Constituent Departments</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]   There shall be an executive office of labor and workforce development, which shall be under the supervision and control of a secretary of labor and workforce development, appointed by the governor. The secretary of labor and workforce development may, pursuant to chapter 30A, adopt regulations for the implementation or interpretation of any law enforced or administered by any department, office, agency, or other entity in the executive office of labor and workforce development. In the executive office shall be the department of labor and the department of workforce development.
Chapter 23: Executive office of labor and workforce development created; adoption of regulations; constituent departments
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 17 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]   There shall be an executive office of labor and workforce development, which shall be under the supervision and control of a secretary of labor and workforce development, appointed by the governor. The secretary of labor and workforce development may, pursuant to chapter 30A, adopt regulations for the implementation or interpretation of any law enforced or administered by any department, office, agency, or other entity in the executive office of labor and workforce development. In the executive office shall be the department of unemployment assistance, the department of career services, the department of industrial accidents, the department of labor standards, and the department of labor relations. Each department shall be headed by a director. The executive office shall be organized and shall function as a single state agency with the authority and control for administrative purposes including, but not limited to, for the purposes of the accounting and financial system of the commonwealth. The secretary shall, notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, identify and consolidate administrative activities and functions common to the separate offices, departments and divisions within the office and may designate such functions "core administrative functions' in order to improve administrative efficiency and preserve fiscal resources; provided, however, that common functions that shall be designated core administrative functions shall include, but shall not be limited to, human resources, financial management, information technology, legal, procurement and asset management.
    </text>
</law>