<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21E" order_by="21E" level="3">Massachusetts Oil And Hazardous Material Release Prevention And Response Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Implementation; Regulations; Response Actions</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The department shall take all action appropriate to secure to the commonwealth the benefits of FWPCA, CERCLA and other pertinent federal laws including the Oil Pollution Act.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     For the purpose of implementing this chapter, FWPCA, CERCLA, and other pertinent federal laws and regulations, the department is authorized and directed to prepare and from time to time update a Massachusetts Contingency Plan which, as nearly as the department deems appropriate and practicable, shall comport with and complement the National Contingency Plan prepared under the authority of 33 USC Sec. 1321(c) and 42 USC Sec. 9605. In preparing said plan the department shall consider and take into account regionally and locally developed contingency plans.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The department shall promulgate such regulations as it deems necessary for the implementation, administration and enforcement of this chapter, FWPCA, CERCLA and other pertinent laws. Such regulations may include provisions waiving or limiting the applicability of this chapter as to any matter which the department determines to be adequately regulated by another program or government agency. The department shall integrate its implementation and enforcement of this chapter with other programs established for the protection of the public health, safety, welfare and the environment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The department shall adopt and from time to time amend or repeal regulations establishing classes or categories of persons or response actions or sites or vessels, or any combination of the foregoing, so that such persons may carry out such response actions at such sites or vessels only after prior issuance of a permit issued by the department; and establishing classes or categories of persons or response actions or sites or vessels, or any combination of the foregoing, so that such persons may carry out such response actions at such sites or vessels without prior issuance of a permit issued by the department.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the existence, source, nature, and extent of a release or threat of release of oil or hazardous materials,
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the nature and extent of danger to public health, safety, welfare, and the environment,
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the magnitude and complexity of the actions necessary to assess, contain, or remove the oil or hazardous material in question,
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the extent to which there are legally enforceable standardized methods and criteria for the class or category of response action in question,
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the extent to which the department needs to be persuaded, or is persuaded, or both, that persons who would obtain permits, or who would be allowed to carry out a response action without a permit, have demonstrated that they are able and willing to carry out the response actions in question in compliance with the provisions of this chapter, all regulations adopted pursuant to this chapter, and all other applicable statutes and regulations, and
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     the extent to which department oversight is necessary to ensure compliance with this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The department shall adopt and from time to time amend or repeal regulations establishing classes or categories of response actions or sites or vessels, or any combination of the foregoing, so that persons who carry out such response actions at such sites or vessels shall be required to cause to be rendered a waste site cleanup activity opinion, as that term is defined in section nineteen of chapter twenty-one A. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, said regulations (1) shall set requirements for reasonable documentation to support such opinions, and (2) shall set requirements for the availability of such opinions to the department and to other persons, and (3) may authorize one or more of the opinions described in clauses (1) through (5) of the definition of waste site cleanup activity opinion, as that term is defined in section nineteen of chapter twenty-one A, to be rendered by persons who are not in possession of a valid license issued pursuant to sections nineteen through nineteen J of chapter twenty-one A, and (4) may establish classes or categories of response actions or sites or vessels, or any combination of the foregoing, for which a waste site cleanup activity opinion need not be rendered. The department may impose terms and conditions on the applicability of such regulations.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>