<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>77A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Wild Canid And Felid Hybrids</catch_line>
    <order_by>77A</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall possess, sell, trade, breed, import, export or release a wild canid hybrid or wild felid hybrid, except as otherwise provided by rules and regulations of the division. Any mammal which is the offspring of the reproduction between any species of wild canid or hybrid wild canid and a domestic dog or hybrid wild canid, or is represented by its owner to be a wolf hybrid, coyote hybrid, coy dog or any other kind of wild canid hybrid, or which is the offspring of the reproduction between any species of wild felid or hybrid wild felid and a domestic cat or hybrid wild felid or is represented by its owner to be a wild felid hybrid. All mammals shall be considered to be wild mammals and subject to the provisions of this chapter. 
The provisions of this act shall not apply to an owner or other person possessing any such animal as of January first, nineteen hundred and ninety-four who has received a permit from the director; provided, however, that such permit has been acquired on or before July thirty-first, nineteen hundred and ninety-four. Such owner or other person shall be subject to the rules and regulations promulgated by the division. Such rules and regulations may include, but shall not be limited to, provisions for the housing of such animals. 
The provisions of this section shall not apply to an owner or person possessing a domesticated show or pet cat registered with a nationally or internationally recognized breeding association or registry which certifies the pedigree and registration of such cat to be without any wild felid parentage for a minimum of three generations.
    </text>
</law>