<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24B3/4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Implementation Of Collaborative Drug Therapy Management;  Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>24B3/4</order_by>
    <text>
        The board of registration in medicine and the board of registration in pharmacy shall issue rules and regulations to implement collaborative drug therapy management pursuant to section 24B1/2 and sections 7 and 9 of chapter 94C. To aid in the implementation, the board of registration in medicine and the board of registration in pharmacy shall consult with at least 1 individual from each of the following groups: the department of public health; the Massachusetts Society of Health-System Pharmacists; the Massachusetts chapter of the American Society of Consultant Pharmacists; the Massachusetts Pharmacists Association; the Massachusetts Independent Pharmacists Association; the Massachusetts Chain Pharmacy Council; the Massachusetts College of Pharmacy and Health Sciences; the Bouvé College of Health Sciences at Northeastern University; the Massachusetts Medical Society; the Massachusetts Academy of Family Physicians; the Massachusetts Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics; the Massachusetts Psychiatric Society; the Massachusetts chapter of the American Academy of Emergency Physicians; the Massachusetts Chapter of the American Medical Directors Association; and the Massachusetts Hospital Association. The rules and regulations shall govern each collaborative practice agreement, shall be defined and limited by section 24B1/2, chapter 94C and other applicable statutes. The board of registration in medicine and the board of registration in pharmacy shall address the following issues: (1) further limitations and conditions on sites and settings where a collaborative practice may take place beyond those of section 24; (2) the qualifications of participating pharmacists and physicians; (3) the scope of conditions or diseases to be managed, the initial list of which shall not include more than 5 disease states considered appropriate for collaborative management, providing that the 5 diseases selected for collaborative management in the retail setting must be from among those referenced in clause (5) of subsection (c) of section 24B1/2; (4) practice protocols; (5) risk management activities; (6) documentation of any initiation, modification or discontinuation of a patient’s medication therapy in the patient’s permanent medical record; (7) outcome measurements; and (8) informed consent procedures. The board of registration in medicine and the board of registration in pharmacy shall reconsider these regulations on a periodic basis, as considered appropriate by the commissioner for the purposes of adding or removing disease states to be managed under collaborative drug therapy treatment, as well as for the purpose of updating the rules and regulations governing collaborative drug therapy management, as necessary.
    </text>
</law>