<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="31A" order_by="31A" level="3">Municipal Personnel Systems</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Provisions Of Personnel Ordinance</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A statement of accepted merit principles pursuant to section four;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The appointment of a personnel director, pursuant to section six;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The specifications of those officials and employees who shall be covered by the ordinance or by-law and those who shall be exempt from all or any part of its provisions. All positions covered by civil service at the time of the rescission exempting department heads shall also be covered by said ordinance or by-law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Provisions establishing the structure and governing the operation of the personnel system, including but not limited to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The recruitment of candidates for positions which assures open competition with emphasis on attracting candidates from groups that are underrepresented in the work force.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The selection of candidates for appointment to positions in a manner which emphasizes to the maximum extent possible, job related criteria.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The selection of candidates for temporary or provisional positions shall only be made on an emergency basis.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Establishing provisions which provide for promotions to higher level positions, including systematic methods, which provide for:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     improved opportunities for upward mobility through training, education and career development assignments, and
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     open competition among qualified applicants.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Provide for probationary appointments of new employees and probationary promotions of current employees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Establishing a classification plan for all positions, including the establishment of position classes, the description of duties and responsibilities of each position, and a statement of the minimum qualifications for each position.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Establishing training and development programs which increase proficiency for employees in their present positions and preparing them for higher level positions.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     Provides for the training and development, including programs for all employees, that would increase proficiency in their current positions and prepare them for higher level positions.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     Establishes a performance evaluation system to be implemented whenever the development and maintenance of such a system is deemed practical by the municipality; provided, however, that in the establishment of such a program, it shall be developed in conjunction with the representatives of labor.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     Outlines disciplinary actions and appeals, including procedures regulating the suspension, demotion, and separation of employees, with the right to appeal any such action through an impartial process.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     In the case of reduction-in-force, seniority as provided in section thirty-nine of chapter thirty-one, shall be the sole criteria in determining the order of layoffs.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     Establishes standards of conduct, including prohibitions against political interference in the personnel system and an assurance of the right of employees to pursue legitimate involvement in the political system.
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     Establishes a centralized personnel record keeping system in the office of the personnel director.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>