<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Investigation Into Suitability Of Applicant For Gaming License</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) Upon receipt of an application for a gaming license, the commission shall instruct the bureau to commence an investigation into the suitability of the applicant. In evaluating the suitability of the applicant, the commission shall consider the overall reputation of the applicant including, without limitation:  (1) the integrity, honesty, good character and reputation of the applicant;  (2) the financial stability, integrity and background of the applicant;  (3) the business practices and the business ability of the applicant to establish and maintain a successful gaming establishment;  (4) whether the applicant has a history of compliance with gaming licensing requirements in other jurisdictions;  (5) whether the applicant, at the time of application, is a defendant in litigation involving its business practices;  (6) the suitability of all parties in interest to the gaming license, including affiliates and close associates and the financial resources of the applicant; and  (7) whether the applicant is disqualified from receiving a license under section 16; provided, however, that in considering the rehabilitation of an applicant for a gaming license, the commission shall not automatically disqualify an applicant if the applicant affirmatively demonstrates, by clear and convincing evidence, that the applicant has financial responsibility, character, reputation, integrity and general fitness as such to warrant belief by the commission that the applicant will act honestly, fairly, soundly and efficiently as a gaming licensee.  (b) If the bureau determines during its investigation that an applicant has failed to: (i) establish the applicant's integrity or the integrity of any affiliate, close associate, financial source or any person required to be qualified by the commission; (ii) demonstrate responsible business practices in any jurisdiction; or (iii) overcome any other reason, as determined by the commission, as to why it would be injurious to the interests of the commonwealth in awarding the applicant a gaming license, the bureau shall cease any further review and recommend that the commission deny the application.  (c) If the bureau has determined that an applicant is suitable to receive a gaming license, the bureau shall recommend that the commission commence a review of the applicant's entire application.
    </text>
</law>