<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118G" order_by="118G" level="3">Health Care Finance And Policy</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>33</section_number>
    <catch_line>Performance Review And Report</catch_line>
    <order_by>33</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 224, Sec. 132.]  (a) The council shall conduct a performance review every 2 years, submit a report of the review to the legislature and the governor and make the report available to the public upon submission to the governor and the legislature. The first report shall be submitted before December 1, 2008.  (b) The performance review and report shall include an evaluation of the health, welfare and satisfaction with services provided of the consumers receiving long-term in-home personal care services from personal care attendants under sections 28 to 33, inclusive, including the degree to which all required services have been delivered, the degree to which consumers receiving services from personal care attendants have ultimately required additional or more intensive services, such as home health care, or have been placed in other residential settings or nursing homes, the promptness of response to consumer complaints and any other issue considered to be relevant.  (c) The performance review report will provide an explanation of the full cost of personal care services, including the administrative costs of the council, unemployment compensation, Social Security and Medicare payroll taxes paid and any oversight costs.  (d) The performance review report will make recommendations to the legislature and the governor for any amendments to sections 28 to 33, inclusive that will further ensure the well-being of consumers, and the most efficient means of delivering required services. In addition, the first performance review report will include findings and recommendations regarding the appropriateness of the council's assumption of responsibility for verification of hours worked by personal care attendants, payment of personal care attendants and other duties.
    </text>
</law>