<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23I" order_by="23I" level="3">The Massachusetts Life Sciences Center</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Small Business Matching Grant Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be established and placed within the center the Massachusetts Small Business Matching Grant Fund, hereinafter referred to in this section as the fund, to be held by the center separate and apart from its other funds. The fund shall be credited any appropriations, bond proceeds or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited thereto, such additional funds as are subject to the direction and control of the center, any pension funds, federal grants or loans, royalties or private investment capital which may properly be applied in furtherance of the objectives of the fund, any proceeds from the sale of qualified investments secured or held by the fund, any fees and charges imposed relative to the making of qualified investments as defined by the center, secured or held by the fund and any other monies which may be available to the center for the purposes of the fund from any other source or sources. Any revenues, deposits, receipts, or funds received through the receipt of royalties, interest, dividends, or the sale of equity instruments shall be deposited in the fund, and shall be available to the center for the purposes described in this section, without further appropriation. All available moneys in the fund that are unexpended at the end of each fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund and shall be available for expenditure in the subsequent fiscal year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The center shall invest and reinvest the fund and the income thereof only as follows: (1) making qualified grants pursuant to subsection (c); (2) investing any funds not required for immediate disbursement in the purchase of such securities as may be lawful investments for fiduciaries in the commonwealth; (3) paying binding obligations associated with such qualified investments which shall be secured by the fund as the same become payable; and (4) paying principal or interest on qualified investments secured by the fund or paying any redemption premium required to be paid when such qualified investments shall be redeemed prior to maturity; provided, however, that monies in the fund shall not be withdrawn at any time in such an amount as would reduce the amount of the fund to less than the minimum requirement thereof established by the center, except for the purpose of paying binding obligations associated with qualified investments which shall be secured by the fund as the same become payable.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter to the contrary, a company need not be a certified life sciences company, as established in section 5, to be eligible for matching grants pursuant to this section. The fund shall be held and applied by the center to make qualified loans, grants or other investments to stimulate increased financing for life sciences and high technology research and development, manufacturing and commercialization in the commonwealth by matching grants to public agencies, independent research institutions, nonprofits or to life sciences or high technology companies to increase and strengthen the commonwealth’s economic development, employment opportunities and commercial and industrial sectors. The fund shall provide matching grants to commonwealth-based life sciences or high technology companies that receive small business innovation research or small business technology transfer grants from the Small Business Administration, pursuant to 15 U.S.C. section 638, to assist companies that have developed new commercialization-ready technologies to reach production and create manufacturing jobs in the commonwealth. Said matching grants shall be used to create manufacturing jobs and may be used for, without limitation, the creation of, and capital improvements for, production facilities, workforce training, product marketing and purchasing infrastructure for product manufacturing. Said matching grants shall be distributed to eligible companies that have commercialization-ready technologies developed with assistance from the Small Business Administration in the form of $1 in matching funds for every $1 granted from the small business innovation research phase IIB grants, phase III grants and the commercialization pilot project established by 15 U.S.C. section 638. Said matching grants shall be awarded in consultation with the Small Business Association of New England. No such grant to any company shall exceed $500,000 annually and the center shall make no such qualified loan, grant or other investment unless: (1) said loan, grant or investment has been approved by a majority vote of the board; (2) the center finds that, to the extent possible, a definite benefit to the commonwealth’s economy may reasonably be expected from said qualified loan, grant or investment; provided, however, that in evaluating a request or application for funding, the center shall consider whether: (i) the loan, grant or investment shall stimulate increased financing for life sciences and high technology research and development, manufacturing and commercialization; (ii) the enterprise has a reasonable chance of success; (iii) center participation is necessary; (iv) the enterprise has the reasonable potential to create a substantial amount of new employment in the commonwealth; (v) the principals of the enterprise have made or are prepared to make a substantial financial and time commitment to the enterprise; (vi) binding commitments have been made to the center by the enterprise for adequate reporting of financial data to the center, which shall include a requirement for an annual or other periodic audit of the books of the enterprise, and for such control on the part of the center as the board shall consider prudent over the management of the company to protect the investment of the center including the board’s right to access, without limitation, financial and other records of the enterprise; and (vii) a reasonable effort has been made to find a professional investor to invest in the enterprise and whether such effort was unsuccessful; and (3) said loan, grant or other investment conforms with rules approved by the board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The center may solicit investments by private institutions or investors in the activities of the fund and may reach agreements with such private institutions or investors regarding the terms of any such investments including, but not limited to, the rights of such investors to participate in the income or appropriation of the fund. To further the objective of securing investments by private institutions or investors in the activities of the fund pursuant to the preceding sentence, the center may develop a proposal relative to the creation of a separate investment entity which shall permit the commingling of the fund’s resources with the maximum participation by such private institutions or investors consistent with the public purpose of the fund and under the terms and conditions established to protect and preserve the assets of the fund; provided, however, that if the creation or operation of such a separate entity would require additional or clarifying amendments to the enabling act of the center, said proposal shall include proposed statutory language with regard thereto. Any additional clarifying amendments to the enabling act shall be submitted by the center to the clerks of the house of representatives and the senate, who shall forward the same to the house and senate committees on ways and means and the joint committee on economic development and emerging technologies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Copies of the approved rules, and any modifications thereto, shall be submitted to the clerks of the house of representatives and the senate, who shall forward the same to the house and senate committees on ways and means and the joint committee on economic development and emerging technologies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Qualified investment transactions made by the center pursuant to the provisions of this section shall not, except as specified in this chapter, be subject to the provisions of chapter 175, or any successor thereto, and shall be payable solely from the Massachusetts Small Business Matching Grant Fund, established by this section and shall not constitute a debt or pledge of the full faith and credit of the commonwealth, the center or any subdivision of the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The center shall not make expenditure from or commitment of the assets of the fund including, but not limited to, the making of qualified investments secured by the fund, if following the making of said qualified investment, the amount of the fund shall be less than the minimum requirement established by the board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     The center shall develop a plan ensuring that fund disbursements made pursuant to this section shall be distributed throughout all regions of the commonwealth.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>