<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23" level="3">Executive Office Of Labor And Workforce Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Agencies Within Department Of Labor;  Duties Of Department;  Funds Within Division Of Unemployment Assistance</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. Repealed by 2011, 3, Sec. 20.]  (a) Within the department, there shall be the following agencies and divisions: the division of industrial accidents, the division of labor relations, and the division of occupational safety.  (b) The duties of the department shall include, and the department shall have authority and responsibility over, the administration and enforcement of section 3, 5, 9H and 11A; the provisions of chapter 111F; the provisions of chapters 149, with the exception of section 160 to 168A, and 151; the provisions of chapter 151A; and the provisions of subsections (b), (c), (e) and (f) of section 197B of chapter 111. Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the attorney general shall have exclusive authority to conduct field investigations, inspections, and civil and criminal prosecutions with respect to, and otherwise enforce, said chapters 149 and laws pertaining to wages, hours and working conditions, child labor and workplace safety and fair competition for bidders on public construction, except the laws pertaining to lead and asbestos hazards and workplace hygienic standards which the department shall enforce.[ There is no subsection (c).]  (d) The following funds shall be within the division of unemployment assistance: the Unemployment Insurance Trust Fund and the Medical Security Trust Fund.
    </text>
</law>