<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94C" order_by="94C" level="3">Controlled Substances Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Trafficking In Marihuana, Cocaine, Heroin, Morphine, Opium, Etc.;  Eligibility For Parole</catch_line>
    <order_by>32E</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) Any person who trafficks in marihuana by knowingly or intentionally manufacturing, distributing, dispensing, or cultivating or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute, dispense, or cultivate, or by bringing into the commonwealth a net weight of fifty pounds or more of marihuana or a net weight of fifty pounds or more of any mixture containing marihuana shall, if the net weight of marihuana or any mixture thereof is:  (1) Fifty pounds or more, but less than one hundred pounds, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than two and one-half nor more than fifteen years or by imprisonment in a jail or house of correction for not less than one nor more than two and one-half years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this section shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of one year and a fine of not less than five hundred nor more than ten thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum one year term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause 2 of paragraph (a) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (2) One hundred pounds or more, but less than two thousand pounds, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than three nor more than fifteen years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this section shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of three years and a fine of not less than two thousand and five hundred nor more than twenty-five thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause (2) of paragraph (a) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 17 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (2) One hundred pounds or more, but less than two thousand pounds, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 2 nor more than fifteen years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this section shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 2 years and a fine of not less than two thousand and five hundred nor more than twenty-five thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause 3 of paragraph (a) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (3) Two thousand pounds or more, but less than ten thousand pounds, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than five nor more than fifteen years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this section shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of five years and a fine of not less than five thousand nor more than fifty thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause (3) of paragraph (a) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 18 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (3) Two thousand pounds or more, but less than ten thousand pounds, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 31/2 nor more than fifteen years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this section shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 31/2 years and a fine of not less than five thousand nor more than fifty thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause 4 of paragraph (a) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (4) Ten thousand pounds or more, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than ten nor more than fifteen years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this section shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of ten years and a fine of not less than twenty thousand nor more than two hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause (4) of paragraph (a) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 19 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (4) Ten thousand pounds or more, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 8 nor more than fifteen years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this section shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 8 years and a fine of not less than twenty thousand nor more than two hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Introductory paragraph of paragraph (b) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (b) Any person who trafficks in a controlled substance defined in clause (4) of paragraph (a) or in clause (3) of paragraph (c) of Class B of section thirty-one by knowingly or intentionally manufacturing, distributing or dispensing or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute or dispense or by bringing into the commonwealth a net weight of fourteen grams or more of a controlled substance as so defined, or a net weight of fourteen grams or more of any mixture containing a controlled substance as so defined shall, if the net weight of a controlled substance as so defined, or any mixture thereof is:[ Introductory paragraph of paragraph (b) as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 102 effective July 1, 2012 until August 2, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (b) Any person who trafficks in a controlled substance defined in clause (4) of paragraph (a), clause (2) of paragraph (c) or in clause (3) of paragraph (c) of Class B of section thirty-one by knowingly or intentionally manufacturing, distributing or dispensing or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute or dispense or by bringing into the commonwealth a net weight of fourteen grams or more of a controlled substance as so defined, or a net weight of fourteen grams or more of any mixture containing a controlled substance as so defined shall, if the net weight of a controlled substance as so defined, or any mixture thereof is:[ Introductory paragraph of paragraph (b) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 20 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.  (b) Any person who trafficks in a controlled substance defined in clause (4) of paragraph (a), clause (2) of paragraph (c) or in clause (3) of paragraph (c) of Class B of section thirty-one by knowingly or intentionally manufacturing, distributing or dispensing or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute or dispense or by bringing into the commonwealth a net weight of 18 grams or more of a controlled substance as so defined, or a net weight of 18 grams or more of any mixture containing a controlled substance as so defined shall, if the net weight of a controlled substance as so defined, or any mixture thereof is:[ Clauses (1) and (2) of paragraph (b) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (1) Fourteen grams or more but less than twenty-eight grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than three nor more than fifteen years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a minimum term of imprisonment of three years, and a fine of not less than two thousand five hundred nor more than twenty-five thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.  (2) Twenty-eight grams or more, but less than one hundred grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than five nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of five years, and a fine of not less than five thousand nor more than fifty thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clauses (1) and (2) of paragraph (b) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 21 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (1) Eighteen grams or more but less than 36 grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 2 nor more than 15 years. No sentence imposed under this clause shall be for less than a minimum term of imprisonment of 2 years, and a fine of not less $2,500 nor more than $25,000 may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.  (2) Thirty-six grams or more, but less than 100 grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 31/2 nor more than 20 years. No sentence imposed under this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 31/2 years, and a fine of not less than $5,000 nor more than $50,000 may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause (3) of paragraph (b) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (3) One hundred grams or more, but less than two hundred grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than ten nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of ten years and a fine of not less than ten thousand nor more than one hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause (3) of paragraph (b) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 22 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (3) One hundred grams or more, but less than two hundred grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 8 nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 8 years and a fine of not less than ten thousand nor more than one hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause (4) of paragraph (b) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (4) Two hundred grams or more, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than fifteen nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of fifteen years and a fine of not less than fifty thousand nor more than five hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause (4) of paragraph (b) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 23 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (4) Two hundred grams or more, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 12 nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 12 years and a fine of not less than fifty thousand nor more than five hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Introductory paragraph of paragraph (c) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (c) Any person who trafficks in heroin or any salt thereof, morphine or any salt thereof, opium or any derivative thereof by knowingly or intentionally manufacturing, distributing or dispensing or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense or by bringing into the commonwealth a net weight of fourteen grams or more of heroin or any salt thereof, morphine or any salt thereof, opium or any derivative thereof or a net weight of fourteen grams or more of any mixture containing heroin or any salt thereof, morphine or any salt thereof, opium or any derivative thereof shall, if the net weight of heroin or any salt thereof, morphine or any salt thereof, opium or any derivative thereof or any mixture thereof is:--[ Introductory paragraph of paragraph (c) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 24 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.  (c) Any person who trafficks in heroin or any salt thereof, morphine or any salt thereof, opium or any derivative thereof by knowingly or intentionally manufacturing, distributing or dispensing or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense or by bringing into the commonwealth a net weight of 18 grams or more of heroin or any salt thereof, morphine or any salt thereof, opium or any derivative thereof or a net weight of 18 grams or more of any mixture containing heroin or any salt thereof, morphine or any salt thereof, opium or any derivative thereof shall, if the net weight of heroin or any salt thereof, morphine or any salt thereof, opium or any derivative thereof or any mixture thereof is:--[ Clauses (1) and (2) of paragraph (c) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (1) Fourteen grams or more but less than twenty-eight grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than five nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of five years and a fine of not less than five thousand nor more than fifty thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.  (2) Twenty-eight grams or more but less than one hundred grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than seven nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of seven years and a fine of not less than five thousand nor more than fifty thousand dollars may be imposed, but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clauses (1) and (2) of paragraph (c) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 25 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (1) Eighteen grams or more but less than 36 grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 31/2 nor more than 20 years. No sentence imposed under this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 31/2 years, and a fine of not less than $5,000 nor more than $50,000 may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.  (2) Thirty-six grams or more but less than 100 grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 5 nor more than 20 years. No sentence imposed under this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 5 years, and a fine of not less than $5,000 nor more than $50,000 may be imposed, but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established herein.[ Clause (3) of paragraph (c) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (3) One hundred grams or more but less than two hundred grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than ten nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of ten years, and a fine of not less than ten thousand nor more than one hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established therein.[ Clause (3) of paragraph (c) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 26 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (3) One hundred grams or more but less than two hundred grams, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 8 nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 8 years, and a fine of not less than ten thousand nor more than one hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established therein.[ Clause (4) of paragraph (c) effective until August 2, 2012. For text effective August 2, 2012, see below.]  (4) Two hundred grams or more, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than fifteen nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of fifteen years and a fine of not less than fifty thousand nor more than five hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established therein.[ Clause (4) of paragraph (c) as amended by 2012, 192, Sec. 27 effective August 2, 2012. For text effective until August 2, 2012, see above.]  (4) Two hundred grams or more, be punished by a term of imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 12 nor more than twenty years. No sentence imposed under the provisions of this clause shall be for less than a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment of 12 years and a fine of not less than fifty thousand nor more than five hundred thousand dollars may be imposed but not in lieu of the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, as established therein.  (d) Any person serving a mandatory minimum sentence for violating this section shall be eligible for parole after serving one-half of the maximum term of the sentence if the sentence is to the house of correction, except that such person shall not be eligible for parole upon a finding of any 1 of the following aggravating circumstances:  (i) the defendant used violence or threats of violence or possessed a firearm, rifle, shotgun, machine gun or a weapon described in paragraph (b) of section 10 of chapter 269, or induced another participant to do so, during the commission of the offense;  (ii) the defendant engaged in a course of conduct whereby he directed the activities of another others who committed any felony in violation of chapter 94C; or  (iii) the offense was committed during the commission or attempted commission of a violation of section 32F or section 32K of chapter 94C.  A condition of such parole may be enhanced supervision; provided, however, that such enhanced supervision may, at the discretion of the parole board, include, but shall not be limited to, the wearing of a global positioning satellite tracking device or any comparable device, which shall be administered by the board at all times for the length of the parole.
    </text>
</law>