<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Annual Report To Governor</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The commissioner of administration shall, on or before the first Wednesday in December of each year ending in an even number, submit a report to the governor listing and discussing the proposals which have been made and the accomplishments which have been achieved during the preceding two years in the areas of improving departmental organization, structure, procedures, and administrative practices; promoting economy and efficiency and avoiding useless labor and expense in the business affairs of the commonwealth; and developing and improving programs, policies and activities which enhance the public service of the commonwealth. Said report shall contain a summary of the objectives of such proposals, their disposition, and such further recommendations for legislative or executive actions concerning these proposals or additional proposals as, in the judgment of the commissioner, should be made in order to improve the programs, services and business affairs of the commonwealth.
Chapter 7: Annual report to governor
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Secs. 45 and 46 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The secretary shall, on or before the first Wednesday in December of each year ending in an even number, submit a report to the governor listing and discussing the proposals which have been made and the accomplishments which have been achieved during the preceding two years in the areas of improving departmental organization, structure, procedures, and administrative practices; promoting economy and efficiency and avoiding useless labor and expense in the business affairs of the commonwealth; and developing and improving programs, policies and activities which enhance the public service of the commonwealth. Said report shall contain a summary of the objectives of such proposals, their disposition, and such further recommendations for legislative or executive actions concerning these proposals or additional proposals as, in the judgment of the secretary, should be made in order to improve the programs, services and business affairs of the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>