<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87WW</section_number>
    <catch_line>Non Residents; Licensed Broker Or Salesman; Power Of Attorney;  Service Of Process</catch_line>
    <order_by>87WW</order_by>
    <text>
        A non-resident may be licensed as a broker and a non-resident individual may be licensed as a salesman upon conforming to all pertinent provisions of sections eighty-seven PP to eighty-seven DDD, inclusive; provided, that the board may exempt from the written examination prescribed in section eighty-seven SS a broker or salesman duly licensed in any other state of the United States under the laws of which a similar exemption is extended to licensed brokers and salesmen of the commonwealth. Such non-resident licensee shall not be required to maintain a usual place of business within the commonwealth; provided, that such non-resident broker shall maintain a usual place of business within such other state in which he is so licensed. 
No license shall be issued to such non-resident until he shall have filed with the chairman of the board a power of attorney constituting and appointing said chairman and his successor his true and lawful attorney, upon whom all lawful processes in any action or legal proceeding against him may be served, and therein shall agree that any lawful process against him which may be served upon his said attorney shall be of the same force and validity as if served on said non-resident, and that the authority thereof shall continue in force irrevocably as long as any liability of said non-resident remains outstanding in the commonwealth. Service of such process shall be made by leaving duplicate copies thereof in the hands or office of the chairman, and the chairman shall forthwith send one of said copies by mail, postage prepaid, addressed to the defendant at his last address as appearing on the records of the board. One of the duplicates of such process, certified by the chairman as having been served upon him, shall be deemed sufficient evidence of such service, and service upon such attorney shall be deemed service upon the principal.
    </text>
</law>