<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="74A" order_by="74A" level="3">Independent Agricultural And Technical Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Agency Disclosure Form Prescribed By State Ethics Commission;  Board Of Trustees Members; Annual Filing</catch_line>
    <order_by>20</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until July 1 preceding the opening of the Essex North Shore agricultural and technical school. Repealed by 2004, 463, Sec. 1. See 2004, 463, Sec. 18 as amended by 2010, 130, Sec. 7.] 
Notwithstanding this chapter or any other general or special law to the contrary, for the purposes of chapter 268A, each school shall be deemed to be a state agency and the appointing official of a member of the board of trustees of such school shall be deemed to be the governor. Members of the board of trustees shall file a disclosure annually with the state ethics commission, the department of education and the governor. The form of the disclosure shall be prescribed by the state ethics commission and shall be signed under penalties of perjury. Such form shall be limited to a statement in which members of the board of trustees shall disclose any financial interest that they or a member of their immediate families, as defined in section 1 of chapter 268A have in any primary or secondary school located in the commonwealth or in any other state or with any person doing business with any primary or secondary school. 
Each member of the board of trustees shall file such disclosure for the preceding calendar year with the commission within 30 days after becoming a member of the board of trustees, on or before September 1 of each year thereafter that such person is a member of the board of trustees and on or before September 1 of the year after such person ceases to be a member of the board of trustees; provided, however, that no member of the board of trustees shall be required to file such disclosure for the year in which he or she ceases to be a member of the board of trustees if he or she served less than 30 days in such year.
    </text>
</law>