<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of Category 2 License</catch_line>
    <order_by>20</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) The commission may issue not more than 1 category 2 license; provided, however, that the category 2 license shall only be issued to an applicant who is qualified under the criteria set forth in this chapter as determined by the commission. If the commission is not convinced that there is an applicant that has both met the eligibility criteria and provided convincing evidence that the applicant will provide value to the commonwealth, no category 2 license shall be awarded.  (b) If a category 2 license is awarded to an applicant with a simulcasting license under chapter 128C as of July 1, 2011, a condition of the gaming license shall be to maintain the simulcasting license pursuant to said chapter 128C. Upon failure to conduct simulcast wagering the commission shall suspend the category 2 license.  (c) If a category 2 license is awarded to an applicant with a live racing license pursuant to chapter 128A as of July 1, 2011 a condition of the gaming license shall be to maintain and complete the annual live racing season pursuant to said chapter 128A. Upon failure to conduct live racing, the commission shall suspend the category 2 license.  (d) For the purposes of subsections (b) and (c), an applicant for a gaming license shall be considered to be the holder of a license under chapter 128A or chapter 128C if the applicant: (i) owns 50.1 or more per cent of the common stock of the company which obtained a license under chapter 128A or 128C; and (ii) includes a person who owns more than 5 per cent of the common stock of the applicant company, directly or indirectly, or is an institutional investor in the gaming license.  (e) A category 2 license issued pursuant to this chapter shall not be transferrable or assignable without the approval of the commission; provided, however, that for 5 years after the initial issuance of a category 2 license, the commission shall only approve such a transfer if: (i) the licensee experiences a change in ownership; or (ii) the licensee fails to maintain suitability or other circumstances which the commission may consider, which, in the opinion of a majority of members of the commission, impacts a licensee's ability to successfully operate a gaming establishment.  (f) A category 2 license issued pursuant to this chapter shall be for a period of 5 years. The commission shall establish procedures for renewal and set the renewal fee based on the cost of fees associated with the evaluation of a licensee; provided, however, that the cost of renewal shall not be less than $100,000. Any renewal fees shall be deposited into the Gaming Revenue Fund.
    </text>
</law>