<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="57" order_by="57" level="3">Congressional, Councillor And Senatorial Districts, And Apportionment Of Representatives</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Division Of State Into Councillor Districts</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 3, 2011. For text effective November 3, 2011, see below.]  For the purpose of choosing councillors until the next apportionment, the commonwealth is divided, conformably with the constitution, into the following 8 councillor districts:  First.--Consisting of the First Bristol and Plymouth; Second Bristol and Plymouth; Cape and Islands; Plymouth and Barnstable; and First Plymouth and Bristol senatorial districts.  Second.--Consisting of the Bristol and Norfolk; Second Middlesex and Norfolk; Norfolk, Bristol and Middlesex; Norfolk, Bristol and Plymouth; and Suffolk and Norfolk senatorial districts.  Third.--Consisting of the First Middlesex; Third Middlesex; First Middlesex and Norfolk; Middlesex and Worcester; and Second Suffolk and Middlesex senatorial districts.  Fourth.--Consisting of the Norfolk and Plymouth; Second Plymouth and Bristol; Plymouth and Norfolk; First Suffolk; and Second Suffolk senatorial districts.  Fifth.--Consisting of the First Essex; Second Essex; First Essex and Middlesex; Second Essex and Middlesex; and Third Essex and Middlesex senatorial districts.  Sixth.--Consisting of the Second Middlesex; Fourth Middlesex; Middlesex and Essex; Middlesex, Suffolk and Essex; and First Suffolk and Middlesex senatorial districts.  Seventh.--Consisting of the First Worcester; Second Worcester; Worcester, Hampden, Hampshire and Franklin; Worcester and Middlesex; and Worcester and Norfolk senatorial districts.  Eighth.--Consisting of the Berkshire, Hampshire and Franklin; Hampden; First Hampden and Hampshire; Second Hampden and Hampshire; and Hampshire and Franklin senatorial districts.
Chapter 57: Division of state into councillor districts
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 152, Sec. 1 effective November 3, 2011. For text effective until November 3, 2011, see above.]  For the purpose of choosing councillors until the next apportionment, the commonwealth shall be divided, conformably with the constitution, into the following 8 councillor districts:  First.--Consisting of the First Bristol and Plymouth; Second Bristol and Plymouth; Cape and Islands; Plymouth and Barnstable; and First Plymouth and Bristol senatorial districts.  Second.--Consisting of the Bristol and Norfolk; Second Middlesex and Norfolk; Norfolk, Bristol and Middlesex; Norfolk, Bristol and Plymouth; and Norfolk and Suffolk senatorial districts.  Third.--Consisting of the Third Middlesex; Fourth Middlesex; First Middlesex and Norfolk; Middlesex and Worcester; and Second Suffolk and Middlesex senatorial districts.  Fourth.--Consisting of the Norfolk and Plymouth; Second Plymouth and Bristol; Plymouth and Norfolk; First Suffolk; and Second Suffolk senatorial districts.  Fifth.--Consisting of the First Essex; Second Essex; First Essex and Middlesex; Second Essex and Middlesex; and First Middlesex senatorial districts.  Sixth.--Consisting of the Third Essex; Second Middlesex; Fifth Middlesex; Middlesex and Suffolk; and First Suffolk and Middlesex senatorial districts.  Seventh.--Consisting of the First Worcester; Second Worcester; Worcester, Hampden, Hampshire and Middlesex; Worcester and Middlesex; and Worcester and Norfolk senatorial districts.  Eighth.--Consisting of the Berkshire, Hampshire, Franklin and Hampden; Hampden; First Hampden and Hampshire; Second Hampden and Hampshire; and Hampshire, Franklin and Worcester senatorial districts.
    </text>
</law>