<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35XX</section_number>
    <catch_line>Horseneck Beach Reservation Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35XX</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 307, Sec. 1 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 307, Sec. 2.]  (a) There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Horseneck Beach Reservation Trust Fund to be used, without further appropriation, for the long-term preservation, maintenance, nourishment and public safety of Horseneck Beach in the town of Westport. Any balance in the fund at the end of the fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund, but shall remain available for expenditure in subsequent fiscal years. No expenditure made from the fund shall cause the fund to become deficient at any point during a fiscal year. An annual report to include projects undertaken, expenditures made and income received by the fund shall be submitted to the clerks of the house of representatives and the senate and to the house and senate committees on ways and means not later than October 1 of each year.  (b) The department of conservation and recreation shall impose a surcharge of $1 upon each fee charged and collected from admission to and parking in the Horseneck Beach Reservation. The additional monies collected from the surcharge shall be deposited into the Horseneck Beach Reservation Trust Fund. Expenditures by the trust for public safety may be made available to the town of Westport's police, fire, ambulance and emergency personnel. On or before November 30 of each year, the department of conservation and recreation shall meet with the board of selectmen of the town of Westport to discuss the maintenance and safety plan for the beach for the next calendar year as well as the balance and expenditures from the Horseneck Beach Reservation Trust Fund.
    </text>
</law>