<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Unused Medication;  Return By Health Care Facilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>25I</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until April 1, 2012. For text effective April 1, 2012, see below.]  The commissioner by rules and regulations may provide that either a resident or consultant pharmacist in a health care facility may return to the pharmacy from which it was purchased any unused medication provided that such medication is sealed in unopened, individually packaged units and within the recommended period of shelf life, and provided that such medication is not a schedule I or II controlled substance as defined in chapter ninety-four C. Such rules and regulations shall permit the pharmacy to which such medication is returned to restock and redistribute such medication, and shall be required to reimburse or credit the purchaser for any such returned medication.
Chapter 111: Guidelines for the reduction of medication waste in licensed facilities
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 69, Sec. 81 effective April 1, 2012. See 2011, 68, Sec. 216. For text effective until April 1, 2012, see above.]  The department, in conjunction with the board of registration in pharmacy and the division of medical assistance, shall establish and implement guidelines to reduce medication waste in facilities licensed by the department, the department of mental health and the department of corrections. The department shall establish such guidelines, based on its review, that are determined to be effective in reducing waste without imposing unreasonable costs on the health care delivery system. In establishing such guidelines the department may consider the following: (i) current technology, standards and reimbursement mechanisms for dispensing and distributing medications to facilities; (ii) requirements implemented in other states for limiting prescription drug waste and any cost-savings realized; (iii) the commonwealth's standards for the return and re-dispensing of patient-specific schedule VI prescription drugs; and (iv) possible incentive mechanisms to prevent prescription drug waste. The department shall promulgate regulations to implement this section.
    </text>
</law>