<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Counties And County Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35" level="3">County Treasurers, State Supervision Of County Accounts And County Finances</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>50</section_number>
    <catch_line>Director Of Accounts; Powers And Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>50</order_by>
    <text>
        The director of accounts shall (a) prepare and submit to the board classification and compensation plans, together with such rules for the administration thereof as he may deem proper; (b) recommend to the board such amendments thereto as he deems expedient, and also advise and report to the board relative to amendments proposed under section fifty-three; (c) keep an official roster of the officers and employees subject to sections forty-eight to fifty-six, inclusive, with such other relevant information as he may deem advisable, furnishing for each county a duplicate roster of such officers and employees of the county for filing in the office of the county commissioners; (d) advise and assist the several county commissioners and the board in carrying out the purposes of said sections; (e) perform such other duties as may be requested by the county commissioners of any county or the board in carrying out said purposes; (f) make a continuing study of personnel problems, employment conditions and economic changes as affecting offices and positions subject to said sections; and (g) investigate and make report to the board on appeals as provided in section fifty-two. 
The director may employ a person skilled and experienced in public classification and compensation work to assist in the performance of the duties imposed upon him by said sections forty-eight to fifty-six, inclusive. Such employment shall not be subject to chapter thirty-one. All expenses incurred by the director under this section and the compensation and expenses payable under section forty-eight shall be paid in the first instance by the commonwealth, from such funds as may be appropriated by the general court; and the several counties, excluding Suffolk, shall reimburse the commonwealth therefor in proportion to their taxable valuations as determined by the director.
    </text>
</law>