<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>49</section_number>
    <catch_line>Ponds On State Boundary; Fishing</catch_line>
    <order_by>49</order_by>
    <text>
        If, in the case of a pond situated partly in the commonwealth and partly in another state, the laws of such other state permit fishing in that part thereof lying within such other state by persons licensed or otherwise entitled under the laws of the commonwealth to fish in that part of such pond lying within the commonwealth, persons licensed or otherwise entitled under the laws of such other state to fish in the part of such pond lying within such other state shall be permitted to fish in that part thereof lying within the commonwealth, and, as to such pond, the operation of the laws of the commonwealth relative to open and closed seasons, limits of catch, minimum sizes of fish caught and methods of fishing shall be suspended upon the adoption and during the continuance in force of rules and regulations relative to those subjects and affecting that part of such pond lying within the commonwealth, which rules and regulations the director is hereby authorized to make, and from time to time add to, alter and repeal. Before making, adding to, altering or repealing such rules and regulations, said director shall confer with the officer or board having like duties in such other state, in order to secure uniformity of laws, rules and regulations as to the whole of such pond, if practicable. Such rules and regulations shall be printed and available for distribution at the office of the director and of the clerk of each city and town in the commonwealth in which any part of such pond is situated or to which it lies adjacent.
    </text>
</law>