<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93J" order_by="93J" level="3">Protection Of Owners And Businesses In The Repairing Of Motor Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Access By Owners Of Motor Vehicles And By Independent Repair Facilities To Motor Vehicle Manufacturer Diagnostic And Repair Information And Diagnostic Repair Tools Otherwise Made Available To Dealers</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 241 effective November 5, 2012.]   All content in any such manufacturer's repair information system shall be made available to owners and to independent repair facilities in the same form and manner and to the same extent as is made available to dealers utilizing such diagnostic and repair information system. Each manufacturer shall provide access to such manufacturer's diagnostic and repair information system for purchase by owners and independent repair facilities on a daily, monthly and yearly subscription basis and upon fair and reasonable terms.  (2)(b) Any manufacturer that sells any diagnostic, service, or repair information to any independent repair facility or other third party provider in a format that is standardized with other manufacturers, and on terms and conditions more favorable than the manner and the terms and conditions pursuant to which the dealer obtains the same diagnostic, service or repair information, shall be prohibited from requiring any dealer to continue purchasing diagnostic, service, or repair information in a proprietary format, unless such proprietary format includes diagnostic, service, repair or dealership operations information or functionality that is not available in such standardized format.  (2)(c)(i) For Model Year 2002 motor vehicles and thereafter, each manufacturer of motor vehicles sold in the commonwealth shall make available for purchase by owners and independent repair facilities all diagnostic repair tools incorporating the same diagnostic, repair and wireless capabilities that such manufacturer makes available to its dealers. Such tools shall incorporate the same functional repair capabilities that such manufacturer makes available to dealers. Each manufacturer shall offer such tools for sale to owners and to independent repair facilities upon fair and reasonable terms.  (2)(c)(ii) Any diagnostic tool or information necessary to diagnose, service or repair a motor vehicle that a manufacturer sells to any independent repair facility in a manner and on terms and conditions more favorable than the manner and the terms and conditions pursuant to which the dealer obtains the same diagnostic tool or information necessary to diagnose, service or repair a motor vehicle, shall also be offered to the dealer in the same manner and on the same terms and conditions as provided to such independent repair facility.  Any manufacturer that sells to any independent repair facility any diagnostic tool necessary to diagnose, service or repair a motor vehicle and such diagnostic tool communicates with the vehicle using the same non-proprietary interface used by other manufacturers, the manufacturer delivering such a diagnostic tool shall be prohibited from requiring any dealer from continuing to purchase that manufacturer's proprietary tool and interface unless such proprietary interface has a capability not available in the non-proprietary interface.  (2)(c)(iii) Each manufacturer shall provide diagnostic repair information to each aftermarket scan tool company and each third party service information provider with whom the manufacturer has appropriate licensing, contractual or confidentiality agreements for the sole purpose of building aftermarket diagnostic tools and third party service information publications and systems. Once a manufacturer makes such information available pursuant to this section, the manufacturer will have fully satisfied its obligations under this section and thereafter not be responsible for the content and functionality of aftermarket diagnostic tools or service information systems.  (2)(d)(i) Commencing in Model Year 2018, except as provided in subsection (2)(e), manufacturers of motor vehicles sold in the commonwealth shall provide access to their onboard diagnostic and repair information system, as required under this section, using an off-the-shelf personal computer with sufficient memory, processor speed, connectivity and other capabilities as specified by the vehicle manufacturer and: (i) a non-proprietary vehicle interface device that complies with the Society of Automotive Engineers SAE J2534, the International Standards Organizations ISO 22900 or any successor to SAE J2534 or ISO 22900 as may be accepted or published by the Society of Automotive Engineers or the International Standards Organizations; or, (ii) an on-board diagnostic and repair information system integrated and entirely self-contained within the vehicle including, but not limited to, service information systems integrated into an onboard display, or (iii) a system that provides direct access to on-board diagnostic and repair information through a non-proprietary vehicle interface such as Ethernet, Universal Serial Bus or Digital Versatile Disc. Each manufacturer shall provide access to the same on-board diagnostic and repair information available to their dealers, including technical updates to such on-board systems, through such non-proprietary interfaces as referenced in this paragraph.  Nothing in this Chapter shall be construed to require a dealer to use the non-proprietary vehicle interface (i.e., SAE J2534 or ISO 22900 vehicle interface device) specified in this subsection, nor shall this Chapter be construed to prohibit a manufacturer from developing a proprietary vehicle diagnostic and reprogramming device, provided that (i) the manufacturer also complies with Provision of such proprietary tools under this paragraph shall not constitute a violation of this chapter even if such tools provide functions not available through the interface set forth in (2)(d)(i), provided such proprietary tools are also available to the aftermarket upon fair and reasonable terms. Nothing in this subsection (2)(d)(ii) authorizes manufacturers to exclusively develop proprietary tools, without a non-proprietary equivalent as set forth in (2)(d)(i), for diagnostic or repair procedures that fall outside the provisions of (2)(d)(ii) or to otherwise operate in a manner inconsistent with the requirements of (2)(d)(i).  (2)(e) Manufacturers of motor vehicles sold in the commonwealth may exclude diagnostic, service and repair information necessary to reset an immobilizer system or security-related electronic modules from information provided to owners and independent repair facilities. If excluded under this paragraph, the information necessary to reset an immobilizer system or security-related electronic modules shall be obtained by owners and independent repair facilities through the secure data release model system as currently used by the National Automotive Service Task Force or other known, reliable and accepted systems.  (2)(f) With the exception of telematics diagnostic and repair information that is provided to dealers, necessary to diagnose and repair a customer's vehicle, and not otherwise available to an independent repair facility via the tools specified in 2(c)(i) and 2(d)(i) above, nothing in this chapter shall apply to telematics services or any other remote or information service, diagnostic or otherwise, delivered to or derived from the vehicle by mobile communications; provided, however, that nothing in this chapter shall be construed to abrogate a telematics services or other contract that exists between a manufacturer or service provider, a motor vehicle owner, and/or a dealer. For purposes of this chapter, telematics services include but are not limited to automatic airbag deployment and crash notification, remote diagnostics, navigation, stolen vehicle location, remote door unlock, transmitting emergency and vehicle location information to public safety answering points as well as any other service integrating vehicle location technology and wireless communications. Nothing in this chapter shall require a manufacturer or a dealer to disclose to any person the identity of existing customers or customer lists.
    </text>
</law>