<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>44E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Acceptance Of Recommendation; Election; Establishment Of District</catch_line>
    <order_by>44E</order_by>
    <text>
        The selectmen of each of the several towns, upon receipt of a recommendation that a regional refuse disposal district be established, shall cause the question of accepting such plan to be presented for determination by vote with printed ballots at the next annual town meeting or at a special town meeting called for the purpose. The mayors of the several cities, upon receipt of a recommendation that a regional refuse disposal district be established, shall submit the question of accepting such plan to the city council within sixty days after receipt of the recommendation. In the case of either a town or a city, the question to be voted on shall be:—“Shall the city (town) accept the provisions of sections 44A to 44K, inclusive, of chapter 40 of the General Laws providing for the establishment of a regional refuse district, together with the towns of ____________________ and the cities of ____________________, and the construction, maintenance and operation of a regional refuse disposal facility by said district in accordance with the provisions of a proposed agreement filed with the selectmen or the mayor?” 
If a majority of the members of each city council voting on the question and a majority of the voters in each town voting on the question shall vote in the affirmative, the proposed regional refuse disposal district shall be deemed to be established forthwith in accordance with the terms of the proposed agreement.
    </text>
</law>