<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21O" order_by="21O" level="3">Operation And Removal Of Underground Storage Tanks</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notification Of Operation Of Underground Storage Tanks;  Requirements; Exceptions</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Each owner of an underground storage tank first put into operation on or after January first, nineteen hundred and ninety-one shall, within thirty days after the tank is first put into operation, notify the department of the existence of such tank, specifying the age, size, type, location, and uses of such tank. The requirements of this subsection (1) shall not apply to any underground storage tank that is (a) a farm or residential tank of one thousand and one hundred gallons or less capacity used for storing motor fuel for noncommercial purposes, or (b) a tank used for storing heating oil for consumptive purposes where stored. In prescribing the form of such notice, the department shall take into account the form of the notice prescribed pursuant to section 9002 of RCRA and the effect on small businesses and other owners and operators.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The requirements of this subsection (2) shall not apply to any underground storage tank that is (a) a farm or residential tank of 1,100 gallons or less capacity used for storing motor fuel for noncommercial purposes, or (b) a tank used for storing heating oil for consumptive use on the premises where stored. By no later than January thirty-first, nineteen hundred and ninety-one, each owner of an underground storage tank that was in operation at any time after January first, nineteen hundred and seventy-four and before January first, nineteen hundred and ninety-one, regardless of whether or not such tank was removed from beneath the surface of the ground at any time, shall notify the department of the existence of such tank, specifying, to the extent known to the owner, the size, type, and location of the tank, and the quantity of substances stored in such tank before the tank ceased being in operation if the tank was removed from beneath the surface of the ground, prior to the submittal of such notice to the department, such notice shall also specify, to the extent known to the owner, the date the tank was removed from beneath the surface of the ground, prior to the submittal of such notice to the department. In prescribing the form of such notice, the department shall take into account the form of the notice prescribed pursuant to section 9002 of RCRA and the effect on small businesses and other owners and operators.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The requirements of this subsection (3) shall not apply to any underground storage tank that is (a) a farm or residential tank of 1,100 gallons or less capacity used for storing motor fuel for noncommercial purposes, or (b) a tank used for storing heating oil for consumptive use on the premises where stored. By no later than December thirty-first, nineteen hundred and ninety-one, each owner of an underground storage tank that was not in operation at any time after January first, nineteen hundred and seventy-four and that was not removed from beneath the surface of the ground on or before January first, nineteen hundred and seventy-four, or the operator of any such tank that has no owner or whose owner cannot be definitely ascertained, shall notify the department of the existence of such tank, specifying, to the extent known to the owner, the size, type, and location of the tank, and the type and quantity of substance stored in such tank before the tank ceased being in operation if the tank was removed from beneath the surface of the ground. If the tank was not removed from beneath the surface of the ground prior to the submittal of such notice to the department such notice shall also specify, to the extent known to the owner or operator, the date the tank was removed from beneath the surface of the ground and age of the tank and all methods used to stabilize the tank after the tank ceased being in operation. In prescribing the form of the notice, the department shall take into account the form of the notice prescribed pursuant to section 9002 of RCRA and the effect on small businesses and other owners and operators.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>