<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111H" order_by="111H" level="3">Massachusetts Low Level Radioactive Waste Management Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Procedures For Adoption Of Management Plan</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The adoption of a management plan under section twelve, the adoption of regulations for source minimization, volume minimization and storage for decay under section thirteen, the adoption of regulations for the selection of any superior site under section fourteen the adoption of regulations for operator selection under section fifteen and the adoption of regulations for the licensing of any facility under section sixteen shall be in accordance with the procedures set forth in this section. The recommendations of the public participation coordinator, made pursuant to section six, shall be implemented to the extent feasible in order to ensure appropriate public participation during the development of such plans and regulations; to ensure that adequate information concerning such plans and regulations is available; to facilitate the conduct of public meetings and other opportunities for public review and comment; and to ensure that public concerns are identified and addressed throughout the development of such plans and regulations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No fewer than four months prior to the initial adoption of a management plan pursuant to section twelve and the initial adoption of regulations under sections thirteen to sixteen, inclusive, the responsible agencies shall issue drafts of such management plan and regulations, together with summaries thereof, for public review and comment. No fewer than thirty days and no more than ninety days after the issuance of such drafts, the responsible agencies and the public participation coordinator shall jointly conduct a minimum of six consolidated public meetings throughout the commonwealth on the drafts and shall accept written comments thereon. Such consolidated public meetings shall be conducted at times and locations to be agreed by the responsible agencies and the public participation coordinator.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The management plan and any regulations adopted under any of sections thirteen to sixteen, inclusive, shall be adopted in accordance with the requirements of sections two to six, inclusive, of chapter thirty A; provided, however, that a public hearing satisfying the requirements of section two of said chapter thirty A shall be required prior to the adoption, amendment or repeal of the management plan or any such regulation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The initial management plan developed under section twelve and the initial regulations developed under sections thirteen to sixteen, inclusive, shall be adopted by January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>