<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="104A" order_by="104A" level="3">Consignment Of Fine Art</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings: 
“Artist”, the person who creates a work of fine art or, if such person is deceased, such person’s heir, legatee, or personal representative. 
“Fine art”, a painting, photograph, sculpture, functional sculpture, hologram, wearable art, drawing, fiber-based work, ceramic-based work, metal work, conceptual-based art, glass-based work, an installation, a work that is created or displayed using computer, digital devices and/or new technology such as, but not limited to, digital prints, digital photographs, CD Roms, DVDs, cyberart, a web/internet-based art work, a performance-based art work and the results of the performance such as, but not limited to, film, video, DVDs, CD Roms, a sound work, an electronic-based work, a work of graphic art, including an etching, lithograph, off set print, silk screen/screen print, or work of graphic art of like nature, a work of calligraphy, an artist’s book, or a work in mixed media including collage, assemblage or any combination of the foregoing art media. 
“Art dealer” or “Consignee”, a person engaged in the business of selling works of fine art, who takes works of fine art on consignment in the regular course of business, other than a person exclusively engaged in the business of selling goods at public auction. 
“Person”, an individual partnership, corporation, association or other group, however organized. 
“Consignment”, a delivery of a work of fine art under which no title to, estate in, or right to possession of, the work of fine art superior to that of the consignor shall vest in the consignee, notwithstanding the consignee’s power or authority to transfer and convey to a third person all of the right, title and interest of the consignor in and to the work of fine art. 
“Consignor”, a person who consigns a work of fine art to a consignee, including but not limited to an artist who creates works of fine art, an artist’s heirs or legatees, or an owner of a work of fine art who holds title to the work of fine art. 
“Deliver” or “Delivery”, the process of physically transporting a work of fine art from a consignor to a consignee, whether done by the consignor personally, by a professional transportation service, or by the services of an agent or dealer who acts on behalf of the consignor.
    </text>
</law>