<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>101</section_number>
    <catch_line>Obscene Literature Control Commission; Members; Appointment, Compensation, Etc.</catch_line>
    <order_by>101</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be an obscene literature control commission consisting of seven members, of whom one shall be an educator, one a representative of the Protestant faith, one a representative of the Catholic faith and one a representative of the Jewish faith, to be appointed by the governor, with the advice and consent of the council, for terms of five years. The governor shall in like manner fill any vacancy for the unexpired term. The members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for all traveling expenses incurred by them in the administration of their duties. Said commission shall, in order to facilitate the enforcement of sections twenty-eight to thirty-two, inclusive, of chapter two hundred and seventy-two, recommend to the attorney general, whenever it appears that a violation of the provisions of said sections has occurred, that appropriate action be taken thereunder. Said commission shall be provided with suitable quarters in the state house or elsewhere, and the attorney general shall provide secretarial, clerical and such other services as he deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this section. Said commission shall meet at least once a month, except that any such meeting may be omitted by a two-thirds’ vote of those present and voting at the preceding meeting. Not more than fifteen meetings shall be held in any year.
    </text>
</law>