<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>181</section_number>
    <catch_line>Three Year Term For Certificate Or License; Trainees</catch_line>
    <order_by>181</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until August 11, 2011. For text effective August 11, 2011, see below.] 
A. The term of a certificate or a license issued under the authority of the board, except a transitional license under subdivision C of section one hundred and eighty, shall be three years from the date of issuance. Notwithstanding the foregoing, each certificate or license originally issued to an individual, except a transitional license under said subdivision C of said section one hundred and eighty, shall be valid until the anniversary of the date of birth of the licensee next occurring more than thirty-six months after the date of issuance. A real estate appraisal trainee shall be eligible for renewal of a trainee license for only one three year period after the original term of the license. 
[There is no subdivision B.] 
Chapter 112: Two year term for certificate or license; date of license expiration; trainees [Text of section as amended by 2010, 447, Sec. 1 effective August 11, 2011. See 2010, 447, Sec. 3. For text effective until August 11, 2011, see above.] 
The term of a certificate or a license issued by the board, except a transitional license under subdivision C of section 180, shall be 2 years from the date of issuance. Notwithstanding the foregoing, each certificate or license originally issued to an individual, except a transitional license under said subdivision C of said section 180, shall be valid until the anniversary of the date of birth of the licensee next occurring more than 24 months after the date of issuance; or the director of the division of professional licensure may designate a date other than a birthday for license expiration. A real estate appraisal trainee shall be eligible for renewal of a trainee license for not more than 4 two-year periods after the original term of the license.
    </text>
</law>