<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="71" order_by="71" level="3">Public Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>54B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Administration Of Medications In School Settings; Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>54B</order_by>
    <text>
        Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the department of public health shall promulgate regulations governing the administration of medications, including psychotropic medications to children in school settings, in accordance with sections seven and nine of chapter ninety-four C. In developing such regulations, the department shall consult with the board of registration in nursing and the board of registration in medicine. 
Notwithstanding any general or special law or regulation to the contrary, no school district shall prohibit students with asthma or other respiratory diseases from possessing and administering prescription inhalers in accordance with department of public health regulations concerning students’ self-administration of prescription medications. 
Notwithstanding any general or special law or regulation to the contrary, no school district shall prohibit students with cystic fibrosis from possessing and administering prescription enzyme supplements in accordance with department of public health regulations concerning students’ self-administration of prescription medications. 
Notwithstanding any general or special law or regulation to the contrary, a school district shall not prohibit a student with diabetes from possessing and administering a glucose monitoring test and insulin delivery system, in accordance with department of public health regulations concerning a student’s self-administration of a prescription medication.
    </text>
</law>