<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23H" order_by="23H" level="3">Workforce Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Workforce Investment Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) There shall be in the department, but not subject to the jurisdiction thereof, a state workforce investment board, hereinafter called the board.  (b) The board shall consist of the governor; 3 members of the senate, 2 of whom shall be appointed by the senate president and 1 of whom shall be appointed by the minority leader; 3 members of the House, two of whom shall be appointed by the speaker of the house and 1 of whom shall be appointed by the minority leader; the secretary of the executive office of labor and workforce development; the secretary of the executive office of housing and economic development; the secretary of the executive office of health and human services; the secretary of education; the chancellor of the board of higher education or another official appointed by the governor representing education and training issues; and the following additional members, as appointed by the governor: 2 mayors or chairs of boards of selectmen; 3 persons with experience with youth activities; 2 persons with experience and expertise in the delivery of workforce investment activities, including 1 president of a community college in the commonwealth; 13 persons representing public government, public secondary and post-secondary education, and organizations representing or providing services to trainees, including at least 4 representatives of organized labor, 2 of who shall be selected from among individuals nominated by state labor federations; and 33 persons representing business and industry in the commonwealth to be selected from among individuals nominated by state business associations and trade organizations, including at least 3 chairs of workforce investment boards. The members shall serve two-year terms at the pleasure of the governor, and shall serve without compensation.  (c) The governor or his designee shall chair the board and shall select an individual to serve as co-chair of the board from among the members representing business and industry. The co-chair shall serve at the pleasure of the governor.[ There is no subsection (d).]  (e) The board shall adopt by-laws to govern its proceedings, and shall carry out the responsibilities required of it under the federal Workforce Investment Act of 1998.  (f) The administrative staff of the board shall be supervised by and shall report to the director of the department of career services. The board shall contract with said department for personnel services and other operating needs. Notwithstanding any law or special act to the contrary, other departments, agencies, divisions, commissions, boards and bureaus of the commonwealth are authorized to provide such information and support as the board may from time to time require in the course of carrying out its responsibilities.[ Subsection (g) added by 2012, 238, Sec. 13 effective August 7, 2012.]  (g) The board, in consultation with the president of the Commonwealth Corporation, shall undertake an annual review of local and regional labor market information to develop regional plans to coordinate training and education activities to target employer needs and to meet the commonwealth's demand for workers. The board shall convene regional meetings that shall include representatives from each local workforce investment area, established by the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, 29 U.S.C. § 2801, et seq and, at a minimum, the presidents of any of the region's community colleges, the principals of any vocational-technical high schools, the executive director of the appropriate workforce investment boards, the fiscal agents for Workforce Investment Act funding, and labor, education and industry leaders in each of the regions to review labor market information and develop the regional plans. The Commonwealth Corporation shall aggregate these findings annually and make a report, which shall be filed with the clerks of the house of representatives and senate, on or before June 30.
    </text>
</law>