<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="62E" order_by="62E" level="3">Wage Reporting System</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Release Of Data To Federal And Out Of State Agencies And Departments Within The Commonwealth;  Use Of Data By Department Of Employment And Training And Department Of Education</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
          Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions, nothing herein shall be construed to prevent the release by the commissioner, pursuant to the terms of federally-mandated wage match programs, of reporting system information to the United States Social Security Administration or to agencies of other states who administer federally-funded welfare and unemployment compensation programs.  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, data gathered as part of the reporting systems may be used for purposes of evaluating employment and earnings outcomes of programs within the Massachusetts workforce development system. The commissioner may provide access to data gathered as part of the reporting systems for research and statistical purposes; but, the data shall be released without personal identifiers. The department of revenue may share reporting system information with the division of unemployment assistance, the division of career services and the department of education in the performance of their official duties.[ Third paragraph effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the commissioner may disclose any information referred to in this chapter to the division of unemployment assistance, the division of insurance and the division of health care finance and policy under an interagency agreement for purposes of the administration and enforcement of sections 34 to 39, inclusive, of chapter 118G and sections 6B, 6C and 18B of chapter 118G and for the administration of the fair share employer contribution requirement under section 188 of chapter 149.[ Third paragraph as amended by 2012, 224, Secs. 54 and 55 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the commissioner may disclose any information referred to in this chapter to the division of unemployment assistance, the division of insurance and the executive office of health and human services under an interagency agreement for purposes of the administration and enforcement of sections 64 to 69, inclusive, of chapter 118E and sections 17 and 18 of chapter 176Q and for the administration of the fair share employer contribution requirement under section 188 of chapter 149.
    </text>
</law>