<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2PPP</section_number>
    <catch_line>Essential Community Provider Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2PPP</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Essential Community Provider Trust Fund, in this section called the trust fund. There shall be credited to the trust fund: (a) any funds that may be appropriated or transferred for deposit into the trust fund; and (b) any income derived from investment of amounts credited to the trust fund. In conjunction with the preparation of the commonwealth's annual financial report, the comptroller shall prepare and issue an annual report detailing the revenues and expenditures of the trust fund. The comptroller shall certify payments, including payments during the accounts payable period, in anticipation of revenues, including receivables due and collectibles during the months of July and August, from the trust fund for the purpose of making authorized expenditures. The health safety net office shall administer the trust fund and disburse funds from the trust fund for the purpose of payments to acute hospitals and community health centers under clause (6) of subsection (b) of section 35 of chapter 118G and any further regulations promulgated by the office.
Chapter 29: Essential Community Provider Trust Fund
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 26 effective November 4, 2012 until January 1, 2013. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Essential Community Provider Trust Fund, in this section called the trust fund. There shall be credited to the trust fund: (a) any funds that may be appropriated or transferred for deposit into the trust fund; and (b) any income derived from investment of amounts credited to the trust fund. In conjunction with the preparation of the commonwealth's annual financial report, the comptroller shall prepare and issue an annual report detailing the revenues and expenditures of the trust fund. The comptroller shall certify payments, including payments during the accounts payable period, in anticipation of revenues, including receivables due and collectibles during the months of July and August, from the trust fund for the purpose of making authorized expenditures. The health safety net office shall administer the trust fund and disburse funds from the trust fund for the purpose of payments to acute hospitals and community health centers under clause (6) of subsection (b) of section 65 of chapter 118E and any further regulations promulgated by the office.
Chapter 29: Essential Community Provider Trust Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Essential Community Provider Trust Fund, in this section called the trust fund. There shall be credited to the trust fund: (a) any funds that may be appropriated or transferred for deposit into the trust fund; and (b) any income derived from investment of amounts credited to the trust fund. In conjunction with the preparation of the commonwealth's annual financial report, the comptroller shall prepare and issue an annual report detailing the revenues and expenditures of the trust fund. The comptroller shall certify payments, including payments during the accounts payable period, in anticipation of revenues, including receivables due and collectibles during the months of July and August, from the trust fund for the purpose of making authorized expenditures. The health safety net office shall administer the trust fund and disburse funds from the trust fund to pay acute hospitals and community health centers under clause (6) of subsection (b) of section 35 of chapter 118G and any further regulations promulgated by the office.
    </text>
</law>