<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>39</section_number>
    <catch_line>Aeronautics Commission; Powers; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>39</order_by>
    <text>
        The commission shall have general supervision and control over aeronautics. 
The commission may provide air transportation for state agencies and officials, provided said agencies or officials pay to the commission the charge established for such service. Said charge shall be set by the commission to equal the hourly operative cost of fuel, hangaring, maintenance, labor, parts, aircraft crew overtime and expenses associated with each flight operation, and the replacement of aircraft equipment. Receipts shall be paid into the state treasury and kept in a separate account and may be expended without further appropriation, for the purposes aforesaid. 
Subject to the approval of the governor, the commission may represent the commonwealth in matters relative to aeronautics before boards, commissions, departments or other agencies of the federal government and other states and international conferences, and before committees of the Congress of the United States. 
For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of sections thirty-five to fifty-two, inclusive, and for the purpose of protecting and insuring the general public interests and safety, and the safety of persons receiving instructions concerning, or operating or using, aircraft and of persons and property being transported in aircraft, and for the purpose of developing and promoting aeronautics within the commonwealth, the commission may perform such acts, may issue and amend such orders and may with the approval of the governor and council, make and amend such reasonable general or special rules and regulations as it deems necessary; provided, however, that such rules and regulations shall not be inconsistent with, or contrary to, any act of the Congress of the United States relating to aeronautics or any regulations promulgated or standards established pursuant thereto. No rule or regulation of the commission shall apply to airports, restricted landing areas, or air navigation facilities owned or operated by the United States within the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>