<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24M</section_number>
    <catch_line>Training For Law Enforcement Personnel Regarding Alcohol Related Offenses;  Alcohol Sensitive Selective Traffic Enforcement Program</catch_line>
    <order_by>24M</order_by>
    <text>
          The officials and agencies designated in this section are hereby directed to perform the duties specified in this section and any other action within their authority in order to ensure effective enforcement of sections twenty-four to twenty-four O, inclusive.  (1) The municipal police training committee established in section one hundred and sixteen of chapter six shall provide training, including but not limited to alcohol education and education concerning the aforesaid sections, to all law enforcement personnel throughout the commonwealth.[ Subparagraph (2) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (2) The chief administrative justice of the trial court department shall provide training, including but not limited to alcohol education and education concerning the aforesaid sections, to all appropriate court personnel throughout the commonwealth, including, but not limited to, judges, district attorneys and probation officers.[ Subparagraph (2) as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 16 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (2) The chief justice of the trial court department shall provide training, including but not limited to alcohol education and education concerning the aforesaid sections, to all appropriate court personnel throughout the commonwealth, including, but not limited to, judges, district attorneys and probation officers.  (3) The courts of the commonwealth shall give priority to the speedy and effective disposition of all matters arising under the aforesaid sections.  (4) The executive office of public safety shall establish and implement an alcohol sensitive selective traffic enforcement program.
    </text>
</law>