<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="128C" order_by="128C" level="3">Simulcast Wagering Of Horse And Dog Racing</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Humane Disposition Of Greyhounds</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 31, 2014. Repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 41. See 2011, 194, Sec. 112. See, also, 2001, 139, Sec. 45 as amended by 2005, 176, Sec. 13; 2006, 54, Sec. 12; 2006, 449, Secs. 19 and 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 12; 2009, 167, Sec. 12; 2010, 203, Sec. 12; 2011, 77, Sec. 12 and 2011, 194, Sec. 84. Expiration of section does not take effect. See 1992, 101, Sec. 13 as amended by 1995, 268, Sec. 20; 1999, 163, Sec. 12; 2000, 354, Sec. 14; 2001, 25, Sec. 1; 2001, 54, Sec. 4; 2001, 70, Sec. 4; 2001, 95, Sec. 4; 2001, 108, Sec. 4; 2001, 121, Sec. 4; 2001, 139, Sec. 39; 2005, 176, Sec. 12; 2006, 54, Sec. 11; 2006, 449, Secs. 18 to 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 11; 2009, 167, Sec. 11; 2010, 203, Sec. 11 and 2011, 77, Sec. 11 and as repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 83. For text effective July 31, 2014, see below.]  No owner, trainer or kennel operator shall cause or permit any racing or retired greyhound to be put to death until reasonable efforts by such owner, trainer, or kennel operator to place such greyhound for adoption with a responsible person or entity have been exhausted. No racing or retired greyhound shall be put to death except in a humane manner. For purposes of this section, the words "in a humane manner'' shall mean by means of euthanasia by lethal injection, or by such other standard of humane killing as may be established by the American Veterinary Medical Association.  The commission shall adopt regulations governing the disposition of all racing greyhounds. For the purposes of this section and said regulations, the word "disposition'' shall mean euthanasia, transfer to another jurisdiction, adoption, or donation or sale for medical research or other purpose. The commission shall maintain accurate records and statistics regarding the disposition of all greyhounds that have participated in dog racing, including schooling races, in the commonwealth. Such records shall include the following information:--  (1) the greyhound's registered name and left and right ear tattoos, the name and address of the greyhound's owner, trainer, and kennel operator at the time of disposition, and the name and address of the race track where the greyhound last raced prior to disposition;  (2) if the greyhound has been transferred to another race track, the name and address of the race track that received the greyhound and the name, business address, telephone number and driver's license number and state of the person who received the greyhound on behalf of the receiving race track;  (3) if the greyhound has been retired for breeding, the name and address of the facility that received the greyhound and the name, business address, telephone number and driver's license number and state of the person who received the greyhound on behalf of the receiving facility;  (4) if the greyhound has been adopted or placed for adoption, the name, address and telephone number of the person or entity that received the greyhound and, if applicable, the name, business address, telephone number and driver's license number and state of the person who received the greyhound on behalf of the adoption facility;  (5) if the greyhound has been euthanized, the name, address, professional title and professional affiliation of the person performing the euthanasia, the manner of euthanasia, and a detailed statement of reasons why the greyhound was euthanized rather than adopted or placed for adoption;  (6) if the greyhound has been sold or donated to an individual, corporation or entity, the name and address of the individual, corporation or entity purchasing or receiving the greyhound, the purpose for which the greyhound is being purchased or received, and the name, business address, telephone number and driver's license number and state of the person who received the greyhound on behalf of the receiving individual, corporation or entity;  (7) if the greyhound's disposition does not fit into any of the above categories, the owner, trainer or kennel operator must state, in detail, the greyhound's destination, the name, business address, telephone number and driver's license number and state of the person who received the greyhound, and the specific purpose for which the greyhound has been received, sold, transferred or donated.  All disposition forms shall be completed and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury by the greyhound's owner, trainer or kennel operator, whose signature shall be witnessed by a designated representative of the state racing commission. Whoever knowingly makes a false written statement on a disposition form shall be punished by imprisonment for up to 2 years and a fine of up to $2,500, or both such fine and imprisonment. A person found guilty of knowingly violating this section for a second or subsequent offense shall be punished by imprisonment for not less than 1, nor more than 5 years, or a fine of not less than $5,000, or both such fine and imprisonment.
Chapter 128C: Thoroughbred and standardbred horse and greyhound dog racing sweepstakes lottery game; development and implementation; regulations for disposition of greyhounds
[ Text of section effective July 31, 2014 does not take effect. See 2011, 194, Secs. 41 and 112. For text effective until July 31, 2014, see above.]  No person licensed by the state racing commission shall put to death, within the commonwealth, a racing greyhound, except in a humane manner. For purposes of this section, the words "in a humane manner'' shall mean by means of euthanasia by lethal injection, or by such other standard of humane killing as may be established by the American Veterinary Association.  The racing commission shall adopt regulations that kennels and other appropriate licensees provide the racing commission with information and other data regarding the dispositions of racing and retired greyhounds. For purposes of this section and such regulations, the word "disposition'', shall mean, euthanasia, transfer to another jurisdiction, or donation for adoption or medical or research purposes. The racing commission shall maintain accurate records and statistics regarding the disposition of all greyhounds who have participated in dog racing, including schooling races, in the commonwealth.  No greyhound licensed by the department of food and agriculture as a Massachusetts-bred greyhound shall be put to death, within the commonwealth, except in a humane manner. For purposes of this paragraph, the words "humane manner'', shall mean, by means of euthanasia by lethal injection or by such other standard of humane killing as may be established by the American Veterinary Medicine Association.  The department of food and agriculture shall adopt regulations requiring owners of Massachusetts-bred greyhounds, or their agents, to provide them with information and other data regarding the disposition of such greyhounds within the commonwealth. For purposes of such regulations, the word "disposition'', shall mean, euthanasia, transfer to another jurisdiction, or donation for adoption or medical research purposes. The department of food and agriculture shall maintain accurate records and statistics regarding the disposition of all Massachusetts-bred greyhounds.  The department of food and agriculture is authorized to certify entities of any kind which provide humane disposition and cremation, or adoption services, including proper implementation of neutering and spaying of all greyhounds prior to adoption, for greyhounds bred for racing who never qualify for pari-mutuel races or for racing greyhounds who have reached the end of their racing career.
    </text>
</law>