<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140D" order_by="140D" level="3">Consumer Credit Cost Disclosure</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Multiple Page Advertisements; Contents; Open End Credit Plan</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purposes of this chapter, or rules or regulations issued thereunder, a catalog or other multiple-page advertisement shall be considered a single advertisement if it clearly and conspicuously displays a credit terms table on which the information required to be stated under this chapter is clearly set forth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No advertisement to aid, promote, or assist directly or indirectly any extension of consumer credit may state:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     That a specific periodic consumer credit amount or installment amount can be arranged, unless the creditor usually and customarily arranges credit payments or installments for that period and in that amount;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That a specified down payment is required in connection with any extension of consumer credit, unless the creditor usually and customarily arranges down payments in that amount.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No advertisement to aid, promote, or assist directly or indirectly the extension of consumer credit under an open-end-credit plan may set forth any of the specific terms of that plan unless it also clearly and conspicuously sets forth all of the following items:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Any minimum or fixed amount which could be imposed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     In any case in which periodic rates may be used to compute the finance charge, the periodic rates expressed as annual percentage rates.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>