<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="30" order_by="30" level="3">General Provisions Relative To State Departments, Commissions, Officers And Employees</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>46C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Management Pay Plan</catch_line>
    <order_by>46C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The following shall be the salary schedule for the management pay plan of the commonwealth: MANAGEMENT SALARY SCHEDULEEffective July 6, 1986(Weekly Rates on Total Cash Basis)
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The increment step provided in the management salary schedule shall be computed in the manner and granted under the following conditions.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Every annual step-rate increase in the salary of any manager of the commonwealth under the management salary schedule set forth in this section shall be initiated by the division of personnel administration, in accordance with said schedule. Notice of the availability of such step-rate salary increase for each manager shall be sent to the appointing authority concerned at least sixty days before such step-rate salary increase would become effective. The said appointing authority shall, in writing to the personnel administrator not later than thirty days before such effective date, certify that upon the basis of the standard performance evaluation system prescribed by the personnel administrator the said manager should be granted such step-rate salary increase. The personnel administrator shall then certify such step-rate salary increases to the comptroller.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     In addition to the annual step-rate salary increase available under the provisions of paragraphs (2) and (3) of this section, a manager may receive an additional step-rate salary increase upon the completion of a program of management training courses as determined by the personnel administrator under the provisions of section twenty-eight A of chapter seven.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     In accordance with the provisions of this section and with regulations established by the personnel administrator with the approval of the commissioner of administration, an appointing authority may, in the initial appointment of a person to a position allocated to the management salary schedule, recruit such person at a rate above the minimum and within the salary range for the job group to which the position is allocated.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5A">
    	     The said administrator shall submit, in writing, to the budget director and the house and senate committees on ways and means a list of positions the incumbents of which have been designated as public health officers in accordance with the provisions of section eight of chapter seventeen. The salaries of such positions shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration on or before June first after recommendation by the personnel administrator, who shall make such recommendation annually on or before May first after having conducted an analysis of salaries for the same or similar types of positions paid by other governments and by private employers with which the commonwealth must compete in securing qualified applicants for such positions. The maximum shall not exceed one hundred and twenty-five per cent of the salary rate set forth at each step-in-range of the management job group to which the positions are allocated in section forty-six C of chapter thirty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     When in accordance with sections forty-five to fifty, inclusive, the position of any manager shall be initially allocated to a job group in the salary schedule, or shall be reallocated to a higher job group, or when in accordance with the said sections any manager shall be transferred or promoted to another position in a different job group, any such manager, for subsequent step-rate increases, shall be credited with the number of years of service which shall correspond to his rate in the job group for such office or position. Any manager reinstated or reemployed, if reinstated or reemployed within three years following his separation from the payroll, shall be credited with the number of years of service which shall correspond to his rate in the job group to which his position at the time of such separation shall then have been allocated; but in no event shall he be paid at a rate lower than that which he shall have been receiving at the time of such separation. Such credit for any manager reinstated or reemployed after three or more years following such separation shall be determined in accordance with rules of the personnel administrator.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Whenever a manager receives a promotion to a position in a higher job group, his rate shall be the next higher rate in said higher job group, or the second next higher rate therein if such new salary rate would result in an increase of salary smaller in amount than the salary increment for such higher job group; provided, however, that if a teacher or supervisor employed in any school or college within any department of the commonwealth is transferred from a position, in which the regular service is rendered from September first to June thirtieth, to a position in which the regular service is rendered for the entire year, he shall be reallocated in the salary schedule from the rate in the salary schedule in effect immediately prior to such transfer to the corresponding step-in-range in the job group which includes the class to which he has been transferred.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     A manager who is demoted to a position in a lower job group shall receive the salary to which his period of service would entitle him if his service had been rendered in such position in the lower job group, but not less than the manager would have been entitled to had his service been continuously in such position in the lower job group.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     No increase in salary shall be effective for any position before the effective date of the appropriation act which includes an appropriation made for the purpose of, and sufficient to cover, the cost of such increase.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     Rates of compensation in the salary schedule are for work hours as provided in section thirty A of chapter one hundred and forty-nine or as otherwise provided by law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     A manager serving on a part-time basis as certified by the appointing authority shall be entitled to the provisions of this chapter in the proportion that his service bears to full time service.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>