<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147" level="3">State And Other Police, And Certain Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>38</section_number>
    <catch_line>Number And Time Of Rounds; Frequency Of Tournaments Or Contests;  Gloves; Protective Devices</catch_line>
    <order_by>38</order_by>
    <text>
        No boxing, kickboxing or other unarmed combative sporting match or exhibition shall exceed 10 rounds; provided, however, if a match is to determine a championship, it may exceed the round limits with the prior approval of the commission. No mixed martial arts match or exhibition shall exceed 3 rounds; provided, however, if a match is to determine a championship, it may exceed the round limits with the prior approval of the commission. No round in a boxing, kickboxing or other unarmed combative sporting match or exhibition shall exceed 3 minutes. No round in a mixed martial arts match or exhibition shall exceed 5 minutes. No contestant in a professional match or exhibition shall participate in more than 10 rounds unless otherwise authorized by the commission, as the case may be, during a 72-hour period. During a contest, contestants in professional boxing and kickboxing matches or exhibitions shall wear gloves weighing at least 8 ounces each unless otherwise authorized by the commission. During a contest, contestants in mixed martial arts and other unarmed combative sporting events, matches or exhibitions shall wear gloves weighing at least 4 ounces each unless otherwise authorized by the commission. Every contestant participating in boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts or other unarmed combative sporting event or exhibition shall be required to wear standard protective devices as outlined by regulation by the commission.
    </text>
</law>