<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7N1/4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Express Warranty By Dealer Of Used Motor Vehicle; Issuance;  Consumer’S Rights And Remedies</catch_line>
    <order_by>7N1/4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     For the purposes of this section the following words shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     (A) (i) No used motor vehicle shall be sold in the commonwealth by a dealer to a consumer unless accompanied by an express written warranty covering the full cost of both parts and labor necessary to repair any defect that impairs the said used motor vehicle’s safety or use; provided, however, that the consumer may be required to pay no more than one hundred dollars total toward the repair of any covered defect, series of defects or combination of defects during the warranty period. Defects that affect only appearance shall not be deemed to impair safety or use for the purposes of this section. For the purposes of this section, defect shall include defect, malfunction or any combination or defects or malfunctions.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     Defects or malfunctions which involve parts or components that are covered or are warranted under an express warranty issued by the dealer of the used motor vehicle shall be excluded from this section if the following conditions have been met: the manufacturer’s warranty has been duly assigned or transferred to the buyer; is enforceable according to its terms; is not inconsistent with this section; and, the seller has assured that the repair authorized by such manufacturer’s express warranty was made.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     The express warranties required by this section shall be of the following durations:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     For a used motor vehicle which, at the time of sale, has been operated less than forty thousand miles, ninety days or three thousand seven hundred and fifty miles, whichever occurs first. Said ninety days or three thousand seven hundred and fifty mile warranty is in addition to any right the consumer may have under section seven N1/2.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     For a used motor vehicle which, at the time of sale, has been operated forty thousand miles or more, but less than eighty thousand miles, sixty days or two thousand five hundred miles, whichever first occur.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     For a used motor vehicle which, at the time of sale, has been operated eighty thousand miles or more, but less than one hundred and twenty-five thousand miles, thirty days or one thousand two hundred and fifty miles, whichever first occur.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     If the used motor vehicle’s true mileage is not known, such warranty period shall be determined by the age of said used motor vehicle in the following manner: a used motor vehicle three years old or less shall have a warranty as provided in clause (i); a used motor vehicle more than three, but less than six years old, shall have a warranty as provided in clause (ii); and a used motor vehicle six years old or more shall have a warranty as provided in clause (iii). A used motor vehicle’s age shall be determined by subtracting its model year from the year in which the warranty holder purchased said used vehicle.
        </section>
        <section prefix="C">
    	     The warranty periods established by this section shall be tolled during any period in which the used motor vehicle is out of service as a result of any repair attempt pursuant to any warranty created by this section. The applicable warranty period shall be extended thirty days from the date of completion of any repair required by this section as to the defect repaired if the warranty would otherwise have expired during such period.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     (A) A dealer may repair, within the meaning of this section, either by performing the repair himself or by arranging and making payment for prompt repair by another.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     A consumer shall return a vehicle for repair under this section by presenting it to the dealer no later than five business days after the expiration of the applicable warranty period and informing him of the defect. Said return period shall be tolled during any time period in which the consumer has notified the dealer of the defect but cannot reasonably present the vehicle to the dealer; including, but not limited to, the reason that a used motor vehicle is inoperable and the dealer refuses to pay the charge to tow said vehicle. The dealer shall immediately accept return of a vehicle when it is so presented. Said used motor vehicle shall be deemed out of service commencing the day it is so presented, notwithstanding any dealer’s failure to accept its return on said day. During the applicable warranty period and the aforesaid return period, the dealer shall pay the reasonable costs of towing from point of breakdown up to thirty miles to obtain required repairs or to return the vehicle to the dealer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     If the dealer fails to repair the same defect within three attempts, or if the used motor vehicle is out of service for more than a cumulative total of ten business days after the consumer has returned it to the dealer for repair of the same, then the dealer shall accept return of the vehicle from the consumer and refund the full repurchase price, less a reasonable allowance for use. A reasonable allowance for use shall be fifteen cents for each mile the used motor vehicle has been operated between its sale and the dealer’s repurchase.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     All dealers shall submit to state-certified, used car arbitration, if such arbitration is requested by the consumer, asserting his or her right to a repurchase under this section, within six months from the date of original delivery to such consumer of a used motor vehicle. State-certified, used car arbitration shall be performed by a professional arbitrator or arbitration firm appointed by the secretary of consumer affairs and business regulation and operating in accordance with the regulations promulgated pursuant to this section, and shall result in a written finding of whether the motor vehicle in dispute meets the standards set forth by this section for vehicles that are required to be repurchased. Said finding shall be issued within forty-five days of receipt by said secretary of a request by a consumer for state-certified arbitration under this section. Said secretary shall promulgate rules and regulations governing the proceedings of state-certified, used car arbitration which shall promote their fairness and efficiency. Such rules and regulations shall include, but not be limited to, a requirement of the personal objectivity of each such arbitrator, and the protection of the right of each party to present its case and to be in attendance during any presentation made by the other party.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     the award was procured by corruption, fraud or other undue means;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     there was evident partiality by an arbitrator or corruption in any of the arbitrators, or misconduct prejudicing the rights of any party; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     the arbitrators exceeded their powers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     At any time within the applicable warranty period and after a consumer has complained of a defect, notwithstanding any objection from the consumer, the dealer shall have the option of repurchasing a used vehicle and refunding the full repurchase price, less a reasonable allowance for use. A reasonable allowance for use shall be fifteen cents for each mile the used motor vehicle had been operated between its sale and the dealer’s repurchase.
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     If the dealer is required to or elects to repurchase a vehicle under the terms of this section, the consumer and dealer shall cooperate with each other to execute all necessary documents in order to clear the title of any encumbrances on the repurchased vehicle.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     It shall be an affirmative defense to any claim under this section that an alleged defect (i) does not impair the vehicle’s use or safety, (ii) is the result of owner negligence, abuse, damage caused by accident, vandalism, or, an attempt to repair the vehicle by a person other than the dealer, the dealer’s designee, or the manufacturer’s representative under clause (ii) of paragraph (A) of subsection (2), (iii) is the result of any attempt by the consumer to modify the vehicle, (iv) was covered or warranted under an express warranty issued by the manufacturer of such used motor vehicle, that such warranty issued by the manufacturer of such used motor vehicle was in effect during the warranty period established by this section, so long as the conditions in said clause (ii) of said paragraph (A) of said subsection (2) are met.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Clear and conspicuous notice of the warranties created by this section, of the rights pertaining thereto, and of the implied warranty of merchantability shall be given to the consumer in writing at the time the consumer purchases a used motor vehicle from the dealer. Failure to provide such notice shall toll the warranty periods under this section until such notice is given.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The secretary of consumer affairs and business regulation shall promulgate rules and regulations to implement the notice provisions of this section. Said rules and regulations shall include the establishment of wording, format, placement, and distribution of all notices specified in this section. In her discretion, and in order to facilitate ease of understanding by consumers, said secretary may consolidate the notices required by this section and any other notices pertaining to the purchase of motor vehicles; provided, however, that such consolidation does not render the notices inconsistent with any of the provisions of this section or any other law. Each notice required by this section shall describe the procedures available to redress violations of this section and shall contain the telephone number of the attorney general’s consumer protection division complaint section and the office of consumer affairs and business regulation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     A dealer’s failure to comply with any of the provisions of this section shall constitute an unfair or deceptive act under the provisions of chapter ninety-three A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary, this section shall not apply to any used motor vehicle sold by a dealer to a consumer for less than seven hundred dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     A private seller shall clearly disclose to any prospective buyer, before the sale is completed, all defects the seller knows of which impair the used motor vehicle’s safety or substantially impair its use. Failure to so disclose known defects shall entitle the buyer, within thirty days after the sale, to rescind the sale and be entitled to return of all monies paid to the seller less a reasonable amount for use as defined in clause (iv) of paragraph (A) subsection (3). In any subsequent action by a buyer under this section, if the court finds that the settlement offer was unreasonable in light of the circumstances or that the private seller has otherwise failed to comply with the requirements of this subsection, in addition to damages, it shall award the buyer reasonable attorneys’ fees and costs; if the court finds that the buyer’s action was frivolous or not in good faith, it shall award the seller reasonable attorneys’ fees and costs. It shall be an affirmative defense in any such action that an alleged defect does not impair the vehicle’s safety, or substantially impair its use, or that it is the result of the buyer’s negligence, abuse, damage caused by accident, vandalism or attempt to modify the vehicle.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     Nothing in this section shall be construed in any way to limit the enforceability of any implied warranties created by law, any rights created by section seven N or seven N1/2, or chapter ninety-three A or any rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, or express warranties given by a dealer in connection with the sale of a used motor vehicle, or any other rights or remedies available to consumers under applicable law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     If a consumer is eligible for relief under the provisions of section seven N1/2, to have repairs effected or other relief provided under the provisions of an express warranty covering such used motor vehicle issued by the manufacturer of such used motor vehicle, said consumer shall make reasonable effort in accordance with the terms and conditions thereof to obtain such relief or repairs before seeking enforcement of rights under this section. If the consumer, notwithstanding his eligibility to do so, is unable to enforce rights under said section seven N1/2 or under such express warranty and the dealer provides such relief or, in accordance with the provisions of this section, repurchases such used motor vehicle, the dealer shall be subrogated to the rights of such consumer against such manufacturer under the provisions of said section seven N1/2, such express warranty and otherwise in accordance with applicable law, and may enforce the same in his name in the superior court or district court department. Such manufacturer shall hold the dealer harmless from and against all damages, liabilities, losses and reasonable expenses of suit, including reasonable attorneys’ fees arising out of or incurred by the dealer by its compliance with the provisions of this section if such manufacturer, having been notified in writing by the dealer that such rights have been asserted by a consumer, fails to resolve the same at its own expense in or within seven business days.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     The licensing authorities responsible pursuant to section fifty-nine of chapter one hundred and forty for licensing used motor vehicle dealers shall distribute copies of this section to each dealer licensed at any time a license is granted or renewed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     The provisions of this section shall not apply to the sale of a leased vehicle by a lessor to the lessee of said vehicle, a family member or employee of said lessee or to the sale of a used motor vehicle by an employer to his employee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     Any action brought pursuant to this section shall be commenced within two years of the date of original delivery of the used motor vehicle to the consumer.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>