<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="3">Department Of Food And Agriculture</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>28</section_number>
    <catch_line>Linked Loan Program; Definitions Applicable To This Section And Sec. 29</catch_line>
    <order_by>28</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purposes of this section and section 29, the following words and phrases shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     There shall be a linked loan program established by the department for the purposes of making linked loans to eligible borrowers. The commissioner shall administer the program and may, in consultation with the secretary of administration and finance, promulgate rules and regulations governing loan applications and the use of program funds for eligible borrowers. In implementing the program, the commissioner shall utilize linked investments with farm credit institutions or linked deposits with other approved commercial bank agricultural lenders. The commissioner shall enter into agreements and place investments with approved lenders to carry out the purposes of the program. The term of the linked investment and linked loan shall be for a period of not more than 4 years. The commissioner shall have the discretion to determine the amount of the loan available to an eligible borrower but no linked loan shall exceed $500,000. The total amount available for the linked loan program shall not exceed $25,000,000 over the life of the program. The commissioner shall disseminate information regarding the linked loan program to eligible borrowers.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>