<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="5" order_by="5" level="3">Printing And Distribution Of Laws And Public Documents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Printing And Distribution Of General Court Manual</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. Repealed by 2012, 165, Sec. 10. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  The clerks of the two branches shall in every odd-numbered year prepare a manual for the general court, of which not more than ten thousand five hundred copies shall be printed under their direction. These copies shall be delivered to the state secretary and by him distributed, so far as the edition will permit, as follows:  To the clerk of each branch of the general court, fifty;  To the assistant clerk of each branch of the general court, thirty;  To the counsel to each branch of the general court, four;  To each member of the general court, five, and upon written application an additional number, not exceeding twenty;  To the governor, the lieutenant governor, and the members of the executive council, five each and, upon written application an additional number, not exceeding fifteen;  To the George Fingold Library, two hundred;  To the private secretary to the governor, the senators and representatives in congress from the commonwealth, the justices, clerks and registers of courts, such assistant clerks of courts as the state secretary may designate, the reporter of decisions, district attorneys, county commissioners, county treasurers, registers of deeds, medical examiners, sheriffs, city and town clerks, Harvard University and all incorporated colleges within the commonwealth, the Massachusetts Historical Society, the New England Historic Genealogical Society, the Boston Athenaeum, the American Antiquarian Society in Worcester, such free public libraries and branches thereof in the commonwealth as the state secretary may designate, and to such other free public libraries in the commonwealth making written application therefor, county law libraries, all incorporated law libraries in the commonwealth and branch libraries maintained by them, and to veteran organizations having headquarters in the state house, one, each;  To associate and special justices, assistant clerks of courts not otherwise provided for, and to reporters entitled to the privileges of the reporters' gallery in either branch of the general court, upon written application, one, each;  To the state secretary and his deputies, the state treasurer and his deputies, the state auditor and his deputies, the attorney-general and his assistants, the commissioner and associate commissioners of each state department, the director of each state division established by statute, the chairman of each state board and commission, and to each institution under the supervision of the state departments of correction, education, mental health, developmental services, public health and public welfare, one, each;  To the state secretary for distribution not otherwise provided for, fifty;  Three hundred copies to the sergeant-at-arms to be reserved under the direction of the clerks of both branches for the use of the general court at its next annual session and three hundred copies for the use of the next succeeding general court.  After making the foregoing distribution or making provision therefor, the state secretary shall place copies of the manual on sale to the general public at a price not less than the cost thereof, as determined by the committees on rules of the senate and house of representatives. After December thirty-first of each even-numbered year copies of the manual remaining on hand may be distributed by the state secretary without charge.
    </text>
</law>