<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="128C" order_by="128C" level="3">Simulcast Wagering Of Horse And Dog Racing</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Regulations Governing Humane Care, Treatment And Transportation Of Racing Greyhounds;  License Suspension Or Revocation</catch_line>
    <order_by>7B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 31, 2014. Repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 41. See 2011, 194, Sec. 112. See, also, 2001, 139, Sec. 45 as amended by 2005, 176, Sec. 13; 2006, 54, Sec. 12; 2006, 449, Secs. 19 and 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 12; 2009, 167, Sec. 12; 2010, 203, Sec. 12; 2011, 77, Sec. 12 and 2011, 194, Sec. 84. Expiration of section does not take effect. See 1992, 101, Sec. 13 as amended by 2001, 139, Sec. 39; 2005, 176, Sec. 12; 2006, 54, Sec. 11; 2006, 449, Secs. 18 and 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 11; 2009, 167, Sec. 11; 2010, 203, Sec. 11 and 2011, 77, Sec. 11 and as repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 83.]  The commission shall adopt regulations governing the humane handling, care, treatment, and transportation of racing greyhounds. The regulations shall include minimum requirements for the handling, housing, feeding, watering, sanitation, ventilation, adequate veterinary care, exercise, and shelter of racing greyhounds, and safety of track surface and banking to prevent injury.  If the commission has reason to believe that any person who is licensed by the commission or who is affiliated with any person, corporation, partnership, trust or any combination of the same or other entity which owns, operates, holds any interest in any race track or other facility which operates pari-mutuel racing of greyhounds, or is licensed to operate such a facility pursuant to section 3 of chapter 128A, violates any provision of this section, or any of the rules or regulations promulgated by the racing commission under this section, the commission may suspend such person's license, and, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, may revoke such license if such violation is determined to have occurred.
    </text>
</law>