<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>178A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Victims; Certification To Receive Information</catch_line>
    <order_by>178A</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until May 4, 2012. For text effective May 4, 2012, see below.] 
A victim of crime, witness, or family member of a homicide victim, all as defined by section one of chapter two hundred and fifty-eight B, shall be certified by the board, upon request, to receive criminal offender record information, provided that the request for said information relates to the offense in which such person was involved. Criminal justice agencies may also disclose to such persons such additional information, including but not limited to evaluative information, as such agencies determine, in their discretion, is reasonably necessary for the security and well being of such persons. 
Chapter 6: Right of victim of crime, witness or family member of homicide victim to obtain criminal offender record information of person accused or convicted; disclosure of other information by criminal justice agencies [Text of section as amended by 2010, 256, Sec. 37 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102. For text effective until May 4, 2012, see above.] 
A victim of crime, witness or family member of a homicide victim, all as defined by section 1 of chapter 258B, may obtain all available criminal offender record information of the person accused or convicted of said crime. Criminal justice agencies may also disclose to such persons such additional information, including, but not limited to, evaluative information, as such agencies determine is reasonably necessary for the security and well being of such persons.
    </text>
</law>