<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="62F" order_by="62F" level="3">Limitation On The Growth Of State Tax Revenues</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
          For the purposes of this chapter the following definitions apply:  "Allowable State Tax Revenues'' means for any fiscal year beginning after June 30, 1986 an amount equal to the computed maximum state tax revenues, as defined herein, for said fiscal year. Provided, however, that if the computed maximum state tax revenues for a fiscal year are less than the amount of allowable state tax revenues for the immediately preceding fiscal year, then allowable state tax revenues for said fiscal year shall be equal to the allowable state tax revenues for the immediately preceding fiscal year. Provided further, that only for the fiscal year ending on June 30, 1986, allowable state tax revenues for said fiscal year shall be equal to the net state tax revenues for said fiscal year.  "Allowable State Tax Growth Factor'' for a fiscal year means a number which equals one-third of the sum derived by adding together for each of the three calendar years ending immediately prior to said fiscal year the quotients which result for each of said calendar years from dividing total Massachusetts wages and salaries for each of said calendar years by total Massachusetts wages and salaries for the calendar year immediately preceding each of said calendar years. Provided, however, that in calculating the allowable state tax growth factor for any fiscal year, the same total for Massachusetts wages and salaries for a calendar year utilized in prior calculations involving said calendar year shall be utilized in subsequent calculations involving said calendar year, notwithstanding periodic adjustments by the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the United States Department of Commerce made in total Massachusetts wages and salaries for said calendar year.  "Commissioner'' means the Commissioner of Revenue as defined in section four (a) of chapter seven of the general laws.  "Computed Maximum State Tax Revenues'' means for any fiscal year beginning after June 30, 1986 an amount determined by multiplying the computed maximum state tax revenues for the immediately preceding fiscal year by the allowable state tax growth factor, as defined herein, for the then current fiscal year. Provided, however, that only for the fiscal year ending on June 30, 1986, computed maximum state tax revenues for said fiscal year shall be equal to the net state tax revenues for said fiscal year.[ Definitions of "Cumulative net state tax revenues'' and "Cumulative permissible tax revenues'' effective until January 1, 2013. Deleted by 2012, 165, Sec. 117. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  "Cumulative net state tax revenues,'' the sum of the net state tax revenues collected in each quarter of the fiscal year, year-to-date.  "Cumulative permissible tax revenues,'' the sum of the permissible tax revenues for each quarter of the fiscal year, year-to-date.  "Excess State Tax Revenues'' means the amount by which net state tax revenues, as defined herein, for a fiscal year exceed the allowable state tax revenues, as defined herein, for said fiscal year.  "Local Governmental Unit'' means any city, town, county, district or other political subdivision of the Commonwealth.  "Massachusetts Wages and Salaries'' means the most current data on annual wages and salaries of citizens of the Commonwealth for the most recently completed calendar year as compiled by the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the United States Department of Commerce, or its successor agency.  "Net State Tax Revenues'' means state tax revenues, as defined herein, as decreased by the amount of state tax revenues abated or refunded.[ Definitions of "Permissible revenue growth rate'' and "Permissible tax revenue'' effective until January 1, 2013. Deleted by 2012, 165, Sec. 117. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  "Permissible revenue growth rate'', growth rate of two percent over the rate of inflation. For this purpose, the rate of inflation shall be the percent increase in the implicit price deflator for state and local government purchases during the most recent twelve-month period for which data is available but shall not be less than 0 per cent.  "Permissible tax revenue,'' for any quarter or year, an amount equal to the cumulative net state tax revenues of the same period in the immediately preceding fiscal year, multiplied by the sum of one plus the permissible revenue growth rate.  "State Tax Revenues'' means the revenues of the Commonwealth from every tax, surtax, receipt, penalty and other monetary exaction, and interest in connection therewith, including but not limited to, taxes and surtaxes on personal income, excises and taxes on retail sales and use, meals, motor vehicle fuels, businesses and corporations, public utilities, alcoholic beverages, tobacco, inheritances, estates, deeds, room occupancy and pari-mutuel wagering; but excluding federal reimbursements, proceeds from bond issues, earnings on investments, tuitions, fees, service charges and other departmental revenues, and revenues directly attributable to the additional taxes levied pursuant to section eighty-eight of chapter six hundred and eighty-four of the Acts of nineteen hundred and seventy-five.  "Taxable Year'' means the taxable year as defined in the Internal Revenue Code of the United States as from time to time amended.
    </text>
</law>