<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7C" order_by="7C" level="3">Capital Asset Management And Maintenance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>47</section_number>
    <catch_line>Public Notice Requirements For Contracts For Designer Services</catch_line>
    <order_by>47</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 165, Sec. 82 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  (a) Each contract for designer services for a project subject to the jurisdiction of the board shall be publicly advertised by the board in a newspaper of general circulation in the area in which the project is located or to be located, and in the central register established under section 20A of chapter 9, and in such places as the board requires by regulation, at least 2 weeks before the deadline for filing applications; provided, however, that each contract for designer services for a project whose estimated cost of construction is not less than $10,000 nor more than $25,000 shall not be required to be advertised in a newspaper of general circulation but shall be required to be advertised in the central register.  (b) The public notice required by subsection (a) shall contain:  (i) a description of the project, including the specific designer services sought, the time period within which the project is to be completed, and, if available, the estimated construction cost;  (ii) if there is a program for the project, a statement of when and where the program will be available for inspection for applicants, and when and where a briefing session will be held for applicants, if one is required by the board's regulations and if there is not a program for the project, a statement to the effect;  (iii) the qualification required of applicants for the projects;  (iv) the categories of designers' consultants, if any, for which applicants must list the names of consultants which the applicant may choose to use; and  (v) whether the fee has been set or will be negotiated, and if the fee has been set, the amount of the fee.
    </text>
</law>