<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87XX1/2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Continuing Education; Certification Of Course Completion</catch_line>
    <order_by>87XX1/2</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person holding a license as a real estate broker or salesman, which is subject to renewal on or after January first, nineteen hundred and ninety-nine, shall, within twenty-four months prior to each renewal, satisfactorily complete courses or programs of instruction approved by the board; provided, that for licenses renewed on or before December thirty-first, two thousand, the attendance at such courses or programs of instruction shall be equal to a total of twelve hours; and provided, further, that for licenses renewed on or after January first, two thousand and one, such number shall be no less than six hours but no more than twelve hours as determined by the board. The curriculum contained in such courses or programs shall contain at least six hours of instruction concerning or related to compliance with laws and regulations selected from any of the following subjects: fair housing; equal employment opportunity; accessibility for the disabled; agency law; environmental issues in real estate; zoning and building codes; real estate appraisal and financing; property tax assessments and valuation; and real estate board regulations. The board shall certify in advance the curriculum forming the basis of such courses or programs which satisfy the provisions of this section. 
Every person who is subject to the requirements of this section shall furnish, in a form satisfactory to the board, written certification that the required courses or programs were successfully completed. Upon successful completion of approved courses or programs, the licensee shall be deemed to have met the continuing education requirements of this section for license renewal. Every person who fails to furnish, in a form satisfactory to the board, written certification that the required courses or programs were completed shall be granted inactive status by the board upon renewal of his license in accordance with section eighty-seven XX. 
Any person failing to meet requirements imposed upon him by this section or who has submitted to the board a false or fraudulent certificate of compliance therewith, shall, after a hearing thereon, which hearing may be waived by such person, be subject to the suspension of his license until such time as such person shall have demonstrated to the satisfaction of the board that he has complied with all the requirements of this section as well as with all other laws, rules and regulations applicable to such licensing. 
The provisions of this section shall not apply to any person licensed by the board under the provisions of section eighty-seven SS who is not required to take an examination to be licensed; provided, however, that any out-of-state licensee who receives reciprocity from the board to practice in the commonwealth shall demonstrate to the board compliance with a continuing education program in such licensee’s home state. 
The provisions of this section shall not apply to any person licensed by the board who has been granted inactive status by the board. A person licensed by the board and whose license is inactive may not engage in the business of, or act as, a real estate broker or salesman, as defined in section eighty-seven PP, except that he may assist with or direct the procuring of prospects and may receive referral fees for such procurement activities. A person licensed by the board whose license is inactive shall be considered unlicensed for purposes of section eighty-seven RR. Engaging in the business of, or acting as, a real estate broker or salesman while a license is inactive, except as otherwise provided for in this section, may be grounds for revocation of such license. A person licensed by the board and whose license is inactive shall renew such license in accordance with section eighty-seven XX while such license is inactive. A person licensed by the board and whose license is inactive may apply to the board to reactivate such license, upon demonstration of the completion of the continuing education requirements for the renewal period immediately preceding the application for reactivation of such license and compliance with all then applicable requirements for licensure. 
The board shall perform such duties and functions necessary to carry out the provisions of this section and shall promulgate rules and regulations pertaining to the development and administration of an inactive license designation. Such rules and regulations shall include, but not be limited to, developing procedures for the granting of inactive status, the reactivation of licenses, renewal fees and the notification of licensees of continuing education requirements prior to license reactivation.
    </text>
</law>