<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Lessors Of Motorcycles; Licensing</catch_line>
    <order_by>32H</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall engage in the business of leasing motorcycles without being licensed by the registrar for such purpose. No such license shall be issued unless the registrar is satisfied from an investigation of the facts that the applicant is a proper person to engage in such business and that he has a place of business suitable for such purpose. A separate license shall be secured for each place of business where a person conducts a business of leasing motorcycles. Application for a license under this section may be filed with the registrar and contain such information as he shall prescribe. Each such application shall be accompanied by an application fee which shall in no event be refunded. If an application is approved by the registrar, the applicant upon payment of an additional fee shall be granted a license, which shall be valid for a period of one year from the date of its issuance and shall be renewed annually. Such fees shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven. The registrar shall issue a license certificate to each licensee, which certificate shall be conspicuously displayed in the place of business of the licensee. 
Any original license may be suspended or revoked by the registrar for cause and any renewed license may be so suspended or revoked for cause occurring during the two years next preceding the date of such renewed license, after a hearing, due notice of which shall be mailed to the licensee at his last known address at least ten days prior to the date of said hearing. 
The registrar may prescribe such rules and regulations as he may deem necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, and may provide that any violation thereof shall be punishable by a fine not to exceed twenty-five dollars. 
Every licensee shall keep such records as the registrar may by regulation require, and he shall keep the records required by and be subject to the provisions of sections thirty-two C, thirty-two D and thirty-two E, and lessees of motorcycles shall be subject to the provisions of sections thirty-two C, thirty-two E and thirty-two F. 
The commissioner of public safety, the police commissioner in Boston, the chief of police of any other city, the selectmen of a town or any police officer authorized by any of said officials, or any person having police powers under section twenty-nine may at any time enter upon any premises used as the place of business of a licensee under this section, to ascertain how he conducts the same, and examine all records and vehicles used in connection with the licensed business. 
Whoever engages in the business of leasing motorcycles without being licensed, shall be punished by a fine of not less than twenty-five dollars nor more than two hundred fifty dollars, or by imprisonment for not less than thirty days nor more than six months, or both.
    </text>
</law>