<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>96</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration Of Home Inspectors; Members</catch_line>
    <order_by>96</order_by>
    <text>
        There is hereby established within the division of professional licensure, a board of registration of home inspectors. Said board shall consist of five members to be appointed by the governor for terms of three years. The members so appointed shall be residents of the commonwealth, three of whom shall be licensed home inspectors who have been actively engaged in the practice of home inspection in the commonwealth for at least five years immediately preceding their appointment and who shall have performed not less than 1,000 home inspections for compensation, one of whom shall be a licensed home inspector who has been actively engaged in the practice of home inspection in the commonwealth for at least five years immediately preceding his appointment and who has performed not less than 150 home inspections for compensation and one of whom shall be a consumer who shall be the owner and principal resident of a residential building. All board members shall be subject to the provisions of chapter 268A. 
Of the initial members appointed to said board, two shall serve for terms of three years, two shall serve for terms of two years and one shall serve for a term of one year. Each member of said board shall hold office until his successor has been qualified. A vacancy in the membership of the board shall be filled for the unexpired term in the manner provided for the original appointment. No member shall serve more than two consecutive terms which shall not include any unexpired term to which he has been appointed. A member may be removed by the governor for cause. 
Said board shall annually elect from among its members, by majority vote, a chairman and vice-chairman. Said board shall meet at least once every three months and may hold additional meetings as necessary to discharge its duties. Members shall receive no compensation but shall be entitled to reasonable travel expenses.
    </text>
</law>