<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35CC</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Military Family Relief Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35CC</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until May 31, 2012. For text effective May 31, 2012, see below.]  There shall be an expendable trust, to be known as the Massachusetts Military Family Relief Fund, the purpose of which is to help members of the Massachusetts National Guard and Massachusetts residents who are members of the reserves of the armed forces of the United States and who were called to active duty after September 11, 2001, and their families, to defray the costs of food, housing, utilities, medical services, and other expenses. The fund shall consist of revenues received by the commonwealth under the provisions of section 6K of chapter 62, from public and private sources as gifts, grants, and donations to further the purposes of the fund. Revenues credited to the fund under this section shall remain in the fund, not subject to appropriation, for application to those purposes and for expenses related to the administration of the fund; provided, however, that said administrative expenses shall not exceed $75,000 annually. The state treasurer shall not deposit the revenues in, or transfer the revenues to, the General Fund or any other fund other than the Massachusetts Military Family Relief Fund. The state treasurer shall deposit monies in the fund in accordance with sections 34 and 34A of chapter 29 in such manner as will secure the highest interest rate available consistent with safety of the fund and with the requirement that all amounts on deposit be available for immediate withdrawal at any time. Revenues received for the Military Family Relief Fund shall be directly paid to the Friends of Massachusetts National Guard and Reserve Families by the military division through the established expendable trust.
Chapter 10: Massachusetts Military Family Relief Fund
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 108, Sec. 4 effective May 31, 2012. For text effective until May 31, 2012, see above.]  There shall be an expendable trust, to be known as the Massachusetts Military Family Relief Fund, the purpose of which is to help members of the Massachusetts National Guard and Massachusetts residents who are members of the reserves of the armed forces of the United States and who were called to active duty after September 11, 2001, and their families, including immediate family members of certain active duty members of the armed forces who were killed in action, to defray the costs of food, housing, utilities, medical services, and other expenses. The fund shall consist of revenues received by the commonwealth under the provisions of section 6K of chapter 62, from public and private sources as gifts, grants, and donations to further the purposes of the fund. Revenues credited to the fund under this section shall remain in the fund, not subject to appropriation, for application to those purposes and for expenses related to the administration of the fund; provided, however, that said administrative expenses shall not exceed $75,000 annually. The state treasurer shall not deposit the revenues in, or transfer the revenues to, the General Fund or any other fund other than the Massachusetts Military Family Relief Fund. The state treasurer shall deposit monies in the fund in accordance with sections 34 and 34A of chapter 29 in such manner as will secure the highest interest rate available consistent with safety of the fund and with the requirement that all amounts on deposit be available for immediate withdrawal at any time. Revenues received for the Military Family Relief Fund shall be directly paid to the Friends of Massachusetts National Guard and Reserve Families by the military division through the established expendable trust.
    </text>
</law>