<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>295G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Standards For Gasoline; Adulteration Or Substitution Of Motor Fuel Or Lubricating Oil</catch_line>
    <order_by>295G</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall sell or offer to sell as gasoline any motor fuel or other substance which has an end point higher than four hundred and thirty-seven degrees Fahrenheit, when tested according to such standard methods as may, from time to time, be prescribed by order, rule or regulation under section two hundred and ninety-five I. 
No person shall adulterate or permit the adulteration of any motor fuel or automotive lubricating oil offered for sale or sold under a brand name or trade-mark or distinguishing mark of the manufacturer or distributor of said products, or substitute or permit the substitution of any other motor fuel or automotive lubricating oil therefor. No person shall sell or dispense, or offer to sell or dispense, from any pump, tank or other dispensing device or container any motor fuel or automotive lubricating oil other than that indicated by the name, trade name, trade-mark, symbol, sign or other distinguishing mark of the manufacturer or distributor of said product, if any, appearing on said pump, tank or other dispensing device or container. 
Every manufacturer or distributor of motor fuel or automotive lubricating oil shall submit samples of said products when requested by the division. 
No person shall sell or offer to sell any automotive lubricating oil for automotive purposes which does not conform with the viscosity classification marked on the container, such classification to be determined according to such standard methods as the division may from time to time prescribe. 
No person shall sell or offer to sell as diesel motor fuel, any motor fuel or other substance which does not conform to standard specifications for diesel motor fuel when tested according to standard methods of testing. Such standard specifications and standard methods of testing may be prescribed by order, rule or regulation promulgated under the provisions of section two hundred and ninety-five I.
    </text>
</law>