<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="101" order_by="101" level="3">Transient Vendors, Hawkers And Pedlers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>33</section_number>
    <catch_line>Temporary Licenses To Sell Articles For Charitable Purposes; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>33</order_by>
    <text>
        The selectmen in a town or in a city such board or officer as may be designated by ordinance may, under such conditions as they may deem proper, grant to any organization engaged exclusively in charitable work, or to a post of any incorporated organization of veterans who served in the military or naval service of the United States in time of war or insurrection, a special license authorizing it, upon a particular day and for a charitable purpose named in such license, to sell, through its accredited agents in the streets and other public places within such city or town, or in any designated part thereof, flags, badges, medals, buttons, flowers, souvenirs, and similar small articles; provided, that no person under sixteen years of age shall be accredited as such agent, that each agent shall wear in plain sight while engaged in selling such articles a badge, provided by such organization or post and approved by the authority issuing the license, bearing upon it the name of such organization or post and the date on which the license is to be exercised, and that no such agent shall be authorized to make or attempt to make such sales in front of any private premises against the objection of the owner or occupant thereof. The exercise of the licenses hereby provided for shall be subject to the provisions of all statutes, ordinances, by-laws, rules and regulations not inconsistent herewith. The fee for such a license shall be established in a town by town meeting action and in a city by city council action, and in a town with no town meeting by town council action, by adoption of appropriate by-laws and ordinances to set such fees, but in no event shall any such fee be greater than ten dollars.
    </text>
</law>