<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40L" order_by="40L" level="3">Agricultural Incentive Areas</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Agricultural Incentive Area Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        The board of selectmen in a town or the mayor of a city with approval of the city council may establish an agricultural incentive area committee for the purpose of investigating, delineating, and establishing an agricultural incentive area in the municipality, hereinafter called area. 
Said committee shall consist of seven members appointed by the board of selectmen or by the mayor with the approval of the city council. Said members shall include one member of the board of selectmen or city council, one member of the planning board, one member of the conservation commission, three residents of the municipality whose principal occupation is agriculture or horticulture and one person from the public at large. 
Each member shall serve for a term of three years, except that in the initial appointments two members shall serve for a term of one year, three members shall serve for a term of two years and two members shall serve for a term of three years. 
Any member of said committee so appointed may, after a public hearing if requested, be removed for cause and a new member appointed by the appointing authority. 
All members of the committee shall serve without compensation. 
The committee shall elect annually a chairman and vice-chairman from its own members and a secretary who need not be a member of the committee. The committee shall hold an annual meeting in March and from time to time at the call of the chairman or upon the request of any two members. Four members of the committee shall constitute a quorum. The committee may, by a vote of a majority of its members then in office, adopt rules and regulations for the conduct of its business. Rules and regulations adopted may be amended or repealed by a two-thirds vote of its members.
    </text>
</law>