<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>160</section_number>
    <catch_line>Killing Dogs Which Have Worried Or Killed Stock Or Fowl;  Bond</catch_line>
    <order_by>160</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  The county commissioners of any county, the mayor of any city, the selectmen of any town, or their agents thereto authorized in writing, may, after written notice to the owner or keeper, enter upon the premises of the owner or keeper of any dog known to them to have worried or killed live stock or fowls, and then and there kill such dog, unless such owner or keeper whose premises are thus entered for the said purpose shall give a bond in the sum of two hundred dollars, with sufficient sureties, approved by the county commissioners, conditioned that the dog shall be restrained for twelve months next ensuing. And if the owner or keeper of the dog declares his intention to give such a bond, said selectmen, chief of police or county commissioners, as the case may be, or his or their agents, shall allow him seven days, exclusive of Sundays and holidays, in which to procure and prepare the same and to present it to them, or to file it with the clerk of the town where the said owner or keeper resides.
Chapter 140: Euthanizing dogs that have worried or killed stock or fowl; bond
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 32 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  The mayor of a city, the selectmen of a town, or their agents who are authorized in writing, to act in such mayor or selectmen's stead may, after written notice to the owner or keeper of a dog, enter upon the premises of the owner or keeper known to such persons to have worried or killed livestock or fowl and then and there euthanize such dog in a humane manner unless such owner or keeper whose premises are entered for that purpose shall give a bond in the sum of $200, with sufficient sureties, conditioned that the dog shall be restrained for 12 months next ensuing. If the owner or keeper of the dog declares an intention to give such a bond, the selectmen, chief of police, or the agent of the selectmen or chief, as the case may be, shall allow the owner or keeper 7 days, exclusive of Sundays and holidays, in which to procure and prepare such bond and to present it, or to file it with the clerk of the town or city in which the owner or keeper resides.
    </text>
</law>