<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Public Markets; Establishment; Conditions; Regulation</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        A city, or a town having a population of not less than ten thousand, may provide and maintain one or more public markets, with suitable buildings and grounds, and for this purpose may acquire land by gift or purchase or lease the same, with or without buildings, and may make alterations in buildings and construct new buildings on land so acquired or leased. Any city or town which does not so maintain a public market shall upon a petition signed by not less than five per cent of its voters designate one or more streets or squares or other public places, suitably situated and approved by the department of agriculture, to be used by farmers as public market places. Such a petition shall be filed with the city or town clerk, and he shall determine whether it contains a sufficient number of signatures and whether such signatures are genuine, and when satisfied that the petition meets the requirements of this section, he shall so certify to the mayor or the chairman of the board of selectmen and shall also notify the commissioner of agriculture that the petition has been filed and state to him the date of filing. Any city or town which maintains a public market or market place in accordance with this section may, subject to the approval of the commissioner of agriculture, make rules and regulations for the management and use thereof, and may prescribe penalties for their violation, and may also designate a market master, who may be a police officer or other municipal officer or employee, and who shall have charge of such markets or market places and shall conduct them in the interest of the market men and their customers, shall enforce said rules and regulations, and shall maintain order within the market limits.
    </text>
</law>