<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="54" order_by="54" level="3">Elections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>64</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notices Or Warrants; Requisites; Time Of Opening And Closing Polls</catch_line>
    <order_by>64</order_by>
    <text>
        Notices or warrants for state and city elections and for the election of town officers in towns where official ballots are used shall specify by name all the offices to be voted for, and state, in the form in which it will appear upon the ballot, any question submitted to the voters. They shall specify the time when the polls will be opened, and in cities and in towns when voting by precincts, when the polls will be closed, and in towns when not voting by precincts, when they may be closed. 
The polls shall in no case be kept open after eight o’clock in the evening. At state elections the polls shall not be closed before eight o’clock in the evening. 
In cities and towns at the election of state officers, the polls may be open as early as fifteen minutes before six o’clock in the forenoon, and shall be open not later than seven o’clock in the forenoon and shall be kept open at least thirteen hours. In cities at the election of city officers, the polls may be open as early as fifteen minutes before six o’clock in the forenoon, and shall be open not later than ten o’clock in the forenoon and shall be kept open at least ten hours. 
In towns, at the election of town officers, the polls may be opened as early as fifteen minutes before six o’clock in the forenoon, and shall be opened as early as twelve o’clock, noon, and shall be kept open at least four hours, and until the time specified in the warrant when they may or will be closed; and in towns not voting by precincts they may be kept open for such longer time as the meeting shall direct. The selectmen in any town may provide that the hours during which the polls shall be open for the purpose of voting on a question to be submitted to the voters of said town shall be the same as the hours designated by said selectmen for the election of town officers. After an announcement has been made by the presiding officer of a time so fixed for closing the polls they shall not be closed at an earlier hour.
    </text>
</law>