<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Investigation By Commissioner; Business Records; Records Of Investigation; Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>24D</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The commissioner may investigate the collection records of a licensee or registrant, and for that purpose the commissioner shall have free access to the books and papers of a licensee or registrant relating thereto. A licensee or registrant shall keep and use the business records in such form and at such location as the commissioner, by regulation, shall determine, which shall enable the commissioner to determine whether the licensee or registrant is complying with this chapter and rules or regulations promulgated hereunder by the commissioner and any other law, rule or regulation applicable to the conduct of the business for which it is licensed or registered under this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commissioner shall preserve a full record of each examination of a licensee including a statement of its condition. All records of investigations and reports of examinations by the commissioner, including workpapers, information derived from the reports or responses to the reports, and any copies thereof in the possession of a licensee under the supervision of the commissioner, shall be confidential and privileged communications, shall not be subject to subpoena and shall not be made public. For the purposes of this subsection, records of investigation and reports of examinations shall include records of investigation and reports of examinations conducted by a financial regulatory agency of the federal government and any other state, and of a foreign government which are considered confidential by the agency or foreign government and which are in possession of the commissioner. In a proceeding before a court, the court may issue a protective order in appropriate circumstances to protect the confidentiality of the record and order that the record on file with the court or filed in connection with the court proceeding be sealed and that the public be excluded from any portion of the proceeding at which the record is disclosed. Copies of the reports of examination shall be furnished to a licensee for its use only and shall not be exhibited to any other person, organization or agency without prior written approval by the commissioner. The commissioner may furnish to regulatory agencies of the federal government, or other states, or of foreign countries, and a law enforcement agency, information, reports and statements relating to the licensees under his supervision as he considers appropriate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     If a licensee or registrant violates sections 24 to 25, inclusive, or fails to maintain its financial condition sufficient to qualify for a license on an original application or for other just cause as the commissioner may determine, the commissioner may, after notice and hearing pursuant to the provisions of chapter 30A, revoke a license or registration or suspend the license or registration for a period as he considers proper.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>