<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111H" order_by="111H" level="3">Massachusetts Low Level Radioactive Waste Management Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19</section_number>
    <catch_line>Site Selection Process; Procedures</catch_line>
    <order_by>19</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The site selection process conducted pursuant to sections twenty and twenty-three shall be in accordance with the procedures set forth in this section. The recommendations of the public participation coordinator, made pursuant to section six, shall be implemented to the extent feasible in order to ensure appropriate public participation in the site selection process; to ensure that adequate information concerning the site selection process is available; to facilitate the conduct of public meetings and other opportunities for public review and comment; and to ensure that public concerns are identified and addressed throughout the site selection process.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     In accordance with the regulations adopted under section four, the board shall retain such consultants as it determines are necessary to complete the site selection process.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Each notice required by section twenty or twenty-three to be given to the chief executive officer of a community shall, at a minimum, explain in detail all actions taken pursuant to sections eleven to seventeen, inclusive, and those actions completed pursuant to section twenty or twenty-three, as well as the remaining actions to be undertaken pursuant to section twenty, twenty-three or twenty-four, and offer the resources of the board and the public participation coordinator to assist communities in participation in the site selection process.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>