<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>60</section_number>
    <catch_line>Urban Center Housing Tax Increment Financing Zone (Uch Tif)</catch_line>
    <order_by>60</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, a city or town by vote of its town meeting, town council or city council with the approval of the mayor where required by law, on its own behalf or in conjunction with 1 or more cities or towns and under regulations issued by the director of housing and community development, in consultation with the department of economic development and the department of revenue, may adopt and prosecute an urban center housing tax increment financing plan, in this section referred to as a UCH-TIF plan, intended to encourage increased residential growth, affordable housing and commercial growth in urban center housing zones and do all things necessary thereto; provided, however, that the UCH-TIF plan shall:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     designate any area of the city or town as an urban center housing tax increment financing zone, in this section referred to as a UCH-TIF zone, which shall be defined as a commercial center characterized by a predominance of commercial land uses, a high daytime or business population, a high concentration of daytime traffic and parking and a need for multi-unit residential properties; provided, however, that the designation of a UCH-TIF zone shall be subject to the approval of the department of housing and community development under regulations adopted by the department consistent with this section; provided further, that a city or town may not enter into any UCH-TIF agreement, as defined in clause (v), unless the area governed by the UCH-TIF agreement is so designated and approved by the department of housing and community development; and provided further, that in the case of a UCH-TIF plan adopted by more than 1 city or town, the areas designated as UCH-TIF zones shall be contiguous areas of those cities and towns;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     describe in detail all construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation and related activities, public and private, contemplated for such UCH-TIF zone as of the date of the adoption of the UCH-TIF plan; provided, however, that in the case of public construction as aforesaid, the UCH-TIF plan shall include a detailed projection of the costs and a betterment schedule for the defrayal of such costs; provided further, that the UCH-TIF plan shall provide that no costs of such public constructions shall be recovered through betterments or special assessments imposed on a party which has not executed a UCH-TIF agreement in accordance with clause (v); and provided, further, that in the case of private construction as aforesaid, the UCH-TIF plan shall include the types of affordable housing and residential and commercial growth which are projected to occur within such UCH-TIF zone, with documentary evidence of the level of commitment therefor including, but not limited to, architectural plans and specifications as required by the regulations;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     authorize tax increment exemptions from property taxes, under clause Fifty-first of section 5 of chapter 59, for a specified term not to exceed 20 years, for any parcel of real property which is located in the UCH-TIF zone and for which an agreement has been executed under clause (v); provided, however, that the UCH-TIF plan shall specify the level of exemptions expressed as exemption percentages, not to exceed 100 per cent to be used in calculating the exemptions for the parcel, and for personal property situated on that parcel, as provided under said clause Fifty-first of said section 5 of said chapter 59; provided, further, that the exemption for each parcel of real property shall be calculated using an adjustment factor for each fiscal year of the specified term equal to the product of the inflation factors for each fiscal year since the parcel first became eligible for such exemption under this clause; provided, further, that the inflation factor for each fiscal year shall be a ratio:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the numerator of which, shall be the total assessed value of all parcels of all residential real estate that are assessed at full and fair cash value for the current fiscal year minus the new growth adjustment factor for the current fiscal year attributable to the residential real estate as determined by the commissioner of revenue under paragraph (f) of section 21C of said chapter 59; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the numerator of which, in a UCH-TIF zone where the property includes a mix of residential and commercial uses, shall be the total assessed value of all parcels of all residential and commercial real estate that are assessed at full and fair cash value for the current fiscal year minus the new growth adjustment factor for the current fiscal year attributable to the residential and commercial real estate as determined by the commissioner of revenue under said paragraph (f) of said section 21C of said chapter 59; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the denominator of which shall be the total assessed value for the preceding fiscal year of all the parcels included in the numerator; provided, however, that such ratio should not be less than 1.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     establish a maximum percentage of the costs of any public construction, referenced in clause (ii) and initiated subsequent to the adoption of the UCH-TIF plan, that can be recovered through betterments or special assessments against real property eligible for tax increment exemptions from property taxes under clause (iii) during the period of the parcel’s eligibility for exemption from annual property taxes under said clause Fifty-first of said section 5 of said chapter 59, notwithstanding chapter 80 or any other general or special law authorizing the imposition of betterments or special assessments;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     include executed agreements, hereinafter referred to as UCH-TIF agreements, between a city and town and each owner of real property which is located in a UCH-TIF zone, but each such agreement shall include, but not be limited to, the following: (1) all material representations of the parties which served as a basis for the descriptions contained in the UCH-TIF plan in accordance with clause (ii) and which served as a basis for the granting of a UCH-TIF exemption; (2) any terms deemed appropriate by the city or town relative to compliance with the UCH-TIF agreement including, but not limited to, what shall constitute a default by the property owner and what remedies shall be allowed between the parties for any such defaults, including an early termination of the agreement; (3) provisions requiring that either 25 per cent of the housing units assisted by the UCH-TIF agreement shall be affordable to occupants or families with incomes at or below 80 per cent of the median income for the area in which the city or town is located as defined by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development or such other requirement of affordable housing as is necessary to achieve financial feasibility for the development pursuant to regulations and guidelines promulgated by the department of housing and community development; (4) provisions stating that housing units that meet the affordability requirements of subclause (3) shall subject to use restrictions as defined in this section; (5) provisions stating that the property shall be subject to an option to purchase and a right of first refusal as defined in subsections (c) and (d); (6) a detailed recitation of the tax increment exemptions and the maximum percentage of the cost of public improvements that can be recovered through betterments or special assessments regarding a parcel of real property pursuant to clauses (iii) and (iv); (7) a detailed recitation of all other benefits and responsibilities inuring to and assumed by the parties to an agreement; and (8) a provision that the agreement shall be binding upon subsequent owners of the parcel of real property; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     delegate to a board, agency or officer of the city or town, the authority to execute agreements in accordance with clause (v).
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     An executed UCH-TIF agreement shall be submitted by the applicable city or town to the department of housing and community development for the approval of the director; provided, however, that the city or town shall, if it has not previously done so, submit a plan showing the boundaries of its urban center housing zone and a report explaining the criteria used by the city or town in establishing the zone; provided, however, that the director shall review each UCH-TIF plan and agreement to determine whether they comply with the terms of this section and any regulations which may be adopted by the director of housing and community development; provided further, that the director shall certify, based upon the information submitted in support of the UCH-TIF plan by the city or town and through such additional investigation as the director shall make, that the plan and agreement are consistent with the requirements of this section and will further the public purpose of encouraging increased residential growth, affordable housing and commercial growth in the commonwealth; provided further, that a city or town may, at any time, revoke its designation of a UCH-TIF zone and, as a consequence of such revocation, shall immediately cease the execution of any additional agreements under clause (v) of subsection (a); provided, further, that a revocation shall not affect agreements relative to property tax exemptions and limitations on betterments and special assessments under said clause (v) of said subsection (a) or use restrictions or options to purchase and rights of first refusal required by this section which were executed before the revocation; provided further, that the board, agency, or officer of the city or town authorized under clause (vi) of said subsection (a) to execute agreements shall forward to the board of assessors a copy of each such agreement, together with a list of the parcels included therein; and provided further, that an executed and approved UCH-TIF shall be recorded in the registry of deeds or the registry district of the land court wherein the land lies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Notwithstanding any other general or special law to the contrary, an affordable housing unit benefiting from a real estate tax exemption under this section that meets the affordability requirements of subclause (3) of clause (v) of subsection (a) shall continue to meet those requirements for 40 years or for its useful life, whichever is longer as may be specified in the recorded restriction. Such restriction shall be approved by the department of housing and community development in accordance with section 32 of chapter 184 and shall be recorded in the registry of deeds or the registry district of the land court wherein the land lies. Upon the expiration of such restrictions, the department of housing and community development or its assignee shall have an option to purchase the property subject to or previously subject to a UCH-TIF agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     (1) Within 120 days after the expiration of the affordability restrictions created under this section, the department or its assignee, who shall be a qualified developer selected pursuant to the terms of this section under the guidelines of the department, shall have an option to purchase the property at its current appraised value reduced by any remaining obligation of the owner. Two impartial appraisers shall determine, within 60 days after the expiration of the affordability restrictions, the current appraised value in accordance with recognized professional standards. Two professionals in the field of multi-unit residential housing shall select each such appraiser. The owner and the department, respectively, shall each designate 1 professional within 30 days after the expiration of the affordability restrictions. If there exists a difference in the valuations provided by the appraisals, the 2 valuations shall be added together and divided by 2 to determine the current appraised value of the property.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Prior to a sale or transfer or other disposition of housing assisted under this section where the department has not previously exercised an option to purchase, an owner shall offer the department or its assignee, who shall be a qualified developer selected under this section under the guidelines of the department, a first refusal option to meet a bona fide offer to purchase the property. The owner shall provide to the department or its assignee written notice, by regular and certified mail, return receipt requested, of his intention to sell, transfer or otherwise dispose of the property. The department or its assignee shall hold a first refusal option for the first 120 days after receipt of the owner’s notice of intent to transfer the property. Failure to respond to the written notice of the owner’s intent to sell, transfer or otherwise dispose of the property within 120 days after the receipt of the notice shall constitute a waiver of the right of first refusal by the department.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     No sale, transfer or other disposition of the land shall be consummated until either the first refusal option period has expired or the owner was notified in writing by the department or assignee in question that the option will not be exercised. Such option may be exercised only by written notice signed by a designated representative of the department or its assignee, mailed to the owner by certified mail at such address as may be specified in his notice of intention and recorded with the registry of deeds or the registry district of the land court of the county in which the affected real property is located, within the option period. If the first refusal option has been assigned to a qualified developer selected under this section under guidelines issued by the department, such written notice shall state the name and address of the developer and the terms and conditions of the assignment. An affidavit before a notary public that the notice of intent was mailed on behalf of the owner shall conclusively establish the manner and time of the giving of the notice, but the affidavit, and the notice that the option will not be exercised shall be recorded with the registry of deeds or the registry district of the land court of the county in which the affected real property is located. Each notice of intention, notice of exercise of the option and notice that the option will not be exercised shall contain the name of the record owner of the land and description of the premises to be sold or converted adequate for identification thereof. Each such affidavit before a notary public shall have attached to it a copy of the notice of intention to which it relates. The notices of intention shall be deemed to have been duly mailed to the parties above specified if addressed to them in care of the keeper of records for the party in question.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Upon notifying the owner in writing of its intention to pursue its first refusal option during such 120-day period, the department or its assignee shall have an additional 120 days, beginning on the date of the termination of the first refusal option period, to purchase the property. The time periods may be extended by mutual agreement between the department or its assignee and the owner of the property; provided, however, that any such extension agreed upon shall be recorded in the registry of deeds or the registry district of the land court of the county in which the affected real property is located. Within a reasonable time after request, the owner shall make available to the department or its assignee any information, which is reasonably necessary for the department to exercise its rights. The department or its assignee may purchase or acquire the property only for the purposes of preserving or providing affordable housing; provided, however, that such housing shall remain affordable for not less than 40 years. Such use restrictions shall be recorded in the registry of deeds or the registry district of the land court wherein the land lies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The owner of property subject to a UCH-TIF plan shall certify to the city or town the income of the families or occupants, upon initial occupancy, of the affordable housing units designated in the UCH-TIF agreement and such certification shall be provided to the department on an annual basis. If the owner fails to provide certification or otherwise fails to comply with the UCH-TIF agreement, including failing to maintain the affordability of housing units assisted under this section, the city or town may place a lien on the property in the amount of the real estate tax exemptions granted pursuant to the UCH-TIF agreement for any year in which the owner is not in compliance with this subsection. If the city or town determines, with the approval of the department of housing and community development, that the owner is unlikely to come into compliance with the affordability requirements of subclause (3) of clause (v) of subsection (a), the city or town may place a lien on the property in the amount of the total real estate tax exemption granted pursuant to the UCH-TIF agreement. Any such lien shall be recorded in the registry of deeds or the registry district of the land court wherein the land lies.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>