<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>66</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing Of Cold Storage Warehouses; Report Of Articles In Cold Storage</catch_line>
    <order_by>66</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall maintain a cold storage or refrigerating warehouse without a license issued by the department of public health. Any person desiring such a license may make written application to such department, stating the situation of his plant. Upon receipt of the application the said department shall cause an examination of the sanitary condition of the plant to be made, and if it is found to be in a sanitary condition and otherwise properly equipped for the business of cold storage, said department upon receipt of a license fee, as determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, shall cause a license to be issued authorizing the applicant to maintain therein a cold storage or refrigerating warehouse for one year. If any warehouse or any part thereof, licensed under this section, is deemed by said department to be conducted in an unsanitary manner, it shall close such warehouse or part thereof, until it has been put in sanitary condition, and said department may also suspend the license if the required changes are not made within a reasonable time. Each such licensee shall submit to the department of public health on or before the fifteenth day of each month, a report on a printed form to be provided by said department, stating the quantities of articles of food placed in cold storage during the month preceding, and also the quantities of articles of food held on the first day of the month in which the report is filed or such other day as the commissioner of public health may from time to time fix.
    </text>
</law>