<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="61A" order_by="61A" level="3">Assessment And Taxation Of Agricultural And Horticultural Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Allowance Or Disallowance Of Application For Valuation; Notice; Liens</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        An application for valuation, assessment and taxation of land under the provisions of this chapter shall be allowed or disallowed by the board of assessors of the city or town in which such land is located within three months of the filing thereof. An application for valuation, assessment and taxation of land under the provisions of this chapter shall be disallowed by the board of assessors of the city or town in which such land is located if, in their judgment such land, in whole or in part, does not qualify thereunder. If any board of assessors shall determine that any application pursuant to this chapter is submitted for the purpose of evading payment of full and proper taxes, such board shall be and hereby is authorized to disallow such application. The failure of a board of assessors to allow or disallow any such application within three months following the filing thereof, shall be deemed an allowance of such application. The board of assessors shall, within ten days of an allowance, or disallowance, send written notice of such allowance, or disallowance, by certified mail to the landowner applicant and shall set forth therein the reason or reasons for disallowance together with a statement advising the landowner of his right to appeal therefrom as provided in section nineteen. In the case of a partial disallowance, the landowner shall be permitted to file an amendment to the original application. 
With respect to the first application relating to a parcel of land which has been approved, and any subsequent such applications after a lapse of time when such land has not been valued, assessed and taxed under this chapter or after a change of record ownership of such land, the board of assessors shall forthwith cause to be recorded in the registry of deeds of the county or district in which the city or town is situated a statement of their action which shall constitute a lien upon the land covered by such application for such taxes as may be levied under the provisions of this chapter. The statement shall name the owner or owners of record and shall include a description of the land adequate for identification. Unless such a statement is recorded the lien shall not be effective with respect to a bona fide purchaser or other transferee without actual knowledge of such lien. Upon application by any record owner, such liens shall be released by the board of assessors with respect to any parcel of land as provided below in this section upon the applicable facts being established by their records or by affidavits or otherwise. 
All liens for special assessments or betterment assessments under section eighteen shall be released in full or in part upon its being so established that any such assessment or portion of such assessment which have become due have been paid. 
All liens for conveyance tax under section twelve, shall be released upon its being so established that no conveyance or change of use by the owner at the time of such release will result in a conveyance tax under said section twelve or that any such taxes which have become due have been paid. 
All liens for roll-back taxes under section thirteen, other than roll-back taxes based on change of use after the date of such release, shall be released upon its being so established that no roll-back taxes have become due or that any such taxes which have become due have been paid. 
The board of assessors shall also have the power and authority to release any such liens to correct any errors or omissions. Any release under this section shall be recorded with the registry of deeds. 
When any land which has been valued, assessed and taxed under this chapter ceases to be so valued, assessed and taxed the board of assessors shall forthwith record in the registry of deeds a statement to that effect which shall include the name of the record owner or owners, the date when such land ceased to be so valued, assessed and taxed and a description of the land adequate for identification. 
All recording fees paid pursuant to the provisions of this chapter whether for statements of liens, certificates, releases or otherwise shall be borne by the owner of record of the land.
    </text>
</law>