<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Distinctive Registration Plates; Environmental Trust Fund; Child Care Quality Fund; 9/11 Victims And Military Heroes Funds</catch_line>
    <order_by>2E</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The registrar shall furnish, upon application, to the owners of private passenger motor vehicles three distinctive registration plates, one of which shall be on the theme of the right whale, one of which shall be on the theme of the Blackstone Valley of the central part of the commonwealth, and the other on a theme representative of the environmental and natural resources of the western part of the commonwealth; provided, however, that the design of the plate themes shall be determined by the trustees of the Environmental Trust Fund, established by section seven of chapter two hundred and thirty-six of the acts of nineteen hundred and eighty-eight, in consultation with and subject to the approval of said registrar and, in the case of the Blackstone Valley plate, in consultation with the Blackstone Valley National Heritage Corridor Commission. There shall be a fee of not less than twenty dollars for such plates in addition to the established registration fee for private passenger motor vehicles, such fee being payable at the time of registration of such vehicle and at each renewal thereof. The portion of the total fee remaining after the deduction of costs directly attributable to the issuance of such plates shall be deposited in said Environmental Trust Fund.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The registrar shall furnish, upon application, to the owners of private passenger motor vehicles distinctive registration plates which shall display on their face a design indicating support for the children of the commonwealth and the words “Invest in Children”. There shall be a fee of not less than twenty dollars for such plates in addition to the established registration fee for private passenger motor vehicles, such fee being payable at the time of registration of such vehicle and at each renewal thereof. The portion of the total fee remaining after the deduction of costs directly attributable to the issuance of such plates shall be deposited within ninety days of receipt thereof in the Child Care Quality Fund established by section 2GG of chapter twenty-nine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The registrar shall furnish, upon application, to the owners of private passenger motor vehicles distinctive registration plates which shall display on their face a design with the image of the American flag and the words “United We Stand” to commemorate the victims and heroes of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attack and the Massachusetts Military heroes from United States military Operations Enduring Freedom, Iraqi Freedom and Noble Eagle. There shall be a fee of not less than $40 for such plates in addition to the established registration fee for private passenger motor vehicles, which shall be payable at the time of registration of such vehicle and at each renewal thereof. The portion of the total fee remaining after the deduction of the costs directly attributable to the issuance of such plates shall be deposited in a registry retained revenue account and of the remaining portion of such fee, 50 per cent shall be directed to the Massachusetts 9/11 Fund, Inc. and distributed by such fund at its discretion for the benefit of the relatives of the Massachusetts victims of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attack on America; 25 per cent shall be directed to the Massachusetts Military Heroes Fund, Inc. and distributed by such fund at its discretion for the benefit of the families of military service personnel from Massachusetts killed while in service to the United States as a result of, or in support of, Operations Enduring Freedom, Iraqi Freedom or Noble Eagle; and 25 per cent shall be deposited in the Commonwealth Security Trust Fund established in section 67 of chapter 10. In the event the Massachusetts 9/11 Fund, Inc. has met its obligations to design, construct and maintain a memorial to the victims of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attack on America, any funds not necessary for the continued maintenance of the memorial shall be made available to the Massachusetts 9/11 Fund, Inc. and distributed by such fund at its discretion for the benefit of the relatives of the Massachusetts victims of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attack on America.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>