<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>81J</section_number>
    <catch_line>Roster Of Registered Professional Engineers And Professional Land Surveyors</catch_line>
    <order_by>81J</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     As a professional engineer:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A person holding a certificate or registration to engage in the practice of engineering, issued to him by a proper authority of a state, commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any foreign country, who, in the opinion of the board, meets the requirements of this chapter, based on verified evidence may, upon application, be registered without further examination.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A graduate of an engineering curriculum of four years or more approved by the board as being of satisfactory standing; and with a specific record of an additional four years or more of experience in engineering work of a grade and character which indicates to the board that the applicant may be competent to practice engineering, and who passes or has passed the required written examination in the fundamentals of engineering, and the required written examination in the principles and practice of engineering. The board may require that the above experience in engineering work be completed prior to admission to the examination in the principles and practice of engineering. Should the board permit the examination to be taken at an earlier date, then the applicant may be required to pass an oral examination as determined by the board. Upon passing such examinations, the applicant shall be granted a certificate of registration to practice engineering in the commonwealth, provided he is otherwise qualified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     An applicant, having satisfactorily completed a four-year college curriculum in engineering or in related science other than the ones approved by the board and eight years or more of progressive experience in engineering work of a character and grade which indicates to the board that the applicant may be competent to practice engineering, and who passes or has passed the required written examination in the fundamentals of engineering designed to show knowledge and skill approximating that obtained through graduation in an approved four-year engineering curriculum, and the required written examination in the principles and practice of engineering, shall be granted a certificate of registration to practice engineering in the commonwealth, provided he is otherwise qualified; provided, however, where an applicant is permitted by the board to be admitted to the examination in the principles and practice of engineering prior to completion of the above experience, the board may require that the applicant pass an oral examination as determined by the board before issuing a certificate of registration.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     An applicant having completed twelve years or more of progressive experience in engineering work of a character and grade, including five years or more in responsible charge of engineering work, which indicates to the board that the applicant may be competent to practice engineering, and who passes or has passed the required written examination in the fundamentals of engineering designed to show basic engineering knowledge and skill and the required written examination in the principles and practice of engineering and an oral examination when required by the board may be granted a certificate of registration to practice engineering in the commonwealth, provided he is otherwise qualified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     An applicant, with a specific record of at least twenty years of lawful practice in engineering work, of which at least ten years have been in responsible charge of important engineering work, and of a grade and character which indicates to the board that the applicant may be competent to practice engineering and who has passed an oral or written examination in the principles and practice of engineering, and is otherwise qualified, shall be registered to practice engineering in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Undergraduate study in an engineering curriculum approved by the board as being of satisfactory standing may be considered as engineering experience on an equivalent full-time basis up to a maximum of three years in computing the number of years of experience in engineering work in clauses (d) and (e) of this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Engineering teaching in a college or university offering an approved engineering curriculum of four years or more may be considered as engineering experience.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     As a professional land surveyor:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A person holding a bachelor of science degree in an approved curriculum and presenting evidence satisfactory to the board that, in addition thereto, he has had at least four years of combined office and field experience in land surveying with a minimum of three years’ experience in responsible charge of land surveying projects under the supervision of a registered professional land surveyor and who has passed the oral and written examinations as required by the board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A person holding two years of formal education in an approved curriculum above high school level with at least sixty semester credit hours passed or equivalent quarter-hours, or the equivalent approved by the board, and presenting evidence satisfactory to the board that in addition thereto he has had at least six years of combined office and field experience in land surveying with a minimum of four years’ experience in responsible charge of land surveying projects under the supervision of a registered professional land surveyor and who has passed the oral and written examinations as required by the board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A person who has a specific record of twelve years or more of lawful practice in surveying work of a character satisfactory to the board and who passes the required written examinations, which shall include questions on laws, procedures and practices pertaining to practices in the commonwealth, and passes an oral examination at the discretion of the board may be granted a certificate of registration to practice surveying provided he is otherwise qualified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A person holding a certificate of registration to engage in the practice of land surveying issued on comparable qualifications from a state, commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, will be given comity consideration. However, he may be asked to take such examinations as the board deems necessary to determine his qualifications, but in any event he shall be required to pass the required written examination of not less than four hours’ duration, which shall include questions on laws, procedures and practices pertaining to practice in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Undergraduate study in a surveying curriculum approved by the board as being of satisfactory standing may be considered as surveying experience on an equivalent full-time basis up to a maximum of two years in computing the number of years of experience in surveying work in clauses (b) and (c) of this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A person, with a record of at least twenty years of lawful practice in land surveying work, of which at least ten years he has been responsible for major land surveying work, of a grade and character which indicates to the board that the person may be competent to practice land surveying and who has passed an oral or written examination in the principles and practice of land surveying, and is otherwise qualified, shall be registered to practice land surveying in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The board shall certify persons who have passed written or oral examinations and shall specify the nature and type of the examination passed in such certification.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A graduate of an approved engineering curriculum of four years or more who has passed the board’s eight-hour written examination in the fundamentals of engineering shall be certified or enrolled as an engineer-in-training, if he is otherwise qualified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     An applicant having satisfactorily completed a four-year college curriculum in engineering or in related science other than the ones approved by the board and a specific record of four or more years of experience in engineering work of grade and character satisfactory to the board, who passes the board’s eight-hour written examination in the fundamentals of engineering shall be certified or enrolled as an engineer-in-training, if he is otherwise qualified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A graduate of an approved land surveying curriculum of four years or more who has had in addition thereto at least two years of combined office and field experience in land surveying, with a minimum of one year in responsible charge of land surveying procedures under the supervision of a registered professional land surveyor, and who has passed the written examinations required by the board shall be certified or enrolled as a land surveyor-in-training, if he is otherwise qualified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     An applicant having at least two years of formal education in an approved curriculum above high school level with at least sixty semester credit hours passed, or equivalent quarter-hours, or the equivalent approved by the board, and who presents evidence satisfactory to the board that in addition thereto he has had at least four years of combined office and field experience in land surveying with a minimum of two years in responsible charge of land surveying projects under the supervision of a registered professional land surveyor, and who has passed the written examinations required by the board shall be certified or enrolled as a land surveyor-in-training, if he is otherwise qualified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     All of the examinations above required may be taken during the period of formal education or subsequently either prior to or following completion of the required experience. Upon completion of required experience, the board shall then certify the applicant as an engineer-in-training or a land surveyor-in-training.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>