<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>202</section_number>
    <catch_line>Signature On, Record, Contents And Term Of Licenses; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>202</order_by>
    <text>
        Licenses granted elsewhere than in Boston to dealers in junk, old metals and second hand articles, junk collectors, pawnbrokers and keepers of billiard saloons, pool or sippio rooms or tables, bowling alleys, roller skating rinks, carousels, inclined railways, Ferris wheels, outdoor exhibitions of fire fighting for the amusement of the public and picnic groves shall be signed by the clerk of the city or town where they are granted. Every such license shall, before being delivered to the licensee, be recorded by such clerk, in a book kept for that purpose. Such license shall set forth the name of the licensee, the nature of the business, and the building or place in such city or town in which it is to be carried on, and shall continue in force until May first following unless sooner revoked. The board or officer issuing such a license shall, except as provided in section seventy-seven, receive for the use of the city or town such amount, not less than two dollars for each license, as the board or officer considers reasonable. In Boston licenses for billiard saloons, pool or sippio rooms or tables, bowling alleys and picnic groves shall be signed by the licensing board and recorded by its clerk and licenses for roller skating rinks, carousels, inclined railways, Ferris wheels and outdoor exhibitions of fire fighting for the amusement of the public shall be signed by the mayor and recorded by his clerk; the other licenses referred to in this section shall be signed by the police commissioner and recorded by his clerk.
    </text>
</law>