<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="128" order_by="128" level="3">Agriculture</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Liability Of Persons Involved In Equine Activities</catch_line>
    <order_by>2D</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     in instructing a participant or renting to a participant an equine for the purpose of riding, driving or being a passenger upon the equine; (2) in renting equipment or tack to a participant; (3) to provide daily care of horses boarded at an equine facility; or (4) to train an equine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The propensity of equines to behave in ways that may result in injury, harm, or death to persons on or around them; (2) the unpredictability of an equine’s reaction to such things as sounds, sudden movement, and unfamiliar objects, persons, or other animals; (3) certain hazards such as surface and subsurface conditions; (4) collisions with other equines or objects; (5) the potential of a participant to act in a negligent manner that may contribute to injury to the participant or others, such as failing to maintain control over the animal or not acting within his ability.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Except as provided in subsection (c), an equine activity sponsor, an equine professional, or any other person, which shall include a corporation or partnership, shall not be liable for an injury to or the death of a participant resulting from the inherent risks of equine activities and, except as provided in said subsection (c), no participant nor participant’s representative shall make any claim against, maintain an action against, or recover from an equine activity sponsor, an equine professional, or any other person for injury, loss, damage, or death of the participant resulting from any of the inherent risks of equine activities.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     This section shall not apply to the racing meetings as defined by section one of chapter one hundred and twenty-eight A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     (i) provided the equipment or tack, and knew or should have known that the equipment or tack was faulty, and such equipment or tack was faulty to the extent that it did cause the injury; or (ii) provided the equine and failed to make reasonable and prudent efforts to determine the ability of the participant to engage safely in the equine activity, and determine the ability of the participant to safely manage the particular equine based on the participant’s representations of his ability;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     owns, leases, rents, has authorized use of, or is otherwise in lawful possession and control of the land, or facilities upon which the participant sustained injuries because of a dangerous latent condition which was known to the equine activity sponsor, equine professional, or person and for which warning signs, pursuant to subsection (d), have not been conspicuously posted;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     commits an act of omission that constitutes willful or wanton disregard for the safety of the participant, and that act of omission caused the injury; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     intentionally injures the participant.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The signs and contracts described in paragraph (1) shall contain the following notice:
        </section>
    </text>
</law>