<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40B" order_by="40B" level="3">Regional Planning</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Committee; Membership; Appointment; Term; Removal;  Vacancies</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        Twenty-one persons residing within the district shall be appointed to an advisory committee for the purpose of providing advice and guidance to said commission and said persons shall be representative of business, labor, professional and civic organizations and other economic interests within the district. Nine members shall be appointed by the director of economic development with the approval of the governor, and twelve members shall be appointed by the commission. Of the initial appointees of the director of economic development, three shall be appointed for a term of one year, three for a term of two years and three for a term of three years. Of the initial appointees of said commission, four shall be appointed for a term of one year, four for a term of two years and four for a term of three years. Upon the expiration of a term of a member of the advisory committee or upon written resignation, his successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of three years, or for the balance of the unexpired term. A member may be removed and a vacancy declared by majority vote of the advisory committee at a regular meeting thereof, consequent upon three consecutive absences from regular advisory committee meetings, and his successor shall be appointed in like manner as the original appointment for the balance of the unexpired term. Each member of said advisory committee shall continue to serve as such until his successor is appointed and qualified. The commission shall, in its by-laws, provide appropriate procedures for the referral of problems, issues and policies for deliberation by the advisory committee.
    </text>
</law>