<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Examiners Of Electricians;  Membership;  Appointment And Term;  Executive Secretary;  Compensation And Expenses</catch_line>
    <order_by>32</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The state examiners of electricians, hereinafter, called the board, shall consist of the state fire marshal, the associate commissioner for the division of occupational education in the department of education, ex officiis, and eight persons to be appointed for terms of three years each by the governor. One of said appointees shall be a representative of the public, subject to the provisions of section nine B and one shall be a local wiring inspector who is an electrician licensed under chapter one hundred and forty-one. Six of said appointees shall be citizens of the commonwealth: one of whom shall be a master electrician who holds a certificate A license issued under said chapter one hundred and forty-one and has at least ten years experience as an employing master electrician; one shall be a master electrician who holds certificate A and certificate B licenses issued under said chapter one hundred and forty-one, is actively engaged in such business and has at least ten years experience as an employing master electrician; one shall be a journeyman electrician who holds a certificate B license issued under said chapter one hundred and forty-one, is a wage earner and has at least ten years practical experience in the installation of wires and appliances for carrying electricity for light, heat or power purposes; one shall be a systems contractor who holds a certificate C license issued under said chapter, is actively engaged in the business of fire warning and security systems as his principal business and has at least ten years experience as an employing systems contractor; one shall be a systems technician who holds a certificate D license issued under said chapter, is a wage earner and has at least ten years practical experience in the installation, repair and maintenance of systems; and one shall be a representative of the New England The state fire marshal shall be chairman. The board shall appoint an executive secretary who shall be a wage earner, a citizen of the commonwealth, and a practical electrician of at least ten years' experience in such installation. The board may also appoint, subject to chapter thirty-one, such other clerical and technical assistants as may be necessary to discharge its duties under chapter one hundred and forty-one and shall establish their duties. The members, ex officiis, shall receive no compensation for their services under chapter one hundred and forty-one, but the appointive members shall each receive for their services thereunder a salary of seven hundred and fifty dollars. The board may expend for the salaries of the appointive members and of the secretary and other employees and for necessary traveling and other expenses for themselves and their employees such sums as are annually appropriated therefor.
Chapter 13: State examiners of electricians; membership; appointment and term; executive secretary; compensation and expenses
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Secs. 37 and 38 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The state examiners of electricians, hereinafter, called the board, shall consist of the state fire marshal, the associate commissioner for the division of occupational education in the department of education, ex officiis, and 9 persons to be appointed for terms of three years each by the governor. One of said appointees shall be a representative of the public, subject to the provisions of section nine B and one shall be a local wiring inspector who is an electrician licensed under chapter one hundred and forty-one. One of the appointees shall be a vocational-technical electrical educator or administrator, who shall be selected from a group of 3 nominees, to be nominated by the Massachusetts Association of Vocational Administrators. Six of said appointees shall be citizens of the commonwealth: one of whom shall be a master electrician who holds a certificate A license issued under said chapter one hundred and forty-one and has at least ten years experience as an employing master electrician; one shall be a master electrician who holds certificate A and certificate B licenses issued under said chapter one hundred and forty-one, is actively engaged in such business and has at least ten years experience as an employing master electrician; one shall be a journeyman electrician who holds a certificate B license issued under said chapter one hundred and forty-one, is a wage earner and has at least ten years practical experience in the installation of wires and appliances for carrying electricity for light, heat or power purposes; one shall be a systems contractor who holds a certificate C license issued under said chapter, is actively engaged in the business of fire warning and security systems as his principal business and has at least ten years experience as an employing systems contractor; one shall be a systems technician who holds a certificate D license issued under said chapter, is a wage earner and has at least ten years practical experience in the installation, repair and maintenance of systems; and one shall be a representative of the New England The state fire marshal shall be chairman. The board shall appoint an executive secretary who shall be a wage earner, a citizen of the commonwealth, and a practical electrician of at least ten years' experience in such installation. The board may also appoint, subject to chapter thirty-one, such other clerical and technical assistants as may be necessary to discharge its duties under chapter one hundred and forty-one and shall establish their duties. The members, ex officiis, shall receive no compensation for their services under chapter one hundred and forty-one, but the appointive members shall each receive for their services thereunder a salary of seven hundred and fifty dollars. The board may expend for the salaries of the appointive members and of the secretary and other employees and for necessary traveling and other expenses for themselves and their employees such sums as are annually appropriated therefor.
    </text>
</law>