<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="30A" order_by="30A" level="3">State Administrative Procedure</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23</section_number>
    <catch_line>Enforcement Of Open Meeting Law; Complaints; Hearing; Civil Action</catch_line>
    <order_by>23</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Subject to appropriation, the attorney general shall interpret and enforce the open meeting law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     At least 30 days prior to the filing of a complaint with the attorney general, the complainant shall file a written complaint with the public body, setting forth the circumstances which constitute the alleged violation and giving the body an opportunity to remedy the alleged violation; provided, however, that such complaint shall be filed within 30 days of the date of the alleged violation. The public body shall, within 14 business days of receipt of a complaint, send a copy of the complaint to the attorney general and notify the attorney general of any remedial action taken. Any remedial action taken by the public body in response to a complaint under this subsection shall not be admissible as evidence against the public body that a violation occurred in any later administrative or judicial proceeding relating to such alleged violation. The attorney general may authorize an extension of time to the public body for the purpose of taking remedial action upon the written request of the public body and a showing of good cause to grant the extension.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Upon the receipt of a complaint by any person, the attorney general shall determine, in a timely manner, whether there has been a violation of the open meeting law. The attorney general may, and before imposing any civil penalty on a public body shall, hold a hearing on any such complaint. Following a determination that a violation has occurred, the attorney general shall determine whether the public body, 1 or more of the members, or both, are responsible and whether the violation was intentional or unintentional. Upon the finding of a violation, the attorney general may issue an order to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     compel immediate and future compliance with the open meeting law;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     compel attendance at a training session authorized by the attorney general;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     nullify in whole or in part any action taken at the meeting;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     impose a civil penalty upon the public body of not more than $1,000 for each intentional violation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     reinstate an employee without loss of compensation, seniority, tenure or other benefits;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     compel that minutes, records or other materials be made public; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     prescribe other appropriate action.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A public body or any member of a body aggrieved by any order issued pursuant to this section may, notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, obtain judicial review of the order only through an action in superior court seeking relief in the nature of certiorari; provided, however, that notwithstanding section 4 of chapter 249, any such action shall be commenced in superior court within 21 days of receipt of the order. Any order issued under this section shall be stayed pending judicial review; provided, however, that if the order nullifies an action of the public body, the body shall not implement such action pending judicial review.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     If any public body or member thereof shall fail to comply with the requirements set forth in any order issued by the attorney general, or shall fail to pay any civil penalty imposed within 21 days of the date of issuance of such order or within 30 days following the decision of the superior court if judicial review of such order has been timely sought, the attorney general may file an action to compel compliance. Such action shall be filed in Suffolk superior court with respect to state public bodies and, with respect to all other public bodies, in the superior court in any county in which the public body acts or meets. If such body or member has not timely sought judicial review of the order, such order shall not be open to review in an action to compel compliance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     As an alternative to the procedure in subsection (b), the attorney general or 3 or more registered voters may initiate a civil action to enforce the open meeting law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     It shall be a defense to the imposition of a penalty that the public body, after full disclosure, acted in good faith compliance with the advice of the public body’s legal counsel.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Payment of civil penalties under this section paid to or received by the attorney general shall be paid into the general fund of the commonwealth.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>