<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>178E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Transmission Of Registration Data To Criminal History Systems Board, Police Departments, And Fbi</catch_line>
    <order_by>178E</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Within 5 days of receiving upon sentence any sex offender required to register under sections 178C to 178Q, inclusive, the agency which has custody of the sex offender, including the department of correction, the department of youth services and each of the houses of correction, shall transmit to the board said sex offender’s registration data, which shall include identifying factors, anticipated future residence, any anticipated secondary addresses, offense history, documentation of any treatment received for a mental abnormality, the official version of any sex offenses, the mittimus, any prior incarceration history, and the projected maximum release date and the earliest possible release date for the sex offender. All custodial agencies shall inform the board immediately of any transfers of sex offenders so that there may be contact with the offender throughout the classification process. The bureau shall classify such a sex offender at least 10 days before the offender’s earliest possible release date. The board shall promptly transmit the registration data to the police departments in the municipalities where the sex offender intends to live, maintain any secondary address and work and where the offense was committed and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The sex offender shall be informed by, and shall acknowledge in writing to, the agency which has custody of the sex offender of the duty to register in the commonwealth and in any state where he resides, is employed, carries on a vocation or is a student, to verify registration information, to give notice of change of address or intended change of address within the commonwealth or in another state and the penalties for failure to do so and for giving false registration information, and of his right to submit to the board, according to section 178L, documentary evidence relative to his risk of reoffense, the degree of dangerousness posed to the public and of his duty to register under this section. If such sex offender is a juvenile at the time of such notification, notification shall also be mailed to such sex offender’s legal guardian or agency having custody of the juvenile in the absence of a legal guardian and his most recent attorney of record. The agency shall transmit such acknowledgment to the board within ten days of receipt of such acknowledgment. Not later than two days before his release from custody, a sex offender shall register by mailing to the board on a form approved by the board and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury, the sex offender’s name, date of birth, home address or intended home address, any secondary addresses or intended secondary addresses, work address or intended work address and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time employee of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution, and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time student of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution. No sex offender shall be released from custody unless such registration has been filled out, signed and mailed to the board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     An agency that has supervision of a sex offender required to register pursuant to sections 178C to 178P, inclusive, on probation or parole shall, within five days of assuming supervision of such sex offender, transmit to the board such sex offender’s registration data which, for purposes of this paragraph, shall include identifying factors, residential address or anticipated future residence, secondary addresses or anticipated secondary addresses, work address, offense history, documentation of any sex offender treatment and documentation of any treatment received for a mental abnormality. The agency shall also report any changes of address of any sex offender required to register pursuant to said sections 178E to 178P, inclusive, within its jurisdiction to the board. The board shall promptly transmit the registration data to the police departments in the municipalities where such sex offender intends to live and work and where the offense was committed and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The sex offender shall be informed by, and shall acknowledge in writing to, the agency which has custody of the sex offender of the duty to register in the commonwealth and in any state where he resides, has any secondary addresses, is employed, carries on a vocation or is a student, to verify registration information and to give notice of change of address, or any secondary addresses or intended change of address within the commonwealth or in another state and the penalties for failure to do so and for giving false registration information, and of his right to submit to the board, according to section 178L, documentary evidence relative to his risk of reoffense, the degree of dangerousness posed to the public and his duty to register under this section. If such sex offender is a juvenile at the time of such notification, notification shall also be mailed to such sex offender’s legal guardian or agency having custody of the juvenile in the absence of a legal guardian, and his most recent attorney of record. A sex offender shall, within two days of receiving such notice, register by mailing to the board on a form approved by the board and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury, the sex offender’s name, date of birth, home address or intended home address, any secondary addresses or intended secondary addresses, work address or intended work address and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time employee of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution, and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time student of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Any court which enters a conviction for a sex offense or adjudication as a youthful offender or as a delinquent juvenile by reason of a sex offense, but does not impose a sentence of confinement of 90 days or more to be served immediately shall inform the sex offender and require the sex offender to acknowledge, in writing, his duty to register in the commonwealth and in any state where he resides, is employed, carries on a vocation or is a student, to verify registration information and to give notice of change of address or intended change of address within the commonwealth or in another state and the penalties for failure to do so and for giving false registration information, and of his right to submit to the board, according to section 178L, documentary evidence relative to his risk of reoffense, the degree of dangerousness posed to the public and of his duty to register under this section. If such sex offender is a juvenile at the time of such adjudication, the legal guardian or agency having custody of the juvenile and his most recent attorney of record shall also be required to acknowledge, in writing, such information. The court shall cause such sex offender’s registration data which, for purposes of this paragraph, shall include identifying factors, anticipated future residence, any anticipated secondary addresses, offense history and documentation of any treatment received for a mental abnormality to be transmitted to the board within five days of sentencing. The board shall promptly transmit the registration data to the police departments in the municipalities where such sex offender intends to live and work and where the offense was committed and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. A sex offender shall, within two days of receiving such notice or of release from confinement, whichever is later, register by mailing to the board on a form approved by the board and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury, the sex offender’s name, date of birth, home address or intended home address, any secondary addresses or intended secondary addresses, work address or intended work address and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time employee of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution, and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time student of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Any court which accepts a plea for a sex offense shall inform the sex offender prior to acceptance and require the sex offender to acknowledge, in writing, that such plea may result in such sex offender being subject to the provisions of sections 178C to 178P, inclusive. Failure to so inform the sex offender shall not be grounds to vacate or invalidate the plea.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Upon written motion of the commonwealth, a court which enters a conviction or adjudication of delinquent or as a youthful offender may, at the time of sentencing, having determined that the circumstances of the offense in conjunction with the offender’s criminal history does not indicate a risk of reoffense or a danger to the public, find that a sex offender shall not be required to register under sections 178C to 178P, inclusive. Such motion by the commonwealth shall state the reasons for such motion with specificity. The court may not make such a finding if the sex offender has been determined to be a sexually violent predator; has been convicted of two or more sex offenses defined as sex offenses pursuant to the Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children and Sexually Violent Offender Registration Act, 42 U.S.C. section 14071, committed on different occasions; has been convicted of a sex offense involving a child or a sexually violent offense; or if the sex offender is otherwise subject to minimum or lifetime registration requirements as determined by the board pursuant to section 178D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     In the case of a sex offender who has been convicted of a sex offense or adjudicated as a youthful offender or as a delinquent juvenile by reason of a sex offense, on or after December 12, 1999, and who has not been sentenced to immediate confinement, the court shall, within 14 days of sentencing, determine whether the circumstances of the offense in conjunction with the offender’s criminal history indicate that the sex offender does not pose a risk of reoffense or a danger to the public. If the court so determines, the court shall relieve such sex offender of the obligation to register under sections 178C to 178P, inclusive. The court may not make such a determination or finding if the sex offender has been determined to be a sexually violent predator; has been convicted of two or more sex offenses defined as sex offenses pursuant to the Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children and Sexually Violent Offender Registration Act, 42 U.S.C. section 14071, committed on different occasions; has been convicted of a sex offense involving a child or a sexually violent offense; or if the sex offender is otherwise subject to minimum or lifetime registration requirements as determined by the board pursuant to section 178D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     A sex offender who moves into the commonwealth from another jurisdiction shall, within two days of moving into the commonwealth, register by mailing to the board on a form approved by the board and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury, the sex offender’s name, date of birth, home address or intended home address, any secondary addresses or intended secondary addresses, work address or intended work address and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time employee of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution, and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time student of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution. The board shall transmit the registration data to the police department in the municipality where such sex offender intends to live and work and, if the sex offender intends to work at or become a student at an institution of higher learning, to the police departments in the municipalities where the sex offender will work or attend such institution and shall transmit the same to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     A sex offender required to register pursuant to sections 178C to 178P, inclusive, who intends to move to a different city or town within the commonwealth shall, not later than ten days prior to establishing such new residence, register by mailing to the board on a form approved by the board and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury, the sex offender’s name, date of birth, home address or intended home address, any secondary addresses or intended secondary addresses, work address or intended work address and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time employee of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution, and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time student of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution. The board shall transmit notice of such change of address to all the police departments in the municipalities where the offense was committed, where the sex offender last registered and where the sex offender intends to live or attend an institution of higher learning and shall transmit the same to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. A sex offender required to register pursuant to said sections 178C to 178P, inclusive, who intends to change his address within a city or town shall notify the board in writing not later than ten days prior to establishing such new residence. The board shall transmit notice of the change of address to the police departments within such city or town, in the municipality where the offense was committed and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     A sex offender required to register pursuant to sections 178C to 178P, inclusive, who intends to move out of the commonwealth shall notify the board not later than ten days before leaving the commonwealth. The board shall transmit notice of the change of address to the police departments in the municipalities where such sex offender last registered, where the offense was committed and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The board shall notify such sex offender of the duty to register in the new jurisdiction and shall forward a copy of his registration data to the appropriate law enforcement agency in such new jurisdiction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     A sex offender required to register pursuant to sections 178C to 178P, inclusive, who intends to change his work address shall notify the board in writing not later than ten days prior to establishing the new work address. The board shall transmit notice of the change of address and, if the sex offender is or intends to become employed part-time or full-time at an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution to the police department in the municipalities where such sex offender previously worked, where such sex offender intends to work, where such sex offender resides or intends to reside and where the offense was committed. The board shall transmit notice of the change of address to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     The registrar of motor vehicles shall inform a person applying for or renewing a license to operate a motor vehicle that he has a duty to register with the board if such person is a sex offender, pursuant to regulations established by the board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     Except as hereinbefore provided, a sex offender residing or working in the commonwealth or working at or attending an institution of higher learning in the commonwealth shall, within ten days of the effective date of this section, register by mailing to the board on a form approved by the board and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury, the sex offender’s name, date of birth, home address or intended home address, any secondary addresses or intended secondary addresses, work address or intended work address and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time employee of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution, and, if the sex offender is or intends to become a part-time or full-time student of an institution of higher learning, the name and address of the institution. The board shall promptly transmit the registration data to the police departments where the sex offender intends to live and work, where the offense was committed and, if the sex offender intends to work at or become a student at an institution of higher learning, to the police departments in the municipalities where the sex offender will work or attend such institution and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The board shall send written notification of the requirements of sections 178C to 178P, inclusive, to the last known address of all sex offenders residing in the commonwealth who, prior to the effective date of this section, have been released from all custody and supervision. If any such sex offender is a juvenile at the time of such notification, notification shall also be mailed to such sex offender’s legal guardian or the agency having custody of the juvenile in the absence of a legal guardian and his most recent attorney of record.
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     Upon registering, verifying registration information or giving notice of change of address or intended change of address under this section, a sex offender shall provide independent written verification of the address at which he is registered or, if changing address, will be registered.
        </section>
        <section prefix="n">
    	     Registration data received by the board and disseminated to law enforcement pursuant to this section shall not be disseminated to the public except in accordance with sections 178D, 178I, 178J and 178K.
        </section>
        <section prefix="o">
    	     A sex offender who plans to work at or attend an institution of higher learning part-time or full-time in the commonwealth shall, within 10 days prior to commencing employment or enrollment in classes at an institution of higher learning, register by mailing to the board on a form approved by the board and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury, the sex offender’s name, date of birth, home address or intended home address, any secondary addresses or intended secondary addresses, work address or intended work address, and the name and address of the institution of higher learning. The board shall transmit notice of such change of address to all police departments in the municipalities where the sex offender plans to work at or attend an institution of higher learning and shall transmit the same to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="p">
    	     A sex offender required to register pursuant to section 178C to 178F, inclusive, who intends to transfer from the institution of higher learning he is attending or stop attending shall notify the board in writing not later than 10 days before leaving the present institution of higher learning and shall provide the board with the name and address of the new institution of higher learning, if applicable. The board shall transmit notice of any such change of address to all police departments in the municipalities where the sex offender previously attended an institution of higher learning and, if applicable, to the police department in the municipality where the sex offender plans to attend an institution of higher learning. The board shall transmit notice of any change of address for the institution of higher learning to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="q">
    	     Any nonresident person enrolled on a full-time or part-time basis, in any public or private education institution in the commonwealth, including any secondary school, trade or professional institution, shall register with the board if such person is required to register as a sex offender in the state in which he resides. Such student shall, within 10 days of attending such institution, register by mailing to the board on a form approved by the board and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury, the student’s name, date of birth, home address, any secondary addresses and the name and address of the educational institution he is attending.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>