<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>111B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Malignant Disease And Benign Brain Related Tumor Registry; Reports</catch_line>
    <order_by>111B</order_by>
    <text>
        The department shall, subject to appropriation, establish a registry to record certain cases of malignant disease and benign brain-related tumors that occur in residents of the commonwealth, and such information concerning these cases as it shall deem necessary and appropriate in order to conduct epidemiologic surveys of cancer and benign brain-related tumors and to apply appropriate preventive and control measures. 
The commissioner shall require the reporting of certain cases of malignant disease and benign brain-related tumors and the submission of such specified additional information on reported cases or control populations as he deems necessary and appropriate for the recognition, prevention, or control of such diseases. 
The department shall, subject to appropriation, maintain comprehensive records of all reports submitted pursuant to this section. Such reports shall be confidential in accordance with section seventy and shall be released by the department only upon written request of the patient, his guardian, executor, attorney, or other person designated in writing by said patient. Such reports and records or information contained therein, may also be released by the department to persons authorized by the commissioner to conduct research studies or to other persons, but no such studies shall identify the subjects of said reports or records. 
Nothing in this section shall be construed to compel any individual to submit to medical or department examination or supervision. 
The department shall make such rules and regulations as are necessary to implement the provisions of this section pursuant to chapter thirty A.
    </text>
</law>