<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138" level="3">Alcoholic Liquors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20</section_number>
    <catch_line>Storage Permits; Special Warehouse Permits; Special Seasonal Permits; Fees; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>20</order_by>
    <text>
        The commission may grant to any holder of a manufacturer’s, farmer-winery, farmer-brewery or wholesaler’s and importer’s license under this chapter a permit to store in any city or town those alcoholic beverages which the licensees are authorized to manufacture, produce or sell; but there shall not be granted to the manufacturer, farmer-winery, farmer-brewery, or wholesaler and importer, in the aggregate, more than 3 permits in the commonwealth-not more than 1 permit in any city or town. A permit so granted to the holder of the license shall authorize him to deliver the beverages from any place of storage for which he has a permit upon orders, which need not be in writing, received by him at the premises covered by his manufacturer’s, farmer-winery, farmer-brewery or wholesaler’s and importer’s license and transmitted to the place of storage covered by the permit. The commission may establish annual fees thereof not exceeding $2,000 for any 1 permit. 
Special warehouse permits may be granted by the commission for the storage of alcoholic beverages in a duly licensed bonded warehouse. A special permit so granted shall authorize the holder thereof to transfer the beverages between any premises for which he has such special permit and any premises covered by his manufacturer’s, farmer-winery, farmer-brewery or wholesaler’s and importer’s license. The fee for a special permit shall be not less than $125 nor more than $1,000. 
Special seasonal permits may be granted by the commission upon payment of a fee of $500 for each such permit, which shall authorize any licensee under section 18 or 19 to store malt beverages in the same city or town in which their licensed premises are located; but the storage shall be in a place properly equipped for the refrigeration of malt beverages and that the authorization shall be effective only for the period between April first and October thirty-first in any year. 
An innholder licensed under chapter one hundred and forty and section twelve of chapter one hundred and thirty-eight is hereby permitted under this section to store wines in a licensed and bonded warehouse. Said licensee shall only be permitted to use the hereinabove described stored wines on such licensee’s premises in the normal course of business and such wines shall not be for resale to other establishments licensed under this chapter. 
Nothing in this section shall be deemed to authorize the transportation of alcoholic beverages in any vehicle not covered by a permit issued under section twenty-two. 
No vote in any city or town under section eleven shall prevent the renewal of any permit under this section. 
The commission may make and enforce rules and regulations covering the storage of alcoholic beverages under permits granted under this section.
    </text>
</law>