<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Natural Heritage And Endangered Species Program; Administration;  Advisory Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>5B</order_by>
    <text>
        The director shall administer the natural heritage and endangered species program in accordance with clauses (3) and (13A) of section four, and shall promulgate rules and regulations, subject to the procedures established in chapter thirty A, for said program, including criteria for the purchase of lands critical to nongame wildlife and endangered species, and for the use of said land for the protection and enhancement of nongame wildlife and for the encouragement of compatible wildlife uses. The commissioner shall appoint, subject to the approval of the fisheries and wildlife board, a natural heritage and endangered species advisory committee of seven members to advise the director on matters pertaining to nongame wildlife and wild plants. One of the members shall be a board member interested in endangered species appointed pursuant to section seven of chapter twenty-one. Of the remaining six members, three shall have technical training and experience and be drawn in the commissioner’s discretion from the fields of ornithology, mammalogy, herpetology, icthyology, and botany, and three shall be persons knowledgeable in the field of natural history. The committee shall select a chairperson annually by majority vote of the members of said committee at a meeting scheduled for such purpose. The members shall serve terms of three years, except for the initial term, three members shall be appointed to serve for one year, two for two years, and two for three years. The committee shall meet at least quarterly and shall also meet at the request of the director or committee chairperson. Committee members shall not receive compensation for their services but shall receive reimbursement from the Natural Heritage and Endangered Species Fund for reasonable expenses necessary to the performance of their duties.
    </text>
</law>