<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>64D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Deferred Compensation Program, Annuity Or Other Defined Contribution Plan;  Required Participation</catch_line>
    <order_by>64D</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Any governmental body, as defined in section sixty-four B, may require any person, who is receiving compensation from the governmental body for services performed and who is not a member of a retirement system as provided under chapter thirty-two or any other retirement system which meets the requirements of The treasurer, or if there is no treasurer, the chief financial officer by whatever name that person is called, on behalf of a governmental body which has accepted the provisions of this section shall contract with any person, who is receiving compensation from the governmental body for services performed for the governmental body and who is not eligible for membership in the retirement system set forth in said chapter thirty-two that pertains to the governmental body, to withhold from that person's compensation at least such amounts as are necessary to provide the minimum level of benefits required to qualify said deferred compensation program, tax sheltered annuity or other defined contribution plan as a retirement system for said person as defined under said Section 3121(b)(7)(F) of said Code and the regulations promulgated thereunder but no greater than permitted under other provisions of the Internal Revenue Code.  All contracts formed with part-time, seasonal or temporary employees pursuant to the provisions of the first paragraph shall entitle the employee to a single-sum distribution of the employee's deferral plus reasonable interest.  A governmental body may accept the provisions of this section by a majority vote of the selectmen for a town, the city council for a city, the county council for a county, the district members in a district, the members of the authority in an authority, and the governing body, by whatever name and in whatever form composed, in any other political subdivision, body politic and corporate, or public instrumentality created by the commonwealth.  Any governmental body already requiring, on the effective date of this act, participation in a public retirement system for persons who are receiving compensation from the governmental body for services performed and who are not members of a retirement system as provided under said chapter thirty-two shall be deemed to have accepted the provisions of this section without the requirement of a majority vote of the selectmen for a town, the city council for a city, the county council for a county, the district members in a district, the members of the authority in an authority, and the governing body, by whatever name and in whatever form composed, in any other political subdivision, body politic and corporate, or public instrumentality created by the commonwealth.
Chapter 29: Deferred compensation program, annuity or other defined contribution plan; required participation
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Any governmental body, as defined in section 64B, may require any person, who is receiving compensation from the governmental body for services performed and who is not a member of a retirement system as provided under chapter 32 or any other retirement system which meets the requirements of The treasurer, or if there is no treasurer, the chief financial officer by whatever name that person is called, on behalf of a governmental body which has accepted this section shall contract with any person, who is receiving compensation from the governmental body for services performed for the governmental body and who is not eligible for membership in the retirement system in said chapter 32 that pertains to the governmental body, to withhold from that person's compensation at least such amounts as are necessary to provide the minimum level of benefits required to qualify said deferred compensation program, tax sheltered annuity or other defined contribution plan as a retirement system for said person as defined under said Section 3121(b)(7)(F) of said Code and the regulations promulgated thereunder but no greater than permitted under other provisions of the Internal Revenue Code.  All contracts formed with part-time, seasonal or temporary employees under the first paragraph shall entitle the employee to a single-sum distribution of the employee's deferral plus reasonable interest.  A governmental body may accept this section by a majority vote of the selectmen for a town, the city council for a city, the county council for a county, the district members in a district, the members of the authority in an authority, and the governing body, by whatever name and in whatever form composed, in any other political subdivision, body politic and corporate, or public instrumentality created by the commonwealth.  Any governmental body already requiring, on the effective date of this section, participation in a public retirement system for persons who are receiving compensation from the governmental body for services performed and who are not members of a retirement system as provided under said chapter 32 shall be deemed to have accepted this section without the requirement of a majority vote of the selectmen for a town, the city council for a city, the county council for a county, the district members in a district, the members of the authority in an authority, and the governing body, by whatever name and in whatever form composed, in any other political subdivision, body politic and corporate, or public instrumentality created by the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>