<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>71</section_number>
    <catch_line>Treasurer's Obligation Regarding Local Aid Intercepts</catch_line>
    <order_by>71</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  No provision of this chapter shall be construed to affect the obligation of the state treasurer to withhold from the receipts, distributions, reimbursements or other assistance payable to any city, town or other local governmental unit under any reimbursement, grant, assistance or other local aid program any amount determined in accordance with section ten of chapter forty-four A or any amount certified to the state treasurer as owing to a public instrumentality of the commonwealth pursuant to paragraph (b) of section ten of chapter three hundred and seventy-two of the acts of nineteen hundred and eighty-four or paragraph (d) of section ten or section eleven of chapter twenty-nine C, or any similar provision relative to local aid intercepts, so-called.
Chapter 29: Treasurer's obligation regarding local aid intercepts
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  This chapter shall not be construed to affect the obligation of the state treasurer to withhold from the receipts, distributions, reimbursements or other assistance payable to any city, town or other local governmental unit under any reimbursement, grant, assistance or other local aid program any amount determined under section 10 of chapter 44 A or any amount certified to the state treasurer as owing to a public instrumentality of the commonwealth under paragraph (b) of section 10 of chapter 372 of the acts of 1984 or paragraph (d) of section 10 or section 11 of chapter 29C, or any similar provision relative to local aid intercepts.
    </text>
</law>