<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Estimates For Purposes Not Covered By Sec. 3;  Evaluation;  Review</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Every officer having charge of any state agency who, in his annual reports or otherwise, recommends or petitions for the expenditure of money by the commonwealth from any source of revenue, including expenditures to be met by assessments or from bond revenues or trust funds, for any purpose not covered by the estimates required to be submitted under section three, shall, annually, on or before a date set by the commissioner, submit detailed estimates thereof to the budget director, together with any other information required by said budget director. Such estimates and other information relating to such state agency before being submitted to the budget director, shall first be submitted to the appropriate secretary, if any, on or before a date set by him; said secretary shall review the same and make such additions thereto, deletions therefrom and modifications therein as he deems appropriate; provided, however, that prior to making any such additions, deletions or modifications, said secretary shall conduct public hearings, for which he shall give five days' public notice prior thereto, on all items for which he shall submit to the governor a recommendation for an appropriation of one million dollars or more.  All copies of such statements and information relative to expenditures from bond revenues shall be submitted to the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance on or before the aforementioned date. The commissioner shall evaluate them as to the priority, necessity, and feasibility of the requests contained therein in relation to long range capital facilities development plans and capital facilities development plans and capital facility projects contained therein, as defined by section thirty-nine A of chapter seven. The commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall submit his evaluation to the officer providing such estimates and information, the budget director, and the appropriate secretary.
Chapter 29: Estimates for purposes not covered by Sec. 3; review; public hearing
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Every officer having charge of any state agency who, in the officer's annual reports or otherwise, recommends or petitions for the expenditure of money by the commonwealth from any source of revenue, including expenditures to be met by assessments or from bond revenues or trust funds, for any purpose not covered by the estimates required to be submitted under section 3, shall, annually, on or before a date set by the secretary of administration and finance, submit detailed estimates thereof to the budget director, together with any other information required by said budget director. Such estimates and other information relating to such state agency before being submitted to the budget director, shall first be submitted to the appropriate secretary, if any, on or before a date set by the secretary; said secretary shall review the same and make such additions, deletions and modifications as the secretary deems appropriate; provided, however, that prior to making any such additions, deletions or modifications, said secretary shall conduct public hearings, for which he shall give at least 5 days public notice, on all items for which the secretary shall submit to the governor a recommendation for an appropriation of $1,000,000 or more.
    </text>
</law>