<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>79</section_number>
    <catch_line>Admissions, Transfers And Discharges Of Tuberculous Patients;  Supervision;  Rates Of Charges</catch_line>
    <order_by>79</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  The department shall have supervision and control of all admissions, transfers, and discharges of tuberculous patients in hospitals within the department or in other hospitals under contract with the department under sections seventy-seven and seventy-eight. The department may adopt regulations concerning such admissions, transfers, and discharges as it deems necessary. The rate or rates for general health supplies, care, services and accommodations to be paid hospitals caring for tuberculosis patients under contract with the department shall be those established by the division of health care finance and policy. No such payment shall be made with respect to any patient not approved for admission by the department. In the case of hospitals under such contracts patients may be admitted who are reasonably suspected of having tuberculosis, but a final diagnosis must be made within sixty days of admission or such longer period as specifically authorized in writing by the department.
Chapter 111: Admissions, transfers and discharges of tuberculous patients; supervision; rates of charges
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 93 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  The department shall have supervision and control of all admissions, transfers, and discharges of tuberculous patients in hospitals within the department or in other hospitals under contract with the department under sections seventy-seven and seventy-eight. The department may adopt regulations concerning such admissions, transfers, and discharges as it deems necessary. The rate or rates for general health supplies, care, services and accommodations to be paid hospitals caring for tuberculosis patients under contract with the department shall be those established by the executive office of health and human services or a governmental unit designated by the executive office. No such payment shall be made with respect to any patient not approved for admission by the department. In the case of hospitals under such contracts patients may be admitted who are reasonably suspected of having tuberculosis, but a final diagnosis must be made within sixty days of admission or such longer period as specifically authorized in writing by the department.
    </text>
</law>