<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>227</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions For Secs. 228 To 235</catch_line>
    <order_by>227</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this section and sections 228 to 236, inclusive, the following words shall, unless the context requires otherwise, have the following meanings:— 
“Board”, the board of registration of massage therapy established in section 98 of chapter 13. 
“Licensed massage school”, a facility which is licensed by the board after meeting minimum standards for training and curriculum as determined in accordance with sections 228 to 236, inclusive. 
“Licensed massage therapy salon”, a place, office, clinic or establishment licensed by the board to offer massage services. 
“Massage”, the systematic treatment of the soft tissues of the body by use of pressure, friction, stroking, percussion, kneading, vibration by manual or mechanical means, range of motion for purposes of demonstrating muscle excursion or muscle flexibility and nonspecific stretching. Massage therapy may include the use of oil, ice, hot and cold packs, tub, shower, steam, dry heat or cabinet baths, in which the primary intent is to enhance or restore the health and well-being of the client. Massage therapy shall not include diagnoses, the prescribing of drugs or medicines, spinal or other joint manipulations or any services or procedures for which a license to practice medicine, chiropractic, occupational therapy, physical therapy or podiatry is required by law. 
“Massage therapist” or “Massage practitioner”, a person licensed by the board who instructs or administers massage or massage therapy for compensation.
    </text>
</law>