<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Practice Upon Filing Of License Application</catch_line>
    <order_by>23C</order_by>
    <text>
        A person who meets the qualifications to be admitted to the examination for licensure as an athletic trainer or an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant or physical therapist or physical therapist assistant, may between the date of filing an application for licensure and the announcement of the results of the next succeeding examination for licensure, according to which application he has filed, practice as an athletic trainer; as an occupational therapist or as an occupation therapy assistant under the direction of an occupational therapist duly licensed under this chapter; as a physical therapist or physical therapist assistant under direction of a physical therapist duly licensed under this chapter. If any person so practicing fails to qualify for or pass the first announced examination after filing for licensure, all privileges under this section shall automatically cease upon due notice to the applicant of such failure. Such privileges shall be renewed upon filing for a second examination for licensure and shall automatically cease upon notice to the applicant that he has failed to pass the second examination. Such privileges may again be renewed upon the applicant petitioning the board for permission to file a third application and said permission being granted by the board, and shall automatically cease upon due notice that he has failed to pass the third examination. The privilege shall not exceed beyond the third examination.
    </text>
</law>