<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>178</section_number>
    <catch_line>Violations; Punishment</catch_line>
    <order_by>178</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until May 4, 2012. For text effective May 4, 2012, see below.] 
Any person who willfully requests, obtains or seeks to obtain criminal offender record information under false pretenses, or who willfully communicates or seeks to communicate criminal offender record information to any agency or person except in accordance with the provisions of sections one hundred and sixty-eight to one hundred and seventy-five, inclusive, or any member, officer, employee or agency of the board or any participating agency, or any person connected with any authorized research program, who willfully falsifies criminal offender record information, or any records relating thereto, shall for each offense be fined not more than five thousand dollars, or imprisoned in a jail or house of correction for not more than one year, or both. 
Chapter 6: Requesting or obtaining criminal offender record information or self-audit under false pretenses; unlawful communication of record information; falsification of record information; unlawful request or requirement that person provide his or her record information; punishment [Text of section as amended by 2010, 256, Sec. 36 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102. For text effective until May 4, 2012, see above.] 
An individual or entity who knowingly requests, obtains or attempts to obtain criminal offender record information or a self-audit from the department under false pretenses, knowingly communicates or attempts to communicate criminal offender record information to any other individual or entity except in accordance with the provisions of sections 168 through 175, or knowingly falsifies criminal offender record information, or any records relating thereto, or who requests or requires a person to provide a copy of his or her criminal offender record information except as authorized pursuant to section 172, shall for each offense be punished by imprisonment in a jail or house of correction for not more than 1 year or by a fine of not more than $5,000 or by both such fine and imprisonment, and in the case of an entity that is not a natural person, the amount of the fine may not be more than $50,000 for each violation. 
An individual or entity who knowingly requests, obtains or attempts to obtain juvenile delinquency records from the department under false pretenses, knowingly communicates or seeks to communicate juvenile criminal records to any other individual or entity except in accordance with the provisions of sections 168 through 175, or knowingly falsifies juvenile criminal records, shall for each offense be punished by imprisonment in a jail or house of correction for not more than 1 year or by a fine of not more than $7,500, or by both such fine and imprisonment, and in the case of an entity that is not a natural person, the amount of the fine may not be more than $75,000 for each violation. 
This section shall not apply to, and no prosecution shall be brought against, a law enforcement officer who, in good faith, obtains or seeks to obtain or communicates or seeks to communicate criminal offender record information in the furtherance of his or her official duties.
    </text>
</law>