<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>172G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Children’S Camps To Obtain Criminal And Juvenile Data; Employees And Volunteers</catch_line>
    <order_by>172G</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until May 4, 2012. For text effective May 4, 2012, see below.] 
Notwithstanding section 172, section 60 or 60A of chapter 119, or any other general or special law to the contrary, operators of camps for children shall obtain all available criminal offender record information and juvenile data as found in the court activity record information from the criminal history systems board of all employees or volunteers prior to employment or volunteer service. Information obtained under this section shall not be disseminated for any purpose other than to further the protection of children. 
Chapter 6: Children’s camps to obtain criminal and juvenile data; employees and volunteers [Text of section as amended by 2010, 256, Sec. 26 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102. For text effective until May 4, 2012, see above.] 
Notwithstanding section 172, section 60 or 60A of chapter 119, or any other general or special law to the contrary, operators of camps for children shall obtain all available criminal offender record information and juvenile data as found in the court activity record information from the department of all employees or volunteers prior to employment or volunteer service. Information obtained under this section shall not be disseminated for any purpose other than to further the protection of children.
    </text>
</law>