<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="59" order_by="59" level="3">Assessment Of Local Taxes</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>75</section_number>
    <catch_line>Omitted Property; Assessments</catch_line>
    <order_by>75</order_by>
    <text>
        If a parcel of real property or the personal property of a person has been unintentionally omitted from the annual assessment of taxes due to a clerical or data processing error or some other good faith reason or, if the personal property of a person was omitted from the annual assessment of taxes but discovered upon an examination of the books, papers, records and other data under section 31A, the assessors shall, in accordance with any rules, regulations and guidelines as the commissioner may prescribe, assess such person for such property. Except for personal property found after an examination under said section 31A which shall be made not later than 3 years and 6 months after the date the true list in which such property should have been returned was due or not later than 3 years and 6 months after the date the return was filed, whichever is later, no such assessment shall be made later than June 20 of the taxable year or 90 days after the date on which the tax bills were mailed, whichever is later. The assessors shall annually, not later than June 30 of the taxable year or 100 days after the date on which the tax bills were mailed if mailed after March 22, return to the commissioner a statement showing the amounts of additional taxes so assessed. The taxes so assessed shall be entered on the tax list of the collector, who shall collect and pay over the same. The assessors shall also deliver to the collector their warrants for the collection of all taxes so entered on the tax list. Such additional assessment shall not render the tax of the town invalid although its amount, in consequence thereof, shall exceed the amount authorized by law to be raised.
    </text>
</law>