<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32</section_number>
    <catch_line>Validation Of By Laws; Procedure</catch_line>
    <order_by>32</order_by>
    <text>
        Except to the extent that a zoning by-law may take effect as provided in section five of chapter forty A, before a by-law takes effect it shall be approved by the attorney general or ninety days shall have elapsed without action by the attorney general after the clerk of the town in which a by-law has been adopted has submitted to the attorney general a certified copy of such by-law with a request for its approval, a statement clearly explaining the proposed by-law, including maps and plans if necessary, and adequate proof that all of the procedural requirements for the adoption of such by-law have been complied with. Such request and proof shall be submitted by the town clerk within thirty days after final adjournment of the town meeting at which such by-law was adopted. If the town clerk fails to so submit such request and proof within such thirty days, the selectmen, within fifteen days thereafter, may submit a certified copy of such by-law with a request for its approval, a statement explaining the proposed by-law, including maps and plans, if necessary, and adequate proof that all procedural requirements for the adoption of such by-law has been complied with. If the attorney general does not, within said ninety days, request of such town clerk in writing further proof of such compliance stating specifically wherein such proof is inadequate, it shall be presumed that the proof submitted was adequate. If the attorney general disapproves a by-law he shall give notice to the town clerk of the town in which the by-law was adopted of his disapproval, with his reasons therefor. If a by-law of a town takes effect by reason of the failure of the attorney general to seasonably act upon a request for its approval, the clerk of such town shall enter in his records a statement that the by-law has become effective by reason of such failure of the attorney general to act. Before a by-law or an amendment thereto takes effect it shall also be published in a town bulletin or pamphlet, copies of which shall be posted in at least five public places in the town; and if the town is divided into precincts, copies shall be posted in one or more public places in each precinct of the town; or instead of such publishing in a town bulletin or pamphlet and such posting, copies thereof may be published at least twice at least one week apart in a newspaper of general circulation in the town. The publication of a zoning by-law shall include a statement that claims of invalidity by reason of any defect in the procedure of adoption or amendment may only be made within ninety days of such posting or of the second publication and a statement indicating where copies of such by-law may be examined and obtained. The requirements of publishing in a town bulletin or pamphlet and posting, or publishing in one or more newspapers, as above, may be dispensed with if notice of the by-laws is given by delivering a copy thereof at every occupied dwelling or apartment in the town, and affidavits of the persons delivering the said copies, filed with the town clerk, shall be conclusive evidence of proper notice hereunder. This section shall not apply to cities. 
Notwithstanding the provisions of the preceding paragraph, if the attorney general finds there to be any defect in the procedure of adoption or amendment of any zoning by-law relating to form or content of the notice of the planning board hearing prescribed in section 5 of chapter 40A, or to the manner or dates on which said notice is mailed, posted or published as required by said section 5, then instead of disapproving the by-law or amendment because of any such defect, the attorney general may proceed under the provisions of this paragraph. If the attorney general so elects, written notice shall be sent to the town clerk within a reasonable time setting forth with specificity the procedural defect or defects found, including a form of notice thereof, whereupon the running of the 90-day period provided for the attorney general’s review pursuant to this section shall be suspended. The town clerk shall forthwith post the notice in a conspicuous place in the town hall for a period of not less than 14 days, and shall publish it once in a newspaper of general circulation in the town. The notice shall state that any resident, the owner of any real property in the town, or any other party entitled to notice of the planning board hearing, who claims that any such defect was misleading or was otherwise prejudicial may, within 21 days of the publication, file with the town clerk a written notice so stating and setting forth the reasons supporting that claim. Forthwith after the expiration of said 21 days, the town clerk shall submit to the attorney general either (a) a certificate stating that no claim was filed within the 21 day period, or (b) a certificate stating that one or more claims were filed together with copies thereof. Upon receipt of the town clerk’s certificate, the 90-day period provided for the attorney general’s review pursuant to this section shall resume; but if the expiration of the 90-day period is less than ten days from the date on which the town clerk’s certificate was received, then the review period shall be extended to the tenth day following such receipt. If no claim was made, the attorney general may waive any such defect; but, if any claim is made then the attorney general may not waive any such defect. However, by not filing a claim under this paragraph, a person shall not be deprived of the right to assert a claim of invalidity arising out of any possible defect in the procedure of adoption or amendment as provided in this section and in section 5 of chapter 40A. 
Notwithstanding the provisions of the first paragraph of this section, the attorney general and the town counsel may, by an agreement in writing setting forth the reasons therefor and filed with the town clerk before the end of the 90-day period, extend the 90-day period provided for the attorney general’s review pursuant to this section for not more than an additional 90 days.
    </text>
</law>