<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="128A" order_by="128A" level="3">Horse And Dog Racing Meetings</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing And Registering Of Agents, Veterinarians, Blacksmiths, Owners, Trainers, Jockeys And Stable Employees;  Badges;  Suspension And Revocation;  Criminal Records</catch_line>
    <order_by>9A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 31, 2014. Repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 39. See 2011, 194, Sec. 112.][ First paragraph effective until July 31, 2014. See 2001, 139, Sec. 45 as amended by 2005, 176, Sec. 13; 2006, 54, Sec. 12; 2006, 449, Secs. 19 and 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 12; 2009, 167, Sec. 12; 2010, 203, Sec. 12; 2011, 77, Sec. 12; 2011, 194, Sec. 84. For text effective July 31, 2014, see below.]  For the purpose of enabling the commission to exercise and maintain a proper control over horse and dog racing conducted under the provisions of this chapter, the rules, regulations and conditions prescribed by the commission under section nine shall provide for the licensing and registering at reasonable and uniform fees, of agents, assumed names, colors, partnerships and minor agreements and shall provide for the licensing at reasonable and uniform fees of veterinarians, blacksmiths, owners, trainers, jockeys and stable employees at horse tracks and veterinarians, owners and trainers of dogs participating in such racing, and any other persons having access to horses and dogs and all pari-mutuel clerks and other persons with access to money wagered on races.[ First paragraph effective July 31, 2014 does not take effect. See 2011, 194, Secs. 39 and 112. For text effective until July 31, 2014, see above.]  For the purpose of enabling the commission to exercise and maintain a proper control over horse and dog racing conducted under the provisions of this chapter, the rules, regulations and conditions prescribed by the commission under section nine shall provide for the licensing and registering at reasonable and uniform fees, of agents, assumed names, colors, partnerships and minor agreements and shall provide for the licensing at reasonable and uniform fees of veterinarians, blacksmiths, owners, trainers, jockeys and stable employees at horse tracks and veterinarians, owners and trainers of dogs participating in such racing, and any other persons having access to horses and dogs.  Such rules and regulations shall also provide for the fingerprinting of all licensees. Every person so licensed shall be required to display and wear a badge containing a photograph. Such rules and regulations may also provide for the suspension and revocation of licenses so granted and for the imposition on persons so licensed of reasonable forfeitures and penalties for the violation of any rule or regulation prescribed by the commission and for the use of the proceeds of such penalties and forfeitures.  The commission shall have access to criminal offender record information of applicants for any license granted pursuant to this chapter, including officers, directors and beneficial owners of ten per cent or more of the stock of a corporation applying for such a license, and for applicants for employment by the commission. Such access shall be exercised in accordance with sections one hundred and sixty-seven to one hundred and seventy-eight, inclusive, of chapter six.
    </text>
</law>