<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensure Of Party Having Financial Interest In A Gaming Establishment Or The Business Of The Gaming Licensee Or Applicant Or Who Is A Close Associate Of A Gaming Licensee Or Applicant</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) The commission shall require anyone with a financial interest in a gaming establishment, or with a financial interest in the business of the gaming licensee or applicant for a gaming license or who is a close associate of a gaming licensee or an applicant for a gaming license, to be qualified for licensure by meeting the criteria provided in sections 12 and 16 and to provide any other information that the commission may require.  (b) For each business that applies for a gaming license, the commission shall determine whether each officer and director of a corporation, other than a publicly-traded corporation, general partner and limited partner of a limited partnership, and member, transferee of a member's interest in a limited liability company, director and manager of a limited liability company which holds or applies for a gaming license meets the standards for qualification of licensure pursuant to sections 12 and 16 and, in the judgment of the commission, any of a business's individual stockholders, lenders, holders of evidence of indebtedness, underwriters, close associates, executives, agents or employees.  (c) A person owning more than 5 per cent of the common stock of the applicant company, directly or indirectly, or a holding, intermediary or subsidiary company of an applicant company may be required to meet the qualifications for licensure under sections 12 and 16. The commission may waive the licensing requirements for institutional investors holding up to 15 per cent of the stock of the applicant company or holding, intermediary or subsidiary company of the applicant company upon a showing by the person seeking the waiver that the applicant purchased the securities for investment purposes only and does not have any intention to influence or affect the affairs or operations of the applicant company or a holding, intermediary or subsidiary company of the applicant company. An institutional investor granted a waiver which subsequently determines to influence or affect the affairs or operations of the applicant company or a holding, intermediary or subsidiary company of the applicant company shall provide not less than 30 days notice to the commission of such intent and the commission shall ensure that the institutional investor meets the qualifications for licensure under said sections 12 and 16 before the institutional investor may take an action that may influence or affect the affairs of the applicant company or a holding, intermediary or subsidiary company of the applicant company. Any company holding over 15 per cent of the applicant company, or a holding, intermediary or subsidiary company of an applicant company, shall be required to meet the qualifications for licensure under said sections 12 and 16.  (d) A person who is required to be qualified for licensure under this section as a general or limited partner shall not serve as such a partner until that person obtains the required approval or waiver from the commission.  (e) The commission shall require any person involved in the financing of a gaming establishment or an applicant's proposed gaming establishment to be qualified for licensure pursuant to sections 12 and 16 and may allow such person to seek a waiver pursuant to the standards in subsection (c).  (f) A person required to be qualified for licensure shall apply for qualification within 30 days after taking a position with the business. A person who is required to be qualified for licensure pursuant to a decision of the commission shall apply for qualification within 30 days after that decision.  (g) If a corporation or other form of business organization applying for a gaming license is, or if a corporation or other form of business organization holding a gaming license is to become, a subsidiary, each holding company, intermediary company and other entity having an interest in the applicant shall be required to be qualified for licensure under sections 12 and 16.  (h) The commission shall require that a company or individual that can exercise control or provide direction to a gaming licensee or applicant for a gaming license or a holding, intermediary or subsidiary company of a gaming licensee or applicant for a gaming license be qualified for licensure under sections 12 and 16; provided, however, that the commission may allow such person to seek a waiver under subsection (c).  (i) The bureau shall investigate each person required to be qualified for licensure under this section and shall: (i) make a recommendation to the commission that the commission shall approve or deny the application for licensure; or (ii) extend the period for issuing a recommendation in order to obtain additional information necessary for a complete evaluation of the application for a license.
    </text>
</law>