<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111C" order_by="111C" level="3">Emergency Medical Services System</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Ems System Advisory Board; Membership; Duties; Advisory Committees</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be within the department an EMS system advisory board, consisting of the commissioner or his designee, as chairman; the state medical director, or his designee; the regional director of each regional emergency medical services council, or his designee; the medical director, of each regional EMS council, or his designee; the registrar of motor vehicles, or his designee; the commissioner of public safety, or his designee; and 27 members appointed by the commissioner, or their designees, as follows: one each from the Massachusetts Medical Society, the Massachusetts Chapter of the American College of Surgeons, the Massachusetts Heart Association, the Massachusetts Nurses Association, the American Red Cross, the Massachusetts Chiefs of Police Association, the Massachusetts Police Association, the Massachusetts Fire Chiefs Association, the Professional Fire Fighters of Massachusetts, the Massachusetts Call/Volunteer Firefighters Association, Massachusetts Hospital Association, Massachusetts Chapter of Emergency Nurses Association, Massachusetts Chapter of the American College of Emergency Physicians, the Massachusetts Council of Community Hospitals, the Massachusetts Association of Emergency Medical Technicians, the Massachusetts Ambulance Association, the Massachusetts Association of Hospital-Based Paramedic Services, the International Association of EMTs & Paramedics, and the Massachusetts Association of Health Maintenance Organizations; one from the volunteer ambulance associations; a representative of the Governors Highway Safety Bureau; a representative of the state 911 department; one person who shall be an expert in EMS for children; one person who shall be an attorney; and three who shall be consumers representative of all regions of the state, to the extent feasible. Each appointed member of the board shall serve a term of three years, or until his successor is appointed and qualified. Appointees shall serve without compensation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The board, in addition to other powers conferred in this chapter, including, without limitation, in subsection (c) of section 3, and in addition to functioning in a general advisory capacity, shall assist in coordinating the efforts of all persons and agencies in the state concerned with the EMS system, and shall render advice on the development of the EMS system where needed. The board shall make an annual report to the commissioner on or before June 30. There shall be established by the department committees advisory to the board, including, without limitation, a trauma systems committee. The trauma systems committee shall be chaired by the commissioner or his designee and shall be composed of an equitable balance of individuals, each identified as representing (1) regional EMS councils, (2) trauma centers, and (3) community hospitals. Other committees may be established and constituted by the board, in its discretion.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>