<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Administration And Enforcement Of Chapters 128 A And 128 C;  Grant Of Simulcasting License To Gaming Establishment</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective May 20, 2012 until July 31, 2014. See 2011, 194, Sec. 110. For text effective July 31, 2014, see below.]  (a) The commission shall administer and enforce chapters 128A and 128C and any other general or special law related to pari-mutuel wagering or simulcasting. The commission shall serve as a host racing commission and an off-track betting commission for purposes of 15 U.S.C. 3001, et seq.  (b) The commission may grant a simulcasting license to a gaming establishment; provided, however, that the commission shall assess a percentage of the wagering received on in-state and out-of-state thoroughbred and harness races equal to that paid by a licensee under chapter 128C and the assessment shall be allocated to the Race Horse Development Fund established in section 60 to support purse assistance and breeding programs; provided further, that in granting any such license to a gaming establishment, the commission shall take into consideration the impact on preexisting facilities licensed pursuant to chapter 128A and said chapter 128C.
Chapter 23K: Administration and enforcement of laws related to pari-mutuel wagering and simulcasting; grant of simulcasting license to gaming establishment or entity previously licensed pursuant to chapters 128A or 128C
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 194, Sec. 17 effective July 31, 2014. See 2011, 194, Sec. 112. For text effective until July 31, 2014, see above.]  (a) The commission shall administer and enforce any general and special law related to pari-mutuel wagering and simulcasting. The commission shall serve as a host racing commission and an off-track betting commission for purposes of 15 U.S.C. 3001, et seq.  (b) The commission may grant a simulcasting license to a gaming establishment or an entity previously licensed pursuant to chapter 128A or chapter 128C; provided, however, that the commission shall require that a minimum of 10 per cent of the wagering received on in-state and out-of-state thoroughbred and harness races be allocated to the Race Horse Development Fund established in section 60 to support purse assistance and breeding programs; provided further, that in granting any such license to a gaming establishment, the commission shall take into consideration the impact on preexisting facilities previously licensed pursuant to said chapters 128A and 128C.
    </text>
</law>