<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="3">Department Of Transitional Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5J</section_number>
    <catch_line>Acceptance Of Direct Cash Assistance Funds On Electronic Benefit Transfer Cards For Purchase Of Alcoholic Beverages, Lottery Tickets Or Tobacco;  Penalty</catch_line>
    <order_by>5J</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 27, 2012. For text effective July 27, 2012, see below.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, an individual or store owner shall not accept direct cash assistance funds held on electronic benefit transfer cards for the purchase of alcoholic beverages, lottery tickets or tobacco products. An individual or store owner who knowingly accepts electronic benefit transfer cards in violation of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500 for the first offense, a fine of not less than $500 nor more than $1,000 for the second offense and a fine of not less than $1,000 for the third or subsequent offense.
Chapter 18: Preventing electronic benefit transfer transactions for certain purchases made using direct cash assistance funds; penalty
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 161, Sec. 2 effective July 27, 2012. For text effective until July 27, 2012, see above.]  (a) The department shall maintain policies and practices as necessary to prevent cash assistance provided under this chapter from being used in any electronic benefit transfer transaction at: liquor stores; casinos, gambling casinos or gaming establishments licensed pursuant to chapter 23K; retail establishments which provide adult-oriented entertainment in which performers disrobe or perform in an unclothed state for entertainment, as defined in Such establishments shall not accept electronic benefits transfer cards. A store owner who knowingly allows a prohibited electronic benefit transfer transaction in violation of this section or subsection (b) of section 5I shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500 for a first offense, by a fine of not less than $500 nor more than $2,500 for a second offense and by a fine of not less than $2,500 for a third or subsequent offense.  (b) A store owner who knowingly violates this section and who also possesses a license to sell alcoholic beverages under section 12 of chapter 138 shall be referred to the appropriate licensing authority for possible disciplinary action pursuant to section 64 of said chapter 138.  (c) A store owner who knowingly violates this section and who also possesses a license to sell lottery tickets under sections 26 and 27 of chapter 10 shall be referred to the director of the state lottery for possible disciplinary action.
    </text>
</law>