<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148" level="3">Fire Prevention</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>26H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Lodging Or Boarding Houses; Automatic Sprinkler Systems</catch_line>
    <order_by>26H</order_by>
    <text>
        In any city or town which accepts the provisions of this section, every lodging house or boarding house shall be protected throughout with an adequate system of automatic sprinklers in accordance with the provisions of the state building code. No such sprinkler system shall be required unless sufficient water and water pressure exists. In such buildings or in certain areas of such buildings, where the discharge of water would be an actual danger in the event of a fire, the head of the fire department shall permit the installation of such other fire suppressant systems as are prescribed by the state building code in lieu of automatic sprinklers. The head of the fire department shall enforce the provisions of this section. 
For the purposes of this section “lodging house” or “boarding house” shall mean a house where lodgings are let to six or more persons not within the second degree of kindred to the person conducting it, but shall not include fraternity houses or dormitories, rest homes or group residences licensed or regulated by agencies of the commonwealth. 
Any lodging or boarding house subject to the provisions of this section shall be equipped with automatic sprinklers within five years after acceptance of this act by a city or town. 
Whoever is aggrieved by the head of the fire department’s interpretation, order, requirement or direction under the provisions of this section, may within forty-five days after the service of notice thereof, appeal from such interpretation, order or requirement to the board of appeals of the fire safety commission as provided in section two hundred and one of chapter six.
    </text>
</law>