<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Counties And County Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36" level="3">Registers Of Deeds</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Records Affecting Title To Real Estate; Copies To Tax Assessors;  Required Information</catch_line>
    <order_by>24B</order_by>
    <text>
        The register, or said register as the assistant recorder of the land court, in each county except Dukes and Nantucket counties, shall, upon the request in writing of the board of assessors of any city or town in his county or district, furnish such board with copies of such instruments recorded or registered in his registry as affect the title to real estate in the city or town of such board and as may be necessary for the records of such board for the purposes of taxation of real estate. 
The said register or said assistant recorder, may at his option, furnish said board with an abstract card or cards in lieu of said copies which shall contain the following information:—the name of the city or town in which the land is situated, the name or names of the grantor and grantee, the date, an abstract of the description, the lot number and description of the plan, if any, referred to, the book and page or certificate of title number of the record, and such other information included in such instruments as is necessary for said board of assessors for its records. 
Said register or assistant recorder shall require from each person who appears before him to record a deed to real property, such information as the commissioner of revenue may deem necessary to assist the assessors in the performance of their duties under sections eleven and thirty-eight of chapter fifty-nine. Said information shall be collected on a form approved by the commissioner of revenue and each completed form shall be forwarded by said register or assistant recorder to the board of assessors of the city or town in which the property lies.
    </text>
</law>