<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Payments For Human Service Programs;  Rules And Regulations Relating To Eligibility</catch_line>
    <order_by>23A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Subject to the provisions of sections twenty-four and twenty-five, the comptroller shall provide for payments by officers receiving advances pursuant to this chapter and to section twenty of chapter eighteen B, to eligible organizations under contract with the commonwealth to provide social, educational or rehabilitative services. Said payments shall be made in accordance with a schedule to be included in each such contract, on the basis of projected expenses or services and shall be adjusted monthly and at the end of each contract, pursuant to the submission of a voucher or other claim for payment, to reflect the actual cost or extent of services rendered.  The comptroller shall establish rules and regulations governing the eligibility of providers to receive such payments including but not limited to, proper incorporation and recording with the secretary of state, and compliance with all applicable state and federal laws. Each such eligible provider shall, at the end of each billing period, submit timely, complete and accurate documentation prepared in accordance with the terms of its contract and with requirements of the comptroller. Any violation of the provisions of this paragraph shall result in ineligibility for such payments for a period of two years from the date of disqualification. Prior to reinstatement of eligibility, a provider must submit proof of ability to comply with the requirements of this section and with any regulations promulgated pursuant to this section. The comptroller shall promulgate rules and regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.
Chapter 29: Payments for human service programs; rules and regulations relating to eligibility
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Subject to sections 24 and 25, the comptroller shall provide for payments by officers receiving advances under this chapter and to section 20 of chapter 18B, to eligible organizations under contract with the commonwealth to provide social, educational or rehabilitative services. Said payments shall be made under a schedule to be included in each such contract, on the basis of projected expenses or services and shall be adjusted monthly and at the end of each contract, under the submission of a voucher or other claim for payment, to reflect the actual cost or extent of services rendered.  The comptroller shall establish rules and regulations governing the eligibility of providers to receive such payments including but not limited to, proper incorporation and recording with the secretary of state, and compliance with all applicable state and federal laws. Each such eligible provider shall, at the end of each billing period, submit timely, complete and accurate documentation prepared under the terms of its contract and with requirements of the comptroller. Any violation of this paragraph shall result in ineligibility for such payments for 2 years from the date of disqualification. Prior to reinstatement of eligibility, a provider shall submit proof of ability to comply with the requirements of this section and with any regulations promulgated under this section. The comptroller shall promulgate rules and regulations necessary to carry out this section.
    </text>
</law>