<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="64C" order_by="64C" level="3">Cigarette Excise</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Cigars And Smoking Tobacco; Payment And Rate Of Excise Tax;  Liability Of Distributors, Retailers And Residents; Nonresident Cigar Distributors; Licenses; Violations And Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>7B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     An excise shall be imposed on all cigars and smoking tobacco held in the commonwealth at the rate of 30 per cent of the wholesale price of such products. This excise shall be imposed on cigar distributors at the time cigars or smoking tobacco are manufactured, purchased, imported, received or acquired in the commonwealth. This excise shall not be imposed on any cigars or tobacco products that (i) are exported from the commonwealth; or (ii) are not subject to taxation by the commonwealth pursuant to any law of the United States.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Every cigar retailer shall be liable for the collection of the excise on all cigars or smoking tobacco in his possession at any time, upon which the excise has not been paid by a cigar distributor, and the failure of any cigar retailer to produce or exhibit to the commissioner or his authorized representative, upon demand, an invoice by a cigar distributor for any cigars or smoking tobacco in his possession, shall be presumptive evidence that the excise thereon has not been paid and that such cigar retailer is liable for the collection of the excise thereon.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The amount of the excise advanced and paid by a cigar distributor or cigar retailer, as provided in this section, shall be added to and collected as part of, the sales price of the cigars or smoking tobacco.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Every person who does not acquire untaxed cigars or smoking tobacco, but acquires taxed cigars and smoking tobacco for sale at retail, shall not be licensed as a cigar distributor under this section, but shall be required, during the period that such person is a retailer of taxed cigars or smoking tobacco, to be licensed as a cigar retailer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A person outside the commonwealth who ships or transports cigars or smoking tobacco to cigar retailers in the commonwealth, to be sold by those cigar retailers, may apply for a license as a nonresident cigar distributor and, if the commissioner issues such a license to him, he shall thereafter be subject to all the provisions of this section and be entitled to act as a cigar distributor, provided he files proof with his application that he has appointed the state secretary as his agent for service of process relating to any matter or issue arising under this section. Such a nonresident person shall also agree to submit his books, accounts and records for examination in the commonwealth during reasonable business hours by the commissioner or his authorized representative.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Every resident of the commonwealth shall be liable for the collection of the excise on all cigars or smoking tobacco in his possession at any time, upon which the excise has not been paid by a cigar distributor or cigar retailer, and the failure of any such consumer to produce or exhibit to the commissioner or his authorized representative, upon demand, an invoice or sales receipt by a cigar distributor or cigar retailer for any cigars or smoking tobacco in his possession, shall be presumptive evidence that the excise thereon has not been paid and that such consumer is liable for the collection of the excise thereon.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     No person shall act as a cigar distributor or cigar retailer in the commonwealth unless licensed to do so in accordance with section 67 of chapter 62C. If a cigar distributor or cigar retailer acts in more than 1 of said capacities at any 1 place of business, he shall procure a license for every capacity in which he acts, unless, upon application to the commissioner, the commissioner determines otherwise. Each license so issued or a duplicate copy thereof shall be prominently displayed on the premises covered by the license.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Except as this section expressly provides to the contrary, the provisions of this chapter and of chapter 62C relative to the assessment, collection, payment, abatement, verification and administration of taxes, including penalties, shall so far as pertinent, apply to the excise tax imposed by this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     For the purposes of section 5, cigars and smoking tobacco shall be tobacco products, cigar distributors shall be wholesalers and cigar retailers shall be retailers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     For the purposes of section 8, untaxed cigars and smoking tobacco found in the commonwealth shall be cigarettes, which have not been returned and are not returnable under section 16 of chapter 62C or section 6 as the context requires.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Any person who knowingly has in his possession a shipping case or other container of cigars or smoking tobacco not bearing the name and address of the person receiving the cigars or smoking tobacco from a manufacturer or such other markings as the commissioner may prescribe and any person knowingly in possession of such a shipping case or other container of cigars or smoking tobacco from which this name and address has been erased or defaced shall, in addition to any other penalty provided by this chapter or chapter 62C, be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for the first offense or not more than $25,000 for each subsequent offense.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Any person who files any false return, affidavit, or statement, or who violates any provision of this section for which no other penalty has been provided shall, in addition to any other penalty provided by this chapter or chapter 62C, be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for the first offense and not more than $25,000 for each subsequent offense.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Whenever the commissioner or a police officer discovers, in the possession of any person not being a licensed cigar distributor or one authorized by the commissioner, any untaxed cigars or smoking tobacco, he may seize and take possession of those cigars and smoking tobacco, together with any vending machine or other receptacle, which shall include, without limitation, a motor vehicle, boat or airplane, in which they are contained or in which they are transported. Such cigars, smoking tobacco, vending machine or other receptacle seized by a police officer shall be turned over to the commissioner and shall be forfeited to the commonwealth. The commissioner shall destroy such cigars or smoking tobacco and shall destroy or otherwise dispose of such vending machine or other receptacle. The commissioner may, within a reasonable time after the seizure, by a public notice at least 5 days before the day of sale, sell the vending machine or other receptacle at public sale and deposit the proceeds in the General Fund.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The state police and all local police authorities may, and at the request of the commissioner or his duly authorized agent shall, enforce this section. Each violation of this section shall be a separate offense.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>