<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21C" order_by="21C" level="3">Massachusetts Hazardous Waste Management Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions Applicable To Secs. 15 To 30</catch_line>
    <order_by>15</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in sections fifteen to thirty, inclusive, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:— 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of insurance. 
“Plan”, the plan of operation established and approved under section twenty-two. 
“Licensee”, a person or entity holding a license to own or operate a hazardous waste collection, treatment, disposal or storage facility, pursuant to this chapter, or which is a facility having interim status pursuant to RCRA and regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter. 
“Insolvent licensee”, a licensee which, after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred and eighty-five, becomes insolvent and is placed under a final order of arrangement, bankruptcy, liquidation, conservation or rehabilitation by a court of competent jurisdiction; or is finally adjudicated to be bankrupt or insolvent by a court of competent jurisdiction; or certifies to the insolvency fund in writing, under the pains and penalties of perjury, that it is insolvent and is found to be insolvent by the insolvency fund or the commissioner of insurance. 
“Impaired licensee”, a licensee which, after December thirty-first, nineteen hundred and eighty-five, is not an insolvent licensee and is found by the insolvency fund or by the commissioner to be potentially unable to satisfy a pending potential covered claim; or is the subject of proceedings under the bankruptcy code; or is placed under an order of receivership, conservation or rehabilitation by a court of competent jurisdiction. 
“Covered claim”, an unsatisfied final judgment against an insolvent licensee entered in a civil action commenced on or after January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-six, for bodily injury or property damage to a third party caused by an accidental occurrence arising from operation of a hazardous waste collection, disposal, treatment or storage facility in the commonwealth. 
“Potential covered claim”, a claim for bodily injury or property damage to a third party caused by an accidental occurrence arising from operation of a hazardous waste collection, disposal, treatment or storage facility in the commonwealth; which is the subject of a civil action against a licensee commenced on or after January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-six; and satisfaction of which is likely to require an amount exceeding the total amount of liability insurance available to satisfy the claim and the assets of the defendants available to satisfy the claim. 
“Generator”, a person who produces hazardous waste while engaged in business within the commonwealth. 
“Insolvency fund”, the Massachusetts hazardous waste insolvency fund established under section sixteen.
    </text>
</law>