<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>111</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notice To Board Of Health That Persons Infected With Dangerous Diseases; Application Of Section</catch_line>
    <order_by>111</order_by>
    <text>
        If a physician knows or has cause to believe that a person whom he visits is infected with a disease dangerous to the public health, or if either eye of an infant whom or whose mother a physician, or a hospital medical officer registered under section nine of chapter one hundred and twelve, visits, becomes inflamed, swollen and red, or shows an unnatural discharge within two weeks after birth, he shall immediately give written notice thereof, signed by him, to the board of health of the town where the patient is being attended by him. If the board of health which receives such written notice is the board of health of a town other than that wherein the patient dwells, it shall, immediately upon receipt of such notice, send a copy thereof to the board of health of the town wherein the patient dwells; and, in addition thereto, the board of health which receives such written notice, whether or not it is the board of health of the town wherein the patient dwells, shall send a copy thereof to the board of health of the town in which the patient is known to have contracted such disease and to the board of health of each town in which he is known to have exposed any person to such disease. If a physician or such a hospital medical officer refuses or neglects to give the notice required by this section he shall be punished by a fine of not less than fifty nor more than two hundred dollars. 
The foregoing provisions of this section shall not apply to tuberculosis, nor shall the foregoing provisions of this section and the provisions of section one hundred and nine apply to venereal diseases as defined under section six, except in the case of eye infections in infants under two weeks of age. Any person having tuberculosis or a venereal disease shall be reported to local boards of health either directly or through the department in accordance with such special rules and regulations as the department may make, having due regard for the best interests of the public.
    </text>
</law>