<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35BB</section_number>
    <catch_line>School Modernization And Reconstruction Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35BB</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     There shall be established on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund, to be known as the School Modernization and Reconstruction Trust Fund. There shall be credited to the fund the dedicated sales tax revenue amount. Annual receipts into the fund on account of any fiscal year shall be considered to meet the full obligation of the commonwealth to the authority for such fiscal year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Amounts in the fund shall be held by the state treasurer or his designee, as trustee and not on account of the commonwealth, exclusively for the purposes of the authority, and the state treasurer shall disburse amounts in the fund to the authority, without further appropriation, upon the request from time to time of the executive director of the authority. All amounts in the fund, including investment earnings, shall be available for expenditure by the authority for any lawful purpose, including without limitation payment of debt service on debt obligations issued by the authority, and may be pledged to secure debt of the authority in such manner and according to such priority as the authority may determine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The authority shall certify annually to the treasurer as trustee with copies provided to the clerks of the house and senate and to the house and senate committees on ways and means that it has made provision in its annual budget and its capital plan under section 17 of chapter 70B for sufficient amounts to be available to meet debt service payments or other payments due under financing obligations, including, without limitation, leases or grant obligations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Subject to applicable restrictions contained in any bond resolution, trust or security agreement or credit enhancement agreement, surety bond or insurance policy related to indebtedness incurred by the authority, including without limitation coverage requirements, if the authority shall determine that the balance of the fund exceeds the amount necessary to achieve the purposes of the authority, including, without limitation, to meet debt service payments, lease payments and grant obligations, the authority may transfer the excess amount to the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     In order to increase the marketability of any bonds or notes of the trust which may be secured by or payable from amounts held in the fund, the sums to be credited to the fund are hereby impressed with a trust for the benefit of the trust and the holders from time to time of the bonds or notes, and in consideration of the acceptance of payment for the bonds or notes, the commonwealth covenants with the purchasers and all subsequent holders and transferees of the bonds or notes that while the bond or note shall remain outstanding, and so long as the principal of or interest on the bond or note shall remain unpaid, the sums to be credited to the fund shall not be diverted from the control of the trust and, so long as the sums are necessary, as determined by the authority in accordance with any applicable bond resolution, trust or security agreement or credit enhancement agreement, surety bond or insurance policy related to indebtedness incurred by the trust, for the purposes for which they have been pledged, the rates of the excises imposed by said chapters 64H and 64I shall not be reduced below the rates prescribed by this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>