<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118A" order_by="118A" level="3">Assistance To The Aged And Disabled</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Program Of Social Services;  Emergency Grants;  Funeral And Burial Costs</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The department shall provide to aged and disabled residents under this chapter a program of social services as set forth in section 2 of chapter 18. In addition to any other benefits authorized by this chapter, the department may provide to such residents grants of assistance in cases of fire, flood or other disaster. The department may pay a sum not exceeding $1,100 toward the funeral and final disposition of a recipient to a funeral establishment if there are insufficient resources to pay for the cost of such funeral and final disposition. The commonwealth shall have the right of reimbursement from whatever resources may exist in the estate of the recipient.
Chapter 118A: Program of social services; emergency grants; funeral and burial costs
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 119 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The department shall provide to aged and disabled residents under this chapter a program of social services as set forth in section 2 of chapter 18. In addition to any other benefits authorized by this chapter, the department may provide to such residents grants of assistance in cases of fire, flood or other disaster. The department may pay a sum not exceeding $1,100 toward the funeral and final disposition of a recipient to a funeral establishment if there are insufficient resources to pay for the cost of such funeral and final disposition and if the total expense of the funeral and final disposition does not exceed $3,500. The commonwealth shall have the right of reimbursement from whatever resources may exist in the estate of the recipient.
    </text>
</law>