<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138" level="3">Alcoholic Liquors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>37</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificate Accompanying Sample Of Beverages To Be Analyzed;  Contents</catch_line>
    <order_by>37</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  A certificate shall accompany each sample of beverages sent for analysis by an officer to the department of public health stating from whom the beverages were seized, the date of the seizure and the name and residence of the officer who seized said beverages. Said department shall note upon said certificate the date of the receipt and the analysis of said alcoholic beverages and the percentage of the alcohol or the composition and quality of said beverages, as the case may be, as required by section thirty-six on a form prescribed by said department of public health.
Chapter 138: Certificate accompanying sample of beverages to be analyzed; contents
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 124 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  A certificate shall accompany each sample of beverages sent for analysis by an officer to the department of state police stating from whom the beverages were seized, the date of the seizure and the name and residence of the officer who seized said beverages. Said department shall note upon said certificate the date of the receipt and the analysis of said alcoholic beverages and the percentage of the alcohol or the composition and quality of said beverages, as the case may be, as required by section thirty-six on a form prescribed by said department of state police.
    </text>
</law>