<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>34</section_number>
    <catch_line>Conviction For Violations; Surrender Of License, Permit Or Certificate</catch_line>
    <order_by>34</order_by>
    <text>
        A license, permit, or certificate issued under a provision of this chapter, except a license issued under clauses (3), (4) or (6) of section twenty-three, held by a person found guilty of, or convicted of, or assessed in any manner after a plea of nolo contendere, or penalized for, a violation of clause (15) of section four or section eleven, twelve, thirteen, sixteen, thirty-two, thirty-three, fifty-four, fifty-seven, fifty-eight, sixty-one, sixty-two, sixty-three, sixty-four, sixty-five, sixty-six, sixty-seven, sixty-eight, seventy, seventy-two, seventy-three, seventy-five or eighty, or a rule or regulation made under the authority thereof, or for fishing, hunting or trapping outside the season established under section five, or for the unlawful taking or possession of a deer, for which that particular license, permit, or certificate was issued, such particular license, permit, or certificate shall be void, and shall immediately be surrendered to an officer authorized to enforce this chapter. Said person or a person acting on his behalf shall not be given or make application for, that particular license, permit or certificate with respect to the violation for which said person was found guilty or penalized as aforesaid, during the period of one year from the date such person was found guilty or penalized, and such particular license, permit or certificate so issued shall be void and shall be surrendered to an officer authorized to enforce this chapter. Every license, permit, or certificate issued under a provision of this chapter, held by a person found guilty or assessed as aforesaid on three or more separate occasions for violations of a provision of this chapter, or a rule or regulation made under the authority thereof, shall be void and shall be immediately surrendered to an officer authorized to enforce this chapter. Said person or a person acting on his behalf shall not be given, or make application for, any license, permit or certificate under this chapter, during the period of one year from the date of his being found guilty or penalized as aforesaid, and such license, permit or certificate so issued shall be void and shall be surrendered to an officer authorized to enforce this chapter. No fee received for a license, permit, or certificate made void under this section shall be refunded to the holder thereof.
    </text>
</law>