<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="5" order_by="5" level="3">Printing And Distribution Of Laws And Public Documents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Pamphlet Edition Of Laws;  Distribution Of Copies Of Individual Laws</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. Repealed by 2012, 165, Sec. 10. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  The state secretary shall also, at the close of each regular session of the general court, publish in pamphlet form such number of copies, not exceeding twenty thousand, as he may determine, of the acts and resolves passed and of any proposed amendments to the constitution passed during such session, and shall at his discretion apportion said copies, excepting one thousand which he may reserve in his office for general distribution, among the clerks of the several towns, to be delivered by them to such inhabitants thereof as apply therefor.  He shall also, as soon as any act or resolve is passed, send a copy thereof to the following: each state department, officer, board or commission whose duties are affected by any such act or resolve, the clerks of the several towns, for the use of the inhabitants thereof, the justices, clerks and registers of courts, district attorneys, sheriffs, justices of the peace authorized to issue warrants and take bail, county law libraries, and all incorporated law libraries and branch libraries maintained by them; provided, however, upon written request approved by him, additional copies may be distributed to the above list and to any other public officials whose duties in his opinion require the use of such copies. He may also send copies to such persons as apply therefor, charging not less than the cost thereof.
    </text>
</law>