<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>30</section_number>
    <catch_line>Public Record Of State Officials And Employees; Salaries; Publication</catch_line>
    <order_by>30</order_by>
    <text>
        The human resources division shall collect at least once in every fiscal year such information relative to certain officials and employees of the commonwealth as shall be furnished to it under section thirty-eight of chapter thirty, which shall cover the fiscal year preceding. From the information so collected it shall keep a record, open to public inspection, showing the name, residence, designation, rate of compensation and date of appointment or qualification of every such official and employee, and any increase in the rate of salary or compensation paid him during the preceding fiscal year. The record shall also contain such other information concerning such officials and employees as, in the opinion of the personnel administrator, may be desirable. The comptroller shall, upon the request of the administrator, verify a list of such officials and employees, the amounts and rates of compensation and other information concerning payments to officials and employees about whom information is furnished. The administrator shall, on or before April fifteenth in each even-numbered year, publish a document containing such information concerning said officials and employees in the employ of the commonwealth on the preceding June thirtieth as, in its opinion, may be of public interest. Said document shall contain such summary and comparative tables as will best show the numbers of officials and employees in the service of the commonwealth during the two years preceding said June thirtieth, and during a further period of two years prior thereto, to be arranged in such manner as will make them of the greatest practical utility. The document may be revised or rearranged at the discretion of the administrator.
    </text>
</law>