<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="75" order_by="75" level="3">University Of Massachusetts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14D</section_number>
    <catch_line>University Of Massachusetts; Extension Board Of Public Overseers</catch_line>
    <order_by>14D</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be within the University of Massachusetts a University of Massachusetts Extension Board of Public Overseers for the purpose of advising and assisting the chancellor of the University of Massachusetts at Amherst in the mission, budget, operation and management of University of Massachusetts Extension programs. Nothing in this section shall directly affect the employment status of personnel. 
The board shall consist of a designee of the president of the university, a designee of the chancellor of the University of Massachusetts at Amherst, the commissioner of food and agriculture or his designee and the following persons to be appointed by the governor: four members of the Massachusetts Farm Bureau Federation, Inc. chosen from a list of 12 members submitted by said federation; one member of the Massachusetts 4-H Foundation, Inc. chosen from a list of three members submitted by said organization; one member of the State 4-H advisory committee chosen from a list of three members submitted by said committee; one member of the Massachusetts Forestry Association chosen from a list of three members submitted by said association; one member of the Massachusetts Audubon Society chosen from a list of three members submitted by said society; two members of the Massachusetts Arborists Association chosen from a list of five members submitted by said association and one member of the Massachusetts Nutrition Board chosen from a list of three members submitted by said board. The chancellor of the University of Massachusetts at Amherst shall appoint the chairperson from among the membership of the board. Members of the board shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed, subject to appropriation, out of any funds available for the purpose, for necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties. 
The appointed members of the board shall serve for terms of five years, except for persons appointed to fill vacancies, who shall serve for the unexpired term. The board shall hold an annual meeting in January and at least three other times during the year. The University of Massachusetts Extension director shall attend all meetings of the board and shall serve as secretary but shall have no vote in its deliberation. Eight members of the board shall constitute a quorum. The board may, by vote of its members then in office, adopt a policy for the conduct of business, including constitution of board membership. Policies may be amended or repealed by a two-thirds vote of its members. 
The director shall prepare an annual budget for board consideration. Such budget shall be adopted by the board and approved by the chancellor of the University of Massachusetts at Amherst. The director shall annually render a complete and detailed report of the activities, outcomes, revenue and expenditures to the board. 
The university on behalf of the board may receive, manage and disburse grants and donations from governmental agencies, other colleges and universities, corporations, foundations, associations and individuals for the purpose of funding the University of Massachusetts Extension and agricultural research programs. Further, the university on behalf of the board may establish and administer trust funds to support such programs.
    </text>
</law>