<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>48A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Cancellation Of Membership Camping Contracts</catch_line>
    <order_by>48A</order_by>
    <text>
        For purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meanings: 
“Membership camping contract” or “Membership camping agreement” means any written agreement of more than one year’s duration, executed in whole or in part within this commonwealth, which grants to a purchaser a nonexclusive right or license to use the campground of a membership camping operator or any portion thereof on a first come, first serve or reservation basis together with other purchasers. Membership camping contract or membership camping agreement also means any written agreement of more than one year’s duration, executed in whole or in part within the commonwealth, which obligates the membership camping operator to transfer or which does in fact transfer to the purchaser title to or an ownership interest in a campground or any portion thereof, and which gives the purchaser a nonexclusive right or license to use the campground of a membership camping operator or any portion thereof, on a first come, first serve or reservation basis together with other purchasers. 
Any person who signs a membership camping contract or membership camping agreement shall have the unqualified right to cancel such contract. This right of cancellation cannot be waived. The right to cancel expires at midnight on the third business day following the date on which the contract was executed. To cancel the membership camping contract, the purchaser must mail notice of your intent to cancel by certified United States mail to the membership camping operator at the address shown in the membership camping contract, postage prepaid. The membership camping operator is required to return all moneys paid in connection with the execution of the membership camping contract, upon proper and timely cancellation of the contract.
    </text>
</law>