<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Federal Safe Drinking Water Assessment; Advisory Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>18A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall have the following meanings unless the context otherwise requires:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the department is authorized and directed to establish a federal safe drinking water act assessment to assist the department in providing technical compliance assistance to and otherwise to regulate all suppliers of water pursuant to the act in the manner set forth in this section. Collection of the assessment may begin on or after July first, nineteen hundred and ninety-three. Matters relating to the rate, collection, cost, enforcement and application and other administrative features of the assessment shall be in accordance with regulations of the department adopted pursuant to section two of chapter thirty A, after consultation with the advisory committee. Such regulations, in addition to such further matters reasonably incidental to the administration of the assessment as may be determined by the department shall:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     provide that the assessment shall be remitted to the department by the end supplier;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     set and provide for periodic revision of, the rate of assessment at a uniform level not to exceed one cent per one thousand gallons of withdrawal, such that receipts in the aggregate are reasonably related to defraying the department’s direct and indirect costs for monitoring, inspections, technical assistance, reporting and enforcement activities necessary to ensure compliance with the act and any regulations of the department adopted to implement the act;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     establish the timing of assessments, collection and remittances;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     establish the manner in which end suppliers engaged in the distribution of water shall apportion and collect amounts necessary to defray the assessment, and their administrative costs relating thereto up to but not more than five percent of the outstanding assessment for all users for the applicable assessment period in the aggregate, from users without further action of the department of telecommunications and energy; provided, however, that each end supplier shall have the option of determining how its invoice to users shall show such defraying amounts and the frequency of invoicing;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     establish reasonable mechanisms for collection and enforcement including but not limited to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     the imposition of penalties not to exceed five thousand dollars per day for failure of end suppliers to remit proper receipts to the department;
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     the setting of a reasonable rate of interest, which shall not be exclusive of applicable penalties, if any, to be borne by the end supplier on overdue remittances; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="C">
    	     the establishment of reasonable audit and reporting procedures;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     establish a program providing for payments in lieu of assessments for any end supplier which cannot meter its withdrawal to the satisfaction of the department, until satisfactory metering has been installed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     establish the assessment rate by October first of each year for the following fiscal year. End suppliers shall be notified by mail of the assessment rate by November first of each year. The department shall mail bills to end suppliers during the month of July of each year for that fiscal year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     All receipts shall be deposited in the Safe Drinking Water Act Fund established pursuant to section two P1/2 of chapter twenty-nine, and used solely for the purposes set forth therein; provided, however, that receipts shall be used solely for administering said act and furthering its purposes. Any unexpended balance may be used to defray the amount of the assessment in future fiscal years. Regulations establishing the assessment pursuant to this section shall not be in effect in any fiscal year in which the department fails to provide from state funds, other than those collected under the terms of this section, a match of seventy-five percent of the amount of the federal grant attributable to the implementation of the act.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     In the event that the requirements of this section conflict with applicable federal requirements pertaining to the establishment and collection of the assessment by the department, such federal requirements shall take precedence over any conflicting requirements of this section and the department shall have the authority to establish, by regulation, and to collect such assessment in accordance with applicable federal requirements.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The department shall establish an advisory committee on administration of the federal safe drinking water assessment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The committee and the department shall undertake the additional responsibility to ensure that regular public service announcements are released to inform the public as to the requirements and costs associated with the act. The committee, with administrative support from the department, shall produce an annual report on the assessment program for the house and senate committees on ways and means and the joint committee on natural resources and agriculture, with a summary of all findings and action taken mailed to all end suppliers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The department shall not collect water quality annual compliance assurance fees for public water supplies.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>