<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23" level="3">Executive Office Of Labor And Workforce Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Division Of Occupational Safety;  Creation;  Powers And Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>11A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  In addition to such staff and facilities as may be necessary in the efficient performance of its duties, there shall be employed in the division of occupational safety persons having special knowledge of the causes and prevention of occupational diseases. It shall be the duty of the division to investigate conditions of occupation with reference to hazards to health and to determine the degree of such hazards, to investigate and evaluate methods for the control of such hazards, to assist in the preparation of rules and regulations for the preventing of occupational accidents and diseases, and, in co-operation with the department of public health or otherwise, to promote occupational health and safety education.
Chapter 23: Department of labor standards; creation; powers and duties
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Secs. 44 and 45 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  In addition to such staff and facilities as may be necessary in the efficient performance of its duties, there shall be employed in the department of labor standards persons having special knowledge of the causes and prevention of occupational diseases. It shall be the duty of the department to investigate conditions of occupation with reference to hazards to health and to determine the degree of such hazards, to investigate and evaluate methods for the control of such hazards, to assist in the preparation of rules and regulations for the preventing of occupational accidents and diseases, and, in co-operation with the department of public health or otherwise, to promote occupational health and safety education.
    </text>
</law>