<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="54" order_by="54" level="3">Elections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>78</section_number>
    <catch_line>Voting For Presidential Electors, Governor, And Lieutenant Governor;  Marking Ballots</catch_line>
    <order_by>78</order_by>
    <text>
        In order to vote for presidential electors, the voter shall make a cross (X) in the square at the right of the party or political designation appearing on the ballot at the right of the surnames of the candidates for president and vice president, to vote for whom such candidates for electors are nominated; and the making of a cross as aforesaid shall be deemed and taken as a vote for such candidates for presidential electors, except as provided in section thirty-three E. A vote by sticker or write-in in the blank space at the end of the list of names of presidential and vice presidential candidates may be cast for those candidates whose names are contained in lists filed with the state secretary under the provisions of section seventy-eight A and shall be deemed to be a vote for each of the candidates for presidential elector whose names are contained in the appropriate list so filed; provided, however, that in such case the voter shall list only the surnames of the candidates for president and vice president. In order to vote for governor and lieutenant governor, the voter shall mark a cross (X) in the square at the right of the names of the group of candidates for said offices for whom he desires to vote, or by inserting the name and residence of any person for either office in the blank space provided therefor; provided, however, that no such inserted name may be that of a candidate whose name is printed upon the ballot as a candidate for the office.
    </text>
</law>