<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>69</section_number>
    <catch_line>Annual License Fees; Revocation Of Certificate; Renewal Of Registration, Educational Requirement</catch_line>
    <order_by>69</order_by>
    <text>
        Every registered optometrist shall, annually, before February first, pay to the board a license fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, in default of which the board may revoke his certificate and his authority to practice optometry thereunder, after a hearing as provided by section seventy-one; but the payment of said fee at or before the time of the hearing, with such additional sum as determined under the aforementioned provision, shall remove the default. An optometrist duly registered and licensed to practice in this commonwealth, whose license has not been revoked, but who shall have temporarily retired from practice or removed from the commonwealth for not exceeding five years, and shall have notified the board of such retirement or removal, may register upon paying the lapsed annual license fees and filing with the board his affidavit as to the facts aforesaid. 
Every optometrist registered under the provisions of this chapter shall, as a condition of continuation of his registration, present to the board, on or before February first in each year on such form as it may provide, evidence satisfactory to the board that in the preceding year he attended an educational conference or pursued an educational program within the commonwealth, in conformity with such requirements relating thereto as the board may from time to time establish by regulation.
    </text>
</law>