<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41" level="3">Officers And Employees Of Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>81U</section_number>
    <catch_line>Approval, Modification Or Disapproval Of Plan By Board; Prerequisites For Decision</catch_line>
    <order_by>81U</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     By a proper bond, sufficient in the opinion of the planning board to secure performance of the construction of ways and the installation of municipal services required for lots in the subdivision shown on the plan, and the planning board may require that the applicant specify the time within which such construction shall be completed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     By a deposit of money or negotiable securities, sufficient in the opinion of the planning board to secure performance of the construction of ways and the installation of municipal services required for lots in the subdivision shown on the plan, and the planning board may require that the applicant specify the time within which such construction shall be completed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     By a covenant, executed and duly recorded by the owner of record, running with the land, whereby such ways and services shall be provided to serve any lot before such lot may be built upon or conveyed, other than by mortgage deed; provided, that a mortgagee who acquires title to the mortgaged premises by foreclosure or otherwise and any succeeding owner of such premises or part thereof may sell any such lot, subject to that portion of the covenant which provides that no lot shall be built upon until such ways and services have been provided to serve such lot; and provided, further, that nothing herein shall be deemed to prohibit a conveyance by a single deed, subject to such covenant, of either the entire parcel of land shown on the subdivision plan or of all lots not previously released by the planning board. A deed of any part of the subdivision in violation hereof shall be voidable by the grantee prior to the release of the covenant but not later than three years from the date of such deed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     By delivery to the planning board of an agreement executed after the recording of a first mortgage covering the premises shown on the plan or a portion thereof given as security for advances to be made to the applicant by the lender, which agreement shall be executed by the applicant and the lender and shall provide for the retention by the lender of funds sufficient in the opinion of the planning board and otherwise due the applicant, to secure the construction of ways and the installation of municipal services. Said agreement shall also provide for a schedule of disbursements which may be made to the applicant upon completion of various stages of the work, and shall further provide that in the event the work is not completed within the time set forth by the applicant, any funds remaining undisbursed shall be available for completion.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>