<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40J" order_by="40J" level="3">Massachusetts Technology Park Corporation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        The following terms as used in this chapter shall have the following meanings, except where the context clearly indicates otherwise:— 
“Board”, the board of directors of the Massachusetts Technology Park Corporation. 
“Center”, a facility established by the Massachusetts Technology Park Corporation pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. 
“Corporation”, the Massachusetts Technology Park Corporation. 
“Current expenses”, as applied to a center or any portion thereof created pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, the amount of reasonable and necessary expenses for the administration and operation of a center after the center has become operational. 
“Director”, shall refer to both an individual who is a member of the board and to an individual who is an advisory member appointed pursuant to clause (i) of section four. 
“Operational”, as applied to a center or any portion thereof created pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, embraces that point in the development of a center at which said center has evidenced both a demonstrated capacity to perform its essential functions and a proven capability to defray its expenses of administration and operation in a manner wholly self-sufficient of regular, annual public maintenance funding. 
“Participating business”, a private business corporation, partnership, firm or entity within the commonwealth engaged in or proposing to engage in the business of the design or manufacture of semi-conductor and microelectronic components, or of products of another technology which may come within the ambit of this chapter pursuant to the provisions of section six, which has undertaken to support and participate in the programs of the Corporation in a manner approved by the board. 
“Participating institution”, a state or independent, non-profit post-secondary educational institution within the commonwealth offering instruction in semi-conductor and microelectronic technologies, or in a field of study or an area of technology which may come within the ambit of this chapter pursuant to the provisions of section six, which has undertaken to support and participate in the programs of the corporation in a manner approved by the board. 
“Post-secondary educational institution”, a state or independent, non-profit post-secondary educational institution within the commonwealth offering instruction in semi-conductor and microelectronic technologies, or in a field of study or an area of technology which may come within the ambit of this chapter pursuant to section six. 
“Project cost”, as applied to a center or any portion thereof created pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, embraces all or any part of the cost of construction, acquisition, alteration, enlargement, reconstruction and remodeling of a center, including all lands, structures, real or personal property, rights, rights of way, air rights, franchises, easements and interests acquired or used in connection with a center, the cost of demolishing or removing any buildings or structures on land so acquired, including the cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or structures may be moved, financing charges, interest prior to, during and for a period after completion of such construction and acquisition, amounts reasonably required to make the center operational, the cost of architectural, engineering, financial and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, estimates of costs and revenues, administrative expenses, expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of constructing the center and such other expenses as may be necessary or incident to the construction and acquisition of the center. 
“Semi-conductor and microelectronic technologies”, that portion of the solid-state electronics field concerned with the design and manufacture of semi-conductors and microelectronic components, and the various sciences and technologies which support the solid-state electronics industry, including technologies concerned with computer-aided design/computer-aided manufacture and successor technologies. 
“Start-up expenses”, as applied to a center or any portion thereof created pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, embraces all or any part of the expenses for the administration and operation of a center incurred in the establishment of a center prior to the time the center becomes operational.
    </text>
</law>