<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>139</section_number>
    <catch_line>Examination And Qualification Of Applicants; Complaints; List Of Licensees</catch_line>
    <order_by>139</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     shall evaluate the qualifications of applicants, supervise examinations and grant licenses to those persons who pass the examination and who are determined to be qualified as speech-language pathologists or audiologists. Examinations shall be held at such times and places as may be determined by the board and at least two examinations for each discipline shall be held in each calendar year. An applicant who fails the examination shall be allowed to take the examination two additional times. Fourth and subsequent examinations shall be at the discretion of the board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     shall evaluate the qualifications of applicants and grant certificates to those persons who are determined to be qualified as speech-language pathology assistants or audiology assistants and may require applicants for certificate renewal to present evidence of the satisfactory completion of continuing education requirements as determined and published by the board;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     may require applicants for license or certificate renewal to be re-evaluated and re-examined and to present evidence of the satisfactory completion of continuing education requirements as determined and published by the board;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     shall receive and investigate complaints relating to the practice of speech-language pathology and audiology and may report the same to the proper prosecuting officers where appropriate. The board may, after a hearing held pursuant to chapter 30A, revoke, suspend or place on probation the license or certificate of or reprimand a speech-language pathologist or audiologist or a speech-language pathology assistant or audiology assistant if such person:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     fraudulently procures a license or certificate;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     has violated any laws relative to the practice of speech-language pathology or audiology or any rule or regulation adopted thereunder;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     has committed professional misconduct in the practice of speech-language pathology or audiology; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     has practiced speech-language pathology or audiology while the ability to so practice was impaired by alcohol or drugs; provided, however, that a person whose license or certificate has been revoked may apply for relicensure or recertification after 1 year from the date of revocation and the board may, in its discretion, grant such relicensure or recertification upon such terms and conditions as the board may deem appropriate; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     shall prepare annually a list of the names and addresses of persons who are licensed or certified to practice speech-language pathology or audiology.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>