<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87AAA</section_number>
    <catch_line>Complaints; Investigation By Board; Revocation Or Suspension Of License; Grounds; Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>87AAA</order_by>
    <text>
        The board may, and upon the verified complaint in writing of an aggrieved person shall, investigate the action of any broker or salesman or any person who attempts to act in such capacity within the commonwealth, and, in addition to any grounds hereinbefore enumerated, may suspend, revoke or refuse to renew any license which it has found to have been obtained by false or fraudulent representation. The board may suspend, revoke or refuse to renew any license, when the board has found as a fact that the licensee, in performing or attempting to perform any act authorized by his license, has (a) knowingly made any substantial misrepresentation; (b) acted in the dual capacity of broker and undisclosed principal in the same transaction; (c) acted for more than one party to a transaction without the knowledge and consent of all the parties for whom he acts; (d) failed, within a reasonable time, to account for or remit any moneys belonging to others which have come into his possession as a broker or salesman; (e) paid commissions or fees to or divided the same with any person, who, being required to be licensed as a broker or salesman in this or any other state, is not so licensed; (f) accepted, given or charged any undisclosed commission, rebate or profit on expenditures for a principal; (g) induced any party to a contract or lease relating to real estate to break the same when such action is effected for the personal gain of the licensee; (h) commingled the money or other property of his principal with his own; (i) failed to give to both the buyer and seller a copy of the purchase and sale agreement; (j) committed any act expressly prohibited in sections eighty-seven RR to eighty-seven CCC, inclusive; (k) affirmatively solicited for sale, lease, or the listing for sale or lease, of residential property on the grounds of alleged change of value due to the presence or the prospective entry into the neighborhood of a person or persons of another race, economic level, religion or ethnic origin or distributes, or causes to be distributed, material or makes statements designated to induce a residential property owner to sell or lease his property due to such change in the neighborhood; or (l) accepted from a prospective seller a net listing, an agreement to sell real estate for a stated price which authorized the broker to keep as commission any amount of money received from the sale of said real estate in excess of the stated price. The board shall, after notice by the Massachusetts commission against discrimination that said commission has made a finding, which finding has become final, that a licensed broker or salesman committed an unlawful practice in violation of chapter one hundred and fifty-one B arising out of or in the course of his occupation as a licensed broker or salesman, shall suspend forthwith the license of said broker or salesman for a period of sixty days, and, if the said commission finds that said violation by such licensed broker or salesman occurred within two years of the date of a prior violation of said chapter one hundred and fifty-one B, which finding has been final, it shall so notify the board, and the board shall forthwith suspend the license of such broker or salesman for a period of ninety days. Whoever violates the provisions of clause (k) shall be punished by a fine of not less than one thousand nor more than twenty-five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or both. 
No broker shall engage in a sale in the commonwealth of real property located in a land development in another state which is the subject of promotional advertising in the commonwealth unless the owner or developer of such land has submitted to the board full particulars regarding such land and the proposed terms of sale thereof and has deposited with the board such sum as it shall determine, to pay the expense of the investigation hereinafter prescribed. Any broker acting for such owner or developer, and his salesmen, shall comply with such rules, regulations, restrictions and conditions pertaining thereto as the board in its discretion may impose. The board shall investigate such matters and all reasonable expenses incurred by the board in such investigation shall be borne by the owner or developer of the property involved. No broker or salesman shall in any manner refer to the board of registration of real estate brokers and salesmen or to any member or employee thereof, in selling, offering for sale, or advertising or otherwise promoting the sale, mortgage or lease of any such property, nor make any representation whatsoever that such property has been inspected or approved or otherwise passed upon by said board or by any official, department or employee of the commonwealth. The board may suspend, revoke or refuse to renew any license when it has found that the licensee has failed to comply with the requirements of this paragraph or any part thereof. 
The board may also suspend, revoke or refuse to renew any license when it has found that the licensee has been convicted of a criminal offence by a court of competent jurisdiction of this or any other state which demonstrates his lack of good moral character to act as a broker or salesman as the case may be. 
The board may reconsider any decision made by it and may reinstate any license which has been suspended and reissue any license which has been revoked. 
Any person whose license is suspended or revoked shall also be liable to such other punishment as may be provided by law.
    </text>
</law>