<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2JJJ</section_number>
    <catch_line>Registers Technological Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2JJJ</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  (a) There shall be established on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Registers Technological Fund for the benefit of the registers of deeds under the control of the state secretary. This fund shall consist of the amounts specified in and collected pursuant to section 31 of chapter 9. The state treasurer shall deposit these amounts into the fund, which shall be expended solely for the purposes of automation, modernization, operation and technological improvements at the registries of deeds. The state secretary for the benefit of the registers under his control, shall submit a spending plan to the clerks of the house of representatives and senate, who shall refer the plan to the house and senate committees on ways and means and house and senate committees on post audit and oversight. In preparing the plan, the secretary shall consult with the commonwealth's chief information officer and require that the projects and purchases funded through disbursements in this section shall be consistent with the enterprise information technology strategy, plan and information technology standards adopted by him. All such monies shall be used to purchase information technology systems that are interoperable with other like systems that are used or will be used by all registries. The plan shall include, but not be limited to, the cost and description of all intangible, personal and real property to be purchased or services to be received and any and all personnel changes for the automation, modernization, operation and technological improvements. If the general court takes no final action relative to the plan within 30 days after the date on which the plan is first referred to those committees, the state treasurer shall disburse the funds according to the plan.  (b) In conjunction with the preparation of the commonwealth's comprehensive annual financial report, the comptroller shall prepare and issue an annual report detailing the revenue and expenditure of the fund.
Chapter 29: Registers Technological Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  (a) There shall be established on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Registers Technological Fund for the benefit of the registers of deeds under the control of the state secretary. This fund shall consist of the amounts specified in and collected under section 31 of chapter 9. The state treasurer shall deposit these amounts into the fund, which shall be expended solely for the purposes of automation, modernization, operation and technological improvements at the registries of deeds. The state secretary for the benefit of the registers under the secretary's control, shall submit a spending plan to the clerks of the house of representatives and senate, who shall refer the plan to the house and senate committees on ways and means and house and senate committees on post audit and oversight. In preparing the plan, the secretary shall consult with the commonwealth's chief information officer and require that the projects and purchases funded through disbursements in this section shall be consistent with the enterprise information technology strategy, plan and information technology standards adopted by the chief information officer. All such monies shall be used to purchase information technology systems that are interoperable with other like systems that are used or will be used by all registries. The plan shall include, but not be limited to, the cost and description of all intangible, personal and real property to be purchased or services to be received and any and all personnel changes for the automation, modernization, operation and technological improvements. If the general court takes no final action relative to the plan within 30 days after the date on which the plan is first referred to those committees, the state treasurer shall disburse the funds according to the plan.  (b) In conjunction with the preparation of the commonwealth comprehensive annual financial report, the comptroller shall prepare and issue an annual report detailing the revenue and expenditure of the fund.
    </text>
</law>