<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>124A</section_number>
    <catch_line>World War Ii, Korean Emergency And Vietnam Conflict Memorial Commission; Members; Compensation; Honor Rolls</catch_line>
    <order_by>124A</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a World War II, Korean Emergency and Vietnam Conflict memorial commission, hereinafter called the commission, consisting of the commissioner of veterans’ services, ex officio, and two persons to be appointed by the governor, of whom one shall be a director of the U.S.S. Massachusetts Memorial Committee, Incorporated, a charitable corporation established under chapter one hundred and eighty. The appointive members of the commission shall be appointed for terms of three years. The members of the commission shall receive no compensation for their services as such members but shall be reimbursed for their necessary traveling expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. 
Upon the transfer of the U.S.S. Massachusetts from the United States to said corporation said commission shall, with the consent of said corporation, erect and maintain thereon an honor roll in memory of those members of the armed forces of the United States from the commonwealth who died in the service of their country during World War II and the Persian Gulf War, also known as Operation Desert Storm, and suitable facilities to honor the dead of said wars. Said U.S.S. Massachusetts is hereby designated as the Massachusetts World War II Memorial. 
Upon the transfer of the U.S.S. Joseph P. Kennedy, Jr. from the United States to said corporation said commission shall, with the consent of said corporation, erect and maintain thereon an honor roll in memory of those members of the armed forces of the United States from the commonwealth who died in the service of their country during the Korean Emergency and the Vietnam Conflict and suitable facilities to honor the dead of said wars. Said U.S.S. Joseph P. Kennedy, Jr. is hereby designated as the Massachusetts Korean Emergency and Vietnam Conflict Memorial.
    </text>
</law>