<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="130" order_by="130" level="3">Marine Fish And Fisheries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Marine Fisheries Advisory Commission</catch_line>
    <order_by>1B</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be in the division of marine fisheries a commission to be known as the marine fisheries advisory commission hereinafter called the commission, which shall consist of nine members, qualified in the field of marine fisheries by training and experience, to be appointed by the governor with the approval of the council. As the term of a member expires, his successor shall be appointed for a term of three years, except that initially three members shall be appointed for terms of two years and three members shall be appointed for terms of one year. The governor may also, with the like approval, fill any vacancy in an unexpired term. No member of the commission shall hold any other position in the department while serving as such, nor for a period of two years thereafter. 
The commission shall annually elect its own chairman and clerk and shall keep accurate records of its meetings and hearings and shall meet at least quarterly and at the call of the chairman. A quorum to conduct business shall consist of five members. The commission shall hold public hearings relative to matters within the jurisdiction of the division and shall make recommendations to the director for the proper management and development of the marine fisheries of the commonwealth. The director or his designee shall attend all meetings and hearings of the commission and may present evidence thereat and shall include in his annual report a report of the commission. The members of the commission shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties.
    </text>
</law>