<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111H" order_by="111H" level="3">Massachusetts Low Level Radioactive Waste Management Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>37</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commencement Of Facility Construction</catch_line>
    <order_by>37</order_by>
    <text>
        Upon the determination of the department of public health that the environmental monitoring program or detailed site characterization of the superior site has yielded representative baseline data, the operator may commence construction of the facility. The operator shall construct, install and, from time to time, in accordance with the regulations adopted under section sixteen and the conditions of its facility license, make additions or improvements to such structures and equipment as are necessary to operate the facility. Said department shall, in cooperation with officials of each site community and according to the regulations adopted pursuant to said section sixteen, periodically inspect such construction to ensure that such regulations and the conditions of the license are satisfied. The board shall appoint a resident engineer having the experience and expertise specified in section forty-two J of chapter seven, who shall represent the board daily at the superior site during the construction of the facility and who shall, in cooperation with officials of each site community, check, inspect and report to the board as to events at the construction site, in order to ensure that the terms of the comprehensive operating contract are satisfied. The commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall assist said department and the board in fulfilling their obligations under this section, and shall advise them on the adequacy of construction activities.
    </text>
</law>