<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132B" order_by="132B" level="3">Massachusetts Pesticide Control Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Pesticide Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be within the department of food and agriculture a pesticide board which shall consist of the commissioner of environmental protection or his designee, the commissioner of food and agriculture or his designee, the director of the division of food and drugs or his designee, the commissioner of fisheries, wildlife and recreational vehicles or his designee, the commissioner of environmental management or his designee, the commissioner of public health or his designee, and seven persons appointed by the governor one of whom shall have been engaged in the commercial production of a plant-related agricultural commodity for at least the preceding five years on land owned or rented by him, one of whom shall have been an active commercial applicator of pesticides for at least the preceding five years, one of whom shall have expertise in the health effects of pesticide use, one of whom shall be a physician, one of whom shall be experienced in the conservation and protection of the environment, and two of whom shall represent the public at large. The commissioner of food and agriculture or his designee shall be chairman of the board. 
The appointive members of the board shall receive fifty dollars for each day or portion thereof spent in the discharge of their official duties and shall be reimbursed for their necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their official duties. Each appointive member shall be appointed for a term of four years, except for persons appointed to fill vacancies who shall serve for the unexpired term. Any member shall be eligible for reappointment. 
The board shall hold an annual meeting in March, and regularly at three other times annually, and from time to time at the call of the chairman or upon the request of any two members. 
Seven members of the board shall constitute a quorum. The board may, by vote of a majority of its members then in office, adopt rules and regulations for the conduct of its business. Rules and regulations adopted may be amended or repealed by a two-thirds vote of its members. 
The board in addition to other powers conferred in this chapter shall advise the commissioner of food and agriculture with respect to the implementation and administration of this chapter. 
The pesticides program director established by section four shall attend meetings of the board, shall serve as secretary thereto, but shall have no vote in its deliberation.
    </text>
</law>