<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118G" order_by="118G" level="3">Health Care Finance And Policy</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Conditions For Reimbursement Or Payment By Governmental Units To Certain Health Care Service Providers;  Penalties For Non Compliance</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 224, Sec. 132.]  Any provider of health care services that receives reimbursement or payment for treatment of injured workers under chapter one hundred fifty-two and any provider of health care services other than an acute or non-acute hospital that receives reimbursement or payment from any governmental unit for general health supplies, care and rehabilitative services and accommodations, shall, as a condition of such reimbursement or payment: (1) permit the secretary, or any designated representative thereof, the attorney general or his designee, to examine such books and accounts as may reasonably be required for it to perform its duties; (2) file with the secretary from time to time or on request, such data, statistics, schedules, or other information as it may reasonably require, including outcome data and such information regarding the costs, if any, of such provider for research in the basic biomedical or health delivery areas or for the training of health care personnel which are included in its charges to the public for health care services, supplies and accommodations; and (3) accept reimbursement or payment at the rates established by the secretary, subject to a right of appeal under section nine, as discharging in full any and all obligations of an eligible person and the governmental unit to pay, reimburse or compensate the provider of health care services in any way for general health supplies, care, and rehabilitative services or accommodations provided.  Any provider of health care services that knowingly fails to file with the division data, statistics, schedules or other information required pursuant to this section or by any regulation promulgated by the division or knowingly falsifies the same shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred nor more than five hundred dollars.  If, upon application by the division or its designated representative, the superior court upon summary hearing determines that a provider of health care services has, without justifiable cause, refused to permit any examination or to furnish information, as required in this section, it shall issue an order directing all governmental units to withhold payment for general health supplies, care and rehabilitative services and accommodations to such provider of services until further order of the court.  In addition, the appropriate licensing authority may suspend or revoke, after an adjudicatory proceeding in accordance with chapter thirty A, the license of any provider of services that knowingly fails to file with the division data, statistics, schedules or other information required by this section or by any regulation of the division or that knowingly falsifies the same.
    </text>
</law>