<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="105A" order_by="105A" level="3">Self Service Storage Facilities</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:— 
“Self-service storage facility”, any real property used for renting or leasing individual storage spaces in which the occupants themselves customarily store and remove their own personal property on a “self-service” basis. 
“Rental agreement”, any written agreement that establishes or modifies the terms, conditions, or rules concerning the use and occupancy of a self-service storage facility. 
“Leased space”, the individual storage space at the self-service facility which is rented to an occupant pursuant to a rental agreement. 
“Occupant”, a person, a sublessee, successor, or assign, entitled to the use of a leased space at a self-service storage facility under a rental agreement. 
“Operator”, the owner, operator, lessor or sublessor of a self-service storage facility, an agent or any other person authorized to manage the facility and shall not mean a warehouseman, unless the operator issues a warehouse receipt, bill of lading, or other document of title for the personal property stored. 
“Personal property”, movable property, not affixed to land, including but not limited to, goods, wares, merchandise, motor vehicles, watercraft, and household items and furnishings. 
“Default”, the failure to perform on time any obligation or duty set forth in the rental agreement. 
“Last known address”, that address provided by the occupant in the rental agreement or the address provided by the occupant in a subsequent written notice of a change of address.
    </text>
</law>