<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="123" order_by="123" level="3">Mental Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32</section_number>
    <catch_line>Charges For Care Of Persons In Facilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>32</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  The department may make charges for the care of any person in its facilities. To the extent that any person in its facilities is eligible for third party payment of charges for care, the department shall make said charges for care at rates established by the division of health care finance and policy. To the extent that third party payment is not available, or is not sufficient to pay said charges, the charges may be recovered from said person, or from any person with a legal obligation to support the person; provided, however, that said person shall be entitled to retain one thousand dollars in cash or personal property; and provided, further, that the department shall make adjustments to the charges based upon said person's individual circumstances. The department also shall establish, by regulation, a system of charges for care in programs funded by or under a contract with the department which is consistent with the provisions of this section.
Chapter 123: Charges for care of persons in facilities
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 136 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  The department may make charges for the care of any person in its facilities. To the extent that any person in its facilities is eligible for third party payment of charges for care, the department shall make said charges for care at rates established by the executive office of health and human services or a governmental unit designated by the executive office. To the extent that third party payment is not available, or is not sufficient to pay said charges, the charges may be recovered from said person, or from any person with a legal obligation to support the person; provided, however, that said person shall be entitled to retain one thousand dollars in cash or personal property; and provided, further, that the department shall make adjustments to the charges based upon said person's individual circumstances. The department also shall establish, by regulation, a system of charges for care in programs funded by or under a contract with the department which is consistent with the provisions of this section.
    </text>
</law>