<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6D" order_by="6D" level="3">Health Policy Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Registration Program For Provider Organizations;  Division Of Insurance Risk Certificate</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 15 effective November 4, 2012.]  (a) The commission shall develop and administer a registration program for provider organizations. A provider organization shall be registered for a term of 2 years and renewable under like terms. The commission shall coordinate with state agencies including, but not limited to, the center, the division of insurance, the executive office of health and human services, the office of Medicaid and the department of public health to minimize duplicative reporting requirements. The commission may enter interagency service agreements to perform these functions including but not limited to the sharing of data collected. The commission, in consultation with the center, shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to ensure the uniform reporting of data collected under this section.  (b) The commission shall require that all provider organizations report the following information for registration and renewal: (i) organizational charts showing the ownership, governance and operational structure of the provider organization, including any clinical affiliations, parent entities, corporate affiliates, and community advisory boards; (ii) the number of affiliated health care professional full-time equivalents and the number of professionals affiliated with or employed by the organization; (iii) the name and address of licensed facilities; and (iv) such other information as the commission considers appropriate.  (c) Upon receiving an application for registration, the commission may, within 30 days, require an applicant to provide additional information to complete or supplement the filing. The commission shall determine whether an application is complete within 45 days of receipt of the application and any supplementary information. The commission shall provide the applicant with a written notice that provider organization's registration is complete and provide a copy of the completed registration materials to the division of insurance. The commission may assess a reasonable registration or administrative fee on the registration of provider organizations to support the commission's operations and administration.  (d) The commission shall support the division of insurance in its review of risk-bearing provider organizations under chapter 176U and the center in its efforts to collect and analyze data. The commission shall promulgate regulations setting forth a process for provider organizations to submit proposed changes to its structure.  (e) A risk bearing provider organization shall provide the commission with a division of insurance risk certificate under chapter 176U. The commission may suspend, revoke or refuse to renew a risk-bearing provider organization's registration for failure to proffer a risk certificate.
    </text>
</law>