<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="117A" order_by="117A" level="3">Support By The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Final Disposition Of Deceased Persons;  Recovery Of Expenses From Deceased's Kindred</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The department shall provide for the decent final disposition of all deceased persons who are at the time of death recipients of aid or assistance under this chapter, all deceased persons who, although without means of support at the time of death, did not apply for such aid or assistance and all unknown persons found dead. The expense thereof may be recovered from their kindred, if any, chargeable by law for their support in the manner provided in this chapter and if the expense of the funeral and final disposition is not paid by the kindred, an amount not exceeding $1,100 shall be paid by the commonwealth to the funeral establishment; provided, however, that the commonwealth shall have the right of reimbursement from whatever resources may exist in the estate of the deceased person.
Chapter 117A: Final disposition of deceased persons; recovery of expenses from deceased's kindred
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 116 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The department shall provide for the decent final disposition of all deceased persons who are at the time of death recipients of aid or assistance under this chapter, all deceased persons who, although without means of support at the time of death, did not apply for such aid or assistance and all unknown persons found dead. The commonwealth may recover this expense from any legally liable family members in the manner provided in this chapter, and if such family members do not pay this expense, the commonwealth shall pay an amount not exceeding $1,100 to the funeral establishment if the total expense of the funeral and final disposition does not exceed $3,500. The commonwealth shall have the right of reimbursement from whatever resources may exist in the estate of the deceased person.
    </text>
</law>