<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>142E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Air Pollution; Preventing And Controlling By Departments, Agencies, Commissions, Authorities And Political Subdivisions</catch_line>
    <order_by>142E</order_by>
    <text>
        Any department, agency, commission, authority or political subdivision of the commonwealth having control and supervision over any building, installation or other property shall cooperate with the department of environmental protection in preventing and controlling pollution of the air insofar as the discharge of any matter from or by such building, installation or other property may cause or contribute to air pollution. 
All departments, agencies, commissions, authorities and political subdivisions shall be subject to rules and regulations adopted by the department pursuant to sections one hundred and forty-two A to one hundred and forty-two C, inclusive. The department may serve upon any such department, agency, commission, authority or political subdivision an order to cease and desist from violating such rules or regulations. If objection to such order is made within ten days, the department, agency, commission, authority or political subdivision so objecting shall be entitled to a hearing before a person designated by the commissioner whose recommendations when adopted, or amended and adopted, by the department of environmental protection shall be a final decision within the meaning of section fourteen of chapter thirty A, subject to judicial review as therein provided. If such order is violated the department may file a bill of complaint in the superior court to enjoin such violation; provided, however, that in such a proceeding the sole questions in issue shall be (1) was the order of the department violated and (2) is the relief sought appropriate.
    </text>
</law>