<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Reporting And Certification Of Tax Revenues Estimated To Have Been Collected From Capital Gains Income During Preceding Periods;  Transfer Of Excess Amounts Collected To Commonwealth Stabilization Fund And State Retiree Benefits Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>5G</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The department of revenue shall report by November 30 to the state comptroller, the executive office for administration and finance and the house and senate committees on ways and means tax revenues estimated to have been collected during the preceding fiscal year from capital gains income. After each quarter, the department of revenue shall certify to the state comptroller the amount of tax revenues estimated to have been collected during the preceding quarter from capital gains income. If the department of revenue certifies that the amount of tax revenues estimated to have been collected from capital gains income exceeds $1,000,000,000 in a fiscal year, the comptroller shall transfer quarterly any such amount that exceeds $1,000,000,000 collected during that fiscal year to the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund established by section 2H. This transfer shall be made before the certification of the consolidated net surplus for the previous fiscal year as provided in section 5C. Five per cent of any amount transferred to the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund under this section shall then be transferred from the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund to the State Retiree Benefits Trust Fund established in section 24 of chapter 32A.
Chapter 29: Reporting and certification of tax revenues estimated to have been collected from capital gains income during preceding periods; transfer of excess amounts collected to Commonwealth Stabilization Fund and other funds
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.][ First paragraph as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 does not take effect. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  After each quarter, the department of revenue shall certify to the state comptroller the amount of tax revenues estimated to have been collected during the preceding quarter from capital gains income. If the department of revenue certifies that the amount of tax revenues estimated to have been collected from capital gains income exceeds the product of $1,000,000,000 and allowable growth in a fiscal year, the comptroller shall transfer quarterly any such amount to the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund established by section 2H.[ First paragraph as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 and amended by 2012, 239, Sec. 8 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 239, Sec. 60. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  After each quarter, the department of revenue shall certify to the state comptroller the amount of tax revenues estimated to have been collected during the preceding quarter from capital gains income. If the department of revenue certifies that the amount of tax revenues estimated to have been collected from capital gains income exceeds $1,000,000,000 in a fiscal year, the comptroller shall transfer quarterly any such amount that exceeds $1,000,000,000 collected during that fiscal year to the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund established in section 2H. The $1,000,000,000 threshold established in the preceding sentence shall be adjusted annually to reflect the average annual rate of growth in United States gross domestic product over the preceding 5 years based on the most recently available data published by the Bureau of Economic Analysis in the United States Department of Commerce.  This transfer shall be made before the certification of the consolidated net surplus for the previous fiscal year under section 5C. The department of revenue shall report by November 30 to the state comptroller, the executive office for administration and finance and the house and senate committees on ways and means tax revenues estimated to have been collected during the preceding fiscal year from capital gains income. The comptroller shall not make adjustment to amounts previously transferred if the capital gains revenue reported on November 30 differs from the amounts estimated during the preceding fiscal year.  Five per cent of any amount transferred to the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund under this section shall then be transferred from the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund to the State Retiree Benefits Trust Fund established in section 24 of chapter 32A and 5 per cent of any amount transferred to the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund under this section shall then be transferred from the Commonwealth Stabilization Fund to the Commonwealth's Pension Liability Fund established in section 22 of chapter 32.
    </text>
</law>