<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Obligations Incurred Against Appropriation Or Subsidiary Accounts For Future Items Delivered Or Services Rendered</catch_line>
    <order_by>12A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Beginning June first of any year, obligations may be incurred against appropriation accounts or subsidiary accounts for items to be delivered or for services to be rendered on or after the beginning of the next fiscal year; provided, however, that said obligations are in accordance with law and the amounts thereof do not exceed one-twelfth of the appropriation account or subsidiary account for the current fiscal year.  Where the allotment of an appropriation account or subsidiary account is a condition precedent to expenditure, the obligations shall not exceed the amount allotted for said appropriation account or subsidiary account; provided, however, that during the month of June the comptroller may prepare warrants and the state treasurer may advance funds to the department of public welfare for the purpose of making payments on and after July first as authorized by chapter six hundred and fifty-eight of the acts of nineteen hundred and sixty-seven; and provided further that said payments are in accordance with law and the amounts thereof do not exceed the amount of the appropriation account or subsidiary account, provided, however, that no funds shall be expended until such funds have been appropriated. The certified copies of the schedules provided for in section twenty-seven shall be filed with the comptroller and the budget director as of June first. Where the allotment of an appropriation account or subsidiary account is required by law, such allotment shall be made as of June first.  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, in order to comply with the Social Security Act, the comptroller may present in his certificate to the governor's council, and the state treasurer, with the consent of the council, may transfer to the United States Treasury before July funds necessary to make July 1 Supplemental Security Income payments to commonwealth benefit recipients.
Chapter 29: Obligations incurred against appropriation or subsidiary accounts for future items delivered or services rendered
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Beginning June 1 of any year, obligations may be incurred against appropriations for items to be delivered or for services to be rendered on or after the beginning of the next fiscal year; provided, however, that said obligations are in accordance with law and the amounts of the obligations do not exceed one-twelfth of that appropriation for the current fiscal year.  Where the allotment of an appropriation is a condition precedent to expenditure, the obligations shall not exceed the amount allotted for said appropriation; provided, however, that during June the comptroller may prepare warrants and the state treasurer may advance funds to the department of transitional assistance to make payments on and after July 1 as authorized by chapter 658 of the acts of 1967; and provided further that said payments are in accordance with law and the amounts of said payments do not exceed the amount of the appropriation, provided, however, that no funds shall be expended until such funds have been appropriated. The certified copies of the schedules provided for in section 27 shall be filed with the comptroller and the budget director as of June 1. If the allotment of an appropriation is required by law, such allotment shall be made as of June 1.[ Third paragraph as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 does not take effect. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, in order to comply with the Social Security Act, the state treasurer may transfer to the United States Treasury before July funds necessary to make July 1 Supplemental Security Income payments to commonwealth benefit recipients.[ Third paragraph as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 and amended by 2012, 239, Sec. 9 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 239, Sec. 60. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  In order to make timely state supplementary payments, the comptroller may present in the comptroller's certificate to the governor's council, and the state treasurer, with the consent of the council, may transfer to the United States Treasury or the entity administering the program of state supplementary payments, before July 1, funds necessary to make July payments to commonwealth benefit recipients.
    </text>
</law>