<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="19A" order_by="19A" level="3">Department Of Elder Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Pharmacy Outreach Program; Medication Education And Intervention Resource Center; Executive Office Of Elder Affairs</catch_line>
    <order_by>4C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meanings:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     There is hereby established the pharmacy outreach program for the purposes of assisting residents of the commonwealth in obtaining free or low cost prescription medications or nonprescription medications from pharmaceutical manufacturers and educating such persons about health care issues related to medications. The office shall administer the program in conjunction with an outside vendor who shall be selected by the office pursuant to procurement regulations promulgated under the authority of the executive office of administration and finance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The pharmacy outreach program shall assist eligible persons in procuring free or low cost prescription medications or nonprescription medications by:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     evaluating the likelihood of success of an eligible person’s obtaining free or low cost prescription medications or nonprescription medications from a participating manufacturer under the guidelines formulated;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     assisting an eligible person with the preparation of an application for prescription medications or nonprescription medications to participating manufacturers; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     coordinating and assisting a physician registered pursuant to section 2 of chapter 112 with communications, including applications, made on behalf of an eligible person to a participating manufacturer for the purpose of obtaining approval of the eligible person in any voluntary drug assistance program.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The pharmacy outreach program shall also establish a medication education and intervention resource center which shall:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     create and maintain a statewide toll free telephone number staffed by individuals who are qualified to counsel and advise eligible persons and anyone participating in the prescription drug subsidized insurance program pursuant to sections 39 and 40, on questions that they may have about prescription drugs or nonprescription drugs;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     sponsor and organize presentations, workshops and screenings in conjunction with other organizations that serve the interests of the elderly and other eligible persons on issues of mental and physical health;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     offer and provide information on prescription medications and nonprescription medications including, but not limited to, information on drug interactions and abuse; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     offer in-person counseling to eligible persons for the purpose of explaining proper medication use and discouraging medication misuse.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The office shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to implement the pharmacy outreach program.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>