<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>172K</section_number>
    <catch_line>Climbing Wall Or Challenge Course Program Employee Or Volunteer Previously Subject To Record Check; Simultaneous Applications For Record Check</catch_line>
    <order_by>172K</order_by>
    <text>
        [First paragraph effective until May 4, 2012. For text effective May 4, 2012, see below.] 
Notwithstanding section 172 or any other general or special law to the contrary, any children’s camp or school that plans to employ or accept as a volunteer for a climbing wall or challenge course program, a person who is or has previously been the subject of a record check pursuant to sections 172G, 172H, 172I or section 38R of chapter 71, shall not be required to conduct a second record check by reason of such person’s employment or volunteering for a climbing wall or challenge course program, within 12 months of the previous record check. Such camp or school may either simultaneously submit to the criminal history systems board applications for a record check under sections 172G, 172H, 172I or section 38R of chapter 71 and this section, or use the information obtained within the prior 12 months under sections 172G, 172H, 172I or section 38R of chapter 71 for the purpose of the climbing wall or challenge course program. If the camp or school submits simultaneous applications, the criminal history systems board shall conduct the most comprehensive record check required by either application, and the results of such record check shall satisfy the camp or school’s obligations to request record information with respect to both job functions. The camp or school may also disseminate information obtained under this section to the department of public safety. The criminal history systems board shall only assess the camp or school 1 fee for simultaneous requests filed pursuant to this section. 
[First paragraph as amended by 2010, 256, Sec. 32 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102. For text effective until May 4, 2012, see above.] 
Notwithstanding section 172 or any other general or special law to the contrary, any children’s camp or school that plans to employ or accept as a volunteer for a climbing wall or challenge course program, a person who is or has previously been the subject of a record check pursuant to sections 172G, 172H, 172I or section 38R of chapter 71, shall not be required to conduct a second record check by reason of such person’s employment or volunteering for a climbing wall or challenge course program, within 12 months of the previous record check. Such camp or school may either simultaneously submit to the department applications for a record check under sections 172G, 172H, 172I or section 38R of chapter 71 and this section, or use the information obtained within the prior 12 months under sections 172G, 172H, 172I or section 38R of chapter 71 for the purpose of the climbing wall or challenge course program. If the camp or school submits simultaneous applications, the department shall conduct the most comprehensive record check required by either application, and the results of such record check shall satisfy the camp or school’s obligations to request record information with respect to both job functions. The camp or school may also disseminate information obtained under this section to the department of public safety. The department shall only assess the camp or school 1 fee for simultaneous requests filed pursuant to this section. 
Information obtained pursuant to this section shall not be disseminated for any purpose other than to further the protection of children.
    </text>
</law>