<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87SS</section_number>
    <catch_line>Applicants For License; Requisites; Attorney At Law;  Examinations; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>87SS</order_by>
    <text>
        No license to engage as a broker or salesman shall be issued to any applicant unless he has complied with all the pertinent provisions of this section and sections eighty-seven TT to eighty-seven DDD, inclusive, and if the applicant is an individual, unless he shall have satisfactorily passed a written examination conducted by the board or an independent testing service designated by the board, and, in the case of an application for a broker’s license by an individual resident of the commonwealth, unless he shall have had his principal place of abode within the commonwealth for one year next prior to the issuance of such license; provided, however, that any applicant who is an attorney at law of the commonwealth shall not be required to take such examination or to have had such principal place of abode for such period. 
Every individual applicant for a license as a salesman who is required to take an examination therefor shall, as a prerequisite to taking such examination, submit proof satisfactory to the board that he has completed courses in real estate subjects approved by the board, such courses to total 40 classroom hours of instruction; provided, however, that applicants having successfully completed a course in real property while enrolled in an accredited law school in the commonwealth may also take such examination. Every individual applicant for a license as a broker who is required to take an examination therefor shall, as a prerequisite to taking such examination, submit proof satisfactory to the board that he has been actively associated with a real estate broker for a period of 3 years as a real estate salesman and that he has completed additional courses in real estate subjects approved by the board, such courses to total 40 classroom hours of instruction. 
Such examination shall be prepared by the board or the designated independent testing service to enable the board to determine the competence of the applicant to transact the business of a broker or a salesman. The board or its designated independent testing service shall conduct such examinations at least six times in each calendar year for broker’s examinations and at least eight times in each calendar year for salesman’s examinations. There shall be no limit placed on the number of applicants who may take the examinations on any examination date. In determining competence the board shall require proof that the applicant has a fair understanding of the principles of real estate practice, real estate agreements and principal and agent relations, of the rudimentary principles of the economics and appraising of real estate, and of the provisions of sections eighty-seven PP to eighty-seven DDD, inclusive. The examination for a salesman’s license shall be based upon the same general subject matter as for a broker’s license, but shall be more elementary in character. 
The board may make, and from time to time alter, amend or repeal rules and regulations for the conduct of such examinations not inconsistent herewith.
    </text>
</law>