<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="57" order_by="57" level="3">Congressional, Councillor And Senatorial Districts, And Apportionment Of Representatives</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Division Of State Into Representative Districts</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
          For the purposes of choosing representatives in the general court until the next federal census and division of the commonwealth into representative districts, the commonwealth is divided, conformably with Article CI and Article CXVII of the Articles of Amendment of the Constitution, into the 160 following representative districts:--Barnstable, Dukes and Nantucket  First Barnstable.--Consisting of precinct 1 of the town of Barnstable, precincts 1 and 2 of the town of Brewster, the town of Dennis, and precincts 1, 2, 3, 4 and 7, of the town of Yarmouth, all in the county of Barnstable.  Second Barnstable.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 and 13, of the town of Barnstable, and precincts 5 and 6, of the town of Yarmouth, both in the county of Barnstable.  Third Barnstable.--Consisting of precincts 3, 4, 5 and 6, of the town of Bourne, precincts 3, 4, 7, 8 and 9, of the town of Falmouth, and the town of Mashpee, all in the county of Barnstable.  Fourth Barnstable.--Consisting of precinct 3 in the town of Brewster, the towns of Chatham, Eastham, Harwich, Orleans, Provincetown, Truro and Wellfleet, all in the county of Barnstable.  Fifth Barnstable.--Consisting of precincts 11 and 12, of the town of Barnstable, precincts 1, 2, and 7 of the town of Bourne, and the town of Sandwich, all in the county of Barnstable; and precinct 9 in the town of Plymouth, in the county of Plymouth.  Barnstable, Dukes and Nantucket.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2, 5 and 6, of the town of Falmouth, in the county of Barnstable; and the towns of Aquinnah, Chilmark, Edgartown, Gosnold, Oak Bluffs, Tisbury and West Tisbury, all in the county of Dukes County; and the town of Nantucket, in the county of Nantucket.Berkshire  First Berkshire.--Consisting of the towns of Adams, Cheshire, Clarksburg, Florida, Hancock, Lanesborough, New Ashford, North Adams, and Williamstown, all in the county of Berkshire.  Second Berkshire.--Consisting of the towns of Dalton, Hinsdale, Peru, precinct B of ward 1, of the city of Pittsfield, Savoy and Windsor all in the county of Berkshire; the towns of, Bernardston, Charlemont, Colrain, Greenfield, Hawley, Heath, Leyden, Monroe, Northfield, and Rowe, all in the county of Franklin.  Third Berkshire.--Consisting of precinct A of ward 1, all precincts of wards 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 and 7, of the city of Pittsfield, in the county of Berkshire.  Fourth Berkshire.--Consisting of the towns of Alford, Becket, Egremont, Great Barrington, Lee, Lenox, Monterey, Mount Washington, New Marlborough, Otis, Richmond, Sandisfield, Sheffield, Stockbridge, Tyringham, Washington and West Stockbridge, all in the county of Berkshire; and the towns of Blandford, Russell, and Tolland, all in the county of Hampden.Bristol  First Bristol.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3 and 6, of the town of Mansfield, and precincts 3, 4 and 5, of the town of Norton, both in the county of Bristol; and the town of Foxborough, in the county of Norfolk.  Second Bristol.--Consisting of all precincts in wards 1 and 2, precinct A of ward 3, and all precincts of wards 4, 5 and 6, of the city of Attleboro, in the county of Bristol.  Third Bristol.--Consisting of precinct 6 of the town of Easton, and all precincts of wards 1, 2, precinct A of ward 3, 5, 7 and 8, of the city of Taunton, both in the county of Bristol.  Fourth Bristol.--Consisting of precincts 1 and 2 of the town of Norton, the towns of Rehoboth and Seekonk, and precincts 4 and 5, of the town of Swansea, all in the county of Bristol.  Fifth Bristol.--Consisting of the towns of Dighton and Somerset, precincts 1, 2 and 3 of the town of Swansea, and all precincts of ward 6, of the city of Taunton, all in the county of Bristol.  Sixth Bristol.--Consisting of precincts B and C of ward 5, precinct C of ward 6, all precincts of wards 7, 8, and 9, of the city of Fall River, and precinct 1, of the town of Freetown, both in the county of Bristol.  Seventh Bristol.--Consisting of precincts B and C of ward 1, ward 2, ward 3, ward 4, and precinct A of ward 5, of the city of Fall River, in the county of Bristol.  Eighth Bristol.--Consisting of precinct A of ward 1, precincts A and B of ward 6 of the city of Fall River, precincts 2 and 3 of the town of Freetown, precincts D, E and F of ward 1 of the city of New Bedford, and the town of Westport, all in the county of Bristol.  Ninth Bristol.--Consisting of the town of Dartmouth, and precincts D, E and F of ward 3, of the city of New Bedford, both in the county of Bristol.  Tenth Bristol.--Consisting of the town of Fairhaven, and precinct A of ward 3, and precinct D and E of ward 4 in the city of New Bedford, in the county of Bristol; and the towns of Marion, Mattapoisett and Rochester, all in the county of Plymouth.  Eleventh Bristol.--Consisting of the town of Acushnet, precincts A, B, and C, of ward 1 and all precincts of ward 2, and precincts B and C of ward 3, of the city of New Bedford, both in the county of Bristol.  Twelfth Bristol.--Consisting of the town of Berkley, precinct B of ward 3 and ward 4 of the city of Taunton, in the county of Bristol; the town of Lakeville, and precincts 2, 4 and 5, of the town of Middleborough, both in the county of Plymouth.  Thirteenth Bristol.--Consisting of precincts A, B, C and F of ward 4, and wards 5 and 6, of the city of New Bedford, in the county of Bristol.  Fourteenth Bristol.--Consisting of precinct B of ward 3, of the city of Attleboro, precincts 1 and 5, of the town of Mansfield, the town of North Attleborough, all in the county of Bristol.Essex  First Essex.--Consisting of the towns of Amesbury and Salisbury, and the city of Newburyport, all in the county of Essex.  Second Essex.--Consisting of precincts 2 and 3 of the town of Boxford, the town of Georgetown, the town of Groveland, precinct 3 of ward 4 and precinct 3 of ward 7, of the city of Haverhill, and the towns of Merrimac, Newbury, and West Newbury, all in the county of Essex.  Third Essex.--Consisting of ward 1, precinct 3 of ward 2, ward 3, precincts 1 and 2 of ward 4, precincts 1 and 3 of ward 5, and ward 6, of the city of Haverhill, in the county of Essex.  Fourth Essex.--Consisting of the towns of Hamilton, Ipswich, Manchester-by-the-Sea, Rowley, Topsfield, and Wenham, all in the county of Essex.  Fifth Essex.--Consisting of the towns of Essex and Rockport, and the city of Gloucester, all in the county of Essex.  Sixth Essex.--Consisting of the city of Beverly, in the county of Essex.  Seventh Essex.--Consisting of the city of Salem, in the county of Essex.  Eighth Essex.--Consisting of precinct 4 of ward 3, and precinct 4 of ward 4, of the city of Lynn, and the towns of Marblehead and Swampscott, all in the county of Essex.  Ninth Essex.--Consisting of precincts 1 and 2 of ward 1, of the city of Lynn, and precincts 1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 and 9, of the town of Saugus, both in the county of Essex; and precincts 1, 2, 3 and 7, of the town of Wakefield, in the county of Middlesex.  Tenth Essex.--Consisting of precincts 3 and 4 of ward 1, ward 2, precincts 1, 2 and 3 of ward 3, precincts 1 and 2 of ward 4, and precincts 2 and 3 of ward 5, of the city of Lynn, in the county of Essex.  Eleventh Essex.--Consisting of precinct 3 of ward 4, precincts 1 and 4 of ward 5, wards 6 and 7, of the city of Lynn, and the town of Nahant, both in the county of Essex.  Twelfth Essex.--Consisting of wards 1, 2, 3, 4 and precincts 1 and 3 of ward 5, of the city of Peabody, in the county of Essex.  Thirteenth Essex.--Consisting of the town of Danvers, precinct 2 of the town of Middleton and, precinct 2 of ward 5 and ward 6, of the city of Peabody, all in the county of Essex.  Fourteenth Essex.--Consisting of precinct 2 of ward 7 in the city of Haverhill, precincts 1 and 3 of ward A and precinct 1 of ward F, of the city of Lawrence, precincts 3, 7, and 10 of the town of Methuen, and precincts 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5 of the town of North Andover, all in the county of Essex.  Fifteenth Essex.--Consisting of precincts 1 and 2 of ward 2, precinct 2 of ward 5 and precinct 1 of ward 7 in the town of Haverhill and precincts 1, 4, 5, 6, 8, 9, 11 and 12 of the town of Methuen, both in the county of Essex.  Sixteenth Essex.--Consisting of precincts 2 and 4 of ward A, ward B, precinct 4 of ward C, precincts 2, 3 and 4 of ward E, and precincts 2, 3 and 4 of ward F, of the city of Lawrence, in the county of Essex.  Seventeenth Essex.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3 and 4, of the town of Andover, precincts 1, 2 and 3, of ward C, ward D, and precinct 1 of ward E, of the city of Lawrence, and precinct 2 in the town of Methuen, all in the county of Essex.  Eighteenth Essex.--Consisting of precincts 1, 5, 6, 7, 8 and 9, of the town of Andover, precinct 1, of the town of Boxford and precincts 6, 7 and 8, of the town of North Andover, all in the county of Essex; and precincts 3 and 3A of the town Tewksbury, in the county of Middlesex.Franklin  First Franklin.--Consisting of the town of Chester, in the county of Hampden, and the towns of Ashfield, Buckland, Conway, Deerfield, Leverett, Montague, Shelburne, Shutesbury, Sunderland, Whately, in the county of Franklin; and the towns of Chesterfield, Cummington, Goshen, Huntington, Middlefield, Plainfield, Williamsburg and Worthington, all in the county of Hampshire.  Second Franklin.--Consisting of the towns of Erving, Gill, New Salem, Orange, Warwick, and Wendell, all in the county of Franklin; and precinct A of the town of Belchertown, in the county of Hampshire; and the towns of Athol, Petersham, Phillipston, Royalston, and Templeton all in the county of Worcester.Hampden  First Hampden.--Consisting of the towns of Brimfield, Holland, Palmer and Wales, all in the county of Hampden; precincts B and C, of the town of Ware, in the county of Hampshire; and the towns of Sturbridge and Warren, both in the county of Worcester.  Second Hampden.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3 and 4, of the town of East Longmeadow, the towns of Hampden, Longmeadow and Monson, all in the county of Hampden.  Third Hampden.--Consisting of the city of Agawam, Granville, and Southwick, in the county of Hampden.  Fourth Hampden.--Consisting of the city of Westfield, in the county of Hampden.  Fifth Hampden.--Consisting of the city of Holyoke, in the county of Hampden.  Sixth Hampden.--Consisting of precinct A of ward 2, precinct A of ward 3, precinct A of ward 4 of the city of Chicopee, precinct E of ward 2 of the city of Springfield, and the town of West Springfield, all in the county of Hampden.  Seventh Hampden.--Consisting of precinct B of ward 6, of the city of Chicopee, the town of Ludlow, precincts E, F and G of ward 8, of the city of Springfield, all in the county of Hampden; and precincts B, C and D, of the town of Belchertown, in the county of Hampshire.  Eighth Hampden.--Consisting of ward 1, precinct B of ward 2, precinct B of ward 3, precinct B of ward 4, precinct B of ward 5, precinct A of ward 6, wards 7, 8 and 9, of the city of Chicopee, in the county of Hampden.  Ninth Hampden.--Consisting of precinct A of ward 5 of the city of Chicopee, and precincts A, B, C, D, F and G of ward 2, precincts C, D, G and H of ward 5, precincts F and H of ward 7, and precincts A, B, D and H of ward 8, of the city of Springfield, both in the county of Hampden.  Tenth Hampden.--Consisting of ward 1, precincts B, C, D, E, F, G and H of ward 3, and precincts A, B and F of ward 6, of the city of Springfield, in the county of Hampden.  Eleventh Hampden.--Consisting of precinct H of ward 2, precinct A of ward 3, ward 4, precincts A, B, E and F of ward 5, precinct E of ward 6, precinct A of ward 7, and precinct C of ward 8, of the city of Springfield, in the county of Hampden.  Twelfth Hampden.--Consisting of precinct 1 of the town of East Longmeadow, precincts C, D, G and H of ward 6, precincts B, C, D, E and G of ward 7, of the city of Springfield, and the town of Wilbraham, all in the county of Hampden.Hampshire  First Hampshire.--Consisting of the town of Montgomery, in the county of Hampden; and the towns of Hatfield, Southampton and Westhampton, and the city of Northampton, all in the county of Hampshire.  Second Hampshire.--Consisting of the towns of Easthampton, precinct 2 of the town of Granby, Hadley and South Hadley, all in the county of Hampshire.  Third Hampshire.--Consisting of the towns of Amherst, precinct 1 of the town of Granby, and the town of Pelham, all in the county of Hampshire.Middlesex  First Middlesex.--Consisting of precinct 1 of the town of Ayer, and the towns of Ashby, Dunstable, Groton, Pepperell and Townsend, all in the county of Middlesex.  Second Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 5, 7, and 8 of the town of Chelmsford and the towns of Littleton and Westford, all in the county of Middlesex.  Third Middlesex.--Consisting of the towns of Hudson, Maynard and Stow, all in the county of Middlesex; and the town of Bolton, in the county of Worcester.  Fourth Middlesex.--Consisting of precinct 1 of ward 2, ward 3, ward 4, ward 5, ward 6, and precinct 2 of ward 7 of the city of Marlborough, in the county of Middlesex; and precincts 1 and 3 of the town of Northborough, and precincts 1 and 3 of the town of Westborough, both in the county of Worcester.  Fifth Middlesex.--Consisting of the town of Natick and Sherborn, both in the county of Middlesex; and precincts 2 and 3, of the town of Millis, in the county of Norfolk.  Sixth Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 7, 9, 10, 11, 12 and 15, of the town of Framingham, in the county of Middlesex.  Seventh Middlesex.--Consisting of the town of Ashland, and precincts 8, 13, 14, 16, 17 and 18, of the town of Framingham, both in the county of Middlesex.  Eighth Middlesex.--Consisting of the towns of Holliston and Hopkinton, both in the county of Middlesex; the town of Southborough, and precinct 2, of the town of Westborough, both in the county of Worcester.  Ninth Middlesex.--Consisting of the town of Lincoln, wards 1, 2 and 3, precinct 1 of ward 4, precinct 2 of ward 5, precinct 1 of ward 6, and precinct 1 of ward 7, of the city of Waltham, both in the county of Middlesex.  Tenth Middlesex.--Consisting of precinct 1 and 4 of ward 1 of the city of Newton, precinct 2 of ward 4, precinct 1 of ward 5, precinct 2 of ward 6, precinct 2 of ward 7, and wards 8 and 9, of the city of Waltham, and precincts 10, 11 and 12, of the town of Watertown, all in the county of Middlesex.  Eleventh Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 2 and 3 of ward 1, ward 2, ward 3, ward 4, and precinct 2 of ward 7, of the city of Newton, in the county of Middlesex.  Twelfth Middlesex.--Consisting of ward 5, ward 6, precincts 1, 3 and 4 of ward 7, and all precincts of ward 8, of the city of Newton, in the county of Middlesex.  Thirteenth Middlesex.--Consisting of precinct 3 in the town of Framingham, ward 1, precinct 2 of ward 2, and precinct 1 of ward 7 in the city of Marlborough, the town of Sudbury, precincts 1, 2 and 3 of the town of Wayland, all in the county of Middlesex.  Fourteenth Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2 and 6, of the town of Acton, the town of Carlisle, precincts 1 and 9, of the town of Chelmsford, and the town of Concord, all in the county of Middlesex.  Fifteenth Middlesex.--Consisting of the town of Lexington, and wards 1 and 7, of the city of Woburn, both in the county of Middlesex.  Sixteenth Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3 and 6, of the town of Chelmsford, and wards 5, 6 and 9, of the city of Lowell, both in the county of Middlesex.  Seventeenth Middlesex.--Consisting of precinct 4, of the town of Chelmsford, ward 1, precinct 3 of ward 2, precincts 2 and 3 of ward 4, and wards 10 and 11, of the city of Lowell, both in the county of Middlesex.  Eighteenth Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 1 and 2 of ward 2, ward 3, precinct 1 of ward 4, and wards 7 and 8, of the city of Lowell, in the county of Middlesex.  Nineteenth Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 1, 1A, 2, 2A, 4 and 4A, of the town of Tewksbury, and precincts 1, 2, 4, 5 and 6, of the town of Wilmington, both in the county of Middlesex.  Twentieth Middlesex.--Consisting of the town of Lynnfield, and precinct 1, of the town of Middleton, both in the county of Essex; and the town of North Reading, and precincts 1, 6, 7 and 8, of the town of Reading, both in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-first Middlesex.--Consisting of the towns of Bedford and Burlington, and precinct 3, of the town of Wilmington, all in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-second Middlesex.--Consisting of the town of Billerica, in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-third Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 1, 3, 5, 6, 7, 9, 11, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20 and 21 of the town of Arlington, precinct 2 of ward 3, and precincts 1 and 2 of ward 6, of the city of Medford, both in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-fourth Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 2, 4, 8, 10 and 12, of the town of Arlington, the town of Belmont, and precincts 1, and 3 of ward 11, of the city of Cambridge, all in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-fifth Middlesex.--Consisting of ward 4, precincts 2 and 3 of ward 6, wards 7 and 8, and precincts 1 and 2 of ward 10, of the city of Cambridge, in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-sixth Middlesex.--Consisting of ward 1, precinct 1 of ward 2, ward 3, and precinct 1 of ward 6, of the city of Cambridge, and ward 1 and precinct 1 of ward 2, of the city of Somerville, both in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-seventh Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 2 and 3 of ward 2, and wards 3, 5 and 6, of the city of Somerville, in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-eighth Middlesex.--Consisting of the city of Everett, in the county of Middlesex.  Twenty-ninth Middlesex.--Consisting of ward 9, precinct 3 of ward 10, and precinct 2 of ward 11 of the city of Cambridge, and precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 and 9, of the town of Watertown, both in the county of Middlesex.  Thirtieth Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3, 4 and 5, of the town of Reading, and all precincts of wards 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6, of the city of Woburn, both in the county of Middlesex.  Thirty-first Middlesex.--Consisting of the towns of Stoneham and Winchester, both in the county of Middlesex.  Thirty-second Middlesex.--Consisting of precinct 2 of ward 5 in the city of Malden, the city of Melrose, and precincts 4, 5 and 6, of the town of Wakefield, all in the county of Middlesex.  Thirty-third Middlesex.--Consisting of ward 2, precinct 1 of ward 3, ward 4, precinct 1 of ward 5, ward 6, precinct 2 of ward 7, and ward 8, of the city of Malden, in the county of Middlesex.  Thirty-fourth Middlesex.--Consisting of wards 4 and 5, precinct 1 of ward 7, and precinct 2 of ward 8, of the city of Medford, and wards 4 and 7, of the city of Somerville, both in the county of Middlesex.  Thirty-fifth Middlesex.--Consisting of ward 1, precinct 2 of ward 3, precinct 1 of ward 7, of the city of Malden, and ward 1 and 2, precinct 1 of ward 3, precinct 2 of ward 7, and precinct 1 of ward 8, of the city of Medford, both in the county of Middlesex.  Thirty-sixth Middlesex.--Consisting of the towns of Dracut and Tyngsborough, both in the county of Middlesex.  Thirty-seventh Middlesex.--Consisting of precincts 3, 4 and 5, of the town of Acton, precinct 2 of the town of Ayer, the towns of Boxborough and Shirley, all in the county of Middlesex; and the town of Harvard, and precinct A, C, and D, of the town of Lunenburg, both in the county of Worcester.Norfolk  First Norfolk.--Consisting of precincts 4 and 5 of ward 3, precincts 1 and 3 of ward 4, precinct 2 of ward 5, and ward 6, of the city of Quincy, and precincts 5, 6, 11, and 12 of the town of Randolph, both in the county of Norfolk.  Second Norfolk.--Consisting of ward 1, precincts 1 and 2 of ward 3, precincts 2 and 4 of ward 4 and precincts 1, 3, 4, and 5 of ward 5, of the city of Quincy, in the county of Norfolk.  Third Norfolk.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3 and 4, of the town of Holbrook, ward 2, and precinct 5 of ward 4, of the city of Quincy, precincts 5, 6, 9, 12 and 16, of the town of Weymouth, all in the county of Norfolk.  Fourth Norfolk.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 7, 8, 10, 11, 13, 14, 15, 17 and 18, of the town of Weymouth, in the county of Norfolk; and precinct 2 of the town of Hingham, in the county of Plymouth.  Fifth Norfolk.--Consisting of the town of Braintree, precinct 1, of the town of Holbrook, precinct 4, of the town of Randolph, all in the county of Norfolk.  Sixth Norfolk.--Consisting of the towns of Avon and Canton, and precincts 1, 5, 7 and 8, of the town of Stoughton, all in the county of Norfolk.  Seventh Norfolk.--Consisting of precincts 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 and 10, of the town of Milton, and precincts 1, 2, 3, 7, 8, 9 and 10, of the town of Randolph, both in the county of Norfolk.  Eighth Norfolk.--Consisting of precinct 4, of the town of Mansfield, in the county of Bristol; and the town of Sharon, precincts 2, 3, 4 and 6, of the town of Stoughton, and precincts 3 and 4, of the town of Walpole, all in the county of Norfolk.  Ninth Norfolk.--Consisting of precincts 3 and 4, of the town of Medfield, precinct 1, of the town of Millis, the towns of Norfolk and Plainville, precinct 5, of the town of Walpole, and the town of Wrentham, all in the county of Norfolk.  Tenth Norfolk.--Consisting of the town of Franklin, and precincts 2, 3 and 4, of the town of Medway, both in the county of Norfolk.  Eleventh Norfolk.--Consisting of the town of Dedham, precinct 8, of the town of Walpole, and the town of Westwood, all in the county of Norfolk.  Twelfth Norfolk.--Consisting of the town of Norwood, precincts 1, 2, 6 and 7, of the town of Walpole, both in the county of Norfolk.  Thirteenth Norfolk.--Consisting of the town of Dover, precincts 1 and 2, of the town of Medfield, and the town of Needham, all in the county of Norfolk.  Fourteenth Norfolk.--Consisting of precinct 4, of the town of Wayland, and the town of Weston, both in the county of Middlesex; and the town of Wellesley, in the county of Norfolk.  Fifteenth Norfolk.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3, 4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12 and 13 of the town of Brookline, in the county of Norfolk.Plymouth[ First paragraph following the caption "Plymouth'' effective until November 3, 2011. For text effective November 3, 2011, see below.]  First Plymouth.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 12, 14 and 15, of the town of Plymouth, in the county of Plymouth.[ First paragraph following the caption "Plymouth'' as amended by 2012, 36, Sec. 14 effective November 3, 2011. See 2012, 36, Sec. 53. For text effective until November 3, 2011, see above.]  First Plymouth.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 10, 11, 12, 14 and 15, of the town of Plymouth, in the county of Plymouth.  Second Plymouth.--Consisting of the town of Carver, precincts 3 and 6, of the town of Middleborough, and the town of Wareham, all in the county of Plymouth.  Third Plymouth.--Consisting of the town of Cohasset, in the county of Norfolk; precincts 1, 3, 4, 5 and 6 of the town of Hingham, the town of Hull, and precinct 3, of the town of Scituate, all in the county of Plymouth.  Fourth Plymouth.--Consisting of the town of Marshfield, and precincts 1, 2, 4, 5 and 6, of the town of Scituate, both in the county of Plymouth.  Fifth Plymouth.--Consisting of the towns of Hanover, Norwell and Rockland, all in the county of Plymouth.  Sixth Plymouth.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6, of the town of Duxbury, and the towns of Hanson and Pembroke, all in the county of Plymouth.  Seventh Plymouth.--Consisting of the towns of Abington, precincts 2, 3 and 4 of the town of East Bridgewater and the town of Whitman, all in the county of Plymouth.  Eighth Plymouth.--Consisting of the town of Raynham, in the county of Bristol; and the town of Bridgewater, in the county of Plymouth.  Ninth Plymouth.--Consisting of ward 2, precincts A, B, C of ward 3, precincts A and D of ward 4, precinct A of ward 5, and precincts A and B of ward 7, of the city of Brockton, in the county of Plymouth.  Tenth Plymouth.--Consisting of precincts B and C of ward 4, precincts B, C and D of ward 5 and ward 6, of the city of Brockton, precinct 1 of the town of East Bridgewater, and the town of West Bridgewater, all in the county of Plymouth.  Eleventh Plymouth.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5, of the town of Easton, in the county of Bristol; and ward 1, precinct D of ward 3, and precincts C and D of ward 7, of the city of Brockton, all in the county of Plymouth.  Twelfth Plymouth.--Consisting of precinct 1, of the town of Duxbury, the towns of Halifax and Kingston, precinct 1 of the town of Middleborough, precincts 1, 11 and 13, of the town of Plymouth, and the town of Plympton, all in the county of Plymouth.Suffolk  First Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13 and 14 of ward 1, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Second Suffolk.--Consisting of ward 2, of the city of Boston, and ward 1, ward 2, precincts 1 and 3 of ward 3, and precincts 1 and 4 of ward 4, of the city of Chelsea, both in the county of Suffolk.  Third Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 7 and 8 of ward 3, precincts 1 and 3 of ward 4, and precinct 1 of ward 5, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Fourth Suffolk.--Consisting of precinct 15 of ward 1, ward 6, precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 and 8 of ward 7, and precinct 3 of ward 13, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Fifth Suffolk.--Consisting of precinct 10 of ward 7, precincts 5, 6, and 7 of ward 8, precinct 6 of ward 12, precincts 1, 2, 4 and 5 of ward 13, precinct 1 of ward 14, precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 7, 8 and 9, of ward 15, and precincts 1 and 2 of ward 17, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Sixth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 2, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13 and 14 of ward 14, precincts 6, 7, 8 and 9 of ward 17, precincts 7 and 8 of ward 18, and precinct 12 of ward 19, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.[ Seventh paragraph following the caption "Suffolk'' effective until February 17, 2012. For text effective February 17, 2012, see below.]  Seventh Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 8, 9, and 10 of ward 4, precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 8 of ward 12, precincts 4 and 5 of ward 9, and precinct 1 of ward 21, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.[ Seventh paragraph following the caption "Suffolk'' as amended by 2012, 36, Sec. 15 effective February 17, 2012. For text effective until February 17, 2012, see above.]  Seventh Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 8, 9 and 10 of ward 4, sub-precinct 2A of ward 5, precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 8 of ward 12, precincts 4 and 5 of ward 9, and precinct 1 of ward 21 of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Eighth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 2 and 3 of ward 2, and ward 5, of the city of Cambridge, in the county of Middlesex; and precinct 5 of ward 3, and precinct 6 of ward 4, and precincts 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 and 11 of ward 5, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Ninth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 2, 4, 5 and 7 of ward 4, precincts 2 and 10 of ward 5, precincts 1, 2, 3, and 4 of ward 8, and precincts 1, 2 and 3 of ward 9, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Tenth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 14, 15 and 16, of the town of Brookline, in the county of Norfolk; and precincts 1, 5, 6, 7, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19 and 20 of ward 20, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Eleventh Suffolk.--Consisting of ward 11, precincts 7 and 9 of ward 12, precinct 3 of ward 14, and precincts 6, 7, 9, 10, 11 and 13, of ward 19 of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Twelfth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 1 and 2 of the town of Milton, in the county of Norfolk; and precincts 8 and 11 of ward 16, precincts 4, 10, 11, 12, 13 and 14 of ward 17, precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 and 21 of ward 18, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Thirteenth Suffolk.--Consisting of precinct 3 of ward 3, of the city of Quincy, in the county of Norfolk; and precinct 9 of ward 7, precincts 6, 7, 8, 9 and 10 of ward 13, precinct 6 of ward 15, precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 9, 10 and 12 of ward 16, and precincts 3 and 5 of ward 17, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Fourteenth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 22 and 23 of ward 18, precincts 3, 8 and 9 of ward 20, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Fifteenth Suffolk.--Consisting of precinct 5, of the town of Brookline, in the county of Norfolk; and ward 10, precincts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 8 of ward 19, and precincts 2 and 4 of ward 20, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Sixteenth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 3 and 10, of the town of Saugus, in the county of Essex; and precincts 2 and 4 of ward 3, precincts 2 and 3 of ward 4, of the city of Chelsea, and precinct 3 of ward 1, precinct 1 of ward 3, ward 4, precincts 1 and 2 of ward 5, and ward 6, of the city of Revere, both in the county of Suffolk.  Seventeenth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 3, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12 and 15 of ward 21, and precincts 2, 3, 6, 9 and 10 in ward 22, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Eighteenth Suffolk.--Consisting of precinct 1, of the town of Brookline, in the county of Norfolk; and precincts 2, 4, 13, 14 and 16 of ward 21, and precincts 1, 4, 5, 7, 8, 11, 12 and 13 of ward 22, of the city of Boston, in the county of Suffolk.  Nineteenth Suffolk.--Consisting of precincts 1 and 2 of ward 1, ward 2, precincts 2 and 3 of ward 3, and precinct 3 of ward 5, of the city of Revere, and the town of Winthrop, both in the county of Suffolk.Worcester  First Worcester.--Consisting of the towns of Holden, Paxton, Princeton, Rutland, precinct 1 of the town of Sterling, and precinct 2 of the town of Westminster, all in the county of Worcester.  Second Worcester.--Consisting of the town of Ashburnham, the city of Gardner, and, the town of Winchendon, and precinct 1 of the town of Westminster, all in the county of Worcester.  Third Worcester.--Consisting of the city of Fitchburg, and precinct B, in the town of Lunenburg, both in the county of Worcester.  Fourth Worcester.--Consisting of the town of Leominster, in the county of Worcester.  Fifth Worcester.--Consisting of precinct A, of the town of Ware, in the county of Hampshire; and the towns of Barre, Brookfield, East Brookfield, Hardwick, Hubbardson, New Braintree, North Brookfield, Oakham, precincts 2, 3 and 4, in the town of Spencer, and the town of West Brookfield, all in the county of Worcester.  Sixth Worcester.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2 and 3 of the town of Charlton, the town of Dudley, the town of Southbridge, and precinct 1, of the town of Spencer, all in the county of Worcester.  Seventh Worcester.--Consisting of the town of Auburn, precinct 4 of the town of Charlton, the town of Millbury, and precincts 2 and 3, of the town of Oxford, all in the county of Worcester.  Eighth Worcester.--Consisting of the town of Bellingham, in the county of Norfolk; the towns of Blackstone, Millville, and Uxbridge, all in the county of Worcester.  Ninth Worcester.--Consisting of the towns of Grafton, Northbridge and Upton, all in the county of Worcester.  Tenth Worcester.--Consisting of precinct 1, of the town of Medway, in the county of Norfolk, and the towns of Hopedale, Mendon and Milford, all in the county of Worcester.  Eleventh Worcester.--Consisting of the town of Shrewsbury, and precincts 4 and 5, of the town of Westborough, both in the county of Worcester.  Twelfth Worcester.--Consisting of the towns of Berlin, Boylston, Clinton, Lancaster, precincts 2 and 4 of the town of Northborough, and precinct 2 of the town of Sterling, all in the county of Worcester.  Thirteenth Worcester.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2, 3 and 4 of ward 1, precinct 2 of ward 3, ward 9, and precinct 1 of ward 10, of the city of Worcester, in the county of Worcester.  Fourteenth Worcester.--Consisting of the town of West Boylston, and precinct 5 of ward 1, ward 2, and precincts 1, 3 and 5 of ward 3, of the city of Worcester, both in the county of Worcester.  Fifteenth Worcester.--Consisting of precincts 2, 3, 4, 5, of ward 10, precinct 4 of ward 3, ward 4, and precinct 3 of ward 5, of the city of Worcester, in the county of Worcester.  Sixteenth Worcester.--Consisting of precincts 1, 2, 4 and 5, of ward 5, ward 6, and precincts 1 and 5 of ward 8, of the city of Worcester, in the county of Worcester.  Seventeenth Worcester.--Consisting of the town of Leicester, and ward 7, and precincts 2, 3 and 4 of ward 8, of the city of Worcester, both in the county of Worcester.  Eighteenth Worcester.--Consisting of the towns of Douglas, precincts 1 and 4 of the town of Oxford, Sutton, and Webster, all in the county of Worcester.
    </text>
</law>