<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="3">The General Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>41</section_number>
    <catch_line>Docket Of Executive And Legislative Agents And Lobbyists;  Educational Seminars For Legislative And Executive Agents; Annual Registration Statements;  Annual Filing Fee;  Identification Cards;  Advisory Opinions</catch_line>
    <order_by>41</order_by>
    <text>
          The state secretary shall keep a docket which may be in the form of an electronic database. All information required to be filed under this section shall be organized into the docket and shall be open and accessible for public inspection during normal business hours.[ Second paragraph effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  The state secretary shall offer educational seminars on the requirements of sections 39 to 50, inclusive, for all legislative agents and executive agents. The seminars shall be conducted in person or offered online through the state secretary's website. All legislative and executive agents shall: (i) before registering with the state secretary and annually thereafter, complete an in person or online seminar offered by the state secretary; and (ii) complete an in person or online seminar offered by the state secretary upon any material change to sections 39 to 50, inclusive, or any regulations promulgated pursuant thereto. The superintendent of the bureau of state office buildings shall, upon request of the state secretary, provide at no cost to the state secretary suitable facilities for such seminars. The state secretary shall adopt regulations for the administration and enforcement of this section.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 4 effective October 31, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 219. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  The state secretary shall offer educational seminars on the requirements of sections 39 to 50, inclusive, for all legislative agents and executive agents. The seminars shall be conducted in person or offered online through the state secretary's website. All legislative and executive agents shall: (i) before registering with the state secretary and annually thereafter, complete an in person or online seminar offered by the state secretary; and (ii) complete an in person or online seminar offered by the state secretary upon any material change to sections 39 to 50, inclusive, or any regulations promulgated pursuant thereto. The superintendent of the bureau of the state house shall, upon request of the state secretary, provide at no cost to the state secretary suitable facilities for such seminars. The state secretary shall adopt regulations for the administration and enforcement of this section.  Each legislative agent, executive agent and lobbyist entity shall file an annual registration statement with the state secretary on forms prescribed and provided by the state secretary. The annual registration shall be completed not later than December 15 of this year preceding the registration year.  A client retaining the services of a legislative agent, executive agent or lobbyist entity shall also file an annual registration statement with the state secretary on forms prescribed and provided by the state secretary. The annual registration shall be completed not later than December 15 of the year preceding the registration year.  A client or lobbyist entity hiring, employing or agreeing to employ a lobbyist entity, legislative agent or executive agent after January 1 of the registration year shall, within 10 days after such employment or agreement, cause the name of the lobbyist entity, legislative agent or executive agent to be registered with the state secretary as provided in this section. Notice of termination of such employment shall also be filed promptly with the state secretary by the client or lobbyist entity.  The state secretary shall assess each lobbyist entity an annual filing fee of $1,000 to register the entity on the docket. The state secretary shall assess each legislative agent and executive agent an annual filing fee of $100 upon entering the agent's name on the docket. The state secretary shall assess each client an annual filing fee of $100 for each lobbyist entity hired by them upon entering the name upon the docket. The state secretary may, in his discretion and upon written request, waive the filing fees not a not-for-profit client or a lobbyist entity which registers to exclusively represent not-for-profit clients.  Upon registration, the state secretary shall issue to each legislative agent and executive agent a license which shall entitle the holder to act as a legislative agent and executive agent for a client that has filed a registration statement pursuant to this section. A nontransferable identification card shall evidence this license and shall include the agent's name and photograph. Each license shall expire on December 31 of each year. Out-of-state legislative agents and executive agents shall submit 3 passport-sized photographs to the state secretary upon registration.  The state secretary shall, upon written request from a person who is or may be subject to sections 39 to 50, inclusive, render advisory opinions on the requirements of those sections. An opinion rendered by the state secretary, unless amended or revoked, shall be a defense in a criminal action brought pursuant to sections 39 to 50, inclusive, and shall be binding on the state secretary, the attorney general or the district attorney in any subsequent proceedings concerning the person who requested the opinion and who acted in good faith, unless material facts were omitted or misstated by the person in the request for an opinion. Such requests shall be confidential; provided, however, that the state secretary may publish such opinions if the name of the requesting person and any other identifying information is not included in such publication unless the requesting person consents to such inclusion.
    </text>
</law>