<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7C" order_by="7C" level="3">Capital Asset Management And Maintenance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>45</section_number>
    <catch_line>Designer Selection Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>45</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 165, Sec. 82 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  (a) There shall be located within the executive office for administration and finance a designer selection board, consisting of 11 members. Eight members shall be appointed by the governor, 3 of whom shall be registered architects, 3 of whom shall be registered engineers, and 2 of whom shall be representatives of the public who are not architect designers, engineers or construction contractors. Three additional members shall be appointed as follows: 1 registered architect by the Massachusetts State Association of Architects, 1 registered engineer by the government affairs council of design professional and 1 general contractor by the associated general contractor. The board shall be expanded from the present 5 members to 11 members according to the following schedule: 1 additional architect, 1 additional engineer, and the 1 general contractor shall be appointed by the designated body within 90 days of the effective date of this section; another additional public representative shall be appointed within 1 year thereafter. Members shall be appointed for terms of 2 years and may be reappointed for no more than 1 successive 2 year term. The director shall designate a representative, who shall be the project manager in the case of a project under the jurisdiction of the office of project management, to act as a nonvoting member of the board for each project under his jurisdiction under consideration by the board. No provision of this section shall operate to reduce the tenure of members of the board serving at the time of the effective date of this section, except that the director of bureau of building construction shall cease to so serve upon the effective date of this section.  (b) Members of the board shall be reimbursed for all necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their official duties.  (c) The board shall employ an executive director who shall be a registered architect or engineer registered in the commonwealth and such other staff or consultants as it may deem necessary, subject to appropriation, for the board. The board and its staff may travel within and without the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>