<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>151F</section_number>
    <catch_line>By Laws; Election Of Chairperson And Executive Director; Corporate Books And Records; Civil Liabilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>151F</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The interstate commission shall, by a majority of the members, within 12 months of the first interstate commission meeting, adopt by-laws to govern its conduct as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the compact including, but not limited to:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     establishing the fiscal year of the interstate commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     establishing an executive committee and such other committees as may be necessary;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     providing reasonable standards and procedures:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     for the establishment of committees; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     governing any general or specific delegation of any authority or function of the interstate commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     providing reasonable procedures for calling and conducting meetings of the interstate commission, and ensuring reasonable notice of each such meeting;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     establishing the titles and responsibilities of the officers of the interstate commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     providing reasonable standards and procedures for the establishment of the personnel policies and programs of the interstate commission. Notwithstanding any civil service or other similar laws of any compacting state, the by-laws shall exclusively govern the personnel policies and programs of the interstate commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     providing a mechanism for cessation of operations of the interstate commission and the equitable return of any surplus funds that may exist upon the termination of the compact after the payment and reserving of all of its debts and obligations;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     providing transition rules for start up administration of the compact; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     establishing standards and procedures for compliance and technical assistance in administering the compact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     (1) The interstate commission shall, by a majority of the members, elect from among its members a chairperson and a vice chairperson, each of whom shall have such authorities and duties as may be specified in the by-laws. The chairperson or, in his or her absence or disability, the vice chairperson, shall preside at all meetings of the interstate commission. The officers so elected shall serve without compensation or remuneration from the interstate commission, except that, subject to the availability of budgeted funds, the officers shall be reimbursed for any actual and necessary costs and expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties and responsibilities as officers of the interstate commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The interstate commission shall, through its executive committee, appoint or retain an executive director for such period, upon such terms and conditions and for such compensation as the interstate commission may deem appropriate. The executive director shall serve as secretary to the interstate commission, and hire and supervise such other staff as may be authorized by the interstate commission, but shall not be a member.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The interstate commission shall maintain its corporate books and records in accordance with the by-laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     (1) The members, officers, executive director and employees of the interstate commission shall be immune from suit and liability, either personally or in their official capacity, for any claim for damage to or loss of property or personal injury or other civil liability caused or arising out of any actual or alleged act, error or omission that occurred within the scope of interstate commission employment, duties or responsibilities. Nothing in this paragraph, however, shall be construed to protect any such person from suit or liability for any damage, loss, injury or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of any such person.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The interstate commission shall defend the commissioner of a compacting state, or his representatives or employees, or the interstate commission’s representatives or employees, in any civil action seeking to impose liability, arising out of any actual or alleged act, error or omission that occurred within the scope of interstate commission employment, duties or responsibilities, or that the defendant had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of interstate commission employment, duties or responsibilities if the actual or alleged act, error or omission did not result from intentional wrongdoing on the part of such person.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The interstate commission shall indemnify and hold the commissioner of a compacting state, his appointed designee or employees, or the interstate commission’s representatives or employees, harmless in the amount of any settlement or judgment obtained against such persons arising out of any actual or alleged act, error or omission that occurred within the scope of interstate commission employment, duties or responsibilities, or that such persons had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of interstate commission employment, duties or responsibilities, if the actual or alleged act, error or omission did not result from gross negligence or intentional wrongdoing on the part of such person.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>