<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>151L</section_number>
    <catch_line>Withdrawal By Compacting State; Default On Obligation Or Responsibility Under Compact</catch_line>
    <order_by>151L</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     (1) Once effective, the compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon each and every compacting state except that a compacting state may withdraw from the compact by enacting a statute specifically repealing the statute which enacted the compact into law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The effective date of withdrawal is the effective date of the repeal.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The withdrawing state shall immediately notify the chairperson of the interstate commission, in writing, upon the introduction of legislation repealing this compact in the withdrawing state.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The interstate commission shall notify the other compacting states of the withdrawing state’s intent to withdraw within 60 days of its receipt thereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The withdrawing state shall be responsible for all assessments, obligations and liabilities incurred through the effective date of withdrawal, including any obligations, the performance of which extend beyond the effective date of withdrawal.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Reinstatement following withdrawal of any compacting state shall occur upon the withdrawing state reenacting the compact or upon such later date as determined by the interstate commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     (1) If the interstate commission determines that any compacting state has at any time defaulted in the performance of any of its obligations or responsibilities under this compact, the by-laws or any duly promulgated rules the interstate commission may impose any or all of the following penalties:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     fines, fees and costs in such amounts as are deemed to be reasonable as fixed by the interstate commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     remedial training and technical assistance as directed by the interstate commission; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     suspension and termination of membership in the compact. Suspension shall be imposed only after all other reasonable means of securing compliance under the by-laws and rules have been exhausted. Immediate notice of suspension shall be given by the interstate commission to the governor, the chief justice or chief judicial officer of the state; the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state’s legislature, and the state council.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The grounds for default shall include, but not be limited to, failure of a compacting state to perform such obligations or responsibilities imposed upon it by this compact, interstate commission by-laws or duly promulgated rules. The interstate commission shall immediately notify the defaulting state, in writing, of the penalty imposed by the interstate commission on the defaulting state pending a cure of the default. The interstate commission shall stipulate the conditions and the time period within which the defaulting state shall cure its default. If the defaulting state fails to cure the default within the time period specified by the interstate commission, in addition to any other penalties imposed herein, the defaulting state may be terminated from the compact upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the compacting states and all rights, privileges and benefits conferred by this compact shall be terminated from the effective date of suspension.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Within 60 days of the effective date of termination of a defaulting state, the interstate commission shall notify the governor, the chief justice or chief judicial officer and the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state’s legislature and the state council of such termination.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The defaulting state shall be responsible for all assessments, obligations and liabilities incurred through the effective date of termination, including any obligations, the performance of which extends beyond the effective date of termination.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The interstate commission shall not bear any costs relating to the defaulting state unless otherwise mutually agreed upon between the interstate commission and the defaulting state.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Reinstatement following termination of any compacting state requires both a reenactment of the compact by the defaulting state and the approval of the interstate commission pursuant to the rules.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The interstate commission may, by majority vote of the members, initiate legal action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or, at the discretion of the interstate commission, in the Federal District wherein the interstate commission’s offices are located, has its offices to enforce compliance with the compact, its duly promulgated rules and by-laws, against any compacting state in default. In the event judicial enforcement is necessary, the prevailing party shall be awarded all costs of such litigation, including reasonable attorneys fees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The compact dissolves effective upon the date of the withdrawal or default of the compacting state which reduces membership in the compact to 1 compacting state.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>