<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132A" order_by="132A" level="3">State Recreation Areas Outside Of The Metropolitan Parks District</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18</section_number>
    <catch_line>Permits And Licenses; Ocean Development Mitigation Fee</catch_line>
    <order_by>18</order_by>
    <text>
        All departments, divisions, commissions, or units of the executive office of energy and environmental affairs and other affected agencies or departments of the commonwealth shall issue permits or licenses for activities or conduct their activities consistently with the act, and shall not permit or conduct any activity which is contrary to the provisions of the Act. Except as provided by sections sixteen B through sixteen F, inclusive, the Act shall not require any additional permits from the office, but other departments, divisions, commissions, units, or other agencies shall confer and consult with the office to ensure compliance with the Act. The attorney general or the appropriate state agency shall take such action as may be necessary from time to time to enforce the provisions of the Act, and the superior court shall have jurisdiction to enforce the provisions thereof. 
Any permit or license issued by a department, division, commission, or unit of the executive office of energy and environmental affairs and other affected agencies or departments of the commonwealth for activities or conduct consistent with this chapter shall be subject to an ocean development mitigation fee as shall be established by the secretary of energy and environmental affairs; provided, however, that no fee shall be assessed on commercial and recreational fishing permits or licenses. All the proceeds of the ocean development mitigation fee shall be deposited in the Ocean Resources and Waterways Trust Fund established pursuant to section 35HH of chapter 10.
    </text>
</law>