<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>261</section_number>
    <catch_line>Unauthorized Use Of Certified Community Health Worker Title; Act Or Service For Which License By Professional Licensing Board Is Required</catch_line>
    <order_by>261</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section added by 2010, 322, Sec. 3 effective January 1, 2012. See 2010, 322, Sec. 4.] 
The title “certified community health worker” shall only be used by individuals who have met the requirements and qualifications for certification as a community health worker as established by the board and have been duly certified by the board. The use by any person not so certified of any words, letters, abbreviations or insignia indicating or implying a person holds such certification shall be in violation of this section for which the board may issue a cease and desist order and seek additional appropriate legal remedies. 
Nothing in this section shall permit a certified community health worker to engage in or perform any act or service for which a license issued by a professional licensing board is required. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent or restrict the practice, service or activities of any person licensed, certified, or registered in the commonwealth under any laws other than board of certification of community health worker laws from engaging in activities within the scope of practice of the profession or occupation for which he is licensed, if he does not represent to the public, directly or indirectly, that he is certified under section 260 and does not use any name, title or designation indicating that the person is certified under said section 260.
    </text>
</law>