<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>29</section_number>
    <catch_line>Cashless Wagering Systems;  Setting And Adjustment Of Betting Limits;  Monthly Statements;  Annual Report To The Commission</catch_line>
    <order_by>29</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  A gaming establishment offering a cashless wagering system shall allow individuals to monitor and impose betting limits on their cashless wagering. The gaming establishment shall allow individuals to set betting limits on their cashless wagering including, but not limited to, per bet limits, hourly limits, daily limits, weekly limits and monthly limits. An individual may lower limits and increase limits; provided, however, that the individual shall not increase betting limits more than once in a 24-hour period. The gaming establishment shall issue to each patron who has been issued a rewards card or who participates in a cashless wagering system by the gaming establishment a monthly statement, mailed to the patron at the patron's physical mailing address, which shall include the patron's total bets, wins and losses; provided, however, that a patron shall be given the opportunity to decline receiving a monthly statement at the time the rewards card is issued or during initial participation in a cashless wagering system; provided further, that a patron may later opt out of receiving monthly statements by providing a written request to cease monthly statements to the gaming establishment. A gaming licensee who has implemented such a program or system shall annually report to the commission the amount of money spent and lost by patrons who have been issued a rewards card or who participated in a cashless wagering system, aggregated by zip code. Activity under this section shall be monitored by the commission. Individuals on the list of excluded persons shall not be permitted to participate in a cashless wagering system.
    </text>
</law>