<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="3">State Superintendent Of Buildings, And State House</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Fee For Use Of State Office Building During Non Business Hours By Non Governmental Individuals, Entities And Groups;  Indemnification;  Disposition Of Monies Received</catch_line>
    <order_by>9A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  The state superintendent of state office buildings shall establish and charge a fee or service charge to nongovernmental individuals, entities and groups using the state house for meetings, receptions or exhibits, which may be waived at the discretion of the superintendent. The superintendent or his designee shall establish such fee or charge based upon the actual cost of use, including personnel, requests for security, preparation, equipment replacement, cleanup, utilities used and compensation for wear on the building. The superintendent or his designee may, in their discretion, require a nongovernment entity to enter into a written agreement indemnifying the commonwealth against any claims for casualty liability and may require the posting of an insurance bond. All monies received by the superintendent under this section shall be by check made payable to the State House Special Event Fund and shall be deposited in that Fund, established by section 35P of chapter 10; provided, however, that the superintendent may retain an amount not to exceed $200,000 annually to be expended after consultation with the state secretary for equipment replacement and educational and cultural programs at the state house.
Chapter 8: Fee for use of state house during non-business hours by non-governmental individuals, entities and groups; indemnification; disposition of monies received
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 16 effective October 31, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 219. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  The superintendent of the state house shall establish and charge a fee or service charge to nongovernmental individuals, entities and groups using the state house for meetings, receptions or exhibits, which may be reduced at the discretion of the superintendent. The superintendent or a designee shall establish such fee or charge based upon the actual cost of use, including personnel, requests for security, preparation, equipment replacement, cleanup, utilities used and compensation for wear on the building. The superintendent, or a designee may, in the superintendent's discretion, require a nongovernment entity to enter into a written agreement indemnifying the commonwealth against any claims for casualty liability and may require the posting of an insurance bond. All monies received by the superintendent under this section shall be by check made payable to and deposited in the State House Special Event Fund, as established in section 35P of chapter 10; provided, however, that the superintendent may retain funds to be expended after consultation with the committee on rules of the 2 branches, acting concurrently, for restoration, equipment repair and replacement and educational and cultural programs and tours at the state house.
    </text>
</law>