<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="113A" order_by="113A" level="3">Uniform Anatomical Gift Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Refusal To Make Anatomical Gift;  Effect Of Refusal</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 39, Sec. 3 effective February 22, 2012.]  (a) An individual may refuse to make an anatomical gift of the individual's body or part by:  (1) a record signed by: (i) the individual; or (ii) subject to subsection (b), another individual acting at the direction of the individual if the individual is physically unable to sign;  (2) the individual's will, whether or not the will is admitted to probate or invalidated after the individual's death; or  (3) any form of communication made by the individual during the individual's terminal illness or injury addressed to at least 2 adults, at least 1 of whom shall be a disinterested witness.  (b) A record signed pursuant to subclause (ii) of clause (1) of subsection (a) shall:  (1) be witnessed by at least 2 adults, at least 1 of whom shall be a disinterested witness, who have signed at the request of the individual; and  (2) state that it has been signed and witnessed as provided in clause (1).  (c) An individual who has made a refusal may amend or revoke the refusal:  (1) in the manner provided in subsection (a) for making a refusal;  (2) by subsequently making an anatomical gift pursuant to section 5 that is inconsistent with the refusal; or  (3) by destroying or canceling the record or portion thereof evidencing the refusal, with the intent to revoke the refusal.  (d) Except as otherwise provided in subsection (h) of section 8, in the absence of an express, contrary indication by the individual set forth in the refusal, an individual's unrevoked refusal to make an anatomical gift of the individual's body or part shall bar all other persons from making an anatomical gift of that individual's body or part.
    </text>
</law>