<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>133D1/2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Global Positioning System Device To Be Worn By Certain Sex Offender Parolees</catch_line>
    <order_by>133D1/2</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person under court ordered parole supervision or under community parole supervision for life for any offense listed within the definition of “sex offense”, a “sex offense involving a child” or a “sexually violent offense” , as defined in section 178C of chapter 6, shall, as a requirement of such parole, wear a global positioning system device, or any comparable device, administered by the board at all times for the length of his parole for any such offense. The board shall, in addition to any other condition, establish defined geographic exclusion zones including, but not limited to, the areas in and around the victim’s residence, place of employment and school and other areas defined to minimize the parolee’s contact with children, if applicable. If the parolee enters an excluded zone, as defined by the terms of his parole, the parolee’s location data shall be immediately transmitted to the police department in the municipality wherein the violation occurred and the board, by telephone, electronic beeper, paging device or other appropriate means. If the board or the parolee’s parole officer believes that the parolee has violated his terms of parole by entering an excluded zone as prescribed in this section, the board or parole officer shall cause the parolee to be taken into temporary custody in accordance with section 149A of chapter 127. 
The fees incurred by installing, maintaining and operating the global positioning system device, or comparable device, shall be paid by the parolee. If a parolee establishes his inability to pay such fees, the board may waive them.
    </text>
</law>