<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132" level="3">Forestry</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>42</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notice Of Proposed Cutting Of Forest Products; Final Work Order;  Report To Director; Appeals</catch_line>
    <order_by>42</order_by>
    <text>
        Every owner of land who proposes to cut forest products on land devoted to forest purposes, or to cause such products to be cut, except as provided in section forty-four, shall send by certified mail or hand deliver written notice of his intention to begin any cutting operation to the abutters of record on file with the assessors of the town in which the land lies, and whose closest boundary is within two hundred feet of the edge of the cutting area, at least ten days prior to operations; and shall send by certified mail or hand deliver, written notice of his intention to begin any cutting operation, and his proposed cutting operation, and his proposed cutting plan, including information as may be necessary to describe such proposed activity, to the director or his agent at the appropriate regional office and to the conservation commission of the town in which the land lies at least ten days prior to operations; and in the case of classified forest land, the owner shall provide a reasonable estimate on the stumpage value of the forest products to be cut and properly paint or blaze any boundaries located within fifty feet of the cutting area. 
No work may commence until a final work order, with a designated file number, is issued to the landowner by said director or his agent except as hereinafter provided. 
The licensed timber harvester shall have a copy of the final work order on the site whenever work is done, for inspection by the director or his agent, who shall give final approval or disapproval to the operation and report in writing to said director the nature of the operation, its extent, the amount of product cut, and such other information as said director may require. 
In the event that the director, or his agent, does not act on the notice of intent within the designated ten days from day of receipt of the notice, work may commence, except in wetland areas as defined in section forty of chapter one hundred and thirty-one, in conformity with the submitted plan, provided the licensed timber harvester shall have a copy of the submitted plan on the site of the operation whenever work is done. 
An applicant landowner or licensed timber harvester who is aggrieved by any decision of the director or his agent may appeal said decision within ten days of receipt of the decision to the director or his designee who shall act as hearing officer and will hold an informal hearing within ten days and render his written decision to said aggrieved party within five days of the hearing. An applicant landowner or licensed timber harvester further aggrieved by the decision of the director may appeal said decision within thirty days to the superior court.
    </text>
</law>