<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>53</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notes Or Bonds Maturing Later Than Three Years After Issuance;  Requirements For Inviting Purchase Proposals;  Waiver</catch_line>
    <order_by>53</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Whenever there is to be an issue of bonds or notes of the commonwealth maturing at a time later than three years from their dates, excepting such bonds or notes as are to be issued for the investment of cash in any of the sinking or other established funds of the commonwealth, the state treasurer shall solicit bids for the purchase thereof, and shall provide reasonable notice to the public of such solicitations. The state treasurer may reserve the right to reject any or all bids. If no bid is accepted, the whole or any part of the loan may be awarded to any person. Compliance with the provisions of this section may be waived with respect to an issue of bonds or notes upon the approval of the finance advisory board, established under the provisions of section ninety-seven of chapter six.
Chapter 29: Notes or bonds maturing later than three years after issuance; requirements for inviting purchase proposals; waiver
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Whenever there is to be an issue of bonds or notes of the commonwealth maturing at a time later than 3 years from their dates, excepting such bonds or notes as are to be issued for the investment of cash in any of the sinking or other established funds of the commonwealth, the state treasurer shall solicit bids for the purchase thereof, and shall provide reasonable notice to the public of such solicitations. The state treasurer may reserve the right to reject any or all bids. If no bid is accepted, the whole or any part of the loan may be awarded to any person. Compliance with this section may be waived with respect to an issue of bonds or notes upon the approval of the state finance and governance board established under section 97 of chapter 6.
    </text>
</law>