<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>98</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration Of Massage Therapy; Composition; Terms; Voting</catch_line>
    <order_by>98</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be within the division of professional licensure a board of registration of massage therapy. The board shall consist of 7 members who shall be appointed by the governor for terms of 3 years. The members appointed shall be residents of the commonwealth, 3 of whom shall be licensed massage therapists who have been actively engaged in the practice of massage therapy in the commonwealth for at least 5 years immediately before their appointments; 1 of whom shall be a health agent, board member or other health professional employed by or elected to a municipal board of health within the commonwealth; 1 of whom shall be an individual who is actively engaged in the operation of a licensed massage school; and 2 of whom shall be consumers who are familiar with the massage therapy field. All board members shall be subject to chapter 268A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     f the initial members appointed to the board, 3 shall serve for terms of 3 years, 2 shall serve for terms of 2 years and 2 shall serve for terms of 1 year. Each member of the board shall hold office until his successor has been appointed. A vacancy in the membership of the board shall be filled for the unexpired term in the manner provided for the original appointment. A member may be removed by the governor for cause.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The board shall at its first meeting and, annually thereafter, elect from among its members, by majority vote, a chairman and vice-chairman. The board shall meet at least once every 3 months and may hold additional meetings as necessary to discharge its duties. Members shall receive no compensation but shall be entitled to reasonable travel expenses. The members of the board shall be public employees for the purposes of chapter 258 for all acts or omissions within the scope of their duties as board members.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>