<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="63" order_by="63" level="3">Taxation Of Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>38N</section_number>
    <catch_line>Economic Development Incentive Program; Tax Credit For Certified Projects</catch_line>
    <order_by>38N</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A corporation subject to tax under this chapter that participates in a certified project, as defined in sections 3A and 3F of chapter 23A, may take a credit against the excise imposed by this chapter to the extent authorized by the economic assistance coordinating council established by section 3B of said chapter 23A, in an amount not to exceed 50 per cent of such liability in a taxable year; provided, however, that the 50 per cent limitation shall not apply if the credit is refundable under subsection (b): (i) for certified expansion projects and certified enhanced expansion projects, as defined in said sections 3A and 3F of said chapter 23A, an amount up to 10 per cent; and (ii) for certified manufacturing retention projects, as defined in said sections 3A and 3F of said chapter 23A, an amount up to 40 per cent of the cost of any property that would qualify for the credit allowed by section 31A if the property were purchased by a manufacturing corporation or a business corporation engaged primarily in research and development and is used exclusively in a certified project, as defined in said sections 3A and 3F of said chapter 23A. A lessee may be eligible for a credit under this subsection for real property leased under an operating lease.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     If a credit allowed to a taxpayer under clause (ii) of subsection (a) exceeds the excise otherwise due under this chapter, 100 per cent of the balance of such credit may, at the option of the taxpayer and to the extent authorized by the economic assistance coordinating council, be refundable to the taxpayer for the taxable year in which qualified property giving rise to that credit is placed in service. If such credit balance is refunded to the taxpayer, the credit carryover provisions of subsection (d) shall not apply. The amount of credit eligible to be refunded shall be determined without regard to the limitations in subsections (a) and (c).
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In the case of a corporation that is subject to a minimum excise under any provision of this chapter, the amount of the credit allowed by this section shall not reduce the excise to an amount less than such minimum excise.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Any corporation entitled to a credit under this section for any taxable year may carry over and apply to its excise for any one or more of the next succeeding ten taxable years, the portion, as reduced from year to year, of those credits which were not allowed by paragraph (a) or paragraph (c) or which exceed the excise for the taxable year; provided, however, that in no event shall the corporation apply the credit to its excise for any taxable year beginning more than five years after the certified project or economic opportunity area ceases to qualify as such under the provisions of chapter twenty-three A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     In the case of corporations filing a combined return of income under section thirty-two B, a credit generated by an individual member corporation under the provisions of this section shall first be applied against the separately determined excise attributable to that member, subject to the limitations of paragraph (a) or paragraph (c). A member corporation with an excess credit may apply its excess credit against the excise of another group member, to the extent that such other member corporation can use additional credits under the limitation of said paragraph (a) or paragraph (c). Unused, unexpired credits generated by member corporations shall be carried over from year to year by the individual corporation that generated the credit. Nothing in this section shall alter the provisions of paragraph (h) of section thirty-one A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     For purposes of this section, the commissioner of revenue may aggregate the activities of all corporations that are members of a controlled group of corporations and, in addition, may aggregate the activities of all entities, whether or not incorporated, under common control as defined in subsection (f) of section forty-one of the Code.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The commissioner of revenue shall promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary to implement the provisions of this section. Such rules and regulations may provide the adjustment of intercompany prices and elimination of intercompany transactions to ensure that all amounts upon which the credit is based reasonably reflect fair market value. In addition, such rules and regulations shall include provisions to prevent the generation of multiple credits with respect to the same property.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>