<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licenses; Issuance; Form; Display</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        Upon the application of any person entitled to receive a sporting, hunting, fishing or trapping license and upon payment of the fee specified therefor in this chapter, and the furnishing of an affidavit by any non-resident desiring to be classified under the first paragraph of section eleven, the director, the clerk of any city or town, persons employed in the department of fisheries, wildlife and environmental law enforcement, the Massachusetts office of business development and the division of fisheries and wildlife and persons authorized by the director to issue such licenses at their place of business located within or without the commonwealth provided such persons are duly bonded, shall issue to such person a sporting, hunting, fishing or trapping license, as the case may be, in such form as the director shall prescribe and furnish. Subject to existing laws, a sporting license shall authorize the licensee to hunt birds and mammals and to fish, a fishing license shall authorize the licensee to fish only, a hunting license shall authorize the licensee to hunt only, and a trapping license shall authorize the licensee to trap mammals only. Each license issued hereunder shall bear a written declaration, signed by the licensee, under penalty of perjury, that data and statements contained in the license are true, and such other data as the director requires. The holder of a hunting, fishing, sporting or trapping license shall, while hunting, fishing or trapping, carry on his person and wear in a visible manner on his outer clothing his license authorizing him to do so in accordance with such rules and regulations as the director may from time to time prescribe. 
At such time as the division of fisheries and wildlife has instituted an automated licensing system, the holder of a hunting, fishing, sporting or trapping license shall carry said license on his person and shall not be required to wear it in a visible manner.
    </text>
</law>