<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Industrial Truck And Internal Combustion Equipment; Operation;  Construction Of Docks</catch_line>
    <order_by>18G</order_by>
    <text>
        Every industrial truck (lift truck or jitney) and tractor, except those guided or controlled by a walking operator shall be equipped with a clearly audible horn or other warning device. 
Every industrial truck (lift truck or jitney) operated from an end platform shall be equipped with a substantial guard to protect the operator. This guard should allow the operator quick and easy access to and from his operating position. 
The division may require every high-lift truck (lift jitney) to be provided with a canopy guard which will protect the operator from falling objects. 
Every high-lift industrial truck (lift jitney) handling small objects or unstable loads shall be equipped with a vertical back rest or back guard at the rear of the load platform. This does not apply to lift trucks equipped with canopy guards in compliance with preceding paragraph. 
Every dock or car plate shall be constructed to support its load. It shall be safely secured in position and shall provide rigid security over its span. The end edges of the plate shall be in substantial contact with the dock or loading platform and the vehicle bed in a manner that will prevent rocking or sliding. Adequate and safe means shall be provided for moving plates. 
Pallets shall be constructed and maintained with strength adequate for the loads being handled. They shall be kept in good repair. Pallets upon which employees customarily walk shall have no surface opening in excess of two inches in width. 
Internal combustion engine-driven equipment shall not be operated inside of buildings or enclosed structures, if such operation would result in harmful exposure to concentrations of dangerous gases or fumes in excess of maximum acceptable concentrations. Exhaust pipes shall be installed in such a manner that the exhaust products shall be discharged so as not to be a hazard to the operator. 
The rated capacity of all high-lift trucks (lift jitneys) shall be displayed at all times on the vehicles so that it is readily visible to the operator. They shall not be loaded beyond their rated capacity. Counterweights may be added to increase lifting capacity, provided they do not impair the stability of the vehicle or stress any of the structural members beyond a safe limit. 
Every employer shall promulgate, post and enforce a set of operating rules. These rules shall govern the control, operation and maintenance of all industrial trucks. 
Refueling of internal combustion engine fuel tanks shall be done in designated areas. Suitable and adequate gasoline pumps shall be used. Gasoline shall not be handled in open containers. Motors shall be stopped and no source of ignition shall be permitted in the vicinity of the refueling operation. Federal and local regulations shall be enforced. 
Before operating any truck, drivers shall check the vehicle and if it is found to be in any way unsafe, it shall be reported to the proper authority and shall not be operated until it has been made safe. Brakes shall be tested on starting each trip.
    </text>
</law>