<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90B" order_by="90B" level="3">Motorboats, Other Vessels And Recreational Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>28A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Suspension Of License And Revocation Of Registration Of Snow Or Recreation Vehicle Due To Violation Of Sec. 26 B; Underage Violations</catch_line>
    <order_by>28A</order_by>
    <text>
        Notwithstanding section 28, upon conviction of, or adjudication of delinquency by reason of a violation of subsections (c) to (e), inclusive, of section 26B the registrar shall immediately suspend the operator’s license or right to operate a motor vehicle and the director shall revoke the registration of any snow vehicle or recreation vehicle issued to such person. The registrar, after having suspended or revoked the license or right to operate of a person pursuant to this section, shall issue a new license or reinstate the right to operate of such person if the prosecution or adjudication of such person is terminated in favor of the defendant or juvenile and the director shall issue a new registration number if a vehicle was registered to such person. The registrar may, after an investigation or upon a hearing, issue a new license or reinstate the right to operate and the director may issue a new snow vehicle or recreation vehicle registration number to a person convicted or adjudicated delinquent for a violation of said subsections (c) to (e), inclusive, of said section 26B; provided, however, that no such license, right to operate or registration shall be reinstated by the registrar or issued by the director to any person so convicted or adjudicated delinquent by reason of said subsection (c) or (d) of said section 26B until 1 year after the date of suspension or revocation following his original conviction or adjudication of delinquency if for a first offense or until 2 years after the date of suspension or revocation if for a subsequent conviction or adjudication of delinquency, or to any person convicted of or adjudicated delinquent by reason of subsection (e) of said section 26B until 5 years after the date of suspension or revocation following his original conviction or adjudication if for a first offense, or until 15 years after the date of suspension or revocation if for a subsequent conviction or adjudication. 
If the person so convicted or adjudicated is under age 17 at the time of a conviction or adjudication of delinquency under subsections (c) to (e), inclusive, of section 26B, inclusive, and he has not been issued a license or right to operate or has not been issued a snow vehicle or recreation vehicle registration number, neither the registrar nor the director shall issue such license or right to operate a motor vehicle or a snow vehicle or recreation vehicle registration until the time periods provided in the previous paragraph have passed and calculation of such time period shall not commence to run until such person reaches age 16 for purposes of issuance of a right to operate a motor vehicle and 16 and one-half for purposes of issuance of a license to operate a motor vehicle and for issuance of a snow vehicle or recreation vehicle registration number.
    </text>
</law>