<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18B" order_by="18B" level="3">Department Of Social Services</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15</section_number>
    <catch_line>Area Boards; Powers And Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>15</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     to act as the representative of the citizens of the area;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     to advise regarding local needs and resources in the development of comprehensive social services for children and families;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     to advise in the recruitment and selection of the area director and assistant area director to be appointed by the commissioner; provided that the commissioner may designate a person to act as area director for a period not to exceed three months in any case in which such office shall be vacant, and
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     to review and approve the annual area plan and to make recommendations concerning the annual budget for the comprehensive social services for children and families of the area;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     to review arrangements and contracts for programs and services which are a part of the program of the area;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     to consult with the commissioner and area director in personnel recruitment and appointment policies within the area, in the establishment of program priorities for the area, and in policies regarding relationships with other agencies and organizations;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     to receive funds under contracts or other agreements from community sources, including municipalities, as authorized for the rendering of services in collaboration with such municipal or other community or private agencies providing cooperative or complementary services;
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     to discuss any matters concerning the area program;
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     to hold at least four regular meetings in each year and to convene special meetings on the call of the president, or ten members of the board, or the area director. The area director shall be notified of, and may participate in, all meetings, but shall not vote;
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     to select from their members annually a president and such other officers as they may deem appropriate. The area board shall adopt rules for their proper organization and for procedures at meetings. Such rules and any subsequent amendments thereto shall be submitted to the commissioner for approval.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>