<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23D" order_by="23D" level="3">Employee Ownership Revolving Loan Fund</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Executive Director; Employees; Utilization Of Other Agencies’ Resources</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        Subject to appropriation, the director of economic development and the director of labor and workforce development shall hire an executive director and such other employees as they may from time to time find necessary for the proper performance of the duties of the program; provided, however, that in the hiring of the executive director said director of economic development and the director of labor and workforce development shall consult with the board of trustees of the economic stabilization fund. At least one such employee shall be hired for the purpose of packaging and reviewing applications for financing by the economic stabilization fund, as provided in section thirteen, and the board of said fund shall have the right to approve the hiring of any persons for this purpose. 
The executive director shall be the executive and administrative head of the program and shall be responsible for administering and enforcing the provisions of law relative to the program. 
The executive director of the industrial services program may utilize the offices, staff, and resources of other agencies of the executive branch including, but not limited to, the Bay State Skills Corporation, the Massachusetts office of business development, the department of labor and workforce development and the department of housing and community development, the Massachusetts community development finance corporation, the Massachusetts government land bank, the Massachusetts industrial finance agency, the Massachusetts Product Development Corporation, the Massachusetts Economic Stabilization Fund, and the Massachusetts Technology Development Corporation and such voluntary and uncompensated services as may from time to time be necessary for the proper performance of the duties and purposes of the program.
    </text>
</law>