<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Financing; Notice Of Intent; Necessity Of Application For Determination Of Need; Acceptance Of Gifts; Governmental Bodies As Applicant; Report</catch_line>
    <order_by>25D</order_by>
    <text>
        Every person, at least thirty days prior to making a public solicitation of funds or otherwise securing financing for construction of a health care facility or a substantial change in the services of a facility, shall file written notice of his intent to do so with the department. In the case of a solicitation of funds from the general public, the department may require such person to file an application for a determination of need for such construction or substantial change in services and to postpone any such public solicitation of funds until such application has been acted upon by the department and such need has been found to exist; provided, however, that failure of the department to comment upon a notice of intent shall not be construed to constitute a determination that such need exists. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit any person or agency subject to sections twenty-five C to twenty-five G, inclusive, from accepting gifts, and the provisions of this section shall not apply to any such solicitation or securing of financing where the undertaking to be funded is not sufficiently specific to constitute the subject matter of an application for determination of need under section twenty-five C. 
Each agency of the commonwealth and its political subdivisions desiring to make substantial capital expenditure for construction of a health care facility or to substantially change the services of such a facility shall make application for determination of need therefor pursuant to section twenty-five C, and the department shall transmit a report of its determination thereon to the agencies empowered to recommend and to make appropriations of money for the applicant agency.
    </text>
</law>