<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>43</section_number>
    <catch_line>Powers And Duties Of Board Of Registration Of Dentistry; Records;  Annual Reports</catch_line>
    <order_by>43</order_by>
    <text>
        The board of registration of dentistry, herein and in sections forty-three A to fifty-three, inclusive, called the board, shall examine applicants for registration in dentistry, and shall investigate all complaints of violations of sections forty-four, forty-nine, fifty-two, fifty-two A, fifty-two C and sixty-five. In aid thereof, the board may make, and shall publish, such rules and regulations as it deems necessary. If, as a result of such investigation, the board has reasonable cause to believe that a violation has occurred, it shall forthwith file a written report of the same with the attorney general who shall, within three months following receipt of such report, notify the board in writing of the action taken with respect to such violation. The board may also bring a petition in equity in the superior court to enjoin the continuation of such violation. Five members of the board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The board shall keep a full record of its proceedings and a registry of all persons registered by it, which shall be public records open to inspection. A transcript of any of the entries in such record, certified by its secretary, shall be competent evidence of the facts stated therein. The board shall make a full and accurate annual report. 
The board shall employ a full-time assistant secretary and it may employ such investigators and other clerical assistance as it deems necessary, all such positions to be subject to the provisions of chapter thirty-one.
    </text>
</law>