<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>26C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Council Of Health In Cities; Members; Qualifications;  Appointment; Terms; Removal; Compensation; Meetings; Function</catch_line>
    <order_by>26C</order_by>
    <text>
        The advisory council of health shall consist of nine persons, two of whom shall be registered physicians and five of whom shall be nonprofessionals. For the purposes of this section “nonprofessionals” shall mean a person whose background and experience indicate that he is qualified to act in the broad public interest. Such person, his spouse, parents, siblings or children shall not be employed by a health care facility, by a nonprofit service corporation established in accordance with chapters one hundred seventy-six A to one hundred seventy-six E, inclusive, nor by a corporation authorized to insure the health of individuals. Such person or his spouse shall not be licensed to practice medicine. No member of said council shall be a member of the city council. The members of said council first appointed hereunder shall be appointed as follows:—three members to serve for one year, three members to serve for two years, and three members to serve for three years, from the first Monday of the following February, and until the qualification of their respective successors, and thereafter three members shall be appointed in January of each year for three years from the first Monday of the following February, and until the qualification of their respective successors. In a city, unless a different mode of appointment or election is provided in the city charter, the members shall be appointed by the mayor, subject to confirmation by the city council, and in a town the members shall be appointed by the board of selectmen. Members may be removed in the same manner, for cause, and vacancies shall be filled in the same manner, by appointment for the remainder of the unexpired term. Members of the advisory council of health shall be compensated at ten dollars a day while on duty plus expenses incurred in line of duty. Said council shall meet quarterly and additional meetings may be held at any time at the call of the commissioner of health who shall act as chairman of said council. The advisory council of health shall advise and assist the commissioner of health.
    </text>
</law>