<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration Of Perfusionists; Members; Officers</catch_line>
    <order_by>11E</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board of registration of perfusionists, herein called the board, to consist of seven members who shall be residents of the commonwealth, to be appointed by the governor who, in his discretion, may seek advice from the Massachusetts Society of Perfusion, or its successor. Four members shall be perfusionists licensed for two years in accordance with the provisions of section 213 or section 217 of chapter 112. Two members shall be licensed physicians, one of whom shall be actively engaged as a cardiovascular surgeon and one of whom shall be an anesthesiologist actively engaged in the practice of cardiac anesthesia, and one member shall be a representative of the general public. No member shall be an employee of a trade association in the field of health care and no member who is a representative of the general public shall be engaged in the practice of any health care profession. 
Members shall be appointed for terms of three years. No member shall be appointed to more than two consecutive full terms but a member appointed for less than a full term may serve two full terms in addition to such part of a full term and a former member shall again be eligible for appointment after a lapse of at least one year. A member may be removed by the governor for neglect of duty, misconduct or malfeasance or misfeasance in office after a written notice of the charges against him and an opportunity to be heard. 
The board shall, at its first meeting and annually thereafter, elect from among its members a chairman, vice chairman and secretary. Officers shall serve until successors are elected and qualified. The board shall meet at the call of the chairman or upon request of four members of the board. The board shall meet at least two times annually. A quorum shall consist of four members present. Board members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual and reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.
    </text>
</law>