<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90B" order_by="90B" level="3">Motorboats, Other Vessels And Recreational Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Discharge Of Sewage Into Waters Designated As A No Discharge Area;  Fine</catch_line>
    <order_by>5C</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person that discharges sewage, whether treated or not, from a marine sanitation device into any waters of the commonwealth designated by the secretary of environmental affairs as a no discharge area pursuant to 33 U.S.C. 1322 shall be punished by a fine not to exceed $2,000 for each violation of this section. 
If a person defaults in the payment of a fine imposed for a violation of this section, or any portion thereof, the court shall cause a copy of the court record reflecting such default to be transmitted forthwith to the director. The court shall send a new copy of such person’s court record to the director upon satisfaction of the fine. After receipt of a court record showing a default for nonpayment of a fine, or portion thereof, the director shall not issue an original certificate of number or renew a certificate of number to the person in default for any boat owned by such person until notified that such fine is satisfied. If a certificate of number was issued to such person prior to receipt of the record showing a default for nonpayment of a fine, or portion thereof, the director shall revoke such certificate of number for any boat owned by such person until notified that such fine is satisfied. 
Notwithstanding section 10G of chapter 21A, all fines collected pursuant to this section shall be paid to the commonwealth for deposit into the General Fund.
    </text>
</law>