<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Contracts For Repair, Etc., On Certain Highway Routes;  Hours Of Nonemergency Work Restricted</catch_line>
    <order_by>8C</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. Repealed by 2012, 165, Sec. 112. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  Any contract for the resurfacing, maintenance, minor reconstruction, or minor repair of any major state highway or numbered route within the city of Boston, between said city and state highway route 128, of state highway route 3 as far south as the junction of state highway route 139, on which the average daily traffic exceeds seventy thousand vehicles per day, and any contract for the maintenance, minor reconstruction, or minor repair of state highway route 128 between its junction with state highway route 3 in the town of Braintree and its junction with U.S. route 1 in the town of Lynnfield, to be awarded by the department of highways, the metropolitan district commission, or by a municipality under section thirty-four of chapter ninety shall, unless such contract involves the performance of emergency work as hereinafter described, provide that no work shall be performed between the hours of six-thirty and nine o'clock ante meridian on lanes inbound to the city of Boston or between the hours of four and six post meridian on lanes outbound from the city of Boston, Monday through Friday, except holidays. No such work, except emergency work, shall be performed on such a highway or route by a public employee during such hours. As used in this section emergency work shall include only those projects immediately necessary to insure the safety of persons using such highways or routes.
    </text>
</law>