<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90B" order_by="90B" level="3">Motorboats, Other Vessels And Recreational Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Powers And Duties Of Director</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Exempt any vessel or class of vessels from the numbering provisions of this chapter if such vessel or class of vessels has been made exempt from the numbering provisions of the Federal Boating Act of 1958 by the secretary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Issue safety certificates in such form and under such terms and conditions as he may designate and may require that any person, before operating on the waters of the commonwealth, any motorboat or other vessel subject to the provisions of this chapter or of any rule or regulation made under authority hereof, shall hold such a valid safety certificate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Prescribe the type of life preservers, life belts, ring buoys or other similar devices to be carried on board motorboats.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Prescribe the type of fire extinguishers to be carried on board motorboats; provided, that any type so prescribed has been approved by the Coast Guard.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Prescribe the type of flame arrestors, backfire traps or similar devices to be used on motorboats with inboard engines and using gasoline as fuel; provided, that any device so prescribed has been approved by the Coast Guard.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Prescribe devices to be used for the proper and efficient ventilation of the bilge of engine and fuel tank compartments of motorboats using liquid of a volatile nature for fuel.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Approve the conduct of motorboat races, including the times, places and any other circumstances of such races, and may require the establishment of safety precautions in connection therewith.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Permit the use of cutouts on motorboats and operated in accordance with the provisions of section six.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Approve professional exhibitions of waterskiing, surfboarding or similar activity, and therefore may suspend the provisions of section eight (c) and (d).
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Establish speed limits for motorboats on any of the rivers, harbors, lakes or ponds located within the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof; provided, however, that the maximum speed limit for jet-skis, surf jets and wet bikes shall be twelve miles per hour; and provided, further that such maximum speed limit shall not apply in rivers, harbors, lakes or ponds where there is no speed limit so established.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     Make the provisions of this chapter and rules and regulations made under authority thereof and such other rules and regulations as he may deem in the interest of the public safety applicable to any vessel not otherwise subject to the provisions of this act when operated or maintained on any waters lying wholly within the land boundaries of the commonwealth, except ponds less than ten acres in area and owned by one person.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     Inquire into the causes of boating accidents and, for such purpose, he may require the attendance of witnesses and the production of books and documents, and may examine witnesses on oath; and such witnesses shall be paid the same fees as in civil actions in the courts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     Suspend or revoke and cancel and require the surrender of any certificate of number issued by him if, in his opinion, after a hearing, after due notice, by him or by some person designated by him, the operator is guilty of violating any provision of this chapter or of any rule and regulation made under authority hereof. Pending such hearing and any appeal from a decision hereunder, said certificate of number shall be suspended.
        </section>
        <section prefix="n">
    	     Approve or disapprove any ordinance or by-law of any city or town which regulates the operation of such vessels and such activities as are subject to the provisions of this chapter or of any rule or regulations made under authority hereof, on such waters of the commonwealth as lie within such city or town.
        </section>
        <section prefix="o">
    	     Prescribe the manner in which and the contents of any reports required to be filed under the provisions of section seventeen.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>