<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90B" order_by="90B" level="3">Motorboats, Other Vessels And Recreational Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Operation While Under Influence Of Intoxicating Liquor Or Narcotics, Etc.; Breath Or Blood Testing; Water Skiing; Professional Exhibitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     (1) No person shall operate any vessel on the waters of the commonwealth with a percentage, by weight, of alcohol in their blood of eight one-hundredths or greater, or while such person is under the influence of intoxicating liquor or marijuana, narcotic drugs, depressant or stimulant substances, as defined in chapter ninety-four C, or the vapors of glue.
        </section>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     Whoever so operates any vessel shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred nor more than one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than two and one-half years, or both.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     A prosecution commenced under the provisions of this paragraph shall not be placed on file or continued without a finding. No trial shall be commenced on a complaint alleging a violation of this paragraph, nor shall any plea be accepted on such a complaint, nor shall the prosecution on such a complaint be transferred to another division of the district court or to a jury-of-six session, until the court receives a report from the commissioner of probation pertaining to the defendant’s record, if any, of prior convictions of like offenses or of assignment to an alcohol education or rehabilitation program because of a like offense; provided, however, that the provisions of this paragraph shall not justify the postponement of any such trial or of the acceptance of any such plea for more than five working days after the date of the defendant’s arraignment. The commissioner of probation shall give priority to requests for such records.
        </section>
        <section prefix="C">
    	     At any time before the commencement of a trial or acceptance of a plea on a complaint alleging a violation of this paragraph, the prosecutor may apply for the issuance of a new complaint pursuant to section thirty-five A of chapter two hundred and eighteen alleging a violation of this paragraph and one or more prior like offenses. If such application is made upon motion of the prosecutor, the court shall stay further proceedings on the original complaint pending the determination of the application for the new complaint. If a new complaint is issued, the court shall dismiss the original complaint and order that further proceedings on the new complaint be postponed until the defendant has had sufficient time to prepare a defense.
        </section>
        <section prefix="D">
    	     If a defendant waives right to a jury trial pursuant to section twenty-six A of chapter two hundred and eighteen on a complaint under this paragraph he shall be deemed to have waived right to a jury trial on all elements of said complaint subject to the right to appeal pursuant to section twenty-seven A of said chapter two hundred and eighteen.
        </section>
        <section prefix="E">
    	     Except as provided herein the provisions of section eighty-seven of chapter two hundred and seventy-six shall not apply to any person charged with a violation of this paragraph if said person has been convicted of or assigned to an alcohol education or rehabilitation program because of a like offense by a court of the commonwealth within a period of six years immediately preceding the commission of the offense with which he is charged.
        </section>
        <section prefix="F">
    	     Notwithstanding the provisions of section six A of chapter two hundred and seventy-nine, the court may order that a defendant convicted of a violation of this subparagraph be actually imprisoned only on designated weekends, evenings or holidays; provided, however, that the provisions of this paragraph shall apply only to a defendant who has not been convicted previously of a like offense or assigned to an alcohol education or rehabilitation program within six years preceding the date of the commission of the offense for which he has been convicted.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     (a) In any prosecution for a violation of paragraph (1), evidence of the percentage, by weight, of alcohol in the defendant’s blood at the time of the alleged offense, as shown by chemical test or analysis of his blood or as indicated by chemical test or analysis of his breath, shall be admissible, and such failure or refusal shall be admissible in any action by the registrar under this section or in any proceedings provided for in section twenty-four N of chapter ninety, and deemed relevant to the determination of the question of whether the defendant was at such time under the influence of intoxicating liquor; provided, however, that if such test or analysis was made by or at the direction of a law enforcement officer, it was made with the consent of the defendant, the results thereof were made available to the defendant upon his request and the defendant was afforded a reasonable opportunity, at his request and at his expense, to have another such test or analysis made by a person or physician selected by him; and provided, further, that blood shall not be withdrawn from any person for the purpose of such test or analysis except by a physician, registered or certified medical technician; and, provided further, that a chemical test or analysis of the defendant’s breath shall be by means of equipment which has been calibrated within thirty days of its use.
        </section>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     If a person arrested for operating a vessel while under the influence of intoxicating liquor refuses to submit to such test or analysis, after having been informed that his license, permit or right to operate motor vehicles shall be suspended and any certificate or numbers may be revoked for a period of one hundred and twenty days for such refusal, no such test or analysis shall be made, but the officer before whom such refusal was made shall immediately prepare a written report of such refusal. Each such report shall be made on a form approved by the registrar, and shall be sworn to under the penalties of perjury by the officer before whom such refusal was made. Each such report shall set forth the grounds for the officer’s belief that the person arrested had been operating a vessel while under the influence of intoxicating liquor, and shall state that such person had refused to submit to such chemical test or analysis when requested by such officer to do so such refusal having been witnessed by another person other than the defendant. Each such report shall identify which police officer requested said chemical test or analysis, and the other person witnessing said refusal. Each such report shall be sent forthwith to the registrar and to the director along with a copy of the notice of intent to suspend in any form, including electronic or otherwise, that the registrar deems appropriate. Upon receipt of such report, the registrar shall suspend any license or permit to operate motor vehicles issued to such person under chapter ninety or the right of such person to operate motor vehicles in the commonwealth under section ten for a period of one hundred and twenty days, and the director may revoke any and all certificates of number of any vessel of such person and may refuse to issue any certificate of number to such vessels for a period of one hundred and twenty days. Said report shall constitute prima facie evidence of the facts set forth therein at any administrative hearing regarding any suspension specified in this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     Any person whose license, permit or right to operate motor vehicles has been suspended or whose certificate of number has been revoked under this paragraph shall be entitled to a hearing before the registrar which shall be limited to the following issues: (i) did the officer have reasonable grounds to believe that such person had been operating a vessel while under the influence of intoxicating liquor on the waters of the commonwealth, (ii) was such person placed under arrest and (iii) did such person refuse to submit to such test or analysis. If, after such hearing, the registrar finds on any one of the said issues in the negative, the registrar shall reinstate such license, permit or right to operate motor vehicles of such person and shall notify the director of such reinstatement. Upon receipt of such notification, the director shall reinstate such certificate of number to the vessel of such person.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     (A) Notwithstanding any of the foregoing, any person convicted of or charged with a violation of paragraph (1) and who has not been previously convicted or assigned to an alcohol education or rehabilitation program because of a like offense, may, if he consents, be placed on probation for not more than two years and shall, as a condition of probation, be ordered to complete a boating safety education course, if he has not previously completed one and received a certificate of same and, if deemed necessary by the court, to complete an alcohol education or rehabilitation program provided or sanctioned by the division of alcoholism, and comply with all conditions of said alcohol education or rehabilitation program. Such conditions of probation shall specify a date before which such boating safety education course and alcohol education or rehabilitation program must be attended and completed. Such order of probation shall be in addition to any penalties imposed as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     The defendant shall pay for the cost of the services provided by the boating safety education course, the alcohol education or rehabilitation program, and the residential alcohol treatment program; however, no person shall be excluded from said programs for inability to pay, provided that such person files an affidavit of indigency or inability to pay with the court, that investigation by the probation officer confirms such indigency or establishes that the payment of such fee would cause a grave and serious hardship to such individual or to the family of such individual, and that the court enters a written finding thereof. In lieu of waiver of the entire amount of said fee, the court may direct such individual to make partial or installment payments of the cost of said program.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     (a) A conviction of a violation of paragraph (1) shall revoke the license or right to operate motor vehicles and may, in the discretion of the director, revoke the certificate of number of the person so convicted, and no appeal, motion for new trial or exceptions shall operate to stay the revocation of the license, right to operate, or certificate of number. Such revoked license and certificate of number shall immediately be surrendered to the prosecuting officer who shall forward the license to the registrar and the certificate of number to the director. The court shall report immediately any revocation, under this paragraph, of a license or right to operate to the registrar and to the police department of the municipality in which the defendant is domiciled and any revocation, under this paragraph, of a certificate of number to the director.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Where the license, right to operate, or certificate of number has been revoked under this paragraph, and such person has not been convicted of a like offense or has not been assigned to an alcohol education or rehabilitation program because of a like offense by a court of the commonwealth within a period of ten years preceding the date of the commission of the offense for which he has been convicted, the registrar shall not restore the license or reinstate the right to operate to such person and the director may refuse to issue a certificate of number to the vessel of such person unless the prosecution of such person has terminated in favor of the defendant, until one year after the date of conviction; provided, however, that if such person has been placed under probation as provided by paragraph (3) of this subsection and has successfully completed all terms of such probation, the registrar shall not restore the license or reinstate the right to operate to such person and the director may refuse to issue a certificate of number to the vessel of such person until forty-five days after the date of conviction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No person shall use any water skis, surfboard or similar device on the waters of the commonwealth negligently so as to endanger the lives or safety of the public, or use any water skis, surfboard or similar device thereon in the nighttime.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No person shall operate any motorboat on the waters of the commonwealth towing a person or persons on water skis, a surfboard or other similar device, unless there is in such motorboat a person who has attained age twelve in addition to the operator in a position to observe the person or persons being towed, and unless such motorboat is equipped with a ladder, steps or similar means by which any person being towed can be taken from the water.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     So much of the provisions of subsection (b) as prohibit the use of water skis, surfboards or similar devices in the nighttime, and the provisions of subsections (c) and (d), shall not apply to a performer engaged in a professional exhibition which has previously been approved by the director.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     (1) Whoever upon any waters of the commonwealth, operates a vessel recklessly, or operates a vessel negligently so that the lives or safety of the public might be endangered, or upon a bet or wager or in a race, or whoever operates a vessel for the purpose of making a record and thereby violates any speed regulation, or whoever without stopping and making known his name, residence and the identification number of his vessel goes away after knowingly colliding with or otherwise causing injury to any other vessel or property, or whoever knowingly makes any false statement in an application for a certificate of number of a vessel shall be punished by a fine of not less than fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not less than thirty days nor more than two years, or both.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A conviction of a violation of this subsection shall be reported forthwith by the court or magistrate to the registrar, who may in any event, and shall unless the court or magistrate recommends otherwise, revoke immediately the license or right to operate and to the director, who may immediately revoke the certificates of number of the person so convicted, and no appeal, motion for new trial or exceptions shall operate to stay the revocation of such license, right to operate or certificates of number. If it appears by the records of the director that the person so convicted is the owner of a vessel or has exclusive control of any vessel as a manufacturer or dealer or otherwise, the director may revoke the certificates of number of any or all vessels so owned or exclusively controlled.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The registrar, after having revoked the license or right to operate of any person under this subsection, in his discretion, may issue a new license or reinstate the right to operate and the director may issue a new certificate of number, if the prosecution of such person in the superior court has terminated in favor of the defendant or after an investigation or upon hearing, the registrar may issue a new license or reinstate the right to operate and the director may issue a new certificate of number to a person convicted in any court of the violation of any provision of this subsection; provided, that no license shall be issued by the registrar to any person convicted of going away without stopping and making known his name, residence and the certificate of number of his vessel after having, while operating such vessel upon any such waters, knowingly collided with or otherwise caused injury to any person, or to any person adjudged a delinquent child by reason thereof under the provisions of section fifty-eight B of chapter one hundred and nineteen, until one year after the date of revocation following his original conviction or adjudication if for a first offense or until two years after the date of revocation following any subsequent conviction or adjudication, or to any person convicted of using a vessel knowing that such use is unauthorized, until one year after the date of revocation following his original conviction or adjudication if for a first offense or until three years after the date of revocation following any subsequent conviction or adjudication, or to any person convicted of violating any other provision of this subsection until sixty days after the date of revocation following his original conviction if for a first offense, or one year after the date of revocation following any subsequent conviction within a period of three years. But the registrar, after investigation, may at any time rescind the revocation of a license or right to operate revoked because of a conviction of operating a vessel upon any such waters negligently so that the lives or safety of the public might be endangered and the director, after investigation, may at any time rescind the revocation of a certificate of number revoked because of a conviction of operating a vessel upon any such waters negligently so that the lives or safety of the public might be endangered.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The prosecution of any person for the violation of any provision of this subsection, if a subsequent offense, shall not, unless the interests of justice require such disposition, be placed on file or otherwise disposed of except by trial, judgment and sentence according to the regular course of criminal proceedings; and such a prosecution shall be otherwise disposed of only on motion in writing stating specifically the reasons therefor and verified by affidavits if facts are relied upon. If the court or magistrate certifies in writing that it is satisfied that the reasons relied upon are sufficient and that the interests of justice require the allowance of the motion, the motion shall be allowed and the certificate shall be filed in the case. A copy of the motion and certificate shall be sent by the court or magistrate forthwith to the director.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     In any prosecution commenced pursuant to this section, introduction into evidence of a prior conviction or prior finding of sufficient facts by either original court papers or certified attested copy of original court papers, accompanied by a certified attested copy of the biographical and informational data from official probation office records, shall be prima facie evidence that a defendant has been convicted previously or assigned to an alcohol education or rehabilitation program because of a like offense by a court of the commonwealth one or more times within a period of six years preceding the date of commission of the offense for which said defendant is being prosecuted.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>