<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40D" order_by="40D" level="3">Industrial Development Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22</section_number>
    <catch_line>Pollution Control Facilities; Financing; Findings; Financing Authority; Applicable Laws</catch_line>
    <order_by>22</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A municipality acting by and through an authority may finance pollution control facilities in the same manner provided by this chapter for industrial development facilities, except as otherwise hereinafter provided.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The requirements of clauses (e), (g), (i), and (k) of subsection (2) of section twelve shall not apply to projects for pollution control. It shall be necessary, however, that the state industrial finance board find that a substantial public benefit will result from the project and in the case of pollution control facilities for water, the division of water pollution control in the department of environmental protection, or, in the case of pollution control facilities for air, the commissioner of environmental protection, has found that the project as designed is in furtherance of the purpose of abating or controlling water pollution or air pollution, as the case may be.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     An authority having industrial development powers or solid waste disposal powers, heretofore or hereafter organized, shall also have pollution control powers under this section but the provisions of this section shall not affect the power of a municipality, acting by and through an authority, to finance pollution control facilities as a part of an industrial development project or solid waste disposal project.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>