<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>79</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration Of Psychologists; Meetings; Election Of Officers; Licenses; Rules And Regulations; Compensation; Assistants</catch_line>
    <order_by>79</order_by>
    <text>
        The board shall, at its first meeting, and at each annual meeting thereafter, organize by electing from among its members a chairman, a vice-chairman and a secretary. Such officers shall serve until their successors are elected and qualified. 
The board shall hold at least two regular meetings each year; but additional meetings may be held upon call of the chairman or the secretary, or at the written request of any three members of the board. Five members of the board shall constitute a quorum. 
The board shall examine and pass upon the qualifications of applicants for licenses to practice psychology in the commonwealth and shall issue licenses to qualified applicants, but no action shall be taken with respect to the granting of a license or its revocation or suspension without the concurrence of at least five members of the board. The board shall issue certifications as health service providers to qualified applicants. The board shall adopt a seal which shall be affixed to all licenses issued by the board. 
The board, in consultation with the director of consumer affairs and business regulations, shall from time to time promulgate such rules and regulations and such amendments thereof and supplements thereto as it may deem necessary. 
The members of the board shall serve without compensation but each member shall be reimbursed for actual expenses reasonably incurred in the performance of his duties as a member on behalf of the board. The board shall be empowered to hire such assistants as it may deem necessary to carry on its activities. 
The board may also appoint psychologists, subject to the approval of the director of consumer affairs and business regulations, who meet the qualifications for appointment to the board, to assist it in administering the examination required by section one hundred and twenty of chapter one hundred and twelve. Said assistance shall be provided under the supervision of a board member.
    </text>
</law>