<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21L" order_by="21L" level="3">Environmental Endangerment Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in the chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:— 
“Buzzards bay”, the waterway bounded and described as follows: from Sakonnet point southward to the north end of the Buzzards bay traffic separation zone, to the southwestern tip of Cuttyhunk island thence through Buzzards bay to the eastern entrance of the Cape Cod canal at the United States Coast Guard “CC” buoy in Cape Cod bay, including Woods Hole passage and Quicks hole. 
“Environmental violation”, a violation of the following statutes or regulations promulgated thereunder: sections 26 to 53, inclusive, of chapter 21; chapter 21C, chapter 21E; sections 142A, 142B and 150A of chapter 111; and section 40 of chapter 131. 
“Natural resources”, land fish, wildlife, biota, air, water, groundwater and drinking water supplies belonging to, managed by, held in trust by, appertaining to or otherwise controlled by the commonwealth or any local government. 
“Organization”, a person other than an individual. 
“Person”, an individual, public or private corporation or authority, trust, firm, joint stock company, partnership, association or other entity and any officer, employee, or agent of such person and any group of persons. 
“Serious bodily injury”, bodily injury which creates a substantial risk of death or which involves unconsciousness, extreme physical pain, protracted and obvious disfigurement, protracted loss or impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ or mental faculty, reproductive or genetic damage or a substantially increased risk of cancer or other chronic ailment. 
“Tank vessel”, a ship that is constructed or adapted to carry, or that carries, oil or other petroleum product in bulk as cargo and that operates on the waters of the commonwealth or transfers oil or other petroleum products in a port or place subject to the jurisdiction of the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>