<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118E" order_by="118E" level="3">Division Of Medical Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Contracts Between Acute And Non Acute Hospital Service Providers And Office Of Medicaid</catch_line>
    <order_by>13F</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 123 effective November 4, 2012.]  All rates of payment to acute hospitals and non-acute hospitals under Title XIX shall be established by contract between the provider of such hospital services and the office of Medicaid, except as provided in subsections (a) and (b), or otherwise permitted by law. All rates shall be subject to all applicable Title XIX statutory and regulatory requirements and shall include reimbursement for the reasonable cost of providing competent interpreter services under section 25J of chapter 111 or section 23A of chapter 123.  All such rates for non-acute hospitals shall be effective as of the date specified in section 13A, unless otherwise specified by law.  (a) For disproportionate share hospitals, the executive office shall establish rates that equal the financial requirements of providing care to recipients of medical assistance.  (b) The executive office, or governmental unit designated by the executive office, shall establish rates of payment which shall apply to emergency services and continuing emergency care provided in acute hospitals to medical assistance program recipients, including examination or treatment for an emergency medical condition or active labor in women or any other care rendered to the extent required by 42 USC 1395(dd), unless such services are provided under an agreement between the office of Medicaid and the acute hospital. Such rates of payment shall reflect the reasonable costs of providing such care, including the costs of providing competent interpreter services under section 25J of chapter 111 or section 23A of chapter 123 and shall take into account the characteristics of the hospital in which such care is provided, including, but not limited to, its status as a teaching hospital, specialty hospital, disproportionate share hospital, pediatric hospital, pediatric specialty unit or sole community provider. An acute hospital shall, when a medical assistance program recipient requires post emergency room care and, after screening and stabilizing the patient's condition, notify the office of Medicaid or its designated representative and assist said office, to the extent possible, in transferring the recipient to an appropriate medical setting under said office's direction. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the hospital to breach its obligation under said 42 USC 1395(dd) or require the recipient to forego any right to refuse transfer under said 42 USC 1395(dd). If an acute hospital is unable or prohibited by law or regulation from transferring the patient under said office's direction, said executive office shall pay for any and all care associated with such patient's treatment including, but not limited to, care or services provided in the emergency room or in an inpatient or outpatient setting. Whenever said office is required to pay for such care rendered in a non-emergency room setting, said office shall pay all reasonable costs for such services in such hospital, as determined by the executive office under this chapter and consistent with Title XIX laws.  No acute hospital may charge to a governmental unit for services provided to publicly aided patients at a rate higher than the rate payable by the office of Medicaid under Title XIX for the same service, unless such service is provided by said office under a unique arrangement such as a selective contract or a managed care contract.  Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to conflict with a waiver of otherwise applicable federal requirements which the office of Medicaid may obtain from the secretary of health and human services to implement a primary care case management system for delivering services, or to implement any other type of managed care service delivery system in which the eligible recipient is directed to obtain services exclusively from 1 provider or 1 group of providers.  If the office of Medicaid, contracts with any third party payer for the provision of medical benefits for medical assistance recipients under Title XIX, said office shall assure that on a quarterly basis such contracted third party payers notify each acute hospital of the number of inpatient days of service provided by the hospital to such recipients covered by such contracts.  (c) The executive office, or a governmental unit designated to perform ratemaking functions by the executive office, shall establish rates of payment which shall apply to community hospitals located in rural and isolated areas where access to other such providers is not reasonably available. Such hospitals, specially designated by the commonwealth as sole community providers, shall receive payment rates calculated to reflect the rural characteristics of such community hospital and the essential nature of the services provided, which rates shall not be less than 97 per cent of such hospitals' reasonable financial requirements.
    </text>
</law>