<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>45</section_number>
    <catch_line>Regulation And Procedure For The Exclusion And Self Exclusion Of Persons From Gaming Establishments</catch_line>
    <order_by>45</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) The commission, by regulation, shall provide for the establishment of a list of excluded persons who are to be excluded from a gaming establishment. In determining the list of excluded persons, the commission may consider, but shall not be limited to: (i) whether a person has been convicted of a criminal offense under the laws of any state or the United States that is punishable by more than 6 months in a state prison, a house of correction or any comparable incarceration, a crime of moral turpitude or a violation of the gaming laws of any state; (ii) whether a person has violated or conspired to violate this chapter relating to: (A) failure to disclose an interest in a gaming establishment for which the person is required to obtain a license; or (B) willful evasion of fees or taxes; (iii) whether a person has a notorious or unsavory reputation which would adversely affect public confidence and trust that the gaming industry is free from criminal or corruptive elements; and (iv) the potential of injurious threat to the interests of the commonwealth in the gaming establishment.  (b) No person shall be placed on the list of excluded persons due to race, color, religion, national origin, ancestry, sexual orientation, disability or sex.  (c) The commission may revoke, limit, condition, suspend or fine a gaming establishment if such establishment knowingly or recklessly fails to exclude or eject from its premises any person placed by the commission on the list of excluded persons.  (d) Whenever the commission places a name on the list of excluded persons, the commission shall serve written notice upon that person by personal service, registered or certified mail return receipt requested to the last ascertainable address or by publication in a daily newspaper of general circulation for 1 week.  (e)(1) Within 30 days of receipt of service by mail or 60 days after the last publication under subsection (d), a person placed on the list of excluded persons may request an adjudicatory hearing before the commission under chapter 30A and show cause as to why the person should be removed from the list of excluded persons. Failure to demand a hearing within the time allotted in this section shall preclude the person from having an administrative hearing, but shall not affect the person's right to petition for judicial review.  (2) Upon receipt of a demand for hearing, the commission shall set a time and place for the hearing. This hearing shall be held not later than 30 days after receipt of the demand for the hearing, unless the time of the hearing is changed by agreement of the commission and the person demanding the hearing.  (3) If upon completion of the hearing the commission determines that the person was wrongfully placed on the list of excluded persons, the commission shall remove the person's name from the list of excluded persons and notify all gaming licensees. A person aggrieved by a final decision of the commission in an adjudicatory proceeding under this section may petition for judicial review under section 14 of chapter 30A.  (f) The commission shall establish a list of self-excluded persons from gaming establishments. A person may request such person's name to be placed on the list of self-excluded persons by filing a statement with the commission acknowledging that the person is a problem gambler and by agreeing that, during any period of voluntary exclusion, the person shall not collect any winnings or recover any losses resulting from any gaming activity at a gaming establishment. The commission shall adopt further regulations, under section 5, for the self-excluded persons list including procedures for placement, removal and transmittal of such list to gaming establishments. The commission may revoke, limit, condition, suspend or fine a gaming establishment if the establishment knowingly or recklessly fails to exclude or eject from its premises any person placed on the list of self-excluded persons.  (g) Gaming establishments shall not market to persons on any excluded persons list and shall deny access to complimentaries, check cashing privileges, club programs and other similar benefits to persons on the self-excluded persons list.  (h) Notwithstanding any other general or special law to the contrary, the self-excluded persons list shall not be open to public inspection. Nothing in this section, however, shall prohibit a gaming establishment from disclosing the identity of persons on the self-excluded persons list under this section to affiliated gaming establishments in this commonwealth or other jurisdictions for the limited purpose of assisting in the proper administration of responsible gaming programs operated by affiliated gaming establishments.  (i) As used in this subsection the following words shall have the following meanings unless the context clearly requires otherwise:  (1) "Immediate family'', the spouse, parent, child, brother or sister of an individual.  (2) "Problem gambler'', a person who chronically or habitually gambles to the extent that such gambling substantially interferes with the person's social or economic functioning or that the person has lost the power of self control over that person's gambling.  An immediate family member or guardian may petition, in writing, a district court for an order of exclusion from gaming establishments applicable to a person whom the petitioner has reason to believe is a problem gambler. Upon receipt of a petition for an order of exclusion of a person and any sworn statements the court may request from the petitioner, the court shall immediately schedule a hearing on the petition and shall cause a summons and a copy of the petition to be served upon the person as provided in section 25 of chapter 276. The person may be represented by legal counsel and may present independent expert or other testimony. The court shall order examination by a qualified psychologist. If after a hearing the court based upon competent testimony finds that the person is a problem gambler and there is a likelihood of serious harm as a result of the person's gambling, the court may order that such person be prohibited from gaming in gaming establishments. The court shall communicate this order to the commission, which shall place the person's name on the list of excluded persons.  (j) A person who is prohibited from gaming in a gaming establishment under this section shall not collect any winnings or recover losses arising as a result of prohibited gaming winnings obtained by a person who is prohibited from gaming in a gaming establishment and such winnings shall be forfeited to the commission and deposited into the Gaming Revenue Fund.  (k) The commission shall pursue an interstate compact for the purposes of sharing information regarding the excluded persons list.
    </text>
</law>