<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23D" order_by="23D" level="3">Employee Ownership Revolving Loan Fund</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>27</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Wide Advisory Council On Displaced Homemakers</catch_line>
    <order_by>27</order_by>
    <text>
        The director of the industrial service program shall appoint members of a state-wide advisory council on displaced homemakers hereafter referred to as the advisory council established for the purpose of making recommendations relative to the implementation and monitoring of a state-wide plan for displaced homemakers. The advisory council, from time to time, shall suggest to said director new programs for displaced homemakers and report its evaluations of existing displaced homemaker programs, services and activities together with recommendations for any necessary changes for the purpose of assisting said director in coordinating, promoting and establishing a state plan for displaced homemakers. The advisory council shall provide the director with recommendations regarding the funding and emergency assistance of regional multi-purpose service centers; shall provide the director with recommendations regarding the coordination of state, the division of occupational education, the job training partnership act and other available funding. 
The advisory council shall be composed of representatives from social service agencies, community based organizations, education, business and training agencies. Membership should also include displaced homemakers, ethnic minorities and a geographic distribution. The director or his designee shall be the executive secretary of said advisory council and a non-voting member.
    </text>
</law>