<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132B" order_by="132B" level="3">Massachusetts Pesticide Control Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Emergency Situations At Schools, Child Care Centers And School Age Child Care Programs; Single Use Waivers For Pesticides</catch_line>
    <order_by>6H</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     If a school official or an operator of a child care center or school age child care program determines that a human health emergency warrants the use of a pesticide not otherwise allowed under this chapter, or warrants its use sooner than two days after providing the required standard written notification, such official or operator may apply for a single-use waiver from the appropriate municipal board of health or agent or director of public health or the department.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The department or appropriate municipal board of health or agent or director of public health shall determine if such a waiver is warranted based on the following criteria:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     whether the pest situation poses an immediate threat to human health; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     whether no viable alternatives to the use of chemical pesticides exist.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In such an emergency situation, the school official or operator of a child care center or school age child care program shall ensure that conspicuous warning signs are posted near the site of the spraying, release, deposit or application prior to, and for at least 72 hours after the spraying, release, deposit or application. Treated areas will be posted with clear and conspicuous warning signs along the perimeter in accordance with regulations to be promulgated by the department governing indoor and outdoor spraying, release, deposit or application of pesticides at schools, day care centers and school age child care programs. In such an emergency situation, the school official or operator of a child care center or school age child care program shall also ensure that standard written notification is provided to employees, pupils or supervised children and their parents or guardians immediately prior to or, if necessary, immediately following the emergency spraying, release, deposit or application. A record of the emergency event, including the identification of the cause and the actions taken to address it, shall be maintained as a part of the records required under section 6\%.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>