<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="75D" order_by="75D" level="3">Private Business Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>License;  Qualifications;  Issuance;  Hearing And Judicial Review;  Course Approval</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until August 1, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 106, Sec. 3. See 2012, 106, Sec. 9.]  Any person desiring to operate a private business school within the commonwealth whose application has been granted initial approval by the state auditor pursuant to section three shall submit to the commissioner, on a form supplied by him, such information as he may require, including but not limited to:  (a) the training and experience of the instructors employed or to be employed by the school;  (b) the building facilities and equipment available or to be available for the instruction to be offered by the school;  (c) the form and content of the courses to be offered by the school;  (d) the particular field of instruction to be offered by the school; and  (e) the form of any contract or agreement to be executed by a prospective student.  If, after investigation, the commissioner finds that the applicant is qualified to operate a private business school, he shall issue a license to such person authorizing the operation of such school.  If the commissioner finds that the applicant is not qualified to operate a private business school, he shall refuse to issue a license. The commissioner shall state his reasons therefor in writing. The applicant shall be entitled to a hearing before the commissioner and judicial review subject to the provisions of chapter thirty A.  The commissioner shall also approve each separate course of instruction offered by a licensee according to such standards or guidelines as may be established by the commissioner. A licensee shall submit course changes, improvements and modifications to the commissioner whenever such changes occur. Course approval shall be valid for two years from the date of issue, but may be revoked or suspended if the commissioner finds that the form or content of the course substantially differs from standards or guidelines established by him.
    </text>
</law>