<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35</section_number>
    <catch_line>Failure To Carry License And Wear It Visibly; Exception Under Automated Licensing System</catch_line>
    <order_by>35</order_by>
    <text>
        The provisions of section thirty-four, except as hereinafter provided, shall not apply to any holder of a sporting, hunting, fishing or trapping license who violates section twelve in that he fails to carry such license on his person and wear it in a visible manner on his outer clothing while fishing, hunting or trapping; provided, that he furnishes definite proof to the person demanding production of his license for inspection, as authorized in section thirty-two, that he is the holder of a valid license. In the event that the holder of such license fails to carry it on his person and wear it in a visible manner, he shall for his first offence be reported to the director of law enforcement; upon his second such offence, his license shall be surrendered and shall be suspended for a period of thirty days from the date of the notice of his second offence, after which it will be returned to him by said director; and upon a subsequent offence his license shall be subject to the provisions of section thirty-four. A person shall surrender such license on demand of any officer empowered to enforce this chapter. 
The provisions of this section which relate to the wearing of a license shall be in effect until such time as the division of fisheries and wildlife has instituted an automated licensing system for hunting, fishing, sporting and trapping licenses.
    </text>
</law>