<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11" level="3">Department Of The State Auditor</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>First Deputy;  Appointment And Removal;  Duties;  Bond</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The state auditor, with the consent of the governor and council, shall appoint a first deputy auditor who shall perform such duties as may be assigned him by the auditor and who may be removed by him for cause at any time, with the consent of the governor and council. If, by reason of sickness, absence or other cause, the auditor is temporarily unable to perform the duties of his office, the first deputy shall perform the same until such disability ceases. In the event of a vacancy in the office of auditor, the first deputy shall be continued in office and shall perform all statutory duties of the auditor until an auditor shall be duly qualified. The first deputy shall give bond to the commonwealth for the faithful discharge of his duties, in a sum not exceeding five thousand dollars.
Chapter 11: First deputy; appointment and removal; duties; bond
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Secs. 106 and 107 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The state auditor shall appoint a first deputy auditor who shall perform such duties as may be assigned him by the auditor and who may be removed by him for cause at any time. If, by reason of sickness, absence or other cause, the auditor is temporarily unable to perform the duties of his office, the first deputy shall perform the same until such disability ceases. In the event of a vacancy in the office of auditor, the first deputy shall be continued in office and shall perform all statutory duties of the auditor until an auditor shall be duly qualified. The first deputy shall give bond to the commonwealth for the faithful discharge of his duties, in a sum not exceeding five thousand dollars.
    </text>
</law>