<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>180</section_number>
    <catch_line>Prerequisites For Examination; Transitional Licenses; Trainees;  Discrimination</catch_line>
    <order_by>180</order_by>
    <text>
        A. As a prerequisite to taking the examination for certification as a state-certified general or state-certified residential real estate appraiser, an applicant shall present evidence satisfactory to the board that he meets the education and experience requirements adopted by the board consistent with and equivalent to the qualification standards adopted in accordance with Title XI by the Appraisal Qualifications Board of the Appraisal Foundation. 
B. As a prerequisite to taking the examination for licensing as a state-licensed real estate appraiser, an applicant shall present evidence satisfactory to the board that he meets the education and experience requirements adopted by the board consistent with and equivalent to the qualification standards adopted in accordance with Title XI by the Appraisal Qualifications Board of the Appraisal Foundation. 
C. Until January first, nineteen hundred and ninety-three, any person who passes the requisite state administered licensing examination but who lacks either the requisite education or requisite experience required for licensing under subdivision B may apply for and receive a transitional license, valid for two years from the date of issuance, and delay satisfaction of the education or experience requirement until expiration of the transitional license. If, by the time of expiration of such transitional license, such person presents evidence satisfactory to the board that he has satisfied the education and experience requirements, a renewal license as a state-licensed real estate appraiser shall be issued to such person. Any transitional license issued pursuant to this section shall indicate its transitional nature, and shall be recorded and reported in the annual report of the board to the Federal Appraisal Subcommittee. 
D. No examination shall be required for real estate appraisal trainees. 
E. In establishing criteria for state certification or state licensure and in promulgating any other regulations governing the performance of state-certified or state-licensed real estate appraisers, the board shall not discriminate against any person or entity solely by virtue of membership or lack of membership in any particular appraisal organization. The board shall not discriminate against any person or entity offering education courses meeting the curriculum requirements established by the board.
    </text>
</law>