<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40W" order_by="40W" level="3">Massachusetts Growth Capital Corporation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section applicable as provided by 2010, 240, Sec. 199. See 2010, 240, Sec. 195.] 
For the purposes of this chapter the following words and terms shall, except where the context clearly indicates otherwise, have the following meanings: 
“Capital participation instruments”, purchase of stock, both common and preferred, convertible securities, warrants, subscriptions, options to acquire, capital loans, and working capital or inventory loans, royalties, and other lawful derivations of the foregoing. 
“Community development corporation” or “CDC”, a certified community development corporation, as defined in section 2 of chapter 40H. 
“Corporation” or “GCC”, the Massachusetts Growth Capital Corporation established iny section 2. 
“Equity investment”, any of the following types of investment activity: (a) a purchase of stock; (b) a purchase of a partnership interest; (c) a purchase of a limited liability company membership interest; or (d) a loan made on such terms that it has sufficient characteristics of equity. 
“Financial products”, loans, equity investments and other similar financing activities including, but not limited to, the purchase of loans originated by a certified community development financial institution, the provision of loan guarantees, or the provision of surety bond guarantees. 
“Project”, (a) the act of making available financial products to small businesses and nonprofit corporations; (b) manufacturing, wholesale, retail, service, or other business activity; (c) economic development activity involving the financing of commercial, industrial or other real estate activity; or (d) other activity from which a community will derive economic benefit. 
“Small business”, a business entity, including its affiliates, that (a) is independently owned and operated; (b) has a principal place of business in the commonwealth; and (c) would be defined as a “small business” under applicable federal law, as established in the United States Code and promulgated from time to time by the United States Small Business Administration.
    </text>
</law>