<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="55B" order_by="55B" level="3">The State Ballot Law Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notice Of Objections</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        The commission with respect to objections to certificates of nominations or nomination papers except those for a special primary or election shall by five o’clock post meridian of the Wednesday following the last day for filing such objections notify all parties involved that objection has been made to their certificates of nomination or nomination papers. 
The commission with respect to objections to signatures or initiative or referendum petitions shall by five o’clock post meridian of the Wednesday following the last day for such objections notify all parties involved that objection has been made to their initiative or referendum petition. 
The commission with respect to objections to supplemental signatures necessary to place an initiative petition on the ballot after rejection by the legislature shall by five o’clock post meridian of the Friday following the last day for filing such objections notify all parties involved that objection has been made to their additional signatures. 
The commission with respect to objections to nominations at state primaries, except special primaries shall by five o’clock post meridian of the Tuesday following the last day for filing such objections notify all candidates affected thereby that objection has been made to their nomination. 
Notification shall be by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested. All notifications shall contain in detail the objections made, as well as the date, time, and the location of said hearing. Notifications shall be addressed to the residences as given in the certificates of nomination, nomination papers, and to the initial ten signers of a petition as the case may be. In addition, such notification shall also contain the rules or procedure that will be used in conducting said hearings.
    </text>
</law>