<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>39D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Construction And Renovation Of Energy Efficient Facilities;  Life Cycle Cost Analysis;  Joint Procurement Of Energy Management Services;  Compliance Report;  Annual Report</catch_line>
    <order_by>39D</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. Repealed by 2012, 165, Sec. 66. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  (a) The commissioner shall require a state agency that initiates the construction of a new facility owned or operated by the commonwealth or a renovation of an existing facility owned or operated by the commonwealth when the renovation costs exceed $25,000 and includes the replacement of systems, components or other building elements which affect energy or water consumption to design and construct or renovate the facility in a manner that minimizes the life-cycle cost of the facility by utilizing energy efficiency, water conservation or renewable energy technologies under the following criteria:  (1) the state agency shall utilize alternate technologies when the life-cycle cost analysis conducted under subsection (b) shows that such systems are economically feasible;  (2) each new educational facility, including a municipal educational facility financed through the school building assistance program, for which the projected demand for hot water exceeds 1,000 gallons per day or which operates a heated swimming pool, shall be constructed, whenever economically and physically feasible, with a solar or other renewable energy system as the primary energy source for the domestic hot water system or swimming pool of the facility;  (3) the division of capital asset management and maintenance or the state agency shall, in the design, construction, equipping and operation of such facilities, coordinate these efforts with the department of energy resources in order to maximize reliance on, and the benefits of, renewable energy research and investment activities; and  (4) all higher education construction projects shall, at a minimum incorporate the MA-CHPS Green Schools Guidelines standards or an equivalent standard.  (b) The division of capital asset management and maintenance or the state agency initiating the construction or renovation of a facility as described in subsection (a) shall conduct a life-cycle cost analysis of any such facility's proposed design that evaluates the short-term and long-term costs and the technical feasibility of using alternate technologies to provide lighting, heat, water heating, air conditioning, refrigeration, gas or electricity. In calculating life-cycle costs, a state agency shall include the value of avoiding carbon emissions, creating renewable energy certificates and other environmental and associated benefits created from the utilization of alternate technologies, as applicable. This value shall be equal to the bid price of the published market value of any such benefit and shall increase or decrease at a projected rate determined by the department of energy resources. To calculate life-cycle costs, a state agency shall use a discount rate equal to the rate that the commonwealth's tax-exempt long-term bonds are yielding at the time of said calculation and shall assume that the cost of fossil fuels and electricity will increase at the rate of 3 per cent per year above the estimated rate of inflation or at a rate determined by the department of energy resources.  (c) Notwithstanding sections 11C and 11I of chapter 25A or any regulations issued thereunder, the division of capital asset management and maintenance may procure energy management services jointly with a state agency or a building authority that is procuring energy or related services. Said sections 11C and 11I shall apply to the extent feasible as determined by the commissioner of energy resources.  (d) For purposes of this section, the term "economically feasible'' shall mean that the cost of installing and operating an alternate technology is lower than the cost of installing and operating the energy, energy-using technology or water-using technology that would otherwise be installed, as determined by a life-cycle cost analysis.  (e) The division of capital asset management and maintenance or the state agency initiating the construction or renovation of a facility subject to the requirements of subsection (a) shall file with the department of energy resources a report detailing the agency's compliance with this section with respect to each such facility.  (f) The department of energy resources shall issue an annual report to the general court detailing the compliance record of all state agencies with the construction and renovation provisions of this section.
    </text>
</law>