<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="31" order_by="31" level="3">Civil Service</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>66</section_number>
    <catch_line>Labor Service Positions In Highways Department;  Certification;  Promotions;  Districts</catch_line>
    <order_by>66</order_by>
    <text>
          The administrator shall certify persons to fill positions in the labor service of the highway division in the Massachusetts Department of Transportation according to districts established by the division. Districts so established shall not be changed unless written notice of such change, including a statement of the reasons therefor, is sent to the administrator at least six months prior to the effective date of the change.  All promotional examinations in the division shall be open to all eligible employees of the division as determined by the administrator, regardless of where they are employed in the division. Notwithstanding the provisions of section thirty-three, in the case of a promotion pursuant to section eight, the length of service of an employee of the division shall be computed without regard to the component or components of the division where such service was performed.[ Third paragraph effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  All promotions in the official service of the division of employment and training in the department of labor and workforce development be made pursuant to section eight or section ten.[ Third paragraph as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 107 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  All promotions in the official service of the department of unemployment assistance be made pursuant to section eight or section ten.
    </text>
</law>