<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>58</section_number>
    <catch_line>Registered Bonds Exchanged For Coupon Bonds Or Defaced Bonds</catch_line>
    <order_by>58</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The state treasurer may, upon terms and regulations prescribed by the governor and council, issue, in denominations of not less than one thousand dollars, registered bonds in exchange for any coupon bonds of the commonwealth, which, with the exception of the coupons, shall be in conformity with the laws authorizing the issue of such coupon bonds. He shall mutilate and retain the bonds so received in exchange. The comptroller shall certify such registered bonds; and he and the state treasurer shall each keep a register of their dates, numbers and amounts, the names of the persons to whom they were issued, when they are payable, and for what bonds they were issued in exchange. The state treasurer may also, upon the same terms and regulations, issue in substitution for mutilated, defaced or endorsed bonds presented to him other bonds of like or equivalent issues.
Chapter 29: Registered bonds exchanged for coupon bonds or defaced bonds
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The state treasurer may, upon terms and regulations prescribed by the governor and council, issue, in denominations of not less than $1,000, registered bonds in exchange for any coupon bonds of the commonwealth, which, with the exception of the coupons, shall be in conformity with the laws authorizing the issue of such coupon bonds. The state treasurer shall mutilate and retain the bonds so received in exchange. The comptroller shall certify such registered bonds; and the comptroller and the state treasurer shall each keep a register of their dates, numbers and amounts, the names of the persons to whom they were issued, when they are payable and for what bonds they were issued in exchange. The state treasurer may also, upon the same terms and regulations, issue in substitution for mutilated, defaced or endorsed bonds presented to the state treasurer other bonds of like or equivalent issues.
    </text>
</law>