<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="3">Department Of The Attorney General, And The District Attorneys</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5J</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employers Preventing Employees From Acting To Further False Claim Actions;  Liability</catch_line>
    <order_by>5J</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (1) No employer shall make, adopt or enforce any rule, regulation, or policy preventing an employee from disclosing information to a government or law enforcement agency or from acting to further a false claims action, including investigating, initiating, testifying, or assisting in an action filed or to be filed pursuant to said sections 5B to 5O, inclusive. No employer shall require as a condition of employment, during the term of employment, or at the termination of employment, that any employee agree to, accept or sign any agreement that limits or denies the employee's rights to bring an action or provide information to a government or law enforcement agency pursuant to said sections 5B to 5O, inclusive. Any such agreement shall be void.  (2) No employer shall discharge, demote, suspend, threaten, harass, deny promotion to, or in any other manner discriminate against an employee in the terms or conditions of employment because of lawful acts done by the employee on behalf of the employee or others in disclosing information to a government or law enforcement agency or in furthering a false claims action, including investigation for, initiation of, testimony for, or assistance in an action filed or to be filed pursuant to sections 5B to 5O, inclusive.  (3) Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, an employer who violates paragraph (2) shall be liable for such damages or equitable relief as a court shall deem appropriate, including: reinstatement with the same seniority status such employee would have had but for the employer's violation of sections 5B to 5O, inclusive, two times the amount of back pay, interest on the back pay, and compensation for any special damage sustained as a result of the employer's violation of said sections 5B to 5O, inclusive. In addition, the defendant shall be required to pay litigation costs and reasonable attorney's fees. An employee may bring an action in the appropriate superior court or the superior court of the county of Suffolk for the relief provided in this section.  (4) An employee who is discharged, demoted, suspended, harassed, denied promotion, or in any other manner discriminated against in the terms and conditions of employment by his employer because of participation in conduct which directly or indirectly resulted in a false claim being submitted to the commonwealth or a political subdivision thereof shall be entitled to the remedies pursuant to paragraph (3) only if both of the following occurred:  (i) the employee has been harassed, threatened with termination or demotion, or otherwise coerced by the employer or its management into engaging in the fraudulent activity in the first place; and  (ii) the employee voluntarily disclosed information prior to being dismissed to a government or law enforcement agency or acts in furtherance of a false claims action, including investigation for, initiation of, testimony for, or assistance in an action filed or to be filed.
Chapter 12: Employers preventing employees from acting to further false claim actions; liability
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 31 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (1) No employer shall make, adopt or enforce any rule, regulation or policy preventing an employee, contractor or agent from disclosing information to a government or law enforcement agency or from acting to further efforts to stop 1 or more violations of sections 5B to 5O, inclusive. No employer shall require as a condition of employment, during the term of employment or at the termination of employment that any employee, contractor or agent agree to, accept or sign an agreement that limits or denies the rights of such employee, contractor or agent to bring an action or provide information to a government or law enforcement agency pursuant to said sections 5B to 5O, inclusive. Any such agreement shall be void.  (2) An employee, contractor or agent shall be entitled to all relief necessary to make that employee, contractor or agent whole if that employee, contractor or agent is discharged, demoted, suspended, threatened, harassed or in any other manner discriminated against in the terms and conditions of employment because of lawful acts done by the employee, contractor, agent or a person associated with the employee, contractor or agent in furtherance of an action under sections 5B to 5O, inclusive, or other efforts to stop a violation of said sections 5B to 5O, inclusive.  (3) Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, relief under paragraph (2) shall include reinstatement with the same seniority status the employee, contractor or agent would have had but for the discrimination, twice the amount of back pay, interest on the back pay and compensation for any special damages sustained as a result of the discrimination. In addition, the defendant shall be required to pay litigation costs and reasonable attorneys' fees. An employee, contractor or agent may bring an action in the appropriate superior court, the superior court of the county of Suffolk or any other appropriate court for the relief provided in this section.  (4) A civil action under this section may not be brought more than 3 years after the date when the violation of this section occurred.
    </text>
</law>