<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="121B" order_by="121B" level="3">Housing And Urban Renewal</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Wages; Labor Requirements; Social Security</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        Each contractor with an operating agency and each subcontractor shall comply with the applicable requirements of chapter one hundred and forty-nine as to wages and hours of labor and any other conditions relating to employment. The attorney general shall enforce this paragraph and shall also have power to petition the court for injunction or other appropriate relief against any operating agency which fails to comply herewith. 
An operating agency shall enter into a compact or compacts with the Social Security Board or take such other action as it may deem appropriate to enable its employees to come within the provisions and obtain the benefits of the Social Security Act. If the employees of such an agency shall come within the provisions of the Social Security Act, their employment shall be included in the term “employment” as used in sections one to seven, inclusive, of chapter one hundred and fifty-one A. 
Except as provided in section twenty-nine of this chapter, the provisions of chapter thirty-one and the rules made thereunder shall not apply to any officer, agent or employee of an operating agency or to any person employed on or in connection with any project of an operating agency. 
Except as provided in sections twenty-eight and thirty all by-laws, ordinances and regulations of the city or town in which any such project lies relating to the construction of buildings, municipal planning, zoning and the protection of public health shall apply to every project of an operating agency located in such city or town.
    </text>
</law>