<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>133</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions Applicable To Secs. 133 A To 133 F</catch_line>
    <order_by>133</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     “Blind persons”, a person who, after examination by a physician or by an optometrist, whichever such person shall select, has been determined to have
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     not more than 20/200 central visual acuity in the better eye with correcting lenses, or
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     an equally disabling loss of the visual field as evidenced by a limitation to the field of vision in the better eye to such a degree that its widest diameter subtends an angle of no greater than 20 degrees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     “Commission”, the Massachusetts Commission for the Blind.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     “Commissioner”, the commissioner of the Massachusetts Commission for the Blind.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     “Jurisdiction”, the control of the maintenance, operation and protection of public buildings and property of the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     “Public buildings or property”, any building, land, or other real property owned by any department or agency of the commonwealth, or any counties thereof, with the exception of any building, land, or other real property under the jurisdiction of any state university or state institution of higher learning.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     “Vending facility”, snack bars, cart service, shelters, counters, and such other appropriate auxiliary equipment which may be operated by blind licensees and which is necessary for the sale of newspapers, periodicals, confections, tobacco products, foods, beverages, and other articles or services dispensed automatically or manually and prepared on or off the premises in accordance with all applicable health laws, and including the vending or exchange of chances for any lottery authorized by law, and conducted by any agency of the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     “Vendor”, a blind person licensed by the commission for the blind to operate a vending facility under the terms of the Randolph-Shepard Act.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     “Randolph-Shepard Act”, the Randolph-Shepard Vending Stand Act (Pub. L. 74-732) as amended by Pub. L. 83-565 and Pub. L. 93-516, 20 U.S.C. Ch. 6A, Sec. 107.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     “Randolph-Shepard Vending Facilities Program”, the program for the operation of vending facilities by blind persons established by the Randolph-Shepard Act.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     “State licensing agency”, the state agency designated by the Commissioner of the Rehabilitation Services Administration under the regulations implementing the Randolph-Shepard Act to issue licenses to blind persons for the operation of vending facilities on federal and other property.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>