<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="143" order_by="143" level="3">Inspection And Regulation Of, And Licenses For, Buildings, Elevators And Cinematographs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>97</section_number>
    <catch_line>Amendments To State Building Code</catch_line>
    <order_by>97</order_by>
    <text>
        Except for the specialized codes, as defined in section ninety-six, which codes shall be amended only by the respective boards, commissions, departments or agencies authorized to do so by law, any person may propose amendments to the state building code. Public hearings shall be held in the city of Boston in May and November of each year, and at such other times and places as the board may determine, to consider petitions for such amendments. Petitions shall be submitted to the board no less than sixty days prior to the public hearing. The subject matter of a petition to be considered shall be indicated in all the required notices. The petitions shall be available for inspection at the office of the board and at the hearing. Any significant changes to the petition shall be the subject of a further public hearing before adoption. Adoption of an amendment to the state building code shall occur upon an affirmative vote by a majority of the members of the board at a regularly convened meeting within ninety days of the final public hearing on the given amendment. 
The board shall send a copy of any amendments to the state building code which are adopted to each inspector of buildings or building commissioner, as defined by section one of chapter one hundred and forty-three, and to the secretary of the executive office of public safety within a reasonable time after filing said amendments with the state secretary.
    </text>
</law>