<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="60" order_by="60" level="3">Collection Of Local Taxes</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>45</section_number>
    <catch_line>Collector’S Deed; Contents; Effect</catch_line>
    <order_by>45</order_by>
    <text>
        The collector shall execute and deliver to the purchaser a deed of the land, stating the cause of sale, the price for which the land was sold, the name of the person on whom the demand for the tax was made, the places where the notices were posted, the name of the newspaper in which the advertisement of the sale was published, and the residence of the grantee, and shall contain a warranty that the sale has in all particulars been conducted according to law. The deed shall convey the land to the purchaser, subject to the right of redemption. The title thus conveyed shall, until redemption or until the right of redemption is foreclosed as hereinafter provided, be held as security for the repayment of the purchase price, with all intervening costs, terms imposed for redemption and charges, with interest thereon, and the premises conveyed, both before and after either redemption or foreclosure, shall also be subject to and have the benefit of all easements and restrictions lawfully existing in, upon or over said land or appurtenant thereto, and, except as provided in section seventy-seven, all covenants and agreements running with said premises either at law or in equity, when so conveyed. Such deed shall not be valid unless recorded within sixty days after the sale. If so recorded it shall be prima facie evidence of all facts essential to the validity of the title thereby conveyed, whether the deed was executed on or before as well as since July first, nineteen hundred and fifteen. No sale hereafter made shall give to the purchaser any right to possession of the land until the right of redemption is foreclosed, as hereinafter provided.
    </text>
</law>