<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132B" order_by="132B" level="3">Massachusetts Pesticide Control Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificates And Licenses; Issuance, Suspension And Revocation</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        Certifications and licenses to use pesticides may be issued to individuals by the department in accordance with the provisions, standards and procedures contained in and established pursuant to this chapter. Each certification and license issued pursuant to this section shall be valid only for the individual to whom it is issued, may not be transferred, and shall not continue in force and effect after the death of the individual to whom it is issued. All certifications and licenses shall be for a period not to exceed one year, unless sooner revoked or suspended. 
The department may authorize individuals to use pesticides in classifications as a certified commercial applicator, a certified private applicator, and a licensed applicator provided, however, that the department shall require that all persons who are applicators of pesticides in public and private places used for human occupation and habitation, except residential properties with three or less dwelling units, shall be so licensed or certified with such special designation. 
The department may establish such categories and subcategories as it deems necessary to restrict or condition the scope of pesticide use permitted within each classification. The department may establish such standards and criteria, take such action and impose such requirements as it deems necessary to determine or redetermine levels of competence and experience to qualify for each classification and each category and subcategory thereof. 
Each applicant for a certification or license shall annually file with the department an application providing thereon such information as the department may require. 
Each applicant desiring to be certified or licensed shall annually pay such application fee, not to exceed twenty dollars, as the department may by regulation require. 
In the event that any individual files with the department an application to renew a certification or license which is in effect on the date of the application for renewal and pays the appropriate fee therewith, such certification or license shall be deemed to be in effect until the earlier of the following two events shall occur: ninety days have elapsed after the certification or license was scheduled to expire; or the department notifies the applicant that the certification or license has been renewed, modified or denied. 
The department may issue a certification or license to an applicant therefor if it determines that the applicant satisfies the criteria established for that certification or license and the category or subcategory for which the certification or license is sought. The department may thus issue a certification or license subject to such terms, conditions, restrictions and requirements as it deems necessary. The department may require that an applicant for a certification or license has obtained and maintains in effect a contract of liability insurance conforming to regulations established by the department. 
The department shall prior to issuing a certificate or license evaluate each applicant to determine his competence with respect to the use and handling of pesticides, or to the use and handling of the pesticides or class of pesticides covered or to be covered by said individual’s certification or license. Said evaluation shall include such examinations as the department may require. Examinations may be taken only upon payment of a fee, not to exceed ten dollars for each examination given, as the department may require by regulation approved by the board. Each examination shall include an evaluation of the applicant’s competence with respect to the use of integrated pest management. 
The department may revoke, suspend, cancel or deny any certification or license, or any class thereof, at any time, if it believes: that the terms or conditions thereof are being violated or are inadequate to avoid unreasonable adverse effects on the environment, or that the holder of or applicant for the certification or license has violated any provision of this chapter or FIFRA or any regulation, standard, order, license, certification or permit issued thereunder or that the holder or applicant for said certification or license is not competent with respect to the use and handling of pesticides, or to the use and handling of the pesticides or class of pesticides covered by said individual’s certification or license. Any person whose certification or license is suspended or revoked hereunder shall also be subject to such other punishment, penalties, sanctions or liabilities as may be provided by law. As part of its determination to refuse to grant, to revoke, or to suspend a certification or license the department may specify a period, not to exceed two years, within which the applicant may not reapply for a certification or license. In the event that the department has refused to issue or has revoked or suspended such a certification or license, and has specified a period for non-application, the department may later, at its discretion, shorten or waive such period. 
The department may, at its discretion, appropriately license or certify any person possessing a valid certification or license, or equivalent rating, issued by the pesticide control agency of any other state or the federal government whose standards for the issuance of such rating are not less stringent than those of the department, provided that the pesticide control agency of that state extends similar privileges to persons so licensed or certified by the commonwealth. Any person so licensed or certified shall be subject to the annual fee requirements of this section.
    </text>
</law>