<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>81</section_number>
    <catch_line>Cooperation With State Agencies;  Agreements</catch_line>
    <order_by>81</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  The commission shall cooperate with the division of industrial accidents in the department of labor and workforce development, the division of employment and training in said department, the departments of transitional assistance, children and families, public health, developmental services and mental health, and such other departments, divisions or subdivisions of the commonwealth as are charged or concerned with the rehabilitation of handicapped persons. Where practicable, the commission shall enter into agreements, confirmed in writing, setting forth procedures whereby said handicapped persons are located and listed to have their fitness and eligibility for rehabilitation services determined by the commission. The commission shall also enter into agreement with the division of employment and training, under which handicapped persons receiving vocational rehabilitation may be referred for preplacement interview or for job placement to the public employment offices established in said division by section nine M of chapter twenty-three; provided, that nothing in said agreement shall prevent reference of said handicapped persons to employment through the commission.
Chapter 6: Cooperation with state agencies; agreements
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Secs. 2 to 4 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  The commission shall cooperate with the department of industrial accidents in the executive office of labor and workforce development, the department of career services in the executive office of labor and workforce development, the departments of transitional assistance, children and families, public health, developmental services and mental health, and such other departments, divisions or subdivisions of the commonwealth as are charged or concerned with the rehabilitation of handicapped persons. Where practicable, the commission shall enter into agreements, confirmed in writing, setting forth procedures whereby said handicapped persons are located and listed to have their fitness and eligibility for rehabilitation services determined by the commission. The commission shall also enter into agreement with the department of career services, under which handicapped persons receiving vocational rehabilitation may be referred for preplacement interview or for job placement to the appropriate one-stop career centers; provided, that nothing in said agreement shall prevent reference of said handicapped persons to employment through the commission.
    </text>
</law>