<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138" level="3">Alcoholic Liquors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Permits To Holders Or Former Holders Of Licenses Authorizing Sales To Licensees; Fees; Excises; Permits For Researchers</catch_line>
    <order_by>22A</order_by>
    <text>
        Upon payment of a fee to be fixed by the commission in each case and subject to such terms and conditions as it may prescribe, it may grant any permit referred to in section two or may grant to any holder or former holder of a license issued by the local licensing authorities who ceases for any reason to conduct the licensed business, or to any suitable individual on his behalf, a permit which shall authorize the holder thereof to sell to any licensee under this chapter any alcoholic beverages the sale of which is or was authorized under his license or former license, or may grant to any person, resident of the commonwealth, lawfully possessing any such beverages a permit which shall authorize him to sell such alcoholic beverages to any licensee under this chapter, or may grant to any individual a permit which shall authorize him to import any alcoholic beverages specified therein which are acquired otherwise than by purchase and are not intended for sale. No fee shall be fixed by the commission and no excise shall be paid to the commonwealth in any case where a charitable hospital is granted a permit to import alcoholic beverages which are acquired otherwise than by purchase and are not intended for sale. 
Upon payment of a fee to be fixed by the commission in each case and subject to such terms and conditions as it may prescribe, it may grant to any suitable individual a permit which shall authorize such individual to accept delivery from a licensee lawfully possessing an alcoholic beverage specified therein which is acquired otherwise than by purchase and not intended for sale. The holder of a permit issued under this paragraph shall use any such alcoholic beverage specified therein solely for research related to consumer consumption of an item having a brand name. Such permit may, in the discretion of the commission, authorize delivery of alcoholic beverages to be consumed on the premises where the research is conducted or off the premises where the research is to be conducted.
    </text>
</law>