<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="30" order_by="30" level="3">General Provisions Relative To State Departments, Commissions, Officers And Employees</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>62B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Environmental Impact Reports; Preparation And Submission; Funding</catch_line>
    <order_by>62B</order_by>
    <text>
        In the case of projects directly undertaken by an agency, the environmental impact report shall be prepared and submitted by the responsible agency. If two or more agencies are responsible, a joint report shall be prepared and submitted by the agency designated by the secretary of environmental affairs. In the case of projects which require a permit or financial assistance from an agency, said report shall be prepared and submitted by the person or agency seeking the permit or financial assistance. 
Public funds made available for the purpose of design of or planning or undertaking a project subject to sections sixty-two to sixty-two H, inclusive, may be expended for the research, preparation, and publication of the report and expenses incidental thereto, and said funds may be transferred or otherwise may be made available to other agencies designated by the secretary of environmental affairs to evaluate the draft or final report. 
An environmental impact report shall contain statements describing the nature and extent of the proposed project and its environmental impact; all measures being utilized to minimize environmental damage; any adverse short-term and long-term environmental consequences which cannot be avoided should the project be undertaken; and reasonable alternatives to the proposed project and their environmental consequences. The secretary shall encourage agencies and persons to commence preparation of reports during the initial planning and design phase of projects. Said report shall be prepared and disseminated to inform the originating or permitting agency, reviewing agencies, the appropriate regional planning commission, the attorney general and the public of the environmental consequences of state actions and the alternatives thereto prior to any commitment of state funds for and prior to the commencement of the project if undertaken by an agency or prior to the issuance of any permit or grant of financial assistance for the project if undertaken by a person.
    </text>
</law>