<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="31A" order_by="31A" level="3">Municipal Personnel Systems</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        In this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the following meaning, unless the context requires otherwise:— 
“Administrator”, the personnel administrator of the human resources division within the executive office for administration and finance. 
“Civil service law”, chapter thirty-one and the rules promulgated pursuant to that chapter. 
“Civil service position”, an office or position, appointment to which is subject to the requirements of chapter thirty-one. 
“Commission”, the civil service commission of the commonwealth. 
“Department” or “division”, the human resources division within the executive office for administration and finance. 
“Local appointing authority”, any person, board, or commission with the power to appoint or employ personnel in municipal service positions. 
“Local chief executive officer”, in a city or town with a manager form of government, the manager of that municipality; in other cities, the mayor; and in other towns, the board of selectmen. 
“Local merit appeals board”, a three member board established under section seven to act on appeals established under sections seven and eight and to act on appeals involving alleged violations of basic merit principles. 
“Municipality”, a city or town in the commonwealth. 
“Municipal employee”, any person compensated by a municipality for personal services performed for the municipality. 
“Municipal personnel office”, the office established under section six, charged by local ordinance with administering the municipal personnel system. 
“Personnel director”, the administrator of a municipal personnel system.
    </text>
</law>