<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="44B" order_by="44B" level="3">Community Preservation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Annual Revenues;  Open Space, Historic Resources And Community Housing</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  In every fiscal year and upon the recommendation of the community preservation committee, the legislative body shall spend, or set aside for later spending, not less than 10 per cent of the annual revenues in the Community Preservation Fund for open space, but not including land for recreational use, not less than 10 per cent of the annual revenues for historic resources and not less than 10 per cent of the annual revenues for community housing. In each fiscal year, the legislative body shall make such appropriations from the Community Preservation Fund as it deems necessary for the administrative and operating expenses of the community preservation committee, but the appropriations shall not exceed 5 per cent of the annual revenues in the Community Preservation Fund. Funds that are set aside shall be held in the Community Preservation Fund and spent in that year or later years, but funds set aside for a specific purpose shall be spent only for the specific purpose. Any funds set aside may be expended in any city or town in the commonwealth. The community preservation funds shall not replace existing operating funds, only augment them.
Chapter 44B: Annual revenues; open space, historic resources and community housing
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 79 effective July 1, 2012 applicable as provided by 2012, 139, Sec. 218 as amended by 2012, 239, Sec. 48. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  In each fiscal year and upon the recommendation of the community preservation committee, the legislative body shall spend, or set aside for later spending, not less than 10 per cent of the annual revenues in the Community Preservation Fund for open space, not less than 10 per cent of the annual revenues for historic resources and not less than 10 per cent of the annual revenues for community housing. In each fiscal year, the legislative body shall make appropriations from the Community Preservation Fund as it deems necessary for the administrative and operating expenses of the community preservation committee and such appropriations shall not exceed 5 per cent of the annual revenues in the Community Preservation Fund. The legislative body may also make appropriations from the Community Preservation Fund as it deems necessary for costs associated with tax billing software and outside vendors necessary to integrate such software for the first year that a city or town implements the this chapter; provided, however, that the total of any administrative and operating expenses of the community preservation committee and the first year implementation expenses shall not exceed 5 per cent of the annual revenues in the Community Preservation Fund.  Funds that are set aside shall be held in the Community Preservation Fund and spent in that year or later years; provided, however, that funds set aside for a specific purpose shall be spent only for the specific purpose. Any funds set aside may be expended in any city or town. The community preservation funds shall not replace existing operating funds, only augment them.
    </text>
</law>