<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>214</section_number>
    <catch_line>Examination Application; Reexamination; Provisional License</catch_line>
    <order_by>214</order_by>
    <text>
        Applicants approved by the board as having met the age, character, education and experience requirements for licensing may take the licensing examination upon filing an application with the board. The board may adopt a regulation requiring that upon attaining a passing score on the licensing examination, the applicant shall apply for a license within two years of the date of passing the examination by paying the required fee and filing the proper application with the board. The regulation may provide that failure to apply for a license within two years of taking the examination shall result in the application being denied and the applicant being reexamined at his own expense. An applicant who fails the licensing examination may be reexamined by filing a new examination application fee with the board or its agent. 
A person who meets the qualifications to be admitted to the approved examination for licensure as a perfusionist may, between the date of filing an application for licensure and the announcement of the results of the next succeeding examination, practice as a provisionally licensed perfusionist provided that he files an approved application with the board and pays a fee determined by the secretary of administration and finance. The board may grant a provisional license to a person who successfully completes a perfusion education program approved by the board and is qualified to be admitted to the examination. Such license shall be valid for one year from the date of its issue and may be renewed for an additional year and shall automatically expire at the end of such time if the applicant fails to pass the complete examination. An application for extension shall be signed by a supervising licensed perfusionist. A provisionally licensed perfusionist shall be under the supervision and direction of a licensed perfusionist at all times during which the provisionally licensed perfusionist performs perfusion. The board shall adopt rules governing such supervision and direction which may not require the immediate physical presence of the supervising licensed perfusionist.
    </text>
</law>