<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32</section_number>
    <catch_line>Records; Manufacturers And Dealers Of Motor Vehicles Or Trailers;  Garages And Open Air Parking Spaces</catch_line>
    <order_by>32</order_by>
    <text>
        Every manufacturer of and dealer in motor vehicles or trailers, and every owner, proprietor, person in control or keeper of a garage, and, in the city of Boston, every owner, proprietor, person in control or keeper of an open air parking space kept open with attendants day and night for the storage or keeping for hire of motor vehicles or trailers, shall keep or cause to be kept in a book a proper record of every motor vehicle or trailer which enters and which leaves his garage, stable, shop or place of business; provided, however, that any dealer in motor vehicles or trailers, or person engaged in the repair or servicing of motor vehicles or trailers, who makes no charge for the storage of motor vehicles or trailers, shall be exempt from keeping the record book above referred to if and so long as he keeps adequate records of the repairs and services performed with respect to the motor vehicles or trailers which come into his custody, which records show in substance the information required to be shown in said book. Said book shall have columns and headings substantially as follows: 
All entries in said book shall be made legibly in ink or with an indelible pencil. The said book shall be kept in some convenient place and the book, the premises where such book is required to be kept and the vehicles stored or parked therein may be inspected at all times by the registrar, his agents, or by any police officer.
    </text>
</law>