<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23A" order_by="23A" level="3">Department Of Economic Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13S</section_number>
    <catch_line>International Trade Office; Commission For Evaluation Of Impact Of State Laws And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>13S</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a commission, within the international trade office, which shall evaluate the continuing impacts on state laws and regulations of international trade policy and international trade agreements, examine proposed international trade agreements, maintain active communications with any individual or entity, as the commission deems appropriate, regarding ongoing developments in international trade agreements and policy; and examine any aspects of international trade, international economic integration and international trade agreements that the members of the commission deem appropriate. For the purposes of this section, “international trade agreement” shall include any international trade or investment agreement or treaty including, but not limited to, the North American Free Trade Agreement, the Central American Free Trade Agreement and agreements concluded by the World Trade Organization. 
The commission shall engage in at least 1 public hearing annually and shall report on the economic and sovereignty impacts of international trade agreements on the commonwealth. The report may include recommendations of support or opposition of revisions in United States trade policy or commitments including, but not limited to, proposed international trade agreements. The annual report shall be transmitted to the clerks of the house of representatives and the senate, the governor, the attorney general, the United States trade representative and each member of the commonwealth’s congressional delegation. 
The commission shall consist of 3 members of the senate, 1 of whom shall be appointed by the minority leader; 3 members of the house of representatives, 1 of whom shall be appointed by the minority leader; the governor or the governor’s designee; the attorney general or the attorney general’s designee; the state treasurer or the treasurer’s designee; a representative from the Massachusetts international trade office; and 9 persons appointed by the governor, 1 of whom shall be a representative of organized labor, 1 of whom shall represent small business, 1 of whom shall be a representative from a human rights organization, 1 of whom shall represent farmers, 1 of whom shall be a representative from an environmental group, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Municipal Association, 1 of whom shall be engaged in the business of exporting goods internationally, 1 of whom shall be a faculty member of a private law school in the commonwealth, with expertise in issues of constitutional federalism and 1 of whom shall be a faculty member of the University of Massachusetts with experience in economics or labor studies.
    </text>
</law>