<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23A" order_by="23A" level="3">Department Of Economic Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Office Of Travel And Tourism; Executive Director; Appointment;  Powers And Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>13E</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be within the partnership an office of travel and tourism which shall be under the supervision and control of an executive director. The powers and duties given to the executive director of the office of travel and tourism in this chapter and in any other general or special law shall be exercised and discharged subject to the direction, control and supervision of the partnership. 
The executive director of the office of travel and tourism shall be appointed by the governor, and serve at the pleasure of the governor. The position of executive director of the office of travel and tourism shall be classified under section 45 of chapter 30 and the executive director of travel and tourism shall devote full time during business hours to the duties of the office of travel and tourism and shall give to the state treasurer a bond for the faithful performance of those duties. 
The executive director of travel and tourism shall be the executive and administrative head of travel and tourism and shall be responsible for administering and enforcing the laws relative to travel and tourism and to any administrative unit of that office. Powers and duties given to an administrative unit of travel and tourism by a general or special law shall be exercised subject to the direction, control and supervision of the executive director of travel and tourism.
    </text>
</law>