<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83" level="3">Sewers, Drains And Sidewalks</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificate Of Acceptance; Effect; Recordation</catch_line>
    <order_by>16A</order_by>
    <text>
        If the rates and charges due to a city, town, municipality, or sewer district, which accepts this section and sections sixteen B to sixteen F, inclusive, and by its clerk, files a certificate of such acceptance in the proper registry of deeds, for supplying or providing for a sewer system or rendering service or furnishing materials in connection therewith to or for any real estate at the request of the owner or tenant are not paid on or before their due date as established by local regulations, ordinances or by-laws, which due date shall be so established as to require payments at least as often as annually, such rates and charges, together with interest thereon and costs relative thereto, shall be a lien upon such real estate as provided in section sixteen B. The register of deeds shall record such certificate of acceptance in a book to be kept for the purpose, which shall be kept in an accessible location in the registry. Sections sixteen B to sixteen F, inclusive, shall also apply to a sewer district which has accepted sections sixteen A to sixteen F, inclusive, and whose clerk has so filed the certificate of acceptance. Wherever in said sections the words “board or officer in charge of the sewer department” or their equivalent appear, they shall also mean and include the officers exercising similar duties in any city, town or district. A fire or water district authorized to provide a sewer system shall, for the purposes of sections sixteen A to sixteen F, inclusive, be deemed to be a sewer district.
    </text>
</law>