<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>78</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>78</order_by>
    <text>
        For purposes of sections 78A to 88, inclusive, the following words and terms shall have the following meanings:— 
“Buyer”, any person who enters into a contract for health club services with a health club. 
“Contract for health club services”, a contract which has the primary purpose of providing a person with the right to use the facilities of a health club or with instruction, training, or assistance by a health club in the preservation, maintenance, encouragement or development of physical fitness, conditioning or well-being, including physical culture, bodybuilding, exercising, weight control, figure development or the teaching of martial arts including judo, karate and self-defense, or any similar course of physical fitness training or assistance. 
“Health club”, each facility or location or group or chain of facilities or locations, in which any person, firm, corporation, partnership, unincorporated association, franchise or other business enterprise offers facilities for or instruction, training or assistance in the preservation, maintenance, encouragement or development of physical fitness, conditioning or well being. Such term shall include, but not be limited to, health spas, sports, tennis, racquet ball, platform tennis and health clubs, figure salons, health studios, gymnasiums, weight control centers or studios, martial arts and self-defense schools, or any other similar course of physical training. 
“Seller”, any person, firm, corporation, partnership, unincorporated association, franchise, franchisor, or other business enterprise which operates a health club or which offers or enters into contracts for health club services.
    </text>
</law>