<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90D" order_by="90D" level="3">Motor Vehicle Certificates Of Title</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance To Transferee;  Surrendered Certificates</catch_line>
    <order_by>19</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Paragraph (a) effective until August 7, 2012. For text effective August 7, 2012, see below.]  (a) The registrar, upon receipt of a properly assigned certificate of title, with an application for a new certificate of title, the required fee and any other documents required by law, shall issue a new certificate of title in the name of the transferee as owner and mail it to the first lienholder named in it or, if none, to the owner.[ Paragraph (a) as amended by 2012, 238, Sec. 46D effective August 7, 2012. For text effective until August 7, 2012, see above.]  (a) The registrar, upon receipt of a properly assigned certificate of title, except as provided for in subsection (e) of section 20, with an application for a new certificate of title, the required fee and any other documents required by law, shall issue a new certificate of title in the name of the transferee as owner and mail it to the first lienholder named in it or, if none, to the owner. If under subsection (e) of section 20, the outstanding certificate of title is not delivered to him, the registrar shall make demand therefor from the holder thereof.  (b) The registrar upon receipt of any application for a new certificate of title by a transferee other than by voluntary transfer, with proof of the transfer, the required fee and any other documents required by law, shall issue a new certificate of title in the name of the transferee as owner. If the outstanding certificate of title is not delivered to him, the registrar shall make demand therefor from the holder thereof.  (c) The registrar shall file and retain every surrendered certificate of title in accordance with section 30 of chapter 90.
    </text>
</law>