<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="71" order_by="71" level="3">Public Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Broadcast And Television Facilities; Cost Of Program; Executive Committee For Educational Television</catch_line>
    <order_by>13F</order_by>
    <text>
        The course of study in elementary and high schools may include instruction by means of educational programs broadcast through the facilities of television stations. The cost of such programs may be shared by cities and towns within viewing range of such television stations and the school committee of each such city or town may include within its budget such funds not to exceed one dollar per pupil enrolled in public elementary and high schools in such city or town, for the payment thereof as it may deem advisable. The state treasurer shall annually, on or before November twentieth, reimburse each city or town which has shared the cost of such programs, as evidenced by the written agreement of each such city or town with the executive committee for educational television, a sum equal to fifty per cent of the total share paid by such city or town for the then current fiscal year. Said reimbursement shall be subject to appropriation and shall not exceed a total reimbursement to the several such cities or towns of more than two hundred and fifty thousand dollars. Other educational agencies may participate in this program by a financial contribution. The board of education, with the advice of the commissioner, shall appoint a committee to co-ordinate and administer such programs. Said committee shall be known as the executive committee for educational television, in this section and sections thirteen G to thirteen I, inclusive, called the committee. The committee shall consist of twelve members, of whom at least seven shall be representatives of contributing school systems. As the term of office of a member expires his successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of four years. The members of the committee shall serve without compensation, except that they may be reimbursed for their necessary expenses actually incurred in the performance of their duties.
    </text>
</law>