<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>151C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Interstate Commission For Adult Offender Supervision; Composition;  Voting; Executive Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>151C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The compacting states hereby create the interstate commission for adult offender supervision.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The interstate commission shall be a body corporate and joint agency of the compacting states.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The interstate commission shall have all the responsibilities, powers and duties set forth herein, including the power to sue and be sued, and such additional powers as may be conferred upon it by subsequent action of the respective legislatures of the compacting states in accordance with the terms of this compact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The interstate commission shall consist of commissioners duly appointed from each of the member states.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     In addition to the commissioners who are the voting representatives of each state, the interstate commission shall include individuals who are not commissioners but who are members of interested organizations; such non-commissioner members shall include a member of the national organizations of governors, legislators, state chief justices, attorneys general and crime victims. All non-commissioner members of the interstate commission shall be ex-officio members. The interstate commission may provide in its by-laws for such additional, ex-officio, non-voting members as it deems necessary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Each compacting state represented at any meeting of the interstate commission is entitled to 1 vote. A majority of the compacting states shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, unless a larger quorum is required by the by-laws of the interstate commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The interstate commission shall meet at least once each calendar year. The chairperson may call additional meetings and, upon the request of 27 or more compacting states, shall call additional meetings. Public notice shall be given of all meetings and meetings shall be open to the public.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     The interstate commission shall establish an executive committee which shall include commission officers, members and others as shall be determined by the by-laws. The executive committee shall have the power to act on behalf of the interstate commission during periods when the interstate commission is not in session, with the except rulemaking power and the power to amend the compact. The executive committee shall oversee the day-to-day activities managed by the executive director and interstate commission staff, administers enforcement and compliance with the provisions of the compact, its by-laws and as directed by the interstate commission and performs other duties as directed by commission or as set forth in the by-laws.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>