<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>101</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Examiners Of Sheet Metal Workers; Members; Terms;  Frequency Of Meetings</catch_line>
    <order_by>101</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be within the division of professional licensure a board of examiners of sheet metal workers to consist of the commissioner of public safety or his designee, the director of professional licensure or his designee and 5 persons, residents of the commonwealth, to be appointed by the governor for terms of 3 years, 2 of whom shall be journeyperson sheet metal workers with at least 10 years of practical experience and who are wage earners, 2 of whom shall be master sheet metal workers with at least 10 years of practical experience in sheet metal work and 1 of whom shall be a representative of the public and subject to section 9B.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No member shall serve for more than 2 consecutive and complete 3-year terms. As the term of the office of a member expires, a successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of 3 years. The governor may fill a vacancy in the board for the unexpired portion of the term.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The board shall annually elect from among its members a chairman and vice-chairman. The board shall meet at least 4 times annually and may hold additional meetings as necessary to discharge its duties. Members shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reasonable travel expenses. The members of the board shall be public employees for the purposes of chapter 258 for all acts or omissions within the scope of their duties as board members.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>