<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18A" order_by="18A" level="3">Department Of Youth Services</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bureau Of Institutional Services; Duties; Assistant Commissioner</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        The bureau of institutional services shall operate the Residential Treatment Unit, Oakdale, the Lyman School for Boys at Westborough, the Industrial School for Boys at Shirley, the Institute for Juvenile Guidance at South Bridgewater, the Industrial School for Girls at Lancaster and Stephen L. French Forestry Camp at East Brewster. Said bureau shall be responsible for all programs within the institutions of the department other than those programs which are primarily clinical or educational, and shall from time to time evaluate such programs to determine their effectiveness. Said bureau shall coordinate programs between institutions and also with other programs of the department to assure effective continuity in the rehabilitative process. 
The commissioner shall appoint an assistant commissioner for the bureau of institutional services who shall have an earned graduate degree from an accredited institution in the social sciences, education, or related fields. Said assistant commissioner shall have had at the time of his appointment at least five years professional experience in working with delinquent children in an institutional setting, with at least two of these years having been spent in an administrative capacity. Said assistant commissioner shall serve at the pleasure of the commissioner. Said assistant commissioner shall from time to time make recommendations to the commissioner relative to the need of major alteration and renovation, expansion, relocation or replacement of existing institutions or camps and the construction of additional institutions or camps.
    </text>
</law>