<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136" level="3">Observance Of A Common Day Of Rest And Legal Holidays</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Sporting Events; Laundry; Transport Of Goods; Tourist Trade;  Licensing Certain Events; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter to the contrary, dancing or any game, sport, fair, exposition, play, entertainment or public diversion, including events authorized under chapter one hundred and twenty-eight A, may be conducted on any legal holiday and any labor, business or work necessary or incidental thereto may be performed on any legal holiday, and any business licensed under chapter one hundred and thirty-eight may be conducted in accordance with the provisions of said chapter on any legal holiday. The transport of goods in commerce, or for a consideration, by motor truck or trailer, between the hours of eight o’clock in the morning and eight o’clock in the evening, shall not be prohibited on any legal holiday to which the provisions of sections five to eleven, inclusive, apply, provided such goods are destined for or emanate from an establishment in the commonwealth for which a permit has been issued under the provisions of section fifteen, or is otherwise lawfully operating on the holiday. The delivery of linen supplies, laundry and diapers shall not be prohibited on any legal holiday, nor shall the processing of laundry for hospitals, clinics, nursing and rest homes, and physicians’ offices be prohibited on any legal holiday. Hunting, if otherwise lawful, shall not be prohibited on any legal holiday. 
The mayor of a city or the selectmen of a town, upon written application therefor, and upon such terms and conditions as they may prescribe, may grant licenses for the maintenance and operation on the last Monday in May, July fourth and the first Monday of September, or the day following when July fourth occurs on Sunday, of establishments for the sale of souvenirs to the tourist trade, articles of beachwear and other goods incidental thereto, at amusement parks or beach resorts. The fee for such a license shall be set by the mayor of a city or the selectmen of a town, but in no event shall any such fee be greater than twenty dollars per event and four hundred dollars per year.
    </text>
</law>