<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87T</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>87T</order_by>
    <text>
        The following words, as used in sections eighty-seven T to eighty-seven KK, inclusive, shall have the following meanings:— 
“Aesthetician”, any person, who with hands or mechanical or electrical apparatus or appliances, or by the use of cosmetic preparations, tonics, lotions, or creams engages for compensation in the practice of cleansing, stimulating, manipulating and beautifying skin. 
“Board”, the board of registration of cosmetology established by section forty-two of chapter thirteen. 
“Cosmetologist”, any person, who, with hands or mechanical or electrical apparatus or appliances, or by the use of cosmetic preparations, antiseptics, tonics, lotions or creams, engages for compensation in any one or any combination of the following practices, to wit:— Massaging, cleansing, stimulating, manipulating, exercising, beautifying the scalp, face, neck, arms, bust or upper part of the body, manicuring the nails, or removing of superfluous hair, by the use of electricity or otherwise, about the body of any person, or any person who is registered to practice hairdressing, aesthetics or manicuring pursuant to the requirements of the board; provided, however, that cosmetologist shall not mean any person who engages in the practice of make-up artistry only. 
“Demonstrator”, any person who engages in behalf of a manufacturer, wholesaler, retailer or distributor in demonstrating the use of any machine or other article pertaining to hairdressing without charge to the person who is subject to such demonstration. 
“Hairdresser”, any person who engages in hairdressing for compensation, except the following persons:— 
1. A barber engaged in his usual occupation, or only in cutting the hair of any person, in any location not subject to said sections eighty-seven T to eighty-seven JJ, inclusive. 
2. A person who engages in behalf of a manufacturer or distributor solely in demonstrating the use of any machine or other article for purposes of sale, without charge to the person who is the subject of such demonstration. 
“Hairdressing”, arranging, dressing, curling, waving, cleansing, cutting, singeing, bleaching, coloring, or similarly treating the hair of any person, or performing work as a cosmetologist as defined in section eighty-seven F, or any combination of any of the foregoing, but not including the removal of superfluous hair or skin blemishes by direct application of an electric current or any treatment of the bust. 
“Instructor”, a person who teaches all branches of hairdressing, manicuring, or aesthetics in a registered school. 
“Operator”, a person engaged in hairdressing or in any of its branches under the supervision of a registered hairdresser. 
“Manicurist”, any person who engages in manicuring for compensation. 
“Manicuring”, the cutting, trimming, polishing, tinting, coloring or cleansing the nails of any person. 
“Manicuring shop”, a shop licensed to do manicuring only on the nails of any person. 
“School”, except in section eighty-seven Z, a school or other institution privately owned, conducted for the purpose of teaching aesthetics or hairdressing and such of its branches as the board may require. 
“Shop”, a shop to which customers come for hairdressing and cosmetology or aesthetics. 
“Student”, a person studying hairdressing, manicuring or aesthetics in a school.
    </text>
</law>