<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>185</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Office On Disability; Director; Appointments</catch_line>
    <order_by>185</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a Massachusetts office on disability, in this section and in sections one hundred and eighty-six to one hundred and eighty-nine, inclusive, called the office, consisting of a director on disability, in this section and in sections one hundred and eighty-six to one hundred and eighty-nine, inclusive, called the director, and an advisory council, as hereinafter described. The director shall be appointed by the governor and shall serve at the pleasure of the governor. The director shall, at the time of his appointment, have substantial professional or administrative experience in a field concerned with disability. 
The position of the director shall be classified in accordance with section forty-five of chapter thirty, and the salary shall be determined in accordance with section forty-six C of said chapter thirty. The director shall devote his full time during business hours to the duties of the office. 
The director shall, with the advice of the advisory council, have sole charge of the supervision and administration of the office. The director may, subject to appropriation, employ and remove such assistant directors and other employees and consultants as he may deem necessary to enable him to perform his duties. The provisions of chapter thirty-one and section nine A of chapter thirty shall not apply to the director or to such assistant directors and consultants as he may appoint. In making such appointments, the director shall make every reasonable effort to ensure that persons with disabilities are employed.
    </text>
</law>