<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>105</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commission On Employment Of People With Disabilities;  Members;  Chairperson;  Appointments</catch_line>
    <order_by>105</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  There shall be a commission on the employment of people with disabilities, in this section and sections 106 and 107, called the commission, consisting of the director of housing and community development, the director of consumer affairs and business regulation, the director of economic development, the secretary of health and human services, the secretary of labor and workforce development, the secretary of transportation and construction, the commissioner of the Massachusetts commission for the blind, the commissioner of the commission for the deaf and hard of hearing, the commissioner of correction, the commissioner of education, the director of career services, the director of industrial accidents, the commissioner of health care finance and policy, the commissioner of mental health, the commissioner of public health, the commissioner of transitional assistance, the commissioner of children and families, the commissioner of youth services, the commissioner of the Massachusetts rehabilitation commission, the commissioner of veterans' services, the chancellor of the system of public higher education, the chairman of the Massachusetts developmental disabilities council, the director of the office of affirmative action, the director of the Massachusetts office on disability and the personnel administrator of the human resources division within the executive office for administration and finance, or their respective designees, who shall serve as ex officio members, and 28 members to be appointed by the governor, three of whom shall represent rehabilitation programs, three of whom shall represent industry, three of whom shall represent employment boards, two of whom shall represent labor, two of whom shall represent education and one of whom shall represent veterans' organizations. It is encouraged that the majority of the remaining appointive members be persons with disabilities. A chairperson or co-chairpersons shall be named by the governor from among the said remaining appointive members. The chairperson or co-chairpersons may appoint additional individuals to serve as ex officio members. Of the appointive members, seven shall be designated in their initial appointment to serve for terms of one year, seven for terms of two years, seven for terms of three years and seven for terms of four years. Upon the expiration of the initial term of an appointive member, his successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of four years. The governor shall in like manner fill any vacancy for the remainder of the unexpired term.
Chapter 6: Commission on employment of people with disabilities; members; chairperson; appointments
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 4 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  There shall be a commission on the employment of people with disabilities, in this section and sections 106 and 107, called the commission, consisting of the director of housing and community development, the director of consumer affairs and business regulation, the director of economic development, the secretary of health and human services, the secretary of labor and workforce development, the secretary of transportation and construction, the commissioner of the Massachusetts commission for the blind, the commissioner of the commission for the deaf and hard of hearing, the commissioner of correction, the commissioner of education, the director of career services, the director of industrial accidents, the executive director of the center for health information and analysis, the commissioner of mental health, the commissioner of public health, the commissioner of transitional assistance, the commissioner of children and families, the commissioner of youth services, the commissioner of the Massachusetts rehabilitation commission, the commissioner of veterans' services, the chancellor of the system of public higher education, the chairman of the Massachusetts developmental disabilities council, the director of the office of affirmative action, the director of the Massachusetts office on disability and the personnel administrator of the human resources division within the executive office for administration and finance, or their respective designees, who shall serve as ex officio members, and 28 members to be appointed by the governor, three of whom shall represent rehabilitation programs, three of whom shall represent industry, three of whom shall represent employment boards, two of whom shall represent labor, two of whom shall represent education and one of whom shall represent veterans' organizations. It is encouraged that the majority of the remaining appointive members be persons with disabilities. A chairperson or co-chairpersons shall be named by the governor from among the said remaining appointive members. The chairperson or co-chairpersons may appoint additional individuals to serve as ex officio members. Of the appointive members, seven shall be designated in their initial appointment to serve for terms of one year, seven for terms of two years, seven for terms of three years and seven for terms of four years. Upon the expiration of the initial term of an appointive member, his successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of four years. The governor shall in like manner fill any vacancy for the remainder of the unexpired term.
    </text>
</law>