<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>21E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensure Of Representatives Of Private Trade Schools</catch_line>
    <order_by>21E</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until August 1, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 106, Sec. 4. See 2012, 106, Sec. 9.]  No representative of any private trade school, which is located within or without the commonwealth shall at the residence of any prospective student solicit enrollments or sell courses therein, make representations or give counsel concerning the educational content or quality of or the benefits to be derived from courses in such school unless licensed by the commissioner of education.  Any person desiring to be a representative of a private trade school shall submit to the commissioner, on a form supplied by him, information setting forth:--  (a) the applicant's name and address;  (b) the applicant's educational qualifications;  (c) the name and address of three business references; and  (d) the name and address of three personal references.  If, after investigation, the commissioner finds that the applicant is qualified to be a representative of a private trade school and is of good moral character, he shall issue a license to such person. The fee for the issuance of such license and for such renewal thereof shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven.  If the commissioner finds that the applicant is not qualified to be a representative of a private trade school, he shall refuse to issue a license.  The commissioner shall state his reasons therefor in writing. The applicant shall be entitled to a hearing before the commissioner and judicial review subject to the provisions of chapter thirty A.  A license issued hereunder shall be valid for two years from date of issue.
    </text>
</law>