<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="15E" order_by="15E" level="3">Interstate Compact On Educational Opportunity For Military Children</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Placement And Attendance</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 108, Sec. 6 effective May 31, 2012.]  (a) When a student transfers before or during the school year, the receiving state school shall initially honor placement of the student in educational courses based on the student's enrollment in the sending state school or educational assessments conducted at the school in the sending state if the courses are offered and space is available. Course placement shall include, but not be limited to, honors, international baccalaureate, advanced placement, vocational, technical and career pathways courses. Continuing the student's academic program from the previous school and promoting placement in academically and career challenging courses should be paramount when considering placement. This shall not preclude the school in the receiving state from performing subsequent evaluations to ensure appropriate placement and continued enrollment of the student in the courses.  (b) The receiving state school shall initially honor placement of the student in educational programs based on current educational assessments conducted at the school in the sending state or participation or placement in like programs in the sending state. Such programs shall include, but not be limited to: (i) gifted and talented programs; and (ii) English as a second language programs. This shall not preclude the school in the receiving state from performing subsequent evaluations to ensure appropriate placement of the student.  (c) In compliance with the federal requirements of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA), 20 U.S.C. section 1400 et seq, the receiving state shall initially provide comparable services to a student with disabilities based on: (i) the student's current individualized education program; (ii) the requirements of section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act, 29 U.S.C. section 794; and (iii) title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act, 42 U.S.C. sections 12131-12165. The receiving state shall make reasonable accommodations and modifications to address the needs of incoming students with disabilities, subject to an existing 504 or title II plan, to provide the student with equal access to education. This shall not preclude the school in the receiving state from performing subsequent evaluations to ensure appropriate placement of the student.  (d) Local education agency administrative officials shall have flexibility in waiving course or program prerequisites or other preconditions for placement in courses or programs offered under the jurisdiction of the local education agency.  (e) A student whose parent or legal guardian is an active duty member of the uniformed services and has been called to duty for, is on leave from or immediately returned from deployment to a combat zone or combat support posting, may be granted additional excused absences at the discretion of the local education agency superintendent to visit with that parent or legal guardian on leave or preparing for or returning from deployment.
    </text>
</law>