<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="25A" order_by="25A" level="3">Division Of Energy Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Department Of Energy Resources; Commissioner</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be within the executive office of energy and environmental affairs a department called the department of energy resources, under the supervision of a commissioner of energy resources, hereinafter the commissioner. The duties given to the commissioner in this chapter and in any other general or special law shall be exercised and discharged subject to the direction, control and supervision of the secretary of energy and environmental affairs. The commissioner shall be appointed by the secretary of energy and environmental affairs, with the approval of the governor, and may, with like approval, be removed. The commissioner shall be a person of skill and experience in the field of energy regulation or policy and shall serve a term coterminous with that of the governor. The position of commissioner shall be classified in accordance with section 45 of chapter 30 and the salary shall be determined in accordance with section 46C of said chapter 30. The commissioner shall devote full time during business hours to the duties of the office. In the case of an absence or vacancy in the office of the commissioner, or in the case of disability as determined by the secretary, the secretary may designate an acting commissioner to serve as commissioner until the vacancy is filled or the absence or disability ceases. The acting commissioner shall have all the powers and duties of the commissioner and shall have similar qualifications as the commissioner.
    </text>
</law>