<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>239</section_number>
    <catch_line>Application Certification Of Sheet Metal Corporation, Partnership, Llc, Llp Or Other Such Entity</catch_line>
    <order_by>239</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A person licensed in the commonwealth as a master sheet metal worker may apply to the board for a certificate of a sheet metal corporation, partnership, LLC, LLP or other such entity upon payment of a fee or a biennial renewal fee, the amounts of which shall be determined annually by the secretary of administration and finance pursuant to section 3B of chapter 7. A certificate of a sheet metal corporation shall authorize a master to conduct the sheet metal business as a corporation; provided, however, that in the corporation the master sheet metal worker shall be designated as an officer of the corporation organized under the laws of the commonwealth. A certificate of sheet metal partnership or LLP shall authorize a master sheet metal worker to conduct the sheet metal business as a partnership or LLP; provided, however, that all partners in such a partnership or LLP shall be master sheet metal workers. A certificate of a sheet metal LLC shall require, as a prerequisite, that a master sheet metal worker be designated as a manager of that LLC. The board shall determine the appropriate requirements for any other business entities not so designated.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No corporation, partnership, LLC, LLP or other entity shall engage in business, advertise the provision of sheet metal work, make application for and take out permits for sheet metal work, bid for sheet metal work, permit its employees to perform sheet metal work or represent that it holds a license or certificate issued by the board unless the entity and all employees who performing such work hold a license or certificate, issued by the board, as further described in chapter 13 and this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The certificate of a sheet metal corporation, partnership, LLP, LLC, or other entity shall only be issued to a master sheet metal worker who shall be responsible for all sheet metal work performed by that entity and its duly licensed employees.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>