<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>74</section_number>
    <catch_line>Alcoholic Beverage License Applicants And Licensees; Building Safety Certificate Of Inspection</catch_line>
    <order_by>74</order_by>
    <text>
        The commission shall require all applicants for alcoholic beverages licenses to submit a valid certificate of inspection, as provided in the state building code, issued by a local inspector, as defined in chapter 143, and signed by the head of the fire department, as defined in chapter 148, for the city, town or district in which the applicant intends to sell alcoholic beverages to be consumed on the premises. The certificate of inspection shall attest to the safety of the building or structure in which the applicant intends to sell alcoholic beverages to be consumed on the premises and that the building or structure meets or exceeds the requirements of the state building code. 
The commission shall require that every license holder submit, annually, a valid certificate of inspection, as provided in the state building code, issued by a local inspector and signed by the head of the fire department for the city, town or district in which the premises is located and from which alcoholic beverages intended to be consumed on the premises are to be sold. The issuance of such certificate shall be a precondition for the issuance or renewal of such a license and the commission may summarily revoke any license upon notice of noncompliance or expiration of such certificate, by operation of law and without a hearing. The commission may presume that such premises conform with the inspectional safety requirements for the premises as provided for in the state building code based upon such certificate, however such presumption may be rebutted. 
Failure by the inspector to issue an annual certificate of inspection, signed by the head of the fire department, may be appealed in accordance with the inspectional safety requirement procedures for appeal as provided in the state building code. 
The commission may authorize the issuance of a temporary license to any applicant or license holder who has been issued a temporary certificate of inspection by a local inspector and signed by the head of the fire department, as provided in the state building code, if the applicant or license holder has complied with the terms therein and the temporary certificate of inspection has not expired. Such temporary license may be revoked by the commission, without a hearing, if the licensee has failed to comply with the terms of such temporary certificate. 
Failure by the inspector to issue an annual certificate of inspection signed by the head of the fire department, may be appealed in accordance with the inspectional safety requirement procedures for appeal as provided for in the state building code. 
The commission shall promulgate rules and regulations to effectuate the purposes of this section.
    </text>
</law>