<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="31" order_by="31" level="3">Civil Service</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>69</section_number>
    <catch_line>Reports Of Appointment Or Employment By Appointing Authority Upon Request; Enforcement; Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>69</order_by>
    <text>
        Every appointing authority shall file, within seven days after the receipt of a written request from the administrator, a report containing the names of all persons who have been appointed or employed by such authority, and have received pay or rendered bills for services or labor performed during the calendar month immediately preceding the date of submission of such request. Such report shall be filed with the administrator and with the state auditor, in the case of the state, and with the auditor or officer responsible for auditing the accounts of such appointing authority, in the case of a city or town. 
Such report shall be in a form prescribed by the administrator, shall be made under penalties of perjury and shall contain the following information: (1) the full name of the person appointed or employed or who rendered a bill for services or labor; (2) a brief description of the nature of the position of such person and of the services or labor which such person has actually performed during such month; (3) for a state position, the title of the position of such person as stated in the payrolls of the appointing authority and for a position in a city or town, either the title of the position authorized by the department, or the title authorized by the appointing authority; (4) the regular salary or wage of the position; (5) the date of employment; and (6) all payments of any kind made to the appointee during said month. Such appointing authority shall not be required to file more than one such report in any month. The report shall be filed with the state auditor, and with the administrator and shall be open to public inspection. 
The supreme judicial court, by mandamus or other appropriate remedy in law or equity, may compel any such appointing authority to comply with this section upon suit or petition of the administrator. 
Any appointing authority who willfully refuses to comply with this section shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars.
    </text>
</law>