<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>185A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Resale Of Tickets; Necessity, Term And Transfer Of License;  Information In Application; Definition Of Resale; Restrictions</catch_line>
    <order_by>185A</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall engage in the business of reselling any ticket or tickets of admission or other evidence of right of entry to any theatrical exhibition, public show or public amusement or exhibition required to be licensed under sections one hundred and eighty-one and one hundred and eighty-two of this chapter or under chapter one hundred and twenty-eight A, whether such business is conducted on or off the premises on which such ticket or other evidence is to be used, without being licensed therefor by the commissioner of public safety, in this and the six following sections called the commissioner. A license shall be granted only upon a written application setting forth such information as the commissioner may require. Each license issued under this section shall be in force until the first day of January next after its date, unless sooner revoked. No such license may be transferred or assigned except upon written permission of the commissioner. The sale of a ticket or pass, entitling the holder thereof to admission to any such theatrical exhibition, public show or public amusement or exhibition upon payment either of nothing or a sum less than that demanded of the public generally, shall be deemed to be a resale thereof within the meaning of this section. 
No person shall engage in or have any interest, as a stockholder or otherwise, in any such business in the conduct of which is or are resold any ticket or tickets of admission or other evidence or evidences of right of entry to any theatrical exhibition, public show or public amusement or exhibition of which said person is the owner or in which he has any interest, as a stockholder or otherwise.
    </text>
</law>