<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32A" order_by="32A" level="3">Contributory Group General Or Blanket Insurance For Persons In The Service Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>17G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Items Medically Necessary For The Diagnosis Or Treatment Of Diabetes; Group Insurance Commission Coverage</catch_line>
    <order_by>17G</order_by>
    <text>
        The commission shall provide to an active or retired employee of the commonwealth who is insured under the group insurance commission coverage for the following items if such items are within a category of benefits or services for which coverage is otherwise afforded, have been prescribed by a health care professional legally authorized to prescribe such items and if the items are medically necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of insulin-dependent, insulin-using, gestational and non-insulin-dependent diabetes: blood glucose monitors; blood glucose monitoring strips for home use; voice-synthesizers for blood glucose monitors for use by the legally blind; visual magnifying aids for use by the legally blind; urine glucose strips; ketone strips; lancets; insulin; insulin syringes; prescribed oral diabetes medications that influence blood sugar levels; laboratory tests, including glycosylated hemoglobin, or HbAlc, tests; urinary protein/microalbumin and lipid profiles; insulin pumps and insulin pump supplies; insulin pens, so-called; therapeutic/molded shoes and shoe inserts for people who have severe diabetic foot disease when the need for therapeutic shoes and inserts has been certified by the treating doctor and prescribed by a podiatrist or other qualified doctor and furnished by a podiatrist, orthotist, prosthetist or pedorthist; supplies and equipment approved by the Federal Drug Administration for the purposes for which they have been prescribed and diabetes outpatient self-management training and education, including medical nutrition therapy, when provided by a certified diabetes health care provider participating with the insurance contract or affiliated with a provider participating with the insurance contract. As used in this section, “certified diabetes health care provider” shall mean a licensed health care professional with expertise in diabetes, a registered dietician or a health care provider certified by the National Certification Board of Diabetes Educators as a certified diabetes educator. When coverage is provided through a nonprofit hospital service corporation or a nonprofit medical corporation, outpatient self-management training and education shall be provided by a certified diabetes health care provider participating with the hospital service plan or medical service agreement or affiliated with a provider participating with the hospital service plan or medical service agreement. When coverage is provided through a health maintenance contract, outpatient self-management training and education, including medical nutrition therapy, shall be provided by a certified diabetes health care provider participating with the health maintenance contract or affiliated with a provider participating with the health maintenance contract. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the commission to contract with a certified diabetes health care provider who is not already under contract with the commission. 
The benefits provided in this section shall meet all other terms and conditions within an insurance plan. Coverage shall not be reduced or eliminated due to the requirements of this section.
    </text>
</law>