<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>33</section_number>
    <catch_line>Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>33</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     For every examination for a learner’s permit.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     For the registration of every motor vehicle; provided that said fee shall be collected every two years. The registrar shall collect such similar fee, in addition to incurred administrative costs for the issuance in connection therewith, at the request of the applicant, of a distinctive initial plate, or of a particular number plate other than a distinctive initial plate; provided, however, that the registrar shall collect a similar fee for the issuance of a number plate bearing the station call letters of an amateur radio operator. Said registrar shall make available to registered owners of motor vehicles any unissued or returned distinctive initialed or numbered registration plates.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     For the registration of every ambulance owned and operated by any hospital or other institution or association supported wholly or in part by public or private donations for charitable purposes, and every motor vehicle or trailer used by the fire or police department of any city or town or park board solely for the official business of such department or board, and every motor vehicle or trailer used by a volunteer fire company, as authorized under chapter 48, in any town solely for fire fighting purposes, no fee shall be collected hereunder.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     For the registration of every motor vehicle and trailer owned by any political subdivision of the commonwealth, and used solely for official business, no fee shall be collected hereunder.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     For the registration of every motor bus not owned as provided in paragraph (4) which is used exclusively under contract with a political subdivision or school district of the commonwealth for the transportation of school children; provided, however, that any such motor bus may also be used for the transportation of persons to and from church and Sunday school services, and for the transportation of children to and from educational and recreational projects sponsored by a city or town or by any association or organization supported wholly or in part by public or private donations for charitable purposes without the payment of an additional registration fee. For the registration of every motor bus used for carrying passengers for hire pursuant to a certificate, license or permit issued by the department of telecommunications and energy in accordance with the provisions of chapter 159A, a fee for each seat. This paragraph and paragraphs (3) and (4) shall apply to the registration of motor vehicles described therein regardless of whether they are designed to be propelled otherwise than by fuel as defined in section 1 of chapter 64A, in this section referred to as “non-gasoline driven”, or designed to be propelled by fuel as so defined, in this section referred to as “gasoline driven”. The term “gasoline driven” as used in this section shall include vehicles propelled by diesel fuel.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     For the registration of every non-gasoline driven automobile used for the transportation of goods, wares or merchandise except an electric motor truck or an electric commercial automobile, or in the case of an electric motor truck or an electric commercial automobile so used, and of every gasoline driven automobile so used, for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the gross weight of such vehicle plus the maximum load to be carried thereon, but in no event less than a specified amount in the case of a non-gasoline driven automobile so used, or a specified amount in the case of a gasoline driven automobile so used.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     For the registration of every non-gasoline driven tractor which is part of a semi-trailer unit used for the transportation of property, a fee for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the weight of the tractor and of the weight of the heaviest semi-trailer with which such tractor is combined and operated, plus the maximum load to be carried by such semi-trailer unit so used, a fee for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the weight of such tractor and of the weight of the heaviest semi-trailer with which such tractor is combined and operated, plus the maximum load to be carried by such semi-trailer and tractor, a fee for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the weight of such tractor and of the weight of the heaviest semi-trailer with which such tractor is combined and operated, plus the maximum load to be carried by such semi-trailer and tractor, but in no event less than a specified amount in the case of a non-gasoline driven tractor which is a part of a semi-trailer unit, or less than a specified amount if gasoline driven.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     For the registration of every semi-trailer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     For the registration of every heavy-duty platform trailer, a fee for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the weight of such vehicle plus the maximum load to be carried, but in no event less than a specified amount.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     For the registration of every trailer for which a fee is not otherwise provided in this section, a fee for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the weight of such trailer and the maximum load to be carried thereon.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     For the registration of every non-gasoline driven tractor not a part of a semi-trailer, a fee for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the weight of the tractor and its equipment, but in no event less than a specified amount; and for the registration of every gasoline driven tractor not a part of a semi-trailer unit, a fee for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the weight of the tractor and its equipment, but in no event less than a specified amount; except that the fee to be collected for the registration of a farm tractor not a part of a semi-trailer unit shall be a specified amount if the tractor is used exclusively for agricultural purposes. The provisions of paragraphs (1) to (6), inclusive, shall not apply to any vehicle the fee for the registration of which is hereinbefore provided for in this section. The aforesaid weight shall mean the weight of such vehicle when fully equipped for the road. The registrar of motor vehicles may establish rules for determining the gross weight, including load, for which any vehicle shall be registered under said paragraphs (1) to (6), inclusive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     For the registration of every motor truck carrying a permanently mounted water well drilling machine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     For the registration of every antique motor car.
        </section>
        <section prefix="14">
    	     For the registration of every auto home.
        </section>
        <section prefix="15">
    	     For the registration of every automobile known as a taxicab, a specified amount when non-gasoline driven and a specified amount when gasoline driven.
        </section>
        <section prefix="16">
    	     For the registration of every motor bus or other motor vehicle, the fee for the registration of which is not hereinbefore provided for, used for carrying passengers for hire and having a seating capacity of seven persons or less, a specified amount for each seat when non-gasoline driven and a specified amount for each seat when gasoline driven, and for the registration of every such motor bus or other vehicle having a seating capacity in excess of seven persons, a specified amount for each seat when non-gasoline driven and a specified amount for each seat when gasoline driven, but in no event less than a specified amount when non-gasoline driven or a specified amount when gasoline driven. In determining seating capacity aforesaid the driver’s seat shall not be included, but the largest number of passengers to be carried in seats shall be included.
        </section>
        <section prefix="17">
    	     For the registration of motor vehicles or trailers owned by or under the control of a manufacturer, dealer, repairman, owner-contractor, repossessor, or farmer, including one or more number plates as allocated by the registrar pursuant to section 5, a fee for the registration and a fee for each number plate furnished by the registrar. For the registration of motor vehicles under the control of a transporter, including one or more number plates and registration certificates as requested in writing by the applicant for registration, a fee for the registration and a fee for each number plate and corresponding certificate of registration furnished by the registrar.
        </section>
        <section prefix="18">
    	     For the registration of every motor vehicle used exclusively for the transportation of goods, wares or merchandise and for every tractor, trailer, semi-trailer, heavy duty platform trailer, or motor truck carrying a permanently mounted water well drilling machine by an owner who applies therefor under section 2 during the period beginning September 1 and ending December 31, in any year, a specified amount of a full year’s registration of said vehicle.
        </section>
        <section prefix="19">
    	     For the registration of every motor vehicle or trailer not specified in the preceding paragraph which the registrar has determined shall be issued on a calendar basis, by an owner who applies therefor under section 2 or section 5 during the period beginning October 1 and ending December 31 in any year, a specified amount of a full year’s registration of said vehicle.
        </section>
        <section prefix="20">
    	     For the substitution of a registration of a motor vehicle or trailer for that of a vehicle previously registered, in accordance with section 2.
        </section>
        <section prefix="21">
    	     For every license to operate motor vehicles or for the renewal thereof; provided, that said fee shall be collected upon issuing an initial license, and shall be collected at least once every five years upon the renewal date of said license from every licensee. No fee shall be collected for a license or renewal thereof restricted to the operation of motor propelled fire apparatus only.
        </section>
        <section prefix="22">
    	     No fee shall be exacted for the registration of one pleasure passenger vehicle owned and principally used by a former prisoner of war who is entitled to display thereon the distinctive number plates authorized by section 2.
        </section>
        <section prefix="23">
    	     For each application for an appointment for an examination for a license to operate motor vehicles. The registrar, for reasons he deems sufficient, may authorize an applicant to be examined without payment of an additional fee when the applicant has been unable to take the examination at the time originally scheduled.
        </section>
        <section prefix="24">
    	     For every additional copy of a certificate of registration or license.
        </section>
        <section prefix="25">
    	     For every certified copy of any application or notice filed with the registrar and for every certified copy of a certificate of registration or license.
        </section>
        <section prefix="26">
    	     For every additional number plate furnished to replace such plates as have been lost or mutilated or are illegible.
        </section>
        <section prefix="27">
    	     For every copy of any record, or any certificate, the fee for which is not otherwise provided herein, except that when an owner has registered a vehicle for the ensuing registration year and thereafter transfers ownership of said vehicle to another before the beginning of said year, or when such owner changes his address before the beginning of said year, the registrar may issue to him a new registration certificate for another vehicle for the ensuing year, or a new registration certificate bearing the new address, without charge other than the additional difference, if any, between the fees for registration of the vehicle transferred and the vehicle sought to be registered for the ensuing year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="28">
    	     The registrar or his authorized agent may, however, furnish without charge copies of certificates of registration and licenses to operate, and copies of other documents relating thereto, to officers of the commonwealth or of any court thereof or of a city or town therein; and the registrar may issue certificates of registration for motor vehicles and licenses to operate the same to any member of the foreign diplomatic corps or to any foreign consular officer who is not a citizen of the United States without the payment of the fees therefor.
        </section>
        <section prefix="29">
    	     No fee shall be exacted for the registration of any vehicle owned by a disabled veteran who is entitled to display thereon the distinctive number plates authorized by section 2, and no fee shall be exacted for the issuance to such disabled veteran of a license to operate such vehicle.
        </section>
        <section prefix="30">
    	     No fee shall be exacted for the registration of a bloodmobile unit or a canteen motor truck owned and used by a charitable corporation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="31">
    	     For a driving instructor’s certificate which shall be valid for a period of one year from the date of issuance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="32">
    	     In the event that any fee computed under any provision of this chapter for the registration of any motor vehicle or trailer includes in its total an odd or even number of cents, such fee shall be adjusted to the nearest half dollar, except for the fees enumerated in paragraph (21). If payment of any fee required under this chapter or chapter 90D is made by check, credit card, debit card or any other payment method and the amount is not duly paid, the registrar of motor vehicles shall withhold issuance of the certificate of title for the motor vehicle, shall prohibit the transfer or swap of the registration, and shall suspend or revoke any learner’s permit, license to operate motor vehicles, certificate of registration or title, number plate, sticker, decal or other item for which such check, credit card, debit card, or other payment method was tendered and order the return of same forthwith. The holder of said item for which said check, credit card, debit card or other payment method used may not apply for, receive or renew any other learner’s permit, license to operate motor vehicles, certificate of registration or title, number plates, stickers, decals, or any other items issued under the provisions of this chapter or said chapter 90D until said amount has been duly paid.
        </section>
        <section prefix="33">
    	     No fee shall be exacted for the registration of a pleasure passenger vehicle owned and principally used by a member of the Legion of Valor of America, Inc. who is entitled to display thereon the distinctive number plates authorized by section 2.
        </section>
        <section prefix="34">
    	     For the issuance of a special parking identification plate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="35">
    	     For the issuance of each permit sticker as provided in section 19D, a specified amount for every 1,000 pounds or fraction thereof of the weight of such motor vehicle, trailer, semi-trailer or semi-trailer unit, including the maximum load to be carried thereon, in excess of the maximum weight for such motor vehicle, trailer, semi-trailer or semi-trailer unit may otherwise be operated under the provisions of section 19A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="36">
    	     For the reinstatement of any license or right to operate a motor vehicle which has been suspended or revoked under subsections (a), (e) and (f) of section 22, sections 22F, 23, 24, except as otherwise provided below, section 24B, 24D, 24G, 24L or section 34J, and section 28 of chapter 266, the fee shall be $500. The fee for reinstatement following revocation under subparagraph (2) of paragraph (c) of subdivision (1) of said section 24 shall be $700 and the fee for such reinstatement following a revocation under subparagraphs (3) and (31/2) of said paragraph (c) of said subdivision (1) of said section 24 shall be $1,200. The fee for reinstatement of any license or right to operate a motor vehicle which has been suspended or revoked under any general or special law shall be $100, but the fee for reinstatement for suspensions and revocation under subsection (c) of section 22 shall be commensurate with the fee established for the corresponding Massachusetts offense resulting in the suspension or revocation under the General Laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="37">
    	     For the registration of every street rod, replica vehicle, specially constructed vehicle or custom vehicle, as defined in section 2H consistent with the vehicle’s intended use and the requirements of 540 CMR 2.05.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>