<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="91" order_by="91" level="3">Waterways</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Docking Of Commercial Vessels; Permits; Applications; Appeal</catch_line>
    <order_by>10C</order_by>
    <text>
        Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, the harbormaster of a city or town or whomsoever is so empowered by said city or town may authorize by written permit the stationing of commercial vessels to a public commercial dock, pier, wharf, float, raft or mooring, fixed or otherwise, within the territorial jurisdiction of such city or town upon such terms, conditions and restrictions as he shall deem necessary. He shall act on application for such permits within a period of seven days from his receipt thereof. 
Such application may be left at the office of the city or town clerk by the master of such commercial vessel. 
If the harbormaster or whomever is so empowered fails to act within such period, such permit shall then be deemed to have been granted. Any refusal to grant such permits within such period shall be in writing by the harbormaster or whomever is so empowered by said city or town and shall include the reasons for such refusal. 
Any person aggrieved by the decision of the harbormaster of said city or town or whomever is so empowered by said city or town relative to such stationing may appeal to the division of waterways of the department within thirty days of such decision. 
Said division shall review the circumstances resulting in such appeal and shall render a ruling either confirming the decision, setting such decision aside, or amending such decision and imposing conditions and restrictions deemed necessary by said office. 
Actions by a harbormaster or said division of waterways under the provisions of this section shall be subject to applicable laws administered by the division of motor boats, the division of marine fisheries, the United States Coast Guard and the United States Corps of Engineers.
    </text>
</law>