<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employing Unlicensed Motor Vehicle Operator;  Permitting Person With Suspended Or Revoked License To Operate Motor Vehicle;  Permitting Person With Ignition Interlock Devise License Restriction To Operate Motor Vehicle Without Devise;  Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Subsections (a) and (b) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (a) Whoever knowingly employs for hire as a motor vehicle operator any person not licensed in accordance with this chapter shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500 and, for a second or subsequent violation, by a fine of not more than $1,000 or imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 1 year, or both.  (b) Whoever knowingly permits a motor vehicle owned by him or under his control to be operated by a person who is unlicensed or whose license has been suspended or revoked shall be punished by 1 year in the house of correction and a fine of not more than $500 for a first offense or, for a second or subsequent offense by a fine of not more than $1,000 or imprisonment in a house of correction for not more than 2 1/2 years, or both.[ Subsections (a) and (b) as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 94 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (a) Whoever knowingly employs for hire as a motor vehicle operator any person not licensed in accordance with this chapter shall be punished for a first offense by a fine of not more than $1,000 and, for a second or subsequent offense, by a fine of not less than $1,000 nor more than $1,500 or imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 1 year, or both such fine and imprisonment.  (b) Whoever, being the owner or person in control of a motor vehicle, knowingly permits such motor vehicle to be operated by a person who is unlicensed or whose license has been suspended or revoked shall be punished for a first offense by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment in a house of correction for not more than 1 year or, for a second or subsequent offense by a fine of not less than $1,000 and not more than $1,500 or imprisonment in a house of correction for not more than 2 1/2 years, or both such fine and imprisonment.  (c) Whoever knowingly permits a motor vehicle owned by him or under his control, which is not equipped with a functioning ignition interlock device, to be operated by a person who has an ignition interlock restricted license shall be punished by 1 year in the house of correction and a fine of not more than $500 for a first offense or, for a second or subsequent offense by a fine of not more than $1,000 or imprisonment in a house of correction for not more than 2 1/2 years, or both. For the purposes of this section the term "certified ignition interlock device'' shall mean an alcohol breath screening device that prevents a vehicle from starting if it detects a blood alcohol concentration over a preset limit of .02 or 20 mg of alcohol per 100 ml of blood.  (d) The registrar may suspend for not more than 1 year the motor vehicle registration of a vehicle used in the commission of a violation of this section or the license or right to operate of the person who commits a violation of this section, or both.
    </text>
</law>