<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificates Of Registration And Number Plates For Street Rods, Replica And Other Custom Vehicles; Determination Of Title Year And Make, Model And Model Year</catch_line>
    <order_by>2H</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For purposes of this section, section 2I and section 33, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The registrar shall issue certificates of registration and number plates for street rods, replica vehicles, specially-constructed vehicles and custom vehicles in accordance with this section. The registrar may assign an appropriate registration plate to a custom vehicle, replica vehicle, specially-constructed vehicle or street rod based upon the vehicle’s intended use and the registration requirements under 540 CMR 2.05.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Street rods, replica vehicles, specially-constructed vehicles and custom vehicles shall not be considered antique motor cars and shall not be eligible for registration pursuant to section 6A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Replica vehicles shall be titled as the year in which the vehicle was built and the make, model and year of the vehicle that is intended to be replicated. A label of “Replica” shall be applied to the title and registration card. Custom vehicles and street rods shall be titled as the year in which the vehicle was built and an appropriate description of the vehicle including make, model and model year; provided, however, that the manufacturer’s name shall continue to be used as the make with a label of “street rod” or “custom vehicle” applied to the title and registration card. Specially-constructed vehicles shall be titled and registered showing the make as “specially constructed” and the year the vehicle was built shall be the vehicle model year.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>