<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Identification Cards For Persons Not Possessing Motor Vehicle Licenses;  Application;  Fee;  Organ Donor Status;  Provision Of Donor Information To Eye And Tissue Banks;  Expiration</catch_line>
    <order_by>8E</order_by>
    <text>
          Any person 14 years of age or older who does not have a valid license to operate motor vehicles may make application to the registrar of motor vehicles and be issued an identification card by the registrar and attested by the registrar as to true name, correct age, photograph and other identifying data as the registrar may require. Every application for an identification card shall be signed and verified by the applicant and shall contain such bona fide documentary evidence of the age and identity of such applicant as the registrar may require. The registrar shall require payment of a fee, to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven at the time application for an identification card is made.  Each applicant shall be asked in writing whether he wishes to become an organ or tissue donor in the application. The registrar shall provide to federally designated organ procurement organizations and other federally registered nonprofit eye and tissue banks serving the commonwealth access to names, dates of birth and other pertinent information of such identification holders in the same manner as provided for licensed drivers under section 8D.[ Paragraph added by 2012, 170, Sec. 1 effective October 28, 2012.]  An identification card or any renewal thereof issued under this section shall expire on an anniversary of the date of birth of the person to whom the identification card was issued, occurring more than 12 months but not more than 60 months after the effective date of the identification card. The anniversary date for an identification card issued to an applicant born on February 29 shall be March 1.
    </text>
</law>