<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="92A1/2" order_by="92A1/2" level="3">Watershed Management</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Environmental Protection Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        The division after consultation with the department of environmental protection, shall make rules and regulations by July 1, 1992 and from time to time thereafter for the protection of the watersheds and the watershed system. The regulations shall include provisions that require notice to the department and the division of applications for variances for uses or structures that affect the watersheds. Notice of hearings on the proposed regulations shall be sent to the chief executive officer of all cities and towns within the watersheds and any other cities and towns affected by such regulations. The division shall file copies of the regulations promulgated in accordance with this section with the clerk of the house of representatives and the clerk of the senate and send copies to the chief executive officer of all the cities and towns within the watersheds and any other cities and towns affected by such regulations. The regulations shall not take effect until 60 days have elapsed from the time of said filing. The division shall cause such rules and regulations to be posted at or near the waters to which they respectively apply, and shall also cause the same to be published at least once in a newspaper published in the county where said waters are in whole or in part situated, and such posting and publication shall be sufficient notice to all persons. The sworn certificate of any senior member of the department of such posting and publication, or of the posting or publication of an order made by the department, shall be prima facie evidence of the posting and publication. A copy of any such rule, regulation or order, attested by any senior member of the department, shall be prima facie evidence that said rule, regulation or order was made by department or by the commissioner, as the case may be.
    </text>
</law>