<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90F" order_by="90F" level="3">Uniform Operation Of Commercial Motor Vehicles Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notification Of Registrar; Traffic Control Convictions; Notification Of Employer; License Suspensions And Previous Employment</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        A. Notification of convictions. Any operator of a commercial motor vehicle holding a license to operate issued by the commonwealth, who is convicted of violating any state law or local ordinance relating to motor vehicle traffic control, in any other state or Canadian Province other than parking violations, shall notify the registrar of motor vehicles. 
Any driver of a commercial motor vehicle holding a driver license issued by the commonwealth, who is convicted of violating any state law or local ordinance relating to motor vehicle traffic control in this or any other state or Canadian Province, other than parking violations, shall notify his or her employer in writing of the conviction within thirty days of the date of conviction. 
B. Notification of suspensions, revocations and cancellations. Each driver whose driver license is suspended, revoked, or cancelled by any state, who loses the privilege to drive a commercial motor vehicle in any state for any period, or who is disqualified from driving a commercial motor vehicle for any period, shall notify his employer of that fact before the end of the business day following the day the driver received notice of that fact. 
C. Notification of previous employment. Each person who applies to be a commercial motor driver must provide the following information for the ten years preceding the date of application. 
A list of the names and addresses of the applicant’s previous employers for which the applicant was a driver of a commercial motor vehicle; the dates between which the applicant drove for each employer; and the reason for leaving that employer. The applicant must certify that all information furnished is true and complete. An employer may require an applicant to provide additional information.
    </text>
</law>