<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="92A1/2" order_by="92A1/2" level="3">Watershed Management</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Debt Service Costs</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section as amended by 2004, 149, Sec. 152 effective until January 15, 2013. See 2004, 149, Sec. 417 as amended by 2006, 139, Sec. 82; 2008, 182, Sec. 78 and 2011, 9, Sec. 23. For text effective January 15, 2013, see below.]  The treasurer of the commonwealth shall charge the Massachusetts Water Resources Authority for the debt service costs of bonds issued pursuant to section 3 of chapter 564 of the acts of 1987 and sections 12 and 13 of chapter 36 of the acts of 1992 for the acquisition of fee simple, development and other rights or interests inland in the areas regulated by the division. The revenue shall be deposited into the Water Supply Protection Trust established in section 73 of chapter 10 for the purposes of meeting said debt service costs. The comptroller shall transfer to the General Fund from the Water Supply Protection Trust that portion of annual assessments against the Massachusetts Water Resources Authority identified as reimbursement for debt service payments that have been previously charged to the General Fund.
Chapter 92A1/2: Debt service costs
[ Text of section effective January 15, 2013. For text effective until January 15, 2013, see above.]  The treasurer of the commonwealth shall charge the Massachusetts Water Resources Authority for the debt service costs of bonds issued pursuant to section 3 of chapter 564 of the acts of 1987 and sections 12 and 13 of chapter 36 of the acts of 1992 for the acquisition of fee simple, development and other rights or interests inland in the areas regulated by the division. The revenue shall be deposited into the general fund for the purposes of meeting said debt service costs, subject to appropriation, for said bonds.
    </text>
</law>