<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="82" order_by="82" level="3">The Laying Out, Alteration, Relocation And Discontinuance Of Public Ways, And Specific Repairs Thereon</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>40C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Excavator’S Responsibility To Maintain Designation Markings; Damage Caused By Excavator</catch_line>
    <order_by>40C</order_by>
    <text>
        After a company has designated the location of its facilities at the location in accordance with section 40B, the excavator shall be responsible for maintaining the designation markings at such locations, unless such excavator requests remarking at the location due to the obliteration, destruction or other removal of such markings. The company shall then remark such location within 24 hours following receipt of such request. 
When excavating in close proximity to the underground facilities of any company when such facilities are to be exposed, non-mechanical means shall be employed, as necessary, to avoid damage in locating such facility and any further excavation shall be performed employing reasonable precautions to avoid damage to any underground facilities including, but not limited to, any substantial weakening of structural or lateral support of such facilities, penetration or destruction of any pipe, main, wire or conduit or the protective coating thereof, or damage to any pipe, main, wire or conduit. 
If any damage to such pipe, main, wire or conduit or its protective coating occurs, the company shall be notified immediately by the excavator responsible for causing such damage. 
The making of an excavation without providing the notice required by section 40A with respect to any proposed excavation which results in any damage to a pipe, main, wire or conduit, or its protective coating, shall be prima facie evidence in any legal or administrative proceeding that such damage was caused by the negligence of such person.
    </text>
</law>