<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Operator’S Licenses; Applications; Examinations</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     held a valid learner’s permit issued pursuant to section 8B or a similar law of another state for a period of not less than six months immediately preceding the date of application for a junior operator’s license under this section and, during such period, has maintained a driving record free of any surchargeable incidents, as described in section 113B of chapter 175 or a similar law of another state and has not had such permit suspended under section 24P or a similar law of another state and has not been convicted of violating any alcohol-related or drug-related law of the commonwealth or a similar alcohol-related or drug-related law of any other state. For the purposes of this section, an alternative disposition of a violation including, but not limited to, having such violation continued without a finding or placed on file shall be deemed to be a conviction. Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any penalty, fine, suspension, revocation or requirement that may be imposed under any other law of the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     attained the age of 16 and one-half years;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     successfully completed a driver education and training course approved by the registrar and presented, in such form as the registrar may require, a certified statement from a parent or guardian, or designee 21 years of age or older if the applicant is an emancipated minor, that in addition to the requirements of the driver education and training course the applicant has completed not less than 40 hours of supervised driving, or 30 hours of supervised driving if the applicant has successfully completed a driver skills development program in a closed, off-road course, as licensed by the registrar pursuant to section 32G 1/2. The registrar shall determine the appropriate method to enforce compliance with the supervised driving requirements provided in this clause. The driver education and training course shall consist of not less than 30 hours of classroom instruction. The driver education and training course shall also consist of not less than 18 hours of on-road instruction conducted by a certified driver education instructor in a motor vehicle. A student shall have not less than 6 hours of observing another student driver and not less than 12 hours of operating a motor vehicle, but no student shall have more than 1 on-road session per day and no session shall be for more than 2 hours in length. The applicant’s parent or guardian, or designee where applicable, shall participate in not less than 2 hours of instruction on the content of driver education curriculum. The registrar shall promulgate regulations to establish the appropriate method of providing the instruction and to enforce compliance. The regulations shall exempt a parent or guardian, or designee where appropriate, from receiving the instruction if he has participated within the preceding 5 years.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     successfully completed such examination and driving test as the registrar may require; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     submitted an application on a form furnished by the registrar, signed by both the applicant and a parent or guardian, along with the fee provided in section 33.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>