<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notice Of Disclosure Required Upon Sale, Lease Or Rental Of Low Speed Motor Vehicles</catch_line>
    <order_by>1G</order_by>
    <text>
        Every licensed motor vehicle dealer and every person engaged in the business of leasing or renting low-speed vehicles to the public shall, upon the sale, lease or rental of such low-speed vehicle to a customer provide a notice of disclosure printed in at least 10-point type. Such original notice shall be signed by the person purchasing, leasing or renting the low-speed vehicle and shall be retained by the merchant and a copy of the signed notice shall be provided to the customer. The merchant shall maintain such original signed disclosure notices for at least 2 years and such signed notices shall be made available for review during normal business hours by the registrar or the registrar’s agents, agents of the attorney general and local and state police. The notice shall be substantially as follows: 
___ 
Operation of Low-Speed Vehicle In Massachusetts 
“Low-Speed Vehicle is a “Motor Vehicle:” This is a “low speed motor vehicle” and like any other motor vehicle under Massachusetts law, it is required to be registered, titled and insured before it can be operated on a public way. It must be inspected within 7 days of registration. 
License/Permit Required: You must have a valid driver’s license or learner’s permit to operate this motor vehicle. The holder of a learner’s permit or Junior Operator’s license is subject to the restrictions applicable to his license/permit. This vehicle must display the distinctive slow moving vehicle emblem on the rear of the vehicle required by General Law Chapter 90, 
Maximum Operating Speed: You cannot legally operate this vehicle at a speed greater than 25 miles per hour. 
Operation Prohibited on Limited Access or Express State Highways: You cannot legally operate this vehicle on or across limited access or express state highways and ways where signs specifically prohibiting low-speed vehicles have been posted. 
No Operation Where Speed Limit Exceeds 30 Miles Per Hour: You cannot legally operate this vehicle on any portion of a public way if the speed limit on that portion of the public way is greater than 30 miles per hour. If the speed limit increases above 30 miles per hour on the portion of the public way immediately ahead, you must get off the public way, if it is safe to do so, after making the appropriate turn signal. If it is not safe to do so, you must move the vehicle as far as possible off of the road surface and wait until a police officer or other public safety officer can be summoned to direct the safe movement of the vehicle. 
Crossing Public Ways with a Speed Limit Less than 30 Miles Per Hour: Unless otherwise prohibited, you may cross a public way at an intersection where the public way to be crossed has a posted speed limit of less than 30 miles per hour, if it is safe to do so. 
Crossing Public Ways with a Speed Limit Between 30-45 Miles Per Hour: You may cross a public way at an intersection where the public way to be crossed has a posted speed limit of 30 miles an hour or more, up to 45 miles per hour, if the crossing begins and ends on a public way with a speed limit of 30 miles per hour or less and the intersection is controlled by traffic signals or stop signs. 
No Crossing of Public Ways where Speed Limit Exceeds 45 Miles Per Hour or Sign Posted: You may not cross a public way in a low-speed vehicle if the public way to be crossed has a posted speed limit higher than 45 miles per hour or where signs have been posted prohibiting crossing of the highway by low-speed vehicles. 
Operator is Subject to All Traffic Laws: You are subject to all traffic laws and regulations of Massachusetts when operating this vehicle. 
Use of Passenger Restraints Required: All occupants of this low speed motor vehicle must be secured by a properly adjusted safety belt (Chapter 90, Any child under the age of 8 shall be properly fastened and secured by a “child passenger restraint,” according to the instructions of the manufacturer, unless such passenger measures more than 57 inches in height. Unless required to be secured by a child passenger restraint, a passenger that is under the age of 13 shall wear a safety belt which is properly adjusted and fastened according to the manufacturer’s instructions (Chapter 90, 
Out-of State Operation: It may be illegal to operate this vehicle in other states so check with each state before you do.” 
___ 
Every licensed motor vehicle dealer and every person engaged in the business of leasing or renting low-speed vehicles to the public who fails to provide a customer with the notice required by this section upon the sale, lease or rental of a low-speed vehicle, shall be fined $25 for each such occurrence.
    </text>
</law>