<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Repair Of Tires On Trucks, Etc.</catch_line>
    <order_by>9C</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person or business servicing multi-piece bus, trailer, tractor or truck rims, shall use a steel cage portable locking device, chains or an equivalent containing device in the inflation of tires on such rims. 
Any person or business servicing multi-piece bus, trailer, tractor or truck rims shall prominently display instructions published by the United States Department of Transportation, or an equivalent display, which shall clearly state procedures involved in the servicing of such rims. For the purposes of this section servicing shall include the inflation of tires on such rims at the service facility. 
Any business servicing multi-piece bus, trailer, tractor or truck rims shall train and instruct all employees who service multi-piece rim wheels in the safety procedures to be followed as specified in the Occupational Safety and Health Administration Standard Part 1910. Any business servicing multi-piece bus, trailer, tractor or truck rims shall not allow an employee to service any multi-piece rim wheel unless the employee has been trained and instructed in correct procedures of mounting, demounting, and all related services, activities and safety precautions for the rim type being serviced and the safe operating procedures as specified in said Occupational Safety and Health Administration Standard Part 1910. Information to be used in the training program shall include as a minimum criteria the data contained in said Occupational Safety and Health Administration Standard Part 1910. 
Whoever violates any provision of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars.
    </text>
</law>