<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90B" order_by="90B" level="3">Motorboats, Other Vessels And Recreational Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22</section_number>
    <catch_line>Registration;  Application;  Period;  Certificate;  Name And Address;  Transferability;  Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>22</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until January 2, 2013. For text effective January 2, 2013, see below.]  No person shall operate a snow vehicle or a recreation vehicle unless the vehicle has been registered in accordance with this chapter and a registration number assigned by the director is displayed on the vehicle. The registration number shall be painted or by means of a decal or sticker which is firmly attached to both sides of the cowling of the vehicle and located so that both are clearly visible and not obstructed. The registration number displayed shall be not less than 3 inches in height and not less than one-half inch in width and shall be in a color that is in marked and distinct contrast to the background to which the number is applied. The registration number shall be maintained in a legible condition at all times. A motor vehicle license or learner's permit shall not be required for the operation of a snow vehicle or a recreation vehicle.[ First paragraph as amended by 2012, 296, Sec. 2 effective January 2, 2013. For text effective until January 2, 2013, see above.]  No person shall operate a snow vehicle or recreation vehicle unless the vehicle has been registered in accordance with this chapter and a registration number assigned by the director is displayed on the vehicle; provided, however, that the director may exempt a participant of a sanctioned race, rally or event who is not a resident of the commonwealth from the requirements of this section. The registration number shall be painted on or displayed by means of a decal or sticker firmly attached to both sides of the cowling of the vehicle and located so that both are clearly visible and not obstructed. A snow vehicle or recreation vehicle without suitable cowling may locate the registration number on the forward suspension components or other suitable location as determined by the director so that it is clearly visible on both sides of the vehicle. The registration number displayed shall be not less than 3 inches in height and not less than 1/2 inch in width and shall be in a color that is in marked and distinct contrast to the background to which the number is applied. The registration number shall be maintained in a legible condition at all times. A motor vehicle license or learner's permit shall not be required for the operation of a snow vehicle or a recreation vehicle.  Application for registration of a snow vehicle or a recreation vehicle shall be made by the owner to the director or his agent on such forms as the director shall prescribe and shall state the name and address of the owner of the vehicle. No person shall knowingly make a false statement in an application for registration of a snow vehicle or recreation vehicle.  Such registration shall be valid for a period ending two years from the date of issuance, unless surrendered, suspended or revoked. The director shall issue a certificate of registration to each such owner on such form as he shall prescribe. Each such owner shall notify the director in writing within thirty days after any change has occurred in the name and address appearing on said registration certificate. No registration issued for any such vehicle may be loaned by any person to another, nor may such registration be transferred except upon application to the director upon such forms as he shall prescribe. Every person operating a snow vehicle or a recreational vehicle shall have the certificate of registration therefor upon his person or in the vehicle, in some easily accessible place, and upon demand shall show the same to a law enforcement officer or to the owner of any land on which he is operating said vehicle. Any person authorized to issue registration certificates for snow vehicles, recreational vehicles, and vessels, who is not employed by the commonwealth, may charge the applicant an administrative fee in addition to the required registration fee. Said administrative fee shall not exceed $1.50 per registration issued.  The fee for initial registration of each such vehicle and for each renewal thereof, other than vehicles for which application is made by a manufacturer or dealer as hereinafter provided, shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration as provided in section 3B of chapter 7, except that no fee shall be collected for the registration of any such vehicle owned by the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof or a vehicle used exclusively for agricultural, forestry, lumbering or construction purposes.  In the case of a recreation vehicle to be operated exclusively for agricultural, forestry, lumbering or construction purposes, the owner of such vehicle may apply for an exemption from the registration fee. The application for exemption shall be on a form prescribed by the director of law enforcement. If the director is satisfied that the vehicle for which a fee exemption is sought is to be operated exclusively for agricultural, forestry, lumbering or construction purposes, the director shall grant the application and the owner of such vehicle shall be exempt from the registration fee for such vehicle. If the vehicle ceases to be operated exclusively for agricultural, forestry, lumbering or construction purposes, the owner shall no longer be exempt from paying such registration fee and shall be required to pay a portion of the registration fee for the year in which the exemption no longer applies. A new application for a fee exemption shall be required for further fee exemption with an application for registration renewal. A fee exemption granted pursuant to this section shall not be admissible nor relevant at trial on the question of whether such vehicle was being operated for agricultural, forestry, lumbering or construction purposes at the time of an alleged violation of this chapter.  Application for a manufacturer's or dealer's registration shall be made to the director in such form as the director shall prescribe and shall state the name and address of the manufacturer or dealer.  Upon receipt of the application and the appropriate fee as hereinafter provided, the director shall forward to the manufacturer or dealer a certificate of registration and such registration numbers as the director may approve, one of which shall be affixed to each snow vehicle or recreation vehicle being operated by or with the express or implied consent of said manufacturer or dealer.  The fee for initial registration of recreation vehicles or snow vehicles owned by or under the control of a manufacturer or dealer and for each renewal thereof shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven. The fee for the registration of each snow vehicle or recreational vehicle of a nonresident shall also be determined by the commissioner of administration. Such registration and each renewal thereof shall be valid for a period ending one year from the date of issuance or renewal, unless surrendered, suspended or revoked.
    </text>
</law>