<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="85" order_by="85" level="3">Regulations And By Laws Relative To Ways And Bridges</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Funeral Processions</catch_line>
    <order_by>14A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The operator of a motor vehicle in a funeral procession shall not drive the vehicle at a speed greater than 55 miles per hour on a highway where the posted speed limit is 55 miles per hour or more or greater than 5 miles per hour below the posted speed limit on a street or road that is not a highway.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A vehicle being operated in any funeral procession must have its headlights and taillights illuminated.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The turn signals must be flashing simultaneously as warning lights on a vehicle that is the first vehicle in a funeral procession and on a vehicle which the operator has reason to believe is the last vehicle in the funeral procession.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Whenever the funeral escort vehicle or funeral lead vehicle in a funeral procession lawfully enters an intersection, either by reason of a traffic control device or at the direction of law enforcement personnel, the remaining vehicles in the funeral procession may continue to follow the funeral lead vehicle through the intersection despite any traffic control device, general law or ordinance to the contrary relative to right-of-way, if the operator of each vehicle exercises reasonable care toward other vehicles and any pedestrians on the roadway.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, an operator of a funeral escort vehicle may, while exercising due care, direct operators of other vehicles in a funeral procession to proceed through an intersection or to make turns or other movements despite any traffic control device signal to the contrary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     A funeral procession shall have the right-of-way at intersections regardless of traffic control devices subject to the following conditions and exceptions:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     operators of vehicles in a funeral procession shall yield the right-of-way to an approaching emergency vehicle emitting an audible siren or flashing emergency lights;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     operators of vehicles in a funeral procession shall yield the right-of-way when directed to do so by law enforcement personnel; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     operators of vehicles in a funeral procession must exercise due care when participating in a funeral procession.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     An operator of a vehicle that is not part of a funeral procession shall not:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     drive between the vehicles forming a funeral procession while the vehicles are in motion except when authorized to do so by law enforcement personnel or when driving an authorized emergency vehicle emitting an audible siren or flashing emergency lights;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     join a funeral procession to secure the right-of-way as granted by subsection (c);
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     pass a funeral procession on a multiple lane highway on the funeral procession’s right side unless the funeral procession is in the farthest left lane; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     enter an intersection, even if the operator is facing a green traffic control signal when a funeral procession is proceeding through a red traffic control signal at the intersection as permitted under subsection (c), unless the operator may do so without crossing the path of the funeral procession. If the red signal changes to green while the funeral procession is within the intersection, the operator of the vehicle facing the green may proceed, subject to the right-of-way of a vehicle participating in a funeral procession.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     a vehicle owned by a funeral home establishment or a licensed or registered certified funeral director, and operated by a funeral director, an employee or an independent contractor of a funeral home may have mounted thereon flashing, rotating or oscillating lights as may be assigned by the registrar of motor vehicles. Such lights shall only be displayed when such owner or operator is proceeding in a funeral procession and at no other time.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Liability for any death, personal injury or property damage that results from, is caused by or arises out of any action or inaction of any operator of a vehicle in a funeral procession under the control of a funeral director, funeral home, funeral escort or their employees or agents shall not be imposed on such funeral director, funeral home, funeral escort or their employees or agents if the funeral procession was operating in accordance with subsections (b) to (d), inclusive, or would have been operating in such compliance but for the operator of 1 or more vehicles in the funeral procession not exercising due care.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     This subsection shall not apply if the death, personal injury or property damage allegedly arose from a negligent act or omission in the operation of a vehicle by the funeral director, funeral home, funeral escort or their employees or agents. The operator of a vehicle in a funeral procession shall not be deemed to be an agent of the funeral director, funeral home or funeral escort unless such operator is an employee of the funeral director, funeral home or funeral escort and is acting in the course of his employment, or unless the operator was retained as an independent contractor of the funeral director, funeral home or funeral escort and is performing services therefore.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     This section shall not create a new cause of action or substantive legal rights against any funeral director, funeral home, funeral escort or their employees or agents. This section shall not affect any immunities from civil liability or defenses established by general law or any immunity from civil liabilities or defense available at common law to which a funeral director, funeral home, funeral escort or their employees or agents may be entitled.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     A funeral procession of not more than 10 vehicles shall have the right, except on Sundays and legal holidays, to use any parkway, boulevard or other public way to the same extent and subject to the same regulations and restrictions as vehicles commonly known as pleasure vehicles.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>