<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="82" order_by="82" level="3">The Laying Out, Alteration, Relocation And Discontinuance Of Public Ways, And Specific Repairs Thereon</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notice Of Proposed Taking And View Or Hearing; Publication</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        Fifteen days at least before the time appointed for a view or hearing, the commissioners shall cause notice of the time and place appointed therefor and a copy of such petition to be served upon the clerk of every town wherein such new highway, alteration, relocation, specific repair, discontinuance or discontinuance of maintenance is prayed for and in the event a plan has been prepared for such new highway, alteration, relocation, specific repair, discontinuance or discontinuance of maintenance the commissioners shall, at least seven days before the date for such hearing or view, mail to the recorded owners of land, subject to a taking because of such new highway alteration, relocation, specific repair, discontinuance or discontinuance of maintenance a notice of the proposed taking and the time and place of such view or hearing. In the event a plan has not been prepared prior to such hearing or view then at least seven days before the final approval of plans for such new highway, alteration, relocation, specific repair, discontinuance or discontinuance of maintenance the commissioners shall provide a hearing for the recorded owners of land subject to taking and mail them notice of such hearing at least seven days before the date set for such hearing. Seven days at least before the time appointed for such view or hearing, they shall cause notice of the time and place appointed therefor to be mailed to each person whose land may be subject to a taking for such purpose, and such notice shall inform such land owner of the proposed taking. They shall also cause copies of the petition, or abstracts thereof, and of the notice, to be posted in two public places in each of said towns and to be published in such newspaper as they shall order; the posting and the last publication to be seven days at least before any view, hearing or adjudication on such petition.
    </text>
</law>