<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Dismissal Of Charges Upon Compliance With Terms Of Probation;  Records; Reports</catch_line>
    <order_by>24E</order_by>
    <text>
        The provisions of this section shall apply to any person convicted of or charged with operating a motor vehicle with a percentage, by weight, of alcohol in their blood of eight one-hundredths or greater, or while under the influence of intoxicating liquor provided said person is qualified for a disposition under section twenty-four D. The provisions of this section shall not apply where notice from the registrar of intention to suspend or revoke a person’s license or right to operate is pending prior to the date of complaint on the offense before the court. 
In order to qualify for a disposition under this section such person shall, in the judgment of the court, have cooperated fully with the investigation as described in section twenty-four D and shall be and have been in full compliance with such order as the court may have made for a one year term of probation as provided therein, including participation in such driver alcohol education programs, alcohol treatment or alcohol treatment and rehabilitation programs as the court may have ordered. 
Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the exercise by a court of its authority under law to make any other disposition of a case of operating under the influence of intoxicating liquor. 
Where a person has been charged with operating a motor vehicle under the influence of intoxicating liquor, and where the case has been continued without a finding and such person has been placed on probation with his consent and where such person is qualified for disposition under this section, a hearing shall be held by the court at any time after sixty days but not later than ninety days from the date where the case has been continued without a finding to review such person’s compliance with the program ordered as a condition of probation and to determine whether dismissal of the charge is warranted. 
At said hearing the probation officer shall submit to the courts a written report which shall include but shall not be limited to a written statement by the supervisor of any program of alcohol education and of any program of alcohol education and of any program of alcohol treatment, rehabilitation, or alcohol treatment and rehabilitation to which the court has assigned such person. Such statement shall consider such person’s participation and attendance in each such court ordered program. The registrar shall submit a written report to the judge at said hearing regarding any entries made on said person’s driving record in the period following placement in the program. If the court finds sufficient basis to conclude that said person has not satisfactorily completed or is not satisfactorily complying with such program, the court may notify the registrar and the registrar shall revoke the person’s license or right to operate forthwith. If the judge finds that the person is satisfactorily complying with the conditions of probation, the judge may enter a dismissal of the charges and issue appropriate orders relative to said person’s participation in a program or relative to a later hearing, subject to the duration of the term of probation. The court shall cause to be entered and to be maintained upon the probation record of said person notice of a dismissal of charges under this section. The probation officer supervising a person pursuant to the provisions of this section shall make a written report to the court if at any time such person has failed to satisfactorily comply with a court ordered program or if such person’s operation of a motor vehicle constitutes a threat to the public safety. Upon receipt of such report the court shall forthwith hold a hearing on the matter. If at such hearing the court determines that said person has failed to satisfactorily comply with such program or that the said operation of a motor vehicle constitutes such a threat, the court may notify the registrar and the registrar shall without further hearing revoke said person’s license or right to operate. Such revocation shall be for the remainder of the period from the date of conviction provided in subparagraph (1) of paragraph (c) of subdivision (1) of section twenty-four. Said person shall thereafter be subject to the same conditions for issuance of a new license or right to operate as any person applying for a new license or right to operate following revocation as provided in subparagraph (1) of paragraph (c) of said subdivision (1). 
Where an order of probation has been revoked by the court, the court shall forthwith so notify the registrar in writing and the registrar shall forthwith revoke said person’s operator’s license or right to operate which was restored under this section and without further hearing.
    </text>
</law>