<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="91" order_by="91" level="3">Waterways</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Secretary As Administrator Of Tidelands; Duties; Public Benefit Review And Public Benefit Determination; Appointment Of Public Information Officer</catch_line>
    <order_by>18B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The secretary shall serve as the administrator of tidelands. The secretary may appoint an individual or individuals to assist him in carrying out the duties of his office. The duties of this office may be exercised in combination with other duties, as the secretary shall see fit.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The secretary shall conduct and complete a public benefit review for any proposed project that is: (i) subject to the licensing provisions of section 13 or 18; or (ii) geographically located on landlocked tidelands, and in either case is required to file hereafter an environmental impact report pursuant to chapter 30. The secretary may conduct and complete a public benefit review for any proposed project that is: (i) subject to the licensing provisions of said section 13 or 18; or (ii) geographically located on landlocked tidelands and in either case is required to file hereafter an environmental notification form pursuant to chapter 30. The public benefit determination of the secretary shall not supersede said chapter 30 or this chapter or any rules or regulations promulgated pursuant thereto and shall not delay the issuance of a license pursuant to this chapter or the completion of a review or any step thereof pursuant to said chapter 30. At the completion of said review, the secretary shall make a public benefit determination, the goal of which shall be to publish on the public record a written public benefit determination of the project.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The secretary shall designate an individual to serve as the chapter 91 public information officer. The chapter 91 public information officer shall answer questions about the chapter 91 process, providing history and context regarding chapter 91 and the public benefits process as it pertains to this chapter.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>