<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>General Registrations;  General Registration Number Plates;  Eligibility</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) The registrar may issue general registrations and general registration number plates in such form as he determines to any person engaged in the following occupations who meet the eligibility requirements stated in this chapter and the rules and regulations of the registry of motor vehicles:  (1) manufacturer;  (2) dealer;  (3) repairman;  (4) recreational vehicle and recreational trailer dealer;  (5) boat and boat trailer dealer;  (6) farmer;  (7) owner-contractor;  (8) transporter; and  (9) person involved in the harvesting of forest products as defined by the regulations of the registry of motor vehicles.  (b) No person shall be eligible for a general registration and general registration number plates unless said person holds the necessary license or permit required by any federal, state or local law for engaging in said occupation, and provides truthful and complete information in the application for general registrations and number plates in the form prescribed by the registrar.  (c) Unless prohibited by this chapter or any rule or regulation of the registry, any motor vehicle or trailer owned or controlled by any person who has been issued a general distinguishing registration number which properly displays the valid corresponding general registration number plate shall be regarded as registered under this chapter; provided however, that no motor vehicle or trailer so registered shall be loaned or let for hire for more than five consecutive days.  (d) An owner-contractor who has received a general registration and number plate may only operate or tow the following vehicles or trailers with said registration and number plate:  (1) Any special mobile equipment as defined in section one;  (2) A mobile construction crane as defined in said section one; and  (3) Any other motor vehicle or trailer authorized by the rules and regulations of the registry.  A dealer in recreational vehicles and recreational vehicle trailers or a dealer in boats and boat trailers who has received such a registration and plate may only operate with said registration trailers owned by him and held for sale and demonstration.  A farmer who has received such a registration and plate may only operate or tow a vehicle or trailer under said registration and plate principally used for and dedicated to carrying on a farm related activity. Such registration and plate may not be used on a passenger motor vehicle.  A transporter, as defined in section one, who has received such a registration and plate may only operate with said registration a motor vehicle or trailer not owned by him and only in the course of such business.[ Subsection (d1/2) inserted by 2012, 139, Sec. 93 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229.]  (d1/2) A corporation engaged in the business of building or repairing boats may attach a single license plate registered and issued by the registry of motor vehicles to any trailer owned by such corporation for use to transport boats on public ways.  (e) Except for a dealer, any person who owns a motor vehicle or trailer registered for operation with a general registration issued under this section shall apply to the registrar for a sticker or decal which indicates that said owner has complied with the requirements of chapters sixty-four H, sixty-four I and ninety D, with respect to each motor vehicle or trailer so registered.  (f) The registrar may make rules and regulations relative to the issuance, use and display of general registration numbers, number plates and stickers or decals issued under this section. The registrar shall prescribe the form of a written voucher document which shall be carried on the person of any operator of a motor vehicle. A copy of said voucher shall be retained by said dealer on the licensed premises.  (g) Whoever makes a false statement in an application for a general registration and number plate shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred nor more than five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not less than thirty days nor more than two years.  (h) In addition to any penalty provided by law, the registrar may suspend or revoke, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, any general registration or number plate if he has reason to believe that the holder thereof has violated the provisions of this section or the rules and regulations of the registry made pursuant hereto.
    </text>
</law>