<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7W</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing Of Emissions Repair Facilities And Technicians; Rules And Regulations; Penalties; Computerized Communication System</catch_line>
    <order_by>7W</order_by>
    <text>
        No person or facility shall conduct inspections of motor vehicles pursuant to section 7A of this chapter or section 142J or 142M of chapter 111 unless such person is licensed by the registrar. 
The registrar, in consultation with the commissioner of environmental protection, shall establish rules and regulations for the licensing and operating requirements of all stations or facilities that conduct inspections pursuant to said section 7A or said section 142J or 142M. 
The registrar, upon granting the opportunity for a hearing, may revoke or suspend any license or certification issued under this section or place conditions or limitations on such license for a violation of any rule or regulation promulgated hereunder. 
A person who is convicted of a violation of any provision of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not more than 30 days or both such fine and imprisonment. 
Notwithstanding the provision of section 30A, the registrar may allow access or inquiry into computer data files under the control of said registrar in order to facilitate the establishment of a computerized communication system between the registry, the department of environmental protection, inspection facilities and any other person or entity in order to enforce compliance with any inspection or enforcement requirements of this chapter or chapter 111 or any other law or rule or regulation related thereto.
    </text>
</law>