<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90B" order_by="90B" level="3">Motorboats, Other Vessels And Recreational Vehicles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Numbering; Exceptions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     A motorboat owned in a country other than the United States temporarily using the waters of the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A motorboat owned by an agency of the United States government or by a state, county, city or town.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Ship’s lifeboats.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     A motorboat numbered in accordance with a numbering system established by the secretary; provided, that the certificate of number or similar document awarding a number to such motorboat is in full force and effect; and provided, further, that such motorboat shall not have been within the commonwealth for a period of time in excess of sixty consecutive days.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     A motorboat numbered in accordance with the numbering system of another state, which system has been approved by the secretary; provided, that the certificate of number or similar document awarding a number to such motorboat is in full force and effect; and provided, further, that such motorboat shall not have been within the commonwealth for a period of time in excess of sixty consecutive days.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     A vessel which has a valid marine document issued by the Bureau of Customs of the United States government or any federal agency successor thereto.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>