<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7N1/2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Defective Or Malfunctioning New Motor Vehicles; Sale And Repair Or Replacement</catch_line>
    <order_by>7N1/2</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     For purposes of this section the following terms shall have the following meanings:
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     If a motor vehicle does not conform to any applicable express or implied warranty, and the consumer reports the nonconformity to the manufacturer of the vehicle, its agent or its authorized dealer during the term of protection, the manufacturer, its agent or its authorized dealer shall effect such repairs as are necessary to conform the vehicle to such warranty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     If the manufacturer, its agent or authorized dealer does not conform the motor vehicle to any such applicable express or implied warranty by curing any nonconformity after a reasonable number of attempts, the manufacturer shall accept return of the vehicle from the consumer. In instances in which a vehicle is sold and subsequently returned, the manufacturer shall refund the full contract price of the vehicle including all credits and allowances for any trade-in vehicle, less any cash award that was made by the manufacturer in an attempt to resolve the dispute and was accepted by the consumer, and a reasonable allowance for use, or shall offer to replace the vehicle. In instances in which a vehicle is leased and subsequently returned, the manufacturer shall refund all payments made by the consumer to the manufacturer under the terms of the lease agreement less any cash award that was made by the manufacturer in an attempt to resolve the dispute and was accepted by the consumer, and a reasonable allowance for use, or shall offer to replace the vehicle. The consumer shall have an unqualified right to reject a manufacturer’s offer of replacement and demand a refund. In instances in which a vehicle is replaced by a manufacturer under the provisions of this section, said manufacturer shall reimburse the consumer for any fees for the transfer of registration or any sales tax incurred by the consumer as a result of such replacement. In instances in which a leased vehicle is replaced by a manufacturer under the terms of this section, an identical model vehicle shall be provided to the consumer for the remaining term of the original lease agreement. In instances in which a vehicle which was financed by the manufacturer or its subsidiary or agent is replaced under the provisions of this section, said manufacturer, subsidiary or agent shall not require the consumer to enter into any refinancing agreement which would create any financial obligations upon such consumer beyond those implied by the original financing agreement. In instances in which a vehicle which was leased from a dealer or manufacturer is replaced under the provisions of this section, said dealer or manufacturer shall not require the consumer to enter into any lease agreement which would create any financial obligations upon such consumer beyond those implied by the original lease agreement. In instances in which a refund is tendered under the provisions of this section, the manufacturer shall also reimburse the consumer for incidental costs including sales tax, registration fee, finance charges and any cost of options added by an authorized dealer. Whenever a vehicle is replaced a refund is given under the provisions of this section, in instances in which towing services and rental vehicles were not made available at no cost to the consumer, the manufacturer shall also reimburse the consumer for towing and reasonable rental costs that were a direct result of vehicle nonconformity. Refunds shall be made to the consumer and lienholder, if any, as their interests may appear. A reasonable allowance for use for all motor vehicles other than motorcycles shall be obtained by multiplying the total contract price of the vehicle, or in the case of a leased vehicle the total amount of payments made by the consumer to the manufacturer under the terms of the lease agreement, by a fraction having as its denominator one hundred thousand and having as its numerator the number of miles that vehicle traveled prior to the manufacturer’s acceptance of its return. A reasonable allowance for use for motorcycles shall be obtained by multiplying the total contract price of the motorcycle by a fraction having as its denominator twenty-five thousand and having as its numerator the number of miles that the vehicle traveled prior to the manufacturer’s acceptance of its return.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     A reasonable number of attempts shall be deemed to have been undertaken to conform a motor vehicle to any applicable express or implied warranties if (a) the same nonconformity has been subject to repair three or more times by the manufacturer or its agents or authorized dealers within the term of protection, but such nonconformity continues to exist or such nonconformity has recurred within the term of protection, or (b) the vehicle is out of service by reason of repair of any nonconformity for a cumulative total of fifteen or more business days during the term of protection; provided, however, that the manufacturer shall be afforded one additional opportunity, not to exceed seven business days, to cure any nonconformity arising during the term of protection, notwithstanding the fact that such additional opportunity to cure commences after the term of protection. Such additional opportunity to cure shall commence on the day the manufacturer first knows or should have known that the limits specified in clause (a) or (b) have been met or exceeded. The term of protection, said fifteen business day period and said additional opportunity to cure shall be extended by any period of time during which repair services are not available to the consumer as a direct result of a war, invasion, fire, flood or other natural disaster. The term of protection, said fifteen business day period and said additional opportunity to cure shall also be extended by that period of time during which repair services are not available as a direct result of a strike; provided, however, that the manufacturer, its agent, or authorized dealer provides or makes provision for the free use of a vehicle to any consumer whose vehicle is out of service by reason of repair during a strike. The burden shall be on the manufacturer to show that any event claimed as a reason for an extension under the provisions of this paragraph was the direct cause for the failure of the manufacturer, its agent or authorized dealer to cure any nonconformity during the time of said event. Extensions for concurrent events shall not be cumulative.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Nothing in this section shall be construed as imposing any liability on an authorized dealer or creating any cause of action by a consumer against a dealer under the provisions of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     All manufacturers shall submit to state-certified, new car arbitration, if such arbitration is requested by the consumer within eighteen months from the date of original delivery to such consumer of a new motor vehicle. State-certified, new car arbitration shall be performed by a professional arbitrator or arbitration firm appointed by the director of consumer affairs and business regulation and operating in accordance with the regulations promulgated pursuant to this section, and shall result in a written finding of whether the motor vehicle in dispute meets the standards set forth by this section for vehicles that are required to be replaced or refunded. Said finding shall be issued within forty-five days of receipt by said director of a request by a consumer for state-certified arbitration under this section. Said director shall promulgate rules and regulations governing the proceedings of state-certified, new car arbitration which shall promote their fairness and efficiency. Such rules and regulations shall include, but not be limited to, a requirement of the personal objectivity of each arbitrator in the results of the dispute he will hear, and the protection of the right of each party to present its case and to be in attendance during any presentation made by the other party. All findings of fact issuing from a state-certified, new car arbitration shall be taken as prima facie evidence of whether the standards set forth in this section for vehicles required to be refunded or replaced have been met in any subsequent action brought by either party ensuing from the matter considered in said arbitration.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6A">
    	     A clear and conspicuous listing of the rights of the consumer under this section shall be affixed by a sticker to a window of each new motor vehicle offered for sale or lease in the commonwealth. An enumeration of these rights shall also be provided along with ownership manual materials. The form and manner of these notices shall be prescribed by the director of consumer affairs and business regulations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Failure to comply with any of the provisions of this section shall constitute an unfair or deceptive act under the provisions of chapter ninety-three A. The failure of a manufacturer either to abide by the decision of a state-certified arbitration or to file a timely appeal shall entitle any prevailing consumer to an award of no less than two times the actual damages, unless said manufacturer can prove that such failure was beyond his control. For the purposes of said chapter ninety-three A, the timely delivery by a manufacturer of a refund or acceptable replacement, pursuant to a finding by state-certified arbitration, shall constitute the granting of relief upon demand.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     Whoever, within twenty-one days of any finding in favor of the consumer of the state-certified, new car arbitration, fails to appeal such finding and does not deliver a refund or replacement vehicle or notify the consumer of the estimated delivery date of the replacement vehicle, shall be punished by a fine of five thousand dollars per day until the delivery of such refund or replacement. The estimated delivery date shall not exceed sixty days from the date the manufacturer notifies the consumer that a delivery will be made. Said fine shall not exceed fifty thousand dollars for each such violation. The amount of said fine shall begin to accumulate on the twenty-second day following the arbitration decision. If eighty-one days has elapsed from the issuance of a finding in favor of the consumer of the state-certified, new car arbitration and no appeal has been taken and no award delivered and no fine paid, the attorney general shall initiate proceedings against said manufacturer for failure to pay said fine. The proceedings initiated pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be commenced in superior court department of the trial court.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>