<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90H" order_by="90H" level="3">Gateway Roads Program</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter the following words shall have, unless the context otherwise requires, the following meanings:— 
“Program”, the Gateway Roads program established by section two. 
“Department”, the division of highways. 
“Commissioner”, the administrator for highways. 
“Secretary”, the secretary of the executive office of transportation and construction. 
“Gateway roads”, the portion of state highway Route 2 between its junction with state highway Route 8 in the town of North Adams and the New York state border, the portion of United States highway Route 20 between its junction with state highway Route 7 in the city of Pittsfield and the New York state border, the portion of United States highway Route 20 between its junction with state highway Route 102 in the town of Lee at Exit 2 of the Massachusetts Turnpike, the portion of state highway Route 7 between its junction with United States highway Route 20 in the town of Lenox and the Connecticut state border, the portion of state highway Route 8 between its junction with United States highway Route 20 in the town of Becket and the Connecticut state border, those portions of United States highway Route 5 between its intersection with interstate highway Route 91 in the town of West Springfield and the Connecticut state border and between its intersection with state highway Route 2 in the town of Greenfield and the Vermont state border, those portions of interstate highway Route 91 between its intersection with interstate highway Route 90 in the town of West Springfield and the Connecticut state border and its intersection with state highway Route 2 in the town of Greenfield and the Vermont state border, interstate highway Route 84, interstate highway Route 395, the portion of state highway Route 146 between its intersection with interstate highway Route 90 in the town of Millbury and the Rhode Island state border, those portions of United States highway Route 1 between its intersection with state highway Route 128 in the town of Dedham and the Rhode Island state border and between its intersection with state highway Route 128 in the city of Peabody, and the New Hampshire state border, those portions of interstate highway Route 95 between its junction with state highway Route 128 in the town of Canton and the Rhode Island state border and between its junction with state highway Route 128 in the city of Peabody and the New Hampshire state border, interstate highway Route 195, the portion of interstate highway Route 93 between its intersection with state highway Route 128 in the city of Woburn and the New Hampshire state border, and state highway Route 3 between its junction with state highway Route 128 in the town of Burlington and the New Hampshire state border. 
“Improvements”, construction, reconstruction, and resurfacing of roads, bridges and bicycle routes and paths, lighting, drainage, storm water runoff, construction and repair of tourist information centers and rest areas, enhanced signage, intermodal integration, acquisition of open space for the purposes of preservation and aesthetic enhancements and other improvements which enhance the attractiveness of the commonwealth as a tourist destination and facilitate the movement of commerce within the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>