<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="2">Public Ways And Works</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90" level="3">Motor Vehicles And Aircraft</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24V</section_number>
    <catch_line>Child Endangerment While Operating A Motor Vehicle Or Vessel Under The Influence; Penalties; Suspension Of License</catch_line>
    <order_by>24V</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Whoever violates paragraph (a) of subdivision (1) of section 24, subsection (a) of section 24G, operating a motor vehicle with a percentage by weight of blood alcohol of eight one-hundredths or greater, or while under the influence of intoxicating liquor in violation of subsection (b) of said section 24G, section 24L, subsection (a) of section 8 of chapter 90B, or section 8A or 8B of chapter 90B, or section 131/2 of chapter 265 with a child 14 years of age or younger in the motor vehicle or vessel shall also be guilty of child endangerment while operating a motor vehicle or vessel under the influence and shall be punished by an enhanced penalty of a fine of not less than $1,000 nor more than $5,000 and by imprisonment in the house of correction for not less than 90 days nor more than 21/2 years. If a defendant has previously violated this subsection or a like offense in another jurisdiction preceding the date of the commission of the offense for which he has been convicted, he shall be punished by a fine of not less than $5,000 nor more than $10,000 and by imprisonment in the house of correction for not less than 6 months nor more than 21/2 years or by imprisonment in state prison for not less than 3 years but not more than 5 years. The sentence of imprisonment imposed upon such person shall not be reduced to less than 6 months, nor suspended, nor shall any such person be eligible for probation, parole, or furlough or receive any deduction from his sentence for good conduct until he shall have served at least 6 months of such sentence but the commissioner of correction may, on the recommendation of the warden, superintendent or other person in charge of a correctional institution, or of the administrator of a county correctional institution, grant to an offender committed under this subsection a temporary release in the custody of an officer of such institution for the following purposes only: to attend the funeral of a relative; to visit a critically ill relative; to obtain emergency medical or psychiatric services unavailable at the institution; or to engage in employment pursuant to a work release program. A sentence imposed under this subsection shall be served consecutively to and not concurrently with the predicate violation of said paragraph (a) of subdivision (1) of section 24, subsection (a) of section 24G, subsection (b) of section 24G, section 24L, subsection (a) of section 8 of chapter 90B, or section 8A or 8B of chapter 90B, section 131/2 of chapter 265. Prosecutions commenced under this subsection shall not be placed on file or continued without a finding.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The registrar shall suspend the license or right to operate of person who violates this section for a period of 1 year for a first offense, and for a period of 3 years for a second or subsequent violation.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>