<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Costs And Fees</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="261" order_by="261" level="3">Costs In Civil Actions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>27A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions Applicable To Secs. 27 A To 27 G</catch_line>
    <order_by>27A</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in sections twenty-seven A to twenty-seven G, inclusive, the following words shall have the following meanings: 
“Indigent”, (a) a person who receives public assistance under aid to families with dependent children, program of emergency aid for elderly and disabled residents or veterans’ benefits programs or who receives assistance under Title XVI of the Social Security Act or the medicaid program, 42 U.S.C.A. 1396, et seq.; (b) a person whose income, after taxes, is 125 per cent or less of the current poverty threshold established annually by the Community Services Administration pursuant to section 625 of the Economic Opportunity Act, as amended; or (c) a person who is unable to pay the fees and costs of the proceeding in which he is involved or is unable to do so without depriving himself or his dependents of the necessities of life, including food, shelter and clothing, but an inmate shall not be adjudged indigent pursuant to section 27C unless the inmate has complied with the procedures set forth in section 29 and the court finds that the inmate is incapable of making payments under the plans set forth in said section 29. 
“Fees and costs”, fees and costs shall not include attorneys’ fees. 
“Normal fees and costs”, the fees and costs a party normally is required to pay in order to prosecute or defend the particular type of proceeding in which he is involved shall include, but not be limited to, the following: in all civil cases, filing or entry fees, including the surcharges required by section four C of chapter two hundred and sixty-two; fees and related costs for service of process, including publications of a citation when publication is ordered; fees and costs for the issuance or service of a subpoena and witness fees for trial or deposition; jury trial fees; removal fees; costs assessed in a bill of costs; in equity, fees for the issuance of an injunction, restraining order, writ or other process; in the probate and family court department, fees for an amendment of record. 
“Extra fees and costs”, the fees and costs, in addition to those a party is normally required to pay in order to prosecute or defend his case, which result when a party employs or responds to a procedure not necessarily required in the particular type of proceeding in which he is involved. They shall include, but not necessarily be limited to, the cost of transcribing a deposition, expert assistance and appeal bonds and appeal bond premiums. 
“Clerk”, the clerk or an assistant clerk or the register or an assistant register. 
“Inmate”, a person committed to, held by or in the custody of the department of correction or a state, county or federal correctional facility or the treatment center under chapter 123A.
    </text>
</law>