<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Costs And Fees</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262" level="3">Fees Of Certain Officers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Uniform Schedule Of Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>4B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The chief administrative justice of the trial court, shall, subject to the approval of the supreme judicial court, establish and periodically revise a uniform schedule of fees to be charged by the various departments of the trial court for court documents and services which shall include, but not be limited to, certificates of orders, decrees, rulings, judgments, attested and unattested copies of court documents, records, blank writs and summons, subpoenas, writs of habeas corpus, for other forms, for approving or disapproving sureties on bonds or recognizances, for tape cassette recordings of proceedings in the trial court department, for commissions to take depositions, and for waivers of notice of marriage.
Chapter 262: Uniform schedule of fees
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 116 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The court administrator of the trial court, shall, subject to the approval of the supreme judicial court, establish and periodically revise a uniform schedule of fees to be charged by the various departments of the trial court for court documents and services which shall include, but not be limited to, certificates of orders, decrees, rulings, judgments, attested and unattested copies of court documents, records, blank writs and summons, subpoenas, writs of habeas corpus, for other forms, for approving or disapproving sureties on bonds or recognizances, for tape cassette recordings of proceedings in the trial court department, for commissions to take depositions, and for waivers of notice of marriage.
    </text>
</law>