<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Costs And Fees</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="261" order_by="261" level="3">Costs In Civil Actions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>27G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Payment Procedure;  Public Record;  Report Of Expenditures</catch_line>
    <order_by>27G</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The clerk shall receive from any indigent party or his attorney all bills and vouchers for any document, service or object rendered to said party for which an order for payment by the commonwealth has been issued, and shall transmit said bills and vouchers and an attested copy of said order to the office of the chief administrative justice, who shall make prompt payment thereon.  The office of the chief administrative justice shall keep a record of all payments or waivers made pursuant to this section and of all repayments made pursuant to section twenty-seven E, including therein the name of the party, his attorney if any, the names and addresses of the person or persons to whom payment is made, the dates each was rendered to the party and the charge for each, and the dates payment was made by the office of the chief administrative justice. This record shall be a public record.  The office of the chief administrative justice shall on or before December first of each year make a written report to the general court indicating the amounts and purposes of all expenditures under sections twenty-seven A to twenty-seven G, inclusive, and making such recommendations for change in the law as he deems necessary.
Chapter 261: Payment procedure; public record; report of expenditures
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 115 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The clerk shall receive from any indigent party or his attorney all bills and vouchers for any document, service or object rendered to said party for which an order for payment by the commonwealth has been issued, and shall transmit said bills and vouchers and an attested copy of said order to the office of the court administrator, who shall make prompt payment thereon.  The office of the court administrator shall keep a record of all payments or waivers made pursuant to this section and of all repayments made pursuant to section twenty-seven E, including therein the name of the party, his attorney if any, the names and addresses of the person or persons to whom payment is made, the dates each was rendered to the party and the charge for each, and the dates payment was made by the office of the court administrator. This record shall be a public record.  The office of the court administrator shall on or before December first of each year make a written report to the general court indicating the amounts and purposes of all expenditures under sections twenty-seven A to twenty-seven G, inclusive, and making such recommendations for change in the law as he deems necessary.
    </text>
</law>