<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="142" order_by="142" level="3">Supervision Of Plumbing</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        In all cities and towns, the examiners shall make and from time to time in like manner alter, amend and repeal rules and regulations relative to the construction, alteration, repair and inspection of plumbing in such cities and towns, which rules and regulations shall be reasonable, uniform and based on generally accepted standards of plumbing practice; provided, however, that the application of such rules and regulations may be varied by the examiners in a particular city or town upon petition of the board of health or health department thereof. The examiners shall adopt a regulation requiring all cities and towns to use a uniform application for a permit to perform plumbing work. 
The examiners shall make and from time to time in like manner alter, amend, and repeal rules and regulations relative to gas fitting in buildings throughout the commonwealth, and relative to liquefied petroleum gas fitting in buildings throughout the commonwealth, and relative to liquefied petroleum gas fitting containers and regulating equipment in such buildings, which rules shall be reasonable, uniform, based on generally accepted standards of engineering practice, and designed to prevent fire, explosion, injury and death, and not inconsistent with rules and regulations relative to the distribution of natural gas which are promulgated pursuant to chapter one hundred and sixty-four or the provisions of chapter one hundred and forty-two or the rules and regulations made under the authority thereof. Any person aggrieved by a ruling interpreting the rules and regulations made under this paragraph, including any person aggrieved by any such rule made by the building commissioner of Boston, may appeal to the examiners in writing within ten days after such ruling; and, subject to the provisions of chapter thirty A relative to adjudicatory proceedings, said examiners shall hear and decide such appeal. Subject to said provisions of chapter thirty A, such decision shall be final and binding upon, and complied with by, all parties in interest.
    </text>
</law>