<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146" level="3">Inspection Of Boilers, Air Tanks, Etc. Licenses Of Engineers, Firemen, And Operators Of Hoisting Machinery</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>53A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Rules And Regulations;  Classifications Of Hoisting Machinery;  Criteria For Issuing Apprentice Operator Licenses</catch_line>
    <order_by>53A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  The commissioner shall issue rules and regulations, pursuant to chapter 30A, embodying the classifications of hoisting machinery and establishing criteria and procedures for the issuance, denial, renewal, suspension and revocation of licenses of apprentice operators of such machinery. However, a final adjudication that there has been a violation of federal or state occupational safety and health regulations, or any rule or regulation adopted by the department, shall be cause for the denial, revocation or suspension of any license issued under this section. Criteria for issuance of such licenses shall include, but not be limited to, training and experience requirements appropriate to the categories of machinery for which the license is intended, and registration with the apprenticeship council within the department of labor and workforce development. A holder of such apprentice license may operate hoisting machinery only under the guidance and supervision of a holder of a license to operate for the category of hoisting machinery to be operated by the apprentice.
Chapter 146: Rules and regulations; classifications of hoisting machinery; criteria of issuing apprentice operators licenses
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 123 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  The commissioner shall issue rules and regulations, pursuant to chapter 30A, embodying the classifications of hoisting machinery and establishing criteria and procedures for the issuance, denial, renewal, suspension and revocation of licenses of apprentice operators of such machinery. However, a final adjudication that there has been a violation of federal or state occupational safety and health regulations, or any rule or regulation adopted by the department, shall be cause for the denial, revocation or suspension of any license issued under this section. Criteria for issuance of such licenses shall include, but not be limited to, training and experience requirements appropriate to the categories of machinery for which the license is intended, and registration with the apprenticeship council within the department of labor standards. A holder of such apprentice license may operate hoisting machinery only under the guidance and supervision of a holder of a license to operate for the category of hoisting machinery to be operated by the apprentice.
    </text>
</law>