<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>46C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Application For License</catch_line>
    <order_by>46C</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person desiring to obtain a license to establish, conduct or keep an employment agency shall make application for such license to the commissioner. Such application shall be made by the owner or owners of the employment agency, and if the employment agency is owned by a corporation, such application shall be made by the president and treasurer thereof. Each application shall be in writing and in a form prescribed by the commissioner, and shall contain the name and address of the applicant; the name under which the employment agency is to be conducted; the street and number of the building or place where the business is to be conducted; the former business or occupations of the applicant; the name and address of the individual who will actually direct and operate the placement activities of the agency, whether such individual be the applicant or another; the length of time such individual has spent as a placement employee; a description of the duties of such individual as a placement employee. Such application shall be accompanied by samples or accurate facsimiles of each and every form which the applicant for a license will require applicants for employment to execute, and such forms shall be approved by the commissioner before a license may be issued. The commissioner shall not approve any such form unless it fairly, clearly and fully represents the contractual terms and conditions between the proposed employment agency and an applicant for employment. Each application for a license shall be accompanied by the affidavits of two reputable residents of the commonwealth that the applicant is a person of good moral character.
    </text>
</law>