<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138" level="3">Alcoholic Liquors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Special Licenses To Managers Of Indoor Or Outdoor Activities; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        In a city or town wherein the granting of licenses to sell all alcoholic beverages or wines and malt beverages only is authorized under this chapter, special licenses for the sale of wines and malt beverages only, or either of them, may be issued by the local licensing authorities, to the responsible manager of any indoor or outdoor activity or enterprise; provided, however, in any city or town wherein the granting of licenses to sell all alcoholic beverages is authorized under this chapter, special licenses for the sale of all alcoholic beverages or wine and malt beverages only, or any of them, may be issued by the local licensing authorities to the responsible manager of any nonprofit organization conducting any indoor or outdoor activity or enterprise. Special licenses for the dispensing of wines and malt beverages in dining halls maintained by incorporated educational institutions authorized to grant degrees may be granted by the local licensing authorities in such a city or town to such institutions; provided, that such beverages shall be served only to persons over twenty-one years of age. The fees for licenses granted under this section shall be fixed from time to time by the local licensing authorities and need not be uniform. 
A license under this section shall not be granted to any person while his application for a license under section twelve is pending before the licensing authorities.
    </text>
</law>