<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>165</section_number>
    <catch_line>Investigators;  Investigation Of Damages Caused By Dogs;  Settlement;  Action Against Owner Or Keeper;  Payments Over To County Treasurer</catch_line>
    <order_by>165</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  The county commissioners, except in Suffolk county, shall appoint one and may appoint not more than four suitable persons, all residents of the county, any one of whom shall, at the request of said commissioners or of the chairman of the selectmen or officer of the police designated as provided in section one hundred and sixty-one, investigate any case of damages done by a dog of which the commissioners, chairman or officer shall have been informed as provided in said section; and if he believes that the evidence is sufficient to sustain an action against the owner or keeper of the dog as provided in said section and believes that such owner or keeper is able to satisfy any judgment recovered in such action, he shall bring the action, unless the owner or keeper before action brought pays him such amount in settlement of the damage as he deems reasonable. Such action may be brought in his own name and in the county where he resides, and he shall prosecute it. The persons so appointed shall also have throughout their respective counties the same powers and authority as police officers, constables or dog officers appointed under provisions of section one hundred and fifty-one, acting under sections one hundred and thirty-seven to one hundred and seventy-five, inclusive. All damages received or recovered under this section shall be paid over to the county treasurer and placed to the credit of the dog fund. The county treasurer shall pay out of the dog fund such reasonable compensation as the county commissioners shall allow for services and necessary expenses under this section and the reasonable expense of prosecuting the said actions. The persons appointed hereunder may be removed at any time by the county commissioners.
Chapter 140: Investigation of damages caused by dogs; settlement; action against owner or keeper; payments over to city or town treasurer
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 35 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  A city or town may investigate any case of damage done by a dog of which the chair of the board of selectmen, mayor or animal control officer shall have been informed as provided in section 161. If the chair, mayor or animal control officer believes that the evidence is sufficient to sustain an action against the owner or keeper of the dog and believes that such owner or keeper is able to satisfy any judgment recovered in an action, the chair, mayor or animal control officer shall bring the action unless the owner or keeper pays the amount in settlement of the damage as the chair, mayor or officer deems reasonable before the action is brought. The action may be brought in the name of the chair, mayor or animal control officer prosecuting the action and the chair, mayor or animal control officer shall have the same powers and authority as animal control officers appointed under section 151 and acting under sections 136A to 174E, inclusive. All damages received or recovered under this section shall be paid over to the city or town treasurer.
    </text>
</law>