<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="142" order_by="142" level="3">Supervision Of Plumbing</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>17</section_number>
    <catch_line>Statements By Manufacturer On Range Boilers And Water Heaters;  Certificates Relative To Cast Iron Water Fronts, Heater Elements And Hot Water Tanks</catch_line>
    <order_by>17</order_by>
    <text>
        No range boiler, tank, vessel or container, ferrous or non-ferrous, in which water is to be heated or stored under pressure for domestic, culinary or sanitary purposes, in this section and in sections eighteen and nineteen referred to as hot water tanks, shall be sold or offered for sale unless it is plainly marked by the manufacturer, by stamping into the metal of the tank, or on a metal plate permanently attached to the tank, in a conspicuous place, as follows:— 
A. Manufacturer’s name or registered trade mark. 
B. Rated capacity of hot water tank in United States gallons. 
C. Hydrostatic pressure in pounds per square inch at which the tank has been tested by the manufacturer, following the words “Tested to”. 
D. Maximum allowable working pressure in pounds per square inch. 
Notwithstanding the requirements of the preliminary paragraph and paragraphs A to D, inclusive, of this section, the markings therein referred to shall not be required, in the case of cast iron hot water fronts, so called, or hot water tanks that are insulated or enclosed in a jacket or casing, to be stamped into the metal thereof or to be stamped on a metal plate permanently attached thereto; provided, that any manufacturer selling such hot water fronts within the commonwealth shall in writing certify to the department of public safety and the board of state examiners of plumbers that every such water front sold by him complies with the pertinent provisions of law; and provided, further, that any manufacturer of hot water tanks that are insulated or enclosed in a jacket or casing which are to be sold within the commonwealth shall certify in writing to the department of public safety and the board of state examiners of plumbers that every such tankless water heater coil or element, or hot water tank manufactured by him complies with the pertinent provisions of law, and shall permanently attach to the largest segment of said jacket or casing, in a conspicuous place, a metal plate which has stamped into the metal thereof the requirements of paragraphs A to D, inclusive.
    </text>
</law>