<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138" level="3">Alcoholic Liquors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Farmer Winery Licenses; Hearing; Appeal; Notices To Interested Parties; Operation Of Winery; Records; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>19B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purpose of encouraging the development of domestic vineyards, the commission shall issue a farmer-winery license to any applicant who is both a citizen and resident of the commonwealth, and to applying partnerships composed solely of such individuals, and to applying corporations organized under the laws of the commonwealth or organized under the laws of any other state of the United States and admitted to do business in this commonwealth and to applying limited liability companies and limited liability partnerships organized under the laws of the commonwealth, subject to such conditions as the commission may prescribe by regulation to address issues of citizenship and residency and the need for a license manager under section 26 as qualifications for a limited liability company or limited liability partnership to hold a license pursuant to this section and sections 15, 18, 18A, 19 and 19C, unless:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     such person does not comply with reasonable application procedures required by the commission; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the commission determines that such person is not of responsible character; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     a church or school located within five hundred feet of the winery premises has objected to issuance of the license in accordance with section sixteen C; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the commission determines that the applicant retains or owns an interest, directly or indirectly, in the business of a licensee under section twelve or fifteen; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the commission determines that the applicant retains or owns an interest, directly or indirectly in more than one business licensed under section eighteen; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     the applicant has not furnished the requisite license fee or bond; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     the commission determines that the co-partners, corporate officials or stockholders of the applicant do not meet the requirements of paragraphs (2), (4) and (5), or that the manager or agent intended to conduct the winery business on the applicant’s behalf does not meet such requirements, or that such co-partners, officials, stockholders, agent or manager remain undisclosed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commission may on its own motion, and shall upon the written request of any applicant who has been refused a farmer-winery license or has been refused transfer or renewal of such a license, hold an evidentiary hearing, notice of which shall be mailed to the applicant at the address given in his application. Such hearing shall be before the commission, or a member thereof. The commission shall present its reasons for refusing issuance. The applicant may appear in person or by counsel, may cross-examine witnesses for the commission and may present evidence. The hearing shall be stenographically or sound recorded. If the hearing is conducted by an examiner, the examiner shall report on the hearing to the commission. The commission shall decide within thirty days of the completion of the hearing whether to issue the winery license or grant the transfer or renewal. If the commission refuses the license, transfer or renewal following the hearing, notice in writing of the refusal shall be mailed to the applicant. In all such cases, the commission shall keep on file a statement in the form of an opinion of the reasons for the refusal, and shall furnish a copy thereof to the applicant.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Any applicant who has appeared before the commission at such a hearing and who has been refused a farmer-winery license or the transfer or renewal of such a license may appeal to the superior court of the county where the applicant resides or has his principal place of business within the commonwealth, or to the superior court for the county of Suffolk.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Every applicant for an original winery license or for a transfer of such a license shall, within seven days after filing an application with the commission, send written notice of his application by registered mail, return receipt requested, to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     each school which offers instruction and training to children of compulsory school age in accordance with sections one and four of chapter seventy-one and which is located within a radius of five hundred feet from the premises on which the winery is to be operated; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     each church as defined in section sixteen C which is located within a radius of five hundred feet from such premises.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     such school or church had actual notice, prior to issuance or transfer, of the application and of the right to object under sixteen C; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     such school or church did not complain as soon as possible after actual notification of the application and of the right to object.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A winegrower may operate a farmer’s winery under such conditions as the commission may prescribe by regulation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A winegrower may import the unfermented juice of fruits, flowers, herbs or vegetables and may, using wine produced by the winegrower, distill wine on the premises of the winegrower for the sole purpose of fortifying other wines produced by the winegrower; provided, however, that a winegrower may not import wine or alcohol into the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     A winegrower may sell wine or winery products:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     at wholesale to any person holding a valid wholesaler’s and importer’s license under section 18;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     at retail by the bottle to consumers, for consumption off the winery premises in accordance with a license issued under section 15, 15F or 19F;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     at retail or wholesale to a person in a state or territory in which the importation and sale of wine is not prohibited by law;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     at wholesale to a person in any foreign country.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     at retail by the glass or bottle to be consumed on the premises prescribed by a license issued by local authority pursuant to section twelve of this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     A winegrower shall not sell at retail to consumers any wine or winery product not produced by or for the winery and sold under the winery brand name. All retail sales shall be made on the winery premises, except where a winegrower obtains additional licenses for the sale of wine to consumers at additional locations off the winery premises at locations authorized by a license issued pursuant to sections 15 and 15F.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     A winegrower may be licensed by local licensing authorities to sell wine for consumption on the winery premises in accordance with the pertinent provisions of section twelve and with such regulations as the commission may prescribe.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     All wines sold by a licensee hereunder shall be sold and delivered in such manner and under such conditions and with such labels or other marks to identify the producer as the commission may prescribe.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     Every winegrower under this section shall keep such records as the commission may prescribe, and shall file with the commission, whenever and as often as it may require, duplicates of copies of such records. The commission shall at all times, through its designated officers or agents, have access to all books, records or other documents of every licensed winegrower relating to the licensee’s winery business.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     The annual license fee for each winegrower, in respect of each winery, shall be computed based on the wine gallonage produced by the winery as follows:
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     Every applicant for a farmer-winery license shall, at the time of filing an application, pay a license fee based on a reasonable estimate of the amount of wine to be produced during the year covered by the license. Persons holding farmer-winery licenses shall report annually at the end of the year covered by the license the amount of wine produced during such year. If the total amount of such wine exceeds the amount permitted by the fee already paid, the licensee shall pay whatever additional fee is owing under this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>