<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>147A</section_number>
    <catch_line>By Laws And Ordinances Relative To Regulation Of Dogs</catch_line>
    <order_by>147A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 193, Sec. 19.]  Any city or town which accepts the provisions of this section is hereby empowered to enact by-laws and ordinances relative to the regulation of dogs. Except as hereinafter provided in clauses (a), (b) and (c), and notwithstanding any contrary provision of sections one hundred and thirty-seven to one hundred and seventy-four D, inclusive, relating to the regulation of dogs or any special law relating to the regulation of dogs, such by-laws and ordinances may relate to, but not be limited to dog licensing, establishing dog fees, disposition of fees, appointment of dog officers, kennel licensing and regulations, procedures for the investigation of and reimbursement for damage caused by dogs, restraining of dogs and establishing penalties for a breach thereof. No such by-law or ordinance shall be inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter relating to (a) the turning over or sale of animals to any business or institution licensed or registered as a research facility or animal dealer, as provided in section one hundred and fifty-one; (b) the minimum confinement period of dogs as provided in section one hundred and fifty-one A; and (c) the methods of execution, as provided in said section one hundred and fifty-one A.  In any city or town which accepts this section, all money received from licenses or recovered as fines under any by-law or ordinance enacted pursuant to the provisions of this section, shall be paid into the treasury of said town or city and shall not thereafter be paid over by the town or city treasurer to the county in which said town or city is located.  Any and all functions relating to the regulation of dogs pursuant to section one hundred and thirty-seven to one hundred and seventy-four D, inclusive, which would otherwise be performed by the county, by the county commissioner or otherwise, shall not be performed by the county on behalf of any city or town which is not a member of the county dog fund.  Any and all costs which would otherwise be paid out of the county dog fund shall not be paid by the county to any city or town which is not a member of the county dog fund, or to any city or town which accepts this section and such cities and towns shall thereupon be responsible for all costs and expenses relating to the regulation of dogs.
    </text>
</law>