<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="143" order_by="143" level="3">Inspection And Regulation Of, And Licenses For, Buildings, Elevators And Cinematographs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>75</section_number>
    <catch_line>Operator’S License; Examination; Qualifications; Fees; Renewal;  Expiration</catch_line>
    <order_by>75</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall operate such apparatus in any public building until he has received a license so to do from an inspector. No such license shall be granted until the applicant has passed an examination proving him to be thoroughly skilled in the working of the mechanical and electrical apparatus or devices used therein or connected therewith, nor unless he has submitted evidence as to his responsibility in regard to the safety of the public, and no person under eighteen shall be eligible for such examination. A fee shall accompany the application for a license. Licenses shall be valid throughout the commonwealth but shall not be assignable or transferable. A license shall continue in force until the date of birth of the licensee occurring more than twelve months but not more than twenty-four months after the date of such license unless suspended or revoked for incompetence or untrustworthiness of the licensee. If any such license or the renewal thereof expires in an even year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the licensee’s date of birth occurring in an even year. If any such license or renewal thereof expires in an odd year any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the licensee’s date of birth occurring in an odd year. A license issued to a person born on February twenty-ninth shall for the purpose of this section expire on March first. Licenses not renewed at the expiration date shall become void, and shall after one year be reinstated only by reexamination of the licensee. A notice of the date of the expiration of a license shall, at least thirty days prior to such date, be sent to the licensee. The fee for said license and each renewal thereof shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provisions of section three B of chapter seven.
    </text>
</law>