<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147" level="3">State And Other Police, And Certain Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>62</section_number>
    <catch_line>Acceptance Of Education, Training Or Service Completed By Applicant As Member Of Armed Forces Toward Qualification Requirements To Receive License Or Certification;  Validity Of License Or Certificate During Active Service Of Holder;  Expedited Licensing Of Spouse Of Member Of Armed Services</catch_line>
    <order_by>62</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 108, Sec. 14A effective May 31, 2012.]  (a) The commissioner shall coordinate and adopt a uniform policy within the department to, upon presentation of satisfactory evidence by an applicant for certification or licensure under the authority of the department, accept education, training or service completed by an individual as a member of the armed forces, as defined in clause Forty-third of section 7 of chapter 4, or the United States military reserves toward the qualifications required to receive the license or certification in question.  (b) Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, if a licensee or certificate holder, who received a license or certificate under the authority of the department, is engaged in active service in the armed forces of the United States, as defined in clause Forty-third of section 7 of chapter 4, the license or certification held by that licensee or certificate holder shall remain valid until the licensee or certificate holder is released from active duty and for a period of not less than 90 days following that release.  (c) Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the commissioner shall establish a procedure within the department to, upon the presentation of satisfactory evidence by an applicant for certification or licensure under the authority of the department, expedite the issuance of a license or certification for a person: (i) who is certified or licensed in a state other than the commonwealth; (ii) whose spouse is a member of the armed forces in the United States; (iii) whose spouse is the subject of a military transfer to the commonwealth; and (iv) who left employment to accompany a spouse to the commonwealth. The procedure shall include, but not be limited to: (1) issuing the person a license or certificate if, in the opinion of the department, the requirements for licensure or certification of the other state are substantially equivalent to the requirements for licensure or certification in the commonwealth; or (2) issuing the person a temporary license or certificate to allow the person to perform services while completing any specific requirements that may be required in the commonwealth but were not required in the state in which the person was licensed or certified.
    </text>
</law>