<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>167</section_number>
    <catch_line>Ordering Dogs To Be Muzzled Or Restrained;  Killing Unmuzzled Or Unrestrained Dogs</catch_line>
    <order_by>167</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  The aldermen or selectmen may order that all dogs shall be muzzled or restrained from running at large during such time as shall be prescribed by such order. After passing such order and posting a certified copy thereof in two or more public places in the town, or, if a daily newspaper is published in such town, by publishing such copy once in such newspaper, the aldermen or selectmen may issue their warrant to one or more of the police officers or constables of such town, who shall, after twenty-four hours from the publication of such notice, kill all dogs found unmuzzled or running at large contrary to such order, and shall receive such compensation therefor as is provided in section one hundred and fifty-one. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a police officer or constable may, in his discretion, hold any such dog for a period not in excess of ten days. If the owner thereof claims such dog and pays to such officer or constable the sum of five dollars, together with one dollar and fifty cents for each day that it is so held, it shall be returned to the owner. The fee of five dollars shall be paid over to the city or town and the remaining moneys shall be retained by such officer or constable as his fee.
Chapter 140: Ordering dogs to be restrained; euthanizing unrestrained dogs
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 36 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  The mayor, aldermen or board of selectmen may order that all dogs shall be restrained from running at large during such times as shall be prescribed by the order. Once passed, a certified copy of the order shall be posted in at least 2 public places in the city or town or, if a daily newspaper is published in the city or town, by publishing a copy once in that newspaper. Following publication, the mayor, aldermen or board of selectmen may issue a warrant to a police officer or constable in a city or town, who shall, not sooner than 24 hours after the publication of the notice, euthanize all dogs in a humane manner that are found running at large contrary to the order. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a police officer or constable may, in the officer's or constable's discretion, hold any such dog for not more than 7 days. If the owner of the dog claims it and pays to the officer or constable a penalty of $40 for each day that the dog has been held, the dog shall be returned to its owner. The amount shall be paid over to the city or town.
    </text>
</law>