<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147" level="3">State And Other Police, And Certain Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Amateur Boxing, Mixed Martial Arts Or Other Unarmed Combative Sporting Events, Sparring Matches And Exhibitions; Acknowledgment Of Rules And Regulations Of Amateur Governing Body; Licensing Of Amateur Referees, Judges And Officials; Limitation On Number And Timing Of Competitions;  Gloves</catch_line>
    <order_by>35A</order_by>
    <text>
        Notwithstanding section 36, the commission shall, in the conduct of all amateur boxing, mixed martial arts or other unarmed combative sporting events, sparring matches and exhibitions sanctioned by the national governing body and its local affiliate which are appointed and recognized by the United States Olympic Committee for such purposes, acknowledge and follow the rules and regulations of the amateur governing bodies. 
No amateur match which is subject to section 32 shall be held unless it is licensed by the commission and sanctioned and supervised by an amateur sanctioning organization approved by the commission. 
The commission shall recognize and license, upon receipt of the classified fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration and finance under section 3B of chapter 7, the amateur referees, judges and other amateur officials assigned to the amateur matches or exhibitions by the amateur governing bodies and certified under their rules and regulations. 
The commission shall cooperate fully with the amateur boxing governing bodies to assure that amateur boxers are eligible to participate and compete for selection to the United States Olympic boxing team. 
No contestant in amateur boxing shall compete in more than 2 tournaments in any 7-day period, nor shall the contestant participate in more than 3 contests between 12 noon on any 1 day and 12:30 a.m. on the following day. All amateur boxing or sparring matches or exhibitions shall terminate not later than 12:30 a.m. on the day following the start of the match. 
During a contest, contestants in amateur boxing or kickboxing matches or exhibitions shall wear gloves weighing at least 8 ounces each unless otherwise authorized by the amateur boxing governing body. During a contest, contestants in amateur mixed martial arts and other unarmed combative sport matches or exhibitions shall wear gloves weighing at least 4 ounces each unless otherwise authorized by the amateur governing body.
    </text>
</law>