<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>46R</section_number>
    <catch_line>Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>46R</order_by>
    <text>
        Whoever violates any provision of sections forty-six B, forty-six C, forty-six E, forty-six F, forty-six J, forty-six K, forty-six L, forty-six M, forty-six N and forty-six O, shall be punished by a fine of not more than five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than one year, or both. Whoever violates any provision of sections forty-six H, forty-six I, and forty-six P, shall be punishable by a fine of not more than twenty-five dollars. The commissioner may institute proceedings based upon any such violation. Each violation of said sections shall constitute a separate offense. Criminal prosecution for any such violation shall not preclude any person from recovering money unlawfully collected, in a civil action. In addition to the penalties provided for in this paragraph, the commissioner may issue a written warning or a civil citation for violations of these sections. Subsections (c) to (i), inclusive, of section 6F1/2 of chapter 149 shall apply to these citations. The director of labor may adopt regulations for the issuance of the written warnings and citations and for the enforcement thereof. 
Information secured pursuant to sections forty-six A to forty-six Q shall be confidential and for the exclusive use and information of the commissioner in the discharge of his duties hereunder. Whoever, except with the authority of the commissioner or pursuant to his rules or regulations, or as otherwise required or authorized by law, shall disclose the same, shall be punished by a fine of not more than one hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or both; provided, that nothing herein shall be construed to prevent the commissioner from conducting any investigation or hearing as provided for in said sections.
    </text>
</law>