<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148" level="3">Fire Prevention</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Heads Of Fire Departments; Permits; Inspections; Records; Fees;  List Of Fire Department Heads</catch_line>
    <order_by>10A</order_by>
    <text>
        The head of the fire department in each city, town or fire district shall grant, in accordance with the rules and regulations of the board, such permits for use in such city, town or fire district as may be required by such rules and regulations, and make such inspections therein, and have and exercise such powers and duties in connection therewith, as the marshal may direct. The head of the fire department shall keep a record of every permit so issued, and shall furnish the marshal with such information in respect to such permits as he may require. The head of the fire department or the marshal may revoke any such permit for cause. A fee of $25 may be charged by the head of the fire department for any permit granted under this section, unless otherwise set in a town by the board of selectmen or town council, or in a city by the mayor, but such fee shall not exceed $50 except as provided in this paragraph. If a smoke detector inspection, conducted pursuant to section 26F, and a carbon monoxide alarm inspection, conducted pursuant to section 26F 1/2, are conducted simultaneously, the owner shall not be subject to an additional fee for the carbon monoxide alarm inspection. The fee for either a carbon monoxide alarm inspection or a smoke detector inspection, conducted separately, shall not exceed: $50 for a single-family dwelling or a single dwelling unit; $100 for a 2-family dwelling; $150 for any building or structure with 6 or fewer residential units; and $500 for any building or structure with more than 6 units. 
The clerk of each city and town shall annually, not later than April first, transmit to the marshal in writing the name and official address of the head of the fire department in his city or town, or in the fire district or districts in which his town is located or which is or are established within his town.
    </text>
</law>