<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147" level="3">State And Other Police, And Certain Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>28</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assistants; Employment; Divulgence Of Information Or False Report;  Penalty</catch_line>
    <order_by>28</order_by>
    <text>
        A licensee may employ to assist him in his business as many persons as he may deem necessary but shall not knowingly employ in connection with his business in any capacity any person who has been convicted of a felony or any former licensee whose license has been revoked. 
If a licensee falsely states or represents that a person is or was in his employ, such false statement or representation shall be cause for revocation of his license. Whoever falsely states or represents that he has been a licensee or employed by a licensee shall be punished by a fine of not less than fifty nor more than five hundred dollars. 
No person shall be employed by any licensee until he shall have executed and furnished to such licensee a statement under oath setting forth his full name, date of birth and residence; his parents’ names and places of birth; the business or occupation in which he has been engaged for the three years immediately preceding the date of filing his statement; and that he has not been convicted of a felony or of any offence involving moral turpitude. Such statements shall be kept on file by the licensee and furnished to the colonel of the state police on demand. 
Any person who is or has been an employee of a licensee and any licensee who divulges to anyone other than to his employer or as his employer shall direct, except before an authorized tribunal, any information acquired by him during such employment in respect to any of the work to which he has been assigned by such employer, and any such employee who wilfully makes a false report to his employer in respect to any such work, shall be punished by a fine of not more than five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both. 
No minor shall be employed as an investigator or guard by a licensee if the use of firearms is required in the performance of his duties.
    </text>
</law>