<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146" level="3">Inspection Of Boilers, Air Tanks, Etc. Licenses Of Engineers, Firemen, And Operators Of Hoisting Machinery</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>67</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licenses;  Duration;  Fees;  Expiration;  Renewal;  Revocation</catch_line>
    <order_by>67</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until May 31, 2012. For text effective May 31, 2012, see below.]  A license shall continue in force until the date of birth of the licensee occurring more than twelve months but not more than twenty-four months after the effective date of such license unless suspended or revoked for incompetence or untrustworthiness of the licensee, except that a special license shall not continue in force after the holder thereof ceases to be employed in the plant specified in the license. If any such license or the renewal thereof expires in an even year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the licensee's date of birth occurring in an even year. If any such license or renewal thereof expires in an odd year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the licensee's date of birth occurring in an odd year. A license issued to a person born on February twenty-ninth shall, for the purposes of this section, expire on March first. The fee for the renewal of a license shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven for the filing thereof; provided, however, that in no case shall the fee for the renewal of a license to operate hoisting machinery be less than sixty dollars, and in no case shall the fee for a new license to operate hoisting machinery be less than seventy-five dollars. Licenses not renewed at expiration date shall become void, and shall after one year be reinstated only by re-examination of the licensee. A notice of the date of expiration of a license shall, at least thirty days prior to such date, be sent to the licensee. The inspector of the division for the town where a licensee resides may issue a renewal license. A person whose license is suspended or revoked shall surrender his license to the chief or an inspector of the division. If a new license of a different grade is issued, the old license shall be destroyed by the examiner.
Chapter 146: Licenses; duration; fees; expiration; renewal; revocation
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 108, Sec. 13 effective May 31, 2012. For text effective until May 31, 2012, see above.]  A license shall continue in force until the date of birth of the licensee occurring more than twelve months but not more than twenty-four months after the effective date of such license unless suspended or revoked for incompetence or untrustworthiness of the licensee, except that a special license shall not continue in force after the holder thereof ceases to be employed in the plant specified in the license. If any such license or the renewal thereof expires in an even year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the licensee's date of birth occurring in an even year. If any such license or renewal thereof expires in an odd year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the licensee's date of birth occurring in an odd year. A license issued to a person born on February twenty-ninth shall, for the purposes of this section, expire on March first. The fee for the renewal of a license shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven for the filing thereof; provided, however, that in no case shall the fee for the renewal of a license to operate hoisting machinery be less than sixty dollars, and in no case shall the fee for a new license to operate hoisting machinery be less than seventy-five dollars. Licenses not renewed at expiration date shall become void, and shall after one year be reinstated only by re-examination of the licensee; provided, however, that if the licensee is on active duty with the armed forces of the United States, the license shall remain valid until the licensee is released from active duty and for a period of not less than 90 days following that release. A notice of the date of expiration of a license shall, at least thirty days prior to such date, be sent to the licensee. The inspector of the division for the town where a licensee resides may issue a renewal license. A person whose license is suspended or revoked shall surrender his license to the chief or an inspector of the division. If a new license of a different grade is issued, the old license shall be destroyed by the examiner.
    </text>
</law>