<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147" level="3">State And Other Police, And Certain Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32</section_number>
    <catch_line>Necessity Of License To Hold Boxing, Kickboxing, Mixed Martial Arts Or Other Unarmed Combative Sporting Event Or Sparring Match Or Exhibition;  Definitions Applicable To Secs. 32 To 51</catch_line>
    <order_by>32</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     In this section and in sections 33 to 51, inclusive, the following words shall, unless a different meaning is clearly required by the context, have the following meanings:-
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts or other unarmed combative sporting event or sparring match or exhibition for a prize or purse, or at which an admission fee is charged, either directly or indirectly, in the form of dues or otherwise, whether professional or amateur, shall take place or be conducted except in accordance with a license granted as hereinafter provided by the commission. Applications for a license shall be accompanied by the fee, as established annually by the commissioner of administration and finance pursuant to section 3B of chapter 7, which may take into consideration the population of the city or town or the seating capacity of the building or place in which the match or exhibition is to be held; provided, however, that a license, the fee for which is established on the basis of seating capacity of a building or place as aforesaid, shall be exercised only in such building or place. Tough-man or similar type matches or exhibitions shall be prohibited. In the case of exhibitions or bouts held in accordance with the rules and regulations of amateur organizations as may be approved by the commission, the commission may issue special licenses without the requirement of a bond as provided in section 34 or payment of the annual fee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Any persons holding, conducting, promoting or participating in a match or exhibition held without a license, as provided in section 33, or a toughman or similar type match or exhibition, shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of corrections for not more than 3 months or by a fine of not more than $5,000, or both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Matches or exhibitions under the governance of the Massachusetts Interscholastic Athletic Association, the National Collegiate Athletic Association or any equivalent school or college organization shall be exempt from the requirements of this section if the competitors are amateurs.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>