<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>151A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of Warrant To Officers;  Duties;  Confinement Of Dogs;  Allowance For Care</catch_line>
    <order_by>151A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  In the several cities and towns of the several counties, except Suffolk county, the mayor or board of selectmen shall annually within ten days after June first issue a warrant to such dog officer or officers directing him or them to seek out, catch and confine all dogs within the city or town which then have not been licensed, collared or harnessed, and tagged, as required by this chapter, and to enter and prosecute a complaint for failure to comply with the provisions of this chapter against the owners or keepers thereof, if known, and to kill or cause to be killed by methods of execution other than gunshot except in case of emergency, T-61, so-called, an euthanasia solution not under the control of the federal Drug Enforcement Administration, unless by a veterinarian, succinylcholine cholide, any drugs that have curariform-like action, electrocution or any other method which causes an unnecessarily cruel death each such dog which after being detained by or for him for a period of ten days shall not then have been licensed, collared or harnessed, and tagged; provided, that at the end of ten days such dog officer may make available for adoption any male or any spayed female dog not found to be diseased, for a sum not less than three dollars and shall keep an account of all moneys received by him for such adoption and shall forthwith pay over such sums to the town treasurer who shall forward all such money to the county treasurer in the same manner as dog license money as provided in section one hundred and forty-seven. Before delivery of any dog so adopted such dog officer shall require the purchaser to show identification and to procure a license and tag for such dog from the clerk of the town where the dog is to be kept. Dogs confined under authority of this section shall be confined in a place suitable for the detention and care of dogs and kept in a sanitary condition, or they may be placed in the care of the holder of a kennel license or of a domestic charitable corporation incorporated exclusively for the purpose of protecting animals from cruelty, neglect or abuse. The county commissioners from time to time shall cause all such places to be inspected and shall make necessary orders in relation thereto. A dog officer having custody of a confined dog shall be allowed the sum of three dollars per day for the care of such dog, payable by the owner or keeper thereof, if known, otherwise from the dog fund.  Every dog officer shall make, keep, and maintain systems of records or forms which fully and correctly disclose the following information concerning each animal in his custody:  The date and location of each apprehension; a description of each animal; place of confinement; if tagged, the name and address of owners of such animal; name and address of new owner including the date of sale or transfer of such animal; and, if animal is destroyed, the dog officer shall record the method and date of destruction and the name of the person who executed such animal. Every dog officer shall forward a copy of said record to the town or city clerk as soon as possible. Copies of such record shall, for a period of two years, be kept in the offices of the county dog office and the city or town clerk where such dog officer is employed.  In the cities and towns of Suffolk county, the mayor or board of selectmen shall annually within seven days after June first issue a warrant to such dog officer or officers directing him to seek out, catch and confine all dogs within the city or town which then have not been licensed, collared or harnessed, and tagged, as required by this chapter, and to enter and prosecute a complaint for failure to comply with the provisions of this chapter against the owners or keepers thereof, if known, and to kill or cause to be killed by methods of execution other than gunshot except in case of emergency, T-61, so-called, an euthanasia solution not under the control of the federal Drug Enforcement Administration, unless by a veterinarian, succinylcholine cholide, any drugs that have curariform-like action, electrocution or any other method which causes an unnecessarily cruel death each such dog which after being detained by or for him for a period of seven days shall not then have been licensed, collared or harnessed, and tagged; provided, that at the end of seven days such dog officer may make available for adoption any male or any spayed female dog not found to be diseased, for a sum not less than three dollars and shall keep an account of all moneys received by him for such adoption and shall forthwith pay over such sums to the town treasurer who shall forward all such money to the county treasurer in the same manner as dog license money as provided in section one hundred and forty-seven. Before delivery of any dog so adopted such dog officer shall require the purchaser to procure a license and tag for such dog from the clerk of the town where the dog is kept. Dogs confined under authority of this section shall be confined in a place suitable for the detention and care of dogs and kept in a sanitary condition, or they may be placed in the care of the holder of a kennel license or of a domestic charitable corporation incorporated exclusively for the purpose of protecting animals from cruelty, neglect or abuse. The county commissioners from time to time shall cause all such places to be inspected and shall make necessary orders in relation thereto. A dog officer having custody of a confined dog shall be allowed the sum of three dollars per day for the care of such dog, payable by the owner or keeper thereof, if known, otherwise from the dog fund.
Chapter 140: Issuance of warrant to officers; duties; confinement of dogs; allowance for care; records
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 21 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  (a) The mayor or board of selectmen, as the case may be, shall annually issue a warrant to the animal control officer directing the officer to seek out, catch and confine all dogs within the city or town which are not licensed, collared or harnessed, or tagged, as required by this chapter, and to enter and prosecute a complaint for failure to comply with this chapter against the owners or keepers of such dogs, if known, and to euthanize or cause to be euthanized only by the administration of barbiturates in a manner deemed acceptable by the American Veterinary Medical Association Guidelines on Euthanasia, or by gunshot in case of emergency, each such dog not licensed, collared or harnessed, or tagged after being detained by or for the officer for a period of 7 days; provided, however, that after 7 days, the animal control officer may make available for adoption any dog found free of disease for a sum of not less than $3 to be determined by the city or town and shall keep an account of all moneys received by the officer for the adoption and shall immediately pay over the moneys to the treasurer who shall forward it to the city or town. Before delivery of a dog so adopted, the animal control officer shall require the purchaser to show identification and to procure a license and tag for the dog from the clerk of the city or town wherein the dog is to be kept. Dogs detained under this section shall be confined in a place suitable for the detention and care of dogs and kept in a sanitary condition, or they may be placed in the care of the holder of a kennel license or of a domestic charitable corporation incorporated exclusively for the purpose of protecting animals from cruelty, neglect or abuse. The commissioner from time to time shall cause such places wherein animals are detained under this section to be inspected and shall make necessary orders in relation thereto. An animal control officer having custody of a detained dog or cat shall be allowed a sum determined by the city or town per day for the care of the dog or cat, payable by the owner or keeper, if known, otherwise by the city or town.  (b) Each animal control officer shall make, keep and maintain systems of records or forms which fully and correctly disclose the following information concerning each animal in the officer's custody: (1) the date and location of apprehension; (2) a description of the animal; (3) the place of detainment; (4) if tagged, the name and address of the owner of the animal; (5) the name and address of a new owner, if any, including the date of sale or transfer of the animal; (6) if the animal is euthanized, the method and date of such euthanization and the name of the person who euthanized the animal; and (7) the date, location and description of an animal euthanized by gunshot in case of emergency, the disposition of the animal remains and a description of the situation requiring the gunshot.  Each animal control officer shall forward a copy of the record to the town or city clerk within 30 days. Copies of the record shall be kept for 2 years in the office of the city or town clerk wherein such animal control officer is employed.
    </text>
</law>