<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147" level="3">State And Other Police, And Certain Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>59</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of License; Effect Of Felony Conviction; Term; Contents;  Renewal</catch_line>
    <order_by>59</order_by>
    <text>
        The commissioner may issue to an applicant complying with the provisions of section fifty-eight a license to engage in the security systems business; provided, however, that no such license shall be issued to any person who has been convicted in any state of the United States of a felony, unless a hearing is held and the commissioner, at his or her discretion, determines a license is appropriate. Any person who has been convicted of a violation of section ninety-nine or ninety-nine A of chapter two hundred and seventy-two shall not be issued a license, unless a hearing is held and the commissioner, at his or her discretion, determines a license is appropriate. If any license has been previously issued to such person, it shall be revoked. 
Such license shall be valid for two years, shall state the name under which the licensed business is to be conducted, and the address of its principal office, and shall be posted by the licensee in a conspicuous place in such office. The name of the business, so licensed, shall not contain any words which denote or imply any association with agencies of the United States, the commonwealth or any of its political subdivisions. Failure to comply with the provisions of this paragraph shall constitute cause for revocation of such license. 
The commissioner may biennially renew and may at anytime for cause, after notice and hearing, revoke any such license. An application for renewal shall be on a form furnished by the commissioner.
    </text>
</law>