<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136" level="3">Observance Of A Common Day Of Rest And Legal Holidays</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Limitation Of Operation Of Sec. 5</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Any manner of labor, business or work not performed for material compensation; provided, no public nuisance is created thereby.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The opening of a store or shop and the sale at retail of foodstuffs therein; provided, not more than a total of three persons, including the proprietor, are employed therein at any one time on Sunday and throughout the week.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The use or repair of any way or bridge, or the payment and collection of any toll incidental thereto.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The conduct of any public service the continuing operation of which is necessary for the maintenance of life, such as, but not limited to, the operation of municipal water and sewage disposal systems, the operation of hospitals and clinics, or the necessary services of physicians, surgeons, dentists and the like.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The making of emergency repairs for the purposes of immediate and necessary protection of persons, or property including realty, or the towing of any motor vehicle or boat for such purpose.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     The manufacture, sale or distribution of steam, electricity, fuel, gas, oxygen, hydrogen, nitrogen, acetylene, carbon dioxide and the calcining of lime, manufacturing processes which for technical reasons require continuous operation, and the processing of checks, items, documents or data by a bank or trust company.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     The operation of radio and television stations; the operation of telephone and telegraph systems; or the preparation, printing, publication, sale and delivery of newspapers, or the taking of pictures.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     The opening and operation of any secular place of business not otherwise prohibited by law if the natural person in control of the business conscientiously believes that the seventh day of the week, or the period which begins at sundown on Friday night and ends at sundown on Saturday night, should be observed as the Sabbath, and causes all places of business in the commonwealth over which he has control to remain closed for secular business during the entire period of twenty-four consecutive hours which he believes should be observed as the Sabbath, and actually refrains from engaging in secular business and from laboring during that period.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     The showing, sale, or rental of noncommercial real property to be used for residential purposes.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     The opening of art galleries or the display and sale therein of paintings, objects of art, catalogues and pictures.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     The operation of libraries.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     The operation of public bathhouses.
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     The operation of boats for purposes of non-commercial fishing and recreation, or the sale of bait for fishing.
        </section>
        <section prefix="14">
    	     The catching or gathering of seafood and fresh water fish not otherwise prohibited by law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="15">
    	     The letting of horses, vehicles, boats or aircraft for pleasure.
        </section>
        <section prefix="16">
    	     The sale and rental of sporting equipment and clothing on premises where the sport for which the equipment or clothing to be sold or rented is carried on.
        </section>
        <section prefix="17">
    	     The retail sale of fuel, gasoline and lubricating oil and the operation of an automotive service facility.
        </section>
        <section prefix="18">
    	     The retail sale of tires, batteries and automotive parts for emergency use.
        </section>
        <section prefix="19">
    	     The operation of a pleasure vehicle or the piloting of an aircraft.
        </section>
        <section prefix="20">
    	     The sale at retail of growing plants, trees or bushes, and articles incidental to the cultivation of such plants, trees or bushes; and the retail sale and delivery of cut flowers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="21">
    	     The cultivation of land, and the raising and harvesting of agricultural products and fruit, and the making of butter and cheese.
        </section>
        <section prefix="22">
    	     The sale, for consumption off the premises, of food prepared by a common victualler licensed under other provisions of law to serve on Sunday.
        </section>
        <section prefix="23">
    	     The selling of kosher wine or the selling or delivery of kosher meat or fish by any natural person who observes Saturday as the Sabbath by closing his place of business from sundown Friday to sundown Saturday.
        </section>
        <section prefix="24">
    	     The making and baking of bakery products and the sale thereof in a shop or store.
        </section>
        <section prefix="25">
    	     The retail sale of tobacco products, soft drinks, confectioneries, baby foods, fresh fruit and fresh vegetables, dairy products and eggs, and the retail sale of poultry by the person who raises the same.
        </section>
        <section prefix="26">
    	     The sale and delivery of ice.
        </section>
        <section prefix="27">
    	     The retail sale of drugs and medicines and the retail sale or rental of mechanical appliances prescribed by physicians or surgeons, and the retail sale of personal health and sanitary supplies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="28">
    	     The retail sale of greeting cards and photographic films and the processing of photographic films.
        </section>
        <section prefix="29">
    	     The sale, at retail, of gifts, souvenirs, antiques, secondhand furniture, handcrafted goods and art goods, in an establishment primarily engaged in the sale of such merchandise, or on the premises of a licensed common victualler.
        </section>
        <section prefix="30">
    	     The opening of a store or shop primarily engaged in the retail sale of pets, and the sale therein of pets and articles necessary for the keeping, care and feeding of pets.
        </section>
        <section prefix="31">
    	     The transport of goods in commerce, or for consideration, by motor truck or trailer; or the loading or unloading of the same.
        </section>
        <section prefix="32">
    	     The transport of goods by rail, water or air; or the loading or unloading of the same.
        </section>
        <section prefix="33">
    	     The transport of persons by licensed carriers and all matters incidental thereto, including the operation of all facilities incidental thereto.
        </section>
        <section prefix="34">
    	     The transport or processing of fresh meat, fresh poultry, fresh fish, fresh seafoods, fresh dairy products, fresh bakery products, fresh fruits or fresh vegetables, or ice, bees, or Irish moss, when circumstances require that such work be done on Sunday; or all return trips necessitated thereby.
        </section>
        <section prefix="35">
    	     The transport of livestock, farm commodities and farming equipment for participation in and return from fairs, expositions or sporting events.
        </section>
        <section prefix="36">
    	     The operation of a lodging place, including the letting of rooms and all services necessary and incidental to the letting of rooms.
        </section>
        <section prefix="37">
    	     The carrying on of the business of bootblack before eleven o’clock in the morning, provided that such business may be carried on at any time at public airports.
        </section>
        <section prefix="38">
    	     The employment for a consideration of musicians in parades by any post or camp of an incorporated organization of veterans of any war in which the United States of America was engaged, or by any incorporated civic, religious or fraternal organization, or by any company or association of policemen or firemen.
        </section>
        <section prefix="39">
    	     The necessary preparation for, and the conduct of, events licensed under section four, or activities as to which, under the provisions of paragraph (7) of section four, sections two, three and four do not apply.
        </section>
        <section prefix="40">
    	     Any labor, business or work necessary to the performance of or incidental to any religious exercises, including funerals and burials, the execution of wills or codicils, the preparation of contracts, the execution of federal, state or municipal tax returns or reports, the preparations for trials by lawyers or any other activity not prohibited nor required to be licensed on Sunday.
        </section>
        <section prefix="41">
    	     Work lawfully done by persons working under permits granted under section seven.
        </section>
        <section prefix="42">
    	     The conduct of the business of an innholder or common victualler.
        </section>
        <section prefix="43">
    	     The conduct of any business licensed under chapter one hundred and thirty-eight which may be conducted on Sunday in accordance with the provisions of said chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="44">
    	     The operation of a car-washing business between eight o’clock in the forenoon and one o’clock in the afternoon, provided that such business may be carried on at any time if not more than a total of two persons are employed therein at any one time on Sunday and throughout the week.
        </section>
        <section prefix="45">
    	     The operation of a coin-operated self-service laundry.
        </section>
        <section prefix="46">
    	     The operation of a coin-operated car-washing business.
        </section>
        <section prefix="47">
    	     The sale of tickets or shares for the state lottery.
        </section>
        <section prefix="48">
    	     The operation of a self-service auto repair center.
        </section>
        <section prefix="49">
    	     The transport of amusement devices, such as carousels, ferris wheels, inclined railways and other similar devices, concessions stands and tents from one location to the next between eight o’clock in the forenoon and one o’clock in the afternoon.
        </section>
        <section prefix="50">
    	     The keeping open of a store or shop and the sale at retail of goods therein, but not including the retail sale of goods subject to chapter 138, and the performance of labor, business, and work directly connected therewith on Sunday. This exemption shall not apply to any legal holiday as defined in clause eighteenth of section 7 of chapter 4, but this exemption shall apply to the day following Christmas Day when Christmas occurs on a Sunday. In any year in which Christmas Day occurs on a Sunday, this exemption shall not apply to that Sunday.
        </section>
        <section prefix="51">
    	     The operation of a home video movie rental business.
        </section>
        <section prefix="52">
    	     The retail sale of alcoholic beverages not to be drunk on the premises on Sundays by retail establishments licensed under section 15 of chapter 138; provided, however, that notwithstanding this chapter, a municipality may prohibit the retail sale of alcoholic beverages on Sundays by licensees under section 15 by vote of the city council or board of selectmen; provided further, that there shall be no such sales prior to the hour of 12:00 noon or on Christmas Day if Christmas occurs on a Sunday; and provided further, that establishments operating under this clause which employ more than 7 persons shall compensate all employees for work performed on a Sunday at a rate of not less than one and one-half of the employee’s regular rate. No employee shall be required to work on a Sunday and refusal to work on a Sunday shall not be grounds for discrimination, dismissal, discharge, deduction of hours or any other penalty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="53">
    	     The operation of commercial auto schools, otherwise known as driver education.
        </section>
        <section prefix="54">
    	     The cutting and styling of hair, manicuring, and the furnishing of related cosmetological and beauty services.
        </section>
        <section prefix="55">
    	     The conduct of banking operations by a bank as defined in section one of chapter one hundred and sixty-seven.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>