<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147" level="3">State And Other Police, And Certain Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licenses For Physician, Promoter, Referee, Judge, Timekeeper, Professional Boxer, Kickboxer, Mixed Martial Arts Contestant Or Other Unarmed Combative Sport Contestant, Or A Manager, Trainer Or Second Of Such A Contestant; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>35</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall act, directly or indirectly, as a physician, promoter, referee, judge, timekeeper, professional boxer, kickboxer, mixed martial arts contestant or other unarmed combative sport contestant, or as manager, trainer or second of such a contestant, at a match or exhibition or as a matchmaker therefor, unless licensed by the commission upon receipt of the classified fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration and finance under section 3B of chapter 7. The commission shall set minimum requirements for licensure based upon skill or other fundamental prerequisites deemed necessary to adequately and safely execute the functions of the respective position. The commission may refuse to license any individual who does not meet those requirements or whose safety and well-being it determines will be put at substantial risk by engaging in their respective position. Whoever acts in such capacity, without being so licensed shall be punished by a fine of not more than $10,000. Any official who desires to officiate without charge at amateur boxing or sparring matches or exhibitions shall be licensed without charge. No person shall be licensed under this section who is under 18 years of age, except as otherwise provided in section 39.
    </text>
</law>