<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>161</section_number>
    <catch_line>Damages Caused By Dogs And Paid By County;  Compensation For Appraisers</catch_line>
    <order_by>161</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  Whoever suffers loss by the worrying, maiming or killing of his live stock or fowls by dogs, outside the premises of the owners or keepers of such dogs, may, if the damage is done in a city, inform the officer of police of the city who shall be designated to receive such information by the authority appointing the police, and, if the damage is done in a town, may inform the chairman of the selectmen of the town, or, if he is absent or ill, any one of the selectmen, who shall proceed to the premises where the damage was done and determine whether the same was inflicted by dogs, and if so, appraise the amount thereof if it does not exceed fifty dollars. If in the opinion of said officer of police, chairman or selectman, the amount of said damage exceeds fifty dollars, the damage shall be appraised, on oath, by three persons, of whom one shall be such officer of police, chairman or selectman, one shall be appointed by the person alleged to be damaged, and the third shall be appointed by the other two. The said appraisers shall consider and include in such damages the labor and time necessarily expended in the finding and collecting of the live stock or fowls injured or separated and the value of those lost or otherwise damaged by dogs. The said officer of police, chairman or selectman shall return a certificate of the damages found, except in Suffolk county, to the treasurer of the county where the damage was done, within ten days after such appraisal is made. The treasurer shall thereupon submit the same to the county commissioners, who within thirty days shall examine all bills for damages, and may upon their own motion or upon request of an interested party shall summon the appraisers and all parties interested and make such investigation as they may think proper, and shall issue an order upon the treasurer of the county for such amounts, if any, as they decide to be just and shall notify all interested parties of their decision. The treasurer, except in Suffolk county, shall pay all orders drawn upon him in full, for the above purpose, and for the expenses of appraisal out of any money in the county treasury, and payments made therefor shall be charged to the dog fund. The appraisers shall receive from the county three dollars each for every such examination made by them, and also twenty cents a mile one way for their necessary travel.
Chapter 140: Damages caused by dogs and paid by city or town; compensation for appraisers
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 32 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  Whoever suffers loss by the worrying, maiming or killing of such person's livestock or fowl by a dog outside the premises of the owner or keeper of the dog, may, if the damage is done in a city, inform the animal control officer and may, if the damage is done in a town, inform the chair of the board of selectmen of the town or, if the chairman is absent or ill, any of the selectmen. The officer, chair or selectman shall proceed to the premises where the damage was done to determine whether the damage was inflicted by a dog and, if so determined, appraise the amount of damage if it does not exceed $100. If in the opinion of the officer, chair or selectman, the amount of damage exceeds $100, the damage shall be appraised, on oath, by 3 persons, 1 of whom shall be the officer, chair or selectman, 1 of whom shall be appointed by the person alleged to be damaged and 1 shall be appointed by the other 2. Within 10 days thereafter, the appraisers shall consider and include in their appraisal the labor and time necessarily to be expended to find and collect the livestock or fowl injured or separated and the value of those lost or otherwise damaged by the dog. The officer, chair or selectman shall return a certificate of the damages found to the treasurer of the city or town in which the damage was done within 10 days after the appraisal is completed. The treasurer shall immediately submit the appraisal to the city or town clerk who, within 30 days, shall examine all bills for damages. The city or town clerk may summons the appraisers or, upon the request of an interested party, shall summons the appraisers and all parties interested and make such investigation as the clerk shall deem proper. The city or town clerk shall issue an order upon the treasurer of the city or town for such amounts, if any, determined to be just and shall notify all interested parties of the decision. The treasurer shall pay all orders drawn upon the treasurer in full, for the above purpose and payments made shall be charged to the city or town.
    </text>
</law>