<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141" level="3">Supervision Of Electricians</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Learners Or Apprentices; Theatrical Companies; Employers Without A Certificate; Liability Insurance</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        Electricians regularly employed by persons, firms or corporations other than holders of certificate A, may install such electrical wiring, conduits and appliances or make such repairs as may be required only on the premises and property of such persons, firms or corporations; provided that such electricians hold journeymen’s licenses, and have otherwise complied with this chapter. Any such person, firm or corporation may employ learners or apprentices to work with and under the direct personal supervision of electricians referred to in this paragraph in said installation and repair work, provided that no such journeyman electrician shall have more than one learner or apprentice working with him and under his supervision as aforesaid; but not more than one such learner or apprentice shall be so employed for each journeyman electrician. 
Electricians employed by theatrical companies may install temporary wiring and appliances required for the purpose of the engagement of any such company, subject to the supervision of a person licensed under this chapter. 
Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law to the contrary, no permit for the performance of electrical work pursuant to chapters one hundred and forty-one and one hundred and forty-three shall be issued by any city or town unless the licensee provides proof of liability insurance, including “completed operation” coverage, which has been issued by an insurance company licensed to do business in the commonwealth, or a bond or other type of indemnity against liability providing substantially equivalent coverage. In lieu of said insurance requirement the permit issuing authority shall accept the signature of the owner or his agent on the uniform application for a permit for work to be performed by electricians.
    </text>
</law>