<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>146</section_number>
    <catch_line>License Valid Throughout State;  Removal Of Dog Into Another Town</catch_line>
    <order_by>146</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  A license duly recorded shall be valid throughout the commonwealth, except that, in the case of the permanent removal of a dog into another town within the commonwealth, the owner or keeper thereof shall, within thirty days after such removal, present the original license and tag of such dog to the clerk of the town to which such dog has been removed, and such clerk shall take up the same and issue to said owner or keeper a transfer license, together with a tag, for such dog upon payment of twenty-five cents which shall be retained by the clerk unless otherwise provided by law. The provisions of section one hundred and thirty-seven relative to the form and furnishing of licenses and tags shall apply to licenses and tags issued under this section.
Chapter 140: License valid throughout state; removal of dog into another town or city
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 18 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  A license duly recorded shall be valid throughout the commonwealth, except that, in the case of the permanent removal of a dog into another town within the commonwealth, the owner or keeper thereof shall, within thirty days after such removal, present the original license and tag of such dog to the clerk of the town or city to which such dog has been removed and the clerk shall take up the same and issue to such owner or keeper a transfer license and a tag for such dog upon payment of an amount to be determined by the city or town which shall be retained by the clerk unless otherwise provided by law. The provisions of section one hundred and thirty-seven relative to the form and furnishing of licenses and tags shall apply to licenses and tags issued under this section.
    </text>
</law>