<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146" level="3">Inspection Of Boilers, Air Tanks, Etc. Licenses Of Engineers, Firemen, And Operators Of Hoisting Machinery</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>62</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificate Of Competency;  Term;  Expiration Date;  Notice;  Renewal;  Lapse;  Reexamination;  Fees;  Suspension Or Revocation</catch_line>
    <order_by>62</order_by>
    <text>
          If the applicant is found competent he shall receive a certificate of competency to inspect steam boilers or to inspect amusement devices, as the case may be; provided, however, that if the holder of a certificate ceases to be employed as an inspector for a period of one year or more his certificate shall lapse and he shall be required to submit to reexamination for a new certificate. The fee for such reexamination shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven. Said certificate shall continue in force until the date of birth of the holder of the certificate occurring more than twelve months but not more than twenty-four months after the effective date of such certificate unless sooner revoked.  If any such certificate of competency to inspect steam boilers or amusement devices or the renewal thereof expires in any even year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the holder's date of birth occurring in an even year.[ Third paragraph effective until May 31, 2012. For text effective May 31, 2012, see below.]  If any such certificate of competency to inspect steam boilers or to inspect amusement devices or renewal thereof expires in an odd year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the holder's date of birth occurring in an odd year. A certificate of competency to inspect steam boilers or to inspect amusement devices issued to a person born on February twenty-ninth shall, for the purposes of this section, expire on March first. The fee for the renewal of the certificate of competency shall be determined pursuant to the aforementioned chapter seven provision. Certificates not renewed at expiration date shall become void, and shall after one year be reinstated only by reexamination of the former holder of the certificate. A notice of the date of expiration of a certificate of competency to inspect steam boilers or to inspect amusement devices shall, at least thirty days prior to such date, be sent to the holder of the certificate. The inspector of the division for the town where a holder of the certificate resides may issue a renewal certificate. A person whose certificate of competency is suspended or revoked shall surrender his certificate to the chief or an inspector of the division.[ Third paragraph as amended by 2012, 108, Sec. 12 effective May 31, 2012. For text effective until May 31, 2012, see above.]  If any such certificate of competency to inspect steam boilers or to inspect amusement devices or renewal thereof expires in an odd year, any subsequent renewal shall expire on the next anniversary of the holder's date of birth occurring in an odd year. A certificate of competency to inspect steam boilers or to inspect amusement devices issued to a person born on February twenty-ninth shall, for the purposes of this section, expire on March first. The fee for the renewal of the certificate of competency shall be determined pursuant to the aforementioned chapter seven provision. Certificates not renewed at expiration date shall become void, and shall after one year be reinstated only by reexamination of the former holder of the certificate; provided, however, that if the holder of a certificate of competency is on active duty with the armed forces of the United States, the certificate shall remain valid until the holder is released from active duty and for a period of not less than 90 days following that release. A notice of the date of expiration of a certificate of competency to inspect steam boilers or to inspect amusement devices shall, at least thirty days prior to such date, be sent to the holder of the certificate. The inspector of the division for the town where a holder of the certificate resides may issue a renewal certificate. A person whose certificate of competency is suspended or revoked shall surrender his certificate to the chief or an inspector of the division.
    </text>
</law>