<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>137C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Inspection Of Kennels;  Revocation, Suspension And Reinstatement Of License;  Nuisance</catch_line>
    <order_by>137C</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  The mayor of a city or selectmen of a town, or in Boston the police commissioner, or a chief of police or a dog officer within his jurisdiction, may at any time inspect or cause to be inspected any kennel and if, in their or his judgment, the same is not being maintained in a sanitary and humane manner, or if records are not properly kept as required by law, the county commissioners, or in Boston the police commissioner, shall by order revoke or suspend, and in case of suspension may reinstate, such license. Upon the petition of twenty-five citizens, filed with the mayor of a city or the selectmen of a town, or in Boston with the police commissioner, setting forth that they are aggrieved, or annoyed to an unreasonable extent, by one or more dogs at a kennel maintained in such city or town, because of the excessive barking or vicious disposition of said dogs or other conditions connected with such kennel constituting a public nuisance, said mayor, selectmen or police commissioner, as the case may be, within seven days after the filing of such petition, shall give notice to all parties in interest of a public hearing to be held within fourteen days after the date of such notice. Within seven days after such public hearing said mayor or selectmen, in Nantucket county or in Suffolk county elsewhere than in Boston, or in Boston said police commissioner, shall make an order either revoking or suspending such kennel license or otherwise regulating said kennel, or dismissing said petition. In counties other than Nantucket or Suffolk, said mayor or selectmen within said seven days shall report in writing to the county commissioners their recommendations and within seven days after receipt of such report said county commissioners shall investigate or cause to be investigated the subject matter of such petition and shall, by order, either affirm or deny such recommendations by suspending or revoking such kennel license or otherwise regulating such kennel, or by dismissing the petition. Written notice of any order under this section revoking, suspending or reinstating a license shall be mailed forthwith to the officer issuing such license and to the holder of such license. Within ten days after such order the holder of such license may bring a petition in the district court within the judicial district of which such kennel is maintained, addressed to the justice of the court, praying that the order may be reviewed by the court, and, after such notice to the officer or officers involved as the court may deem necessary, it shall review such action, hear the witnesses and affirm such order unless it shall appear that it was made without proper cause or in bad faith, in which case such order shall be reversed. The decision of the court shall be final and conclusive upon the parties. Any person maintaining a kennel after the license therefor has been so revoked, or while such license is so suspended, shall be punished by a fine of not more than fifty dollars.
Chapter 140: Inspection of kennels; revocation, suspension and reinstatement of license; nuisance
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 193, Sec. 6 effective October 31, 2012. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  The mayor of a city, the selectmen of a town, the police commissioner in the city of Boston, a chief of police or an animal control officer may at any time inspect a kennel or cause the inspection of a kennel. If, in the judgment of such person or body, the kennel is not being maintained in a sanitary and humane manner or if records are not properly kept as required by law, such person or body shall, by order, revoke or suspend the license for the kennel. Upon the petition of 25 citizens, filed with the mayor of a city, the selectmen of a town or the police commissioner in the city of Boston setting forth a statement that such citizens are aggrieved or annoyed to an unreasonable extent by a dog maintained in such city or town due to excessive barking or other conditions connected with a kennel constituting a nuisance, the mayor, selectmen or police commissioner, as the case may be, shall, within 7 days after the filing of the petition, give notice to all parties in interest of a public hearing to be held within 14 days after the date of such notice. The mayor, selectmen or police commissioner shall, within 7 days after the public hearing, investigate or cause to be investigated the subject matter of the petition and shall, by order, either suspend or revoke the kennel license, otherwise regulate the kennel or dismiss the petition. Written notice of an order revoking or suspending the license, regulating the kennel or dismissing the petition shall be mailed immediately to the officer issuing the license and to the holder of the license. Within 10 days after the order, the holder of the license may bring a petition in the district court within the judicial district in which the kennel is maintained, addressed to the justice of the court, praying that the order be reviewed by the court. After notice to all parties as the court may consider necessary, the court shall review the action, hear the witnesses and affirm the order unless it shall appear that it was made without proper cause or in bad faith, in which case the order shall be reversed. The decision of the court shall be final and conclusive upon the parties. A person maintaining a kennel after the license to maintain a kennel has been so revoked, or while such a license is suspended, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $250.
    </text>
</law>