<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139" level="3">Common Nuisances</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18</section_number>
    <catch_line>Removal Of Gaming Booth Near Place Of Public Gathering</catch_line>
    <order_by>18</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 22, 2011. For text effective November 22, 2011, see below.]  The aldermen or the selectmen, upon complaint made to them under oath that the complainant has reason to believe and does believe that a booth, shed or other temporary erection, situated within one mile of a muster field, cattle show ground, or other place of public gathering, is used and occupied for the sale of spirituous or fermented liquor, or for the purpose of gaming, may order the owner or occupant thereof to vacate and close the same forthwith. If the owner or occupant fails so to do, the aldermen or selectmen may forthwith abate such booth, shed or erection as a nuisance, and may pull down or otherwise destroy the same through the agency of any force, civil or military.
Chapter 139: Removal of booths used for sale of liquors or for illegal gaming from places of public gathering
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 194, Sec. 45 effective November 22, 2011. For text effective until November 22, 2011, see above.]  The aldermen or the selectmen, upon complaint made to them under oath that the complainant has reason to believe and does believe that a booth, shed or other temporary erection, situated within one mile of a muster field, cattle show ground, or other place of public gathering, is used and occupied for the sale of spirituous or fermented liquor, or for the purpose of illegal gaming, may order the owner or occupant thereof to vacate and close the same forthwith. If the owner or occupant fails so to do, the aldermen or selectmen may forthwith abate such booth, shed or erection as a nuisance, and may pull down or otherwise destroy the same through the agency of any force, civil or military.
    </text>
</law>