<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>147B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Counties;  Rules And Regulations Relating To Dogs;  Limitations</catch_line>
    <order_by>147B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 193, Sec. 20.]  Any county which by a two-thirds vote of the county commissioners and with advisory board approval accepts the provisions of this section is hereby authorized to establish rules and regulations relative to the regulation of dogs; provided, however, that such rules and regulations shall not have effect in a city or town which accepts the provisions of section one hundred and forty-seven A. Except as hereinafter provided in clauses (a), (b) and (c), and notwithstanding any contrary provision of sections one hundred and thirty-seven to one hundred and seventy-four D, inclusive, relating to the regulation of dogs, such rules and regulations may relate to, but not be limited to, dog licensing, establishing dog fees, disposition of fees, appointment of dog officers, kennel licensing and regulations, procedures for the investigation of and reimbursement for damage caused by dogs, restraining of dogs and establishing penalties for a breach hereof. No such rule or regulation shall be inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter relating to (a) the turning over or sale of animals to any business or institution licensed or registered as a research facility or animal dealer, as provided in section one hundred and fifty-one; (b) the minimum confinement period of dogs as provided in section one hundred and fifty-one A; (c) the methods of execution, as provided in said section one hundred and fifty-one A; (d) emergency care, treatment or disposal of injured dogs or cats, as provided in section one hundred and fifty-one B.
    </text>
</law>