<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147" level="3">State And Other Police, And Certain Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>60</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employee Statements; Filing; Security Check; False Statements By Licensee Or Employee; Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>60</order_by>
    <text>
        A person, firm or corporation licensed under the provisions of sections fifty-eight and fifty-nine may employ in his security systems business as many persons as he may deem necessary, but no person shall be employed by any licensee until he shall have executed and furnished to such licensee a statement under oath setting forth his full name, date of birth and residence, his parents names and places of birth, the business or occupation in which he has been engaged for the three years immediately preceding the date the statement is furnished and that he has or has not been convicted of a felony or of any offense involving moral turpitude. Such statements shall be kept on file by the licensee and furnished to the commissioner who shall have a security check performed on said employment applicant. Upon completion of the security check, the commissioner, at his or her own discretion, shall furnish to the qualified applicant a certificate of clearance which shall be valid for two years. 
If a licensee falsely states or represents that a person was or is in his employ, such false statement or representation shall be cause for revocation or suspension of his license and shall be subject to the penalties set forth in section fifty-seven. Whoever falsely states or represents that he is employed or has been employed by a licensee shall be punished by a fine of not less than fifty nor more than five hundred dollars.
    </text>
</law>