<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="2">Public Safety And Good Order</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140" level="3">Licenses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>46J</section_number>
    <catch_line>List Of Emigrant Agents; Necessity Of License; Transportation Of Applicants For Employment; Lodging And Meals; Statement To Prospective Employee</catch_line>
    <order_by>46J</order_by>
    <text>
        Each recruiting domestic agency which directly or indirectly engages or uses the services of an emigrant agent, shall furnish the commissioner a list containing the name and address of all emigrant agents from whom it accepts job applicants. If such emigrant agents are required to be licensed in the places in which they recruit employees, no employment agency, directly or indirectly, shall accept applicants from other than duly licensed emigrant agents. 
Each recruiting domestic employment agency which is responsible, directly or indirectly, for bringing into the commonwealth applicants from out of the commonwealth but within the United States and which has arranged for their transportation to the city or town in the commonwealth where the agency is licensed to conduct business shall provide that the transportation of such applicants be by duly licensed common carriers of passengers. 
Each recruiting domestic employment agency responsible for bringing into the commonwealth an applicant for employment from out of the commonwealth but within the United States shall provide at its own expense suitable lodging and meals for any such applicant who is not placed in employment the day he arrives at the office of the employment agency from the time he reports at such agency until he is placed, or is returned to the place from which he was recruited, or is given the option of returning to such place as hereinafter provided. 
Each recruiting domestic employment employment agency responsible for bringing into the commonwealth an applicant for employment from out of the commonwealth but within the United States shall provide the return fare and reasonable allowance for one day’s meals to any such applicant who was not placed in employment, or who was placed in employment and said employment terminated within thirty days thereafter and who is without employment, and desires to return to the place from which he was recruited. 
The bond required to be deposited under section forty-six F shall secure performance of the provisions of the preceding two paragraphs. No domestic recruiting employment agency shall bring into the commonwealth any applicant for employment without the commonwealth but within the United States unless and until such agency has given such applicant a written statement, on a form approved by the commissioner showing the nature and duties of the job for which the applicant is recruited, the anticipated wages, the amount of the agency fee, the amount for transportation that the applicant will have to repay if such amount has been advanced by the agency, and the amount of any other advances or charges. Such statement shall indicate when such amounts are payable to the agency. A copy of such statement shall be kept on file by the agency, and the copy shall have indicated on it the date when, and by whom, the original statement was given to the applicant.
    </text>
</law>