<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Development And Industrial Commission; Establishment; Duties;  Membership; Tenure; Removals; Vacancies</catch_line>
    <order_by>8A</order_by>
    <text>
        A city or town which accepts this section may establish a development and industrial commission for the promotion and development of the industrial resources of said city or town. Such commission shall conduct researches into industrial conditions, investigate and assist in the establishment of educational or commercial projects, including projects involving private enterprise, for the purpose of expanding or strengthening the local economy, and shall seek to co-ordinate the activities of unofficial bodies organized for said purposes, and may advertise, prepare, print and distribute books, maps, charts and pamphlets which in its judgment will further the purposes for which it is established. The commission may appoint such clerks and other employees as it may require. 
Such commission shall consist of not less than five nor more than fifteen members. The members in cities shall be appointed by the mayor, subject to the provisions of the city charter, except in cities operating under a Plan D or Plan E form of city charter, said appointments shall be by the city manager, subject to the provisions of the city charter; and in towns they shall be appointed by the selectmen, excepting towns having a manager form of government, in which towns such appointments shall be made by the town manager. When a commission is first established, the terms of the members shall be for such length, not exceeding five years, and so arranged that the terms of approximately one fifth of the members will expire each year, and their successors shall be appointed for terms of five years each. Any member of a board so appointed in a city may be removed for cause after a public hearing, if requested, by the mayor with the approval of the city council. A vacancy occurring otherwise than by expiration of term shall be filled for the unexpired term in a city in the same manner as an original appointment, and in a town as provided in section eleven of chapter forty-one.
    </text>
</law>