<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>42A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Collection Of Rates And Charges For Supplying Of Water; Lien For Delinquent Charges</catch_line>
    <order_by>42A</order_by>
    <text>
        If the rates and charges due to a city, town or water district, which accepts this section and sections forty-two B to forty-two F, inclusive, by vote of its city council or of the voters in town or district meeting and, by its clerk, files a certificate of such acceptance in the proper registry of deeds, for supplying or providing for water or rendering service or furnishing materials in connection therewith to or for any real estate at the request of the owner or tenant are not paid on or before their due date as established by local regulations, ordinances or by-laws, which due dates shall be so established as to require payments at least as often as semi-annually, such rates and charges, together with interest thereon and costs relative thereto, shall be a lien upon such real estate as provided in section forty-two B. The register of deeds shall record such certificate of acceptance in a book to be kept for the purpose, which shall be kept in an accessible location in the registry. Sections forty-two B to forty-two F, inclusive, shall also apply to a water district which has accepted sections forty-two A to forty-two F, inclusive, and whose clerk has so filed the certificate of acceptance. Wherever in said sections the words “board or officer in charge of the water department” or their equivalent appear, they shall also mean and include the officers exercising similar duties in any city, town or district. A fire district authorized to supply water shall, for the purposes of sections forty-two A to forty-two F, inclusive, be deemed to be a water district.
    </text>
</law>