<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44" level="3">Municipal Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Districts; Right To Borrow Money; Purposes; Amount</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        Districts may by a two thirds vote authorize the incurring of debt for purposes prescribed, and payable within the periods specified, by sections seven and eight, so far as they are authorized by law to make expenditures for the purposes mentioned therein, and the amounts of debt so incurred shall be limited to the amounts prescribed for towns by sections eight and ten; provided that debt of any such district incurred for any purpose mentioned in clause (3), (4), (4A), (5), (6), (7), or (7A) of section eight under any special act heretofore or hereafter enacted shall not be included in the amount of debt which is subject to the limit prescribed by said section eight for debt for such purposes. The limitation contained in the first paragraph of section seven shall be applicable to loans authorized by districts for purposes provided under section seven. 
In the fiscal year of organization of a newly established district, whether established under general or special law, the borrowing capacity for purposes specified in section seven and limited in amount by section ten, and for purposes specified in section eight, shall be based on an amount determined by applying to the equalized valuation of the town in which the district is located the same ratio which the assessors’ valuation of the taxable property of the district for that year bears to the assessors’ valuation of the taxable property of the town for the same year. In the case of a newly established district which is located in two or more towns, said borrowing capacity shall be based on the total amount determined by applying to the equalized valuation of each of the towns in which any part of the district is located the same ratio which the assessors’ valuation of the taxable property of the district in the respective towns for that year bears to the assessors’ valuation of the taxable property of said town for the same year.
    </text>
</law>