<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4K</section_number>
    <catch_line>Public Works Municipal Mutual Aid Agreement; Procedure For Joining Agreement; Advisory Committee; Requests To Receive Assistance; Rights And Responsibilities Of Requesting And Sending Parties</catch_line>
    <order_by>4K</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     There shall be a statewide public works municipal mutual aid agreement to facilitate the provision of public works resources across jurisdictional lines in the case of a public works incident that requires mutual aid assistance from 1 or more municipalities. The mutual aid assistance to be provided under the agreement shall include, but not be limited to, services related to public works, personnel, equipment, supplies and facilities to prepare for, prevent, mitigate, respond to and recover from public works incidents.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     If a governmental unit that is not a city or town wishes to join the agreement, the chief executive officer of the governmental unit may act on its behalf to join the agreement by notifying the advisory committee in writing. The governmental unit shall be a party to the agreement 30 days after receipt by the advisory committee of the written notification.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     If a governmental unit in a state contiguous to the commonwealth wishes to join the agreement, the governmental unit may join the agreement by notifying the advisory committee in writing. The governmental unit shall be a party to the agreement 30 days after receipt by the advisory committee of the written notification.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     There shall be a statewide public works municipal mutual aid advisory committee to consist of the secretary of public safety and security or his designee, who shall serve as chair of the committee; and 1 member appointed by the secretary of public safety and security from each of the following: the Massachusetts Highway Association; the New England Chapter of the American Public Works Association, who shall be a resident of the commonwealth; the New England Water Environment Association, who shall be a resident of the commonwealth; the Massachusetts Tree Wardens’ and Foresters’ Association; the Massachusetts Water Works Association; and the Massachusetts Municipal Association.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Each party shall identify not more than 3 points of contact to serve as the primary liaison for all issues relating to the agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     An oral or written request for mutual aid assistance under the agreement shall include the following information:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     a description of the public works incident response and recovery functions for which assistance is needed;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     the nature, type and amount of public works services, personnel, equipment, materials, supplies or other resources being requested;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     the manner in which the resources shall be used and deployed;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     a reasonable estimate of the length of time for which the resources shall be needed;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     the location to which the resources shall be deployed; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     the requesting party’s point of contact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A party that receives a request for mutual aid assistance shall provide and make available, to the extent reasonable and practicable under the circumstances, the resources requested by the requesting party; provided, however, that a sending party may withhold requested resources to the extent necessary to provide reasonable protection and coverage for its own jurisdiction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The requesting party shall be responsible for the overall operation, assignment and deployment of resources, equipment and personnel provided by a sending party. The sending party shall retain direct supervision, command and control of personnel, equipment and resources provided by the sending party unless otherwise agreed to by the requesting party and the sending party. During the course of rendering mutual aid assistance under the agreement, the sending party shall be responsible for the operation of its equipment and for any damage thereto unless the sending party and the requesting party agree otherwise.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A sending party shall document its costs of providing mutual aid assistance under the agreement, including direct and indirect payroll and employee benefit costs, travel costs, repair costs and the costs of materials and supplies. A sending party shall also document the use of its equipment and the quantities of materials and supplies used while providing mutual aid assistance under the agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Except as otherwise agreed to by the parties, the requesting party shall seek reimbursement under any applicable federal and state disaster assistance programs for the costs of responding to the public works incident. The requesting party and each sending party shall receive, based on the documented costs of providing mutual aid assistance, its pro rata share of the disaster assistance reimbursement provided to the requesting party.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     While providing mutual aid assistance under the agreement, employees of a sending party shall: (i) be afforded the same powers, duties, rights and privileges as they are afforded in the sending party’s geographical jurisdiction or location; (ii) be considered similarly licensed, certified or permitted in the requesting party’s jurisdiction if the employee holds a valid license, certificate or permit issued by the employee’s governmental unit; and (iii) receive the same salary, including overtime, that they would be entitled to receive if they were operating in their own governmental unit. In the absence of an agreement to the contrary, the sending party shall be responsible for all such salary expenses, including overtime.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Each party to the agreement shall waive all claims and causes of action against all other parties that may arise out of their activities while rendering or receiving mutual aid assistance under the agreement, including travel outside of its jurisdiction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Each requesting party shall defend, indemnify and hold harmless each sending party from all claims by third parties for property damage or personal injury which may arise out of the activities of the sending party or its employees, including travel, while providing mutual aid assistance under the agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     All equipment requested and deployed pursuant to the statewide municipal mutual assistance agreement shall be insured by the sending party.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     This section shall not affect, supersede or invalidate any other statutory or contractual mutual aid or assistance agreements involving parties to the agreement including, but not limited to, those established pursuant to section 4A. A party may enter into supplementary mutual aid agreements with other parties or jurisdictions.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>