<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Transfer Of Land; Procedure</catch_line>
    <order_by>15A</order_by>
    <text>
        Whenever a board or officer having charge of land, including land acquired for playground purposes pursuant to the provisions of section fourteen of chapter forty-five, but excluding land acquired for park purposes, constituting the whole or any part of an estate held by a city or town within its limits for a specific purpose shall determine that such land is no longer needed for such purpose, whether such land was acquired before or after the effective date of this section and whether acquired by eminent domain, purchase, gift, devise or otherwise, such board or officer shall forthwith give notice of such determination to the city council of the city or the board of selectmen of the town. At any time after the receipt of such notice, the city council of the city by a two thirds vote of all its members, in the case of a city having a city manager, with the approval of said city manager, and in the case of other cities, with the approval of the mayor, or the town by a two thirds vote at a regular or special town meeting, may transfer the care, custody, management and control of such land to the same or another board or officer of the city or town for another specific municipal purpose, any provision of general or special law to the contrary notwithstanding; provided, that no such transfer shall be valid if it is in violation of any term or condition of the title of the city or town to such land. 
In any city or town which accepts the provisions of this paragraph, when land is being transferred for the purpose of constructing low and moderate income housing, the vote required of the city council or the town meeting shall be by a majority vote.
    </text>
</law>