<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44" level="3">Municipal Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>53E3/4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Energy Revolving Loan Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>53E3/4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Notwithstanding section 53 to the contrary, a city or town may establish an Energy Revolving Loan Fund to provide loans to owners of privately-held real property in the city or town for energy conservation and renewable energy projects on their properties so as to prioritize energy efficiency as the first step toward reducing greenhouse gas emissions associated with buildings.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The fund shall be established by ordinance or by-law. Before adoption of the ordinance or by-law, the board of selectmen, town council or the city council, as the case may be, shall conduct a public hearing on the question of its adoption. The ordinance or by-law shall designate an administrator for the fund and may provide for rules, regulations and procedures for administration of the fund and eligibility for loans the city or town considers necessary or proper to carry out this section. The administrator may consult with the division of green communities established in section 10 of chapter 25A in developing such regulations, rules and procedures for administration of the fund. The fund administrator may be a board, department or officer, or may consist of 1 or more members from 1 or more boards, departments or officers, of the city or town. A city or town which is a member of a regional planning commission may enter into a cooperative agreement with that commission to perform as administrator for the fund. A regional governmental entity or county, if the county may incur debt under chapter 35 or any other general or special law extending a county’s debt limit, may establish a fund subject to this section and may appoint a person to be the administrator of the fund.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     As authorized by section 4A of chapter 40, 2 or more municipalities may, in a city by vote of the city council, or, in a town by vote of the board of selectmen, enter into an agreement to jointly establish and administer a common fund.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The fund administrator shall have the following powers and duties:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     to make loans to owners of real property to finance or refinance the costs of energy conservation and renewable energy projects on their properties; provided, however, that no loan shall be made unless an energy audit of the property has been conducted on or after July 2, 2008, and any energy conservation measures established by the fund administrator for participation in the program have been implemented;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     to execute and deliver on behalf of the city or town all loan agreements and other instruments necessary or proper to make the loan and secure its repayment;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     to record the notice of the agreement required by subsection (f) and any other loan instruments;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     to apply for and accept grants or gifts for purposes of the fund; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     to exercise any other powers or perform any other duties that the city or town may grant by ordinance or by-law to carry out this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The city or town treasurer shall be the custodian of the fund, which shall be maintained as a separate account and into which shall be deposited:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     all monies appropriated and all proceeds from bonds issued under clause (3C) of the first paragraph of section 7 for purpose of providing loans to private property owners for energy conservation and renewable energy projects;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     all funds received from the commonwealth or any other source for those purposes;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     all repayments of the loans made by property owners under this section and any reserve or other required payments made by the owners in connection with the loans; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     any other amounts required to be credited to the fund by any law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Whenever a city or town enters into a loan agreement with a property owner under this section, a notice of the agreement shall be recorded as a betterment and shall be subject to chapter 80 relative to the apportionment, division, reassessment and collection of assessment, abatement and collections of assessments, and to interest; provided, however, that for purposes of this section, the lien shall take effect by operation of law on the day immediately following the due date of the assessment or apportioned part of the assessment and the assessment may bear interest at a rate determined by the city or town treasurer by agreement with the owner at the time the agreement is entered into between the city or town and the property owner. In addition to remedies available under said chapter 80, the property owner shall be personally liable for the repayment of the total costs incurred by the city or town under this section; provided, however, that upon assumption of the personal obligation by a purchaser or other transferee of all of the original owner’s interest in the property at the time of conveyance and the recording of the assumption, the owner shall be relieved of the personal liability.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The fund administrator shall file annually, not later than June 30, a report detailing the amount of money in the fund, loans made and repayments received, and shall also include the types of projects financed. The report shall be filed with the chief executive officer of the city or town, the executive office of administration and finance, the joint committee on municipalities and regional government, the senate and house committees on ways and means and the clerks of the senate and the house of representatives.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>