<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40J" order_by="40J" level="3">Massachusetts Technology Park Corporation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6E</section_number>
    <catch_line>E Health Institute Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>6E</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the corporation the E-Health Institute Fund, hereinafter referred to as the fund, for the purpose of supporting the advancement of health information technology in the commonwealth, including, but not limited to, the full deployment of electronic health records. There shall be credited to the fund any appropriations, proceeds of any bonds or notes of the commonwealth issued for the purpose, or other monies authorized by the general court and designated thereto; any federal grants or loans; any private gifts, grants or donations made available; and any income derived from the investment of amounts credited to the fund. The director of the institute shall seek, to the greatest extent possible, private gifts, grants and donations to the fund. The corporation shall hold the fund in an account or accounts separate from other funds. The fund shall be administered by the executive director without further appropriation; provided, however, that any disbursement or expenditure from the fund for grants or for contracts with implementing organizations, as provided in section 6D, shall be approved by the health information technology council established under said section 6D. Amounts credited to the fund shall be available for reasonable expenditure by the corporation, subject to the approval of the health information technology council where such approval is required under this chapter, for such purposes as the corporation determines are necessary to support the dissemination and development of health information technology in the commonwealth, including, but not limited to, for the grant program established in said section 6D and for contracts with implementing organizations provided for in said section 6D.
Chapter 40J: E-Health Institute Fund
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 38 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  (a) There shall be established and set up on the books of the corporation a separate fund to be known as the e-Health Institute Fund, referred to in this section as the fund. There shall be credited to the fund revenue from appropriations or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited to the fund, including but not limited to any investment income earned on the fund's assets and all other sources. The corporation shall hold the fund in an account or accounts separate from other funds, including other funds established under this chapter. Amounts credited to the fund shall be available for reasonable expenditure by the corporation, without further appropriation, for any and all activities consistent with this section and supportive of the purposes specified in section 6D, including but not limited to, in the form of grants, contracts, loans and such other vehicles as the corporation may determine are appropriate. Amounts credited to the fund shall be expended or applied only with the approval of the executive director of the corporation upon consultation with the health information technology council established under section 2 of chapter 118I of the General Laws. Amounts credited to the fund shall not be applied to the commonwealth's match for federal funds for which a state match is required unless the federal funds to be matched are allocated to the corporation for use to further the purposes set out in this section, as reasonably determined by the executive director of the corporation; provided, however, that there are no other sources of funds available to meet federal matching requirements in order to secure such federal funds, as reasonably determined by the executive director of the corporation. Revenues deposited in the fund that are unexpended at the end of the fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund and shall be available for expenditure in the following fiscal year.[ There is no subsection (b).]
    </text>
</law>