<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41" level="3">Officers And Employees Of Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>111M</section_number>
    <catch_line>Emergency Medical Technicians; Leave Without Loss Of Pay While Incapacitated</catch_line>
    <order_by>111M</order_by>
    <text>
        In any city or town which accepts this section, an employee of a city or town or fire or water district who is responsible for delivering emergency medical services under the provisions of chapter one hundred and eleven C, and who is incapacitated for duty because of injury sustained in the performance of his duty without fault of his own shall be granted leave without loss of pay for the period of such incapacity; provided, that no such leave shall be granted for any period after such emergency medical personnel has been retired or pensioned in accordance with law or for any period after a physician designated by the board or personnel authorized to appoint emergency medical personnel in such city, town or district determines that such incapacity no longer exists. All amounts payable under this section shall be paid at the time and in the same manner as, and for all purposes shall be deemed to be, the regular compensation of such emergency medical personnel. This section shall also apply to any such employee who is subject to the provisions of chapter one hundred and fifty-two if he is injured while delivering emergency medical services and if he waives the provisions of said chapter. 
Where the injury causing the incapacity of an emergency medical personnel for which he is granted a leave without loss of pay and is paid compensation in accordance with the provisions of this section, was caused under circumstances creating legal liability in some person to pay damages in respect thereof, either the person so injured or the city, town or fire or water district paying such compensation may proceed to enforce the liability of such person in any court of competent jurisdiction. The sum recovered shall be for the benefit of the city, town or fire or water district paying such compensation, unless the sum is greater than the compensation paid to that person so injured. For the purposes of this section, “excess” shall mean the amount by which the total sum received in payment for the injury, exclusive of interest and costs, exceeds the amount paid under this section as compensation to the person so injured. The party bringing the action shall be entitled to any costs recovered by him. Any interest received in such action shall be apportioned between the city, town, or fire or water district and the person so injured in proportion to the amounts received by them respectively, inclusive of interest and costs. The expense of any attorney’s fees shall be divided between the city, town, or fire or water district and the person so injured in proportion to the amounts received by them respectively. 
Whoever intentionally or negligently injures an emergency medical personnel for which he is granted a leave without loss of pay and is paid compensation in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be liable in tort to the city, town or fire or water district paying such compensation for all costs incurred by such city, town, or fire or water district in replacing such injured emergency medical personnel which are in excess of the amount of compensation paid.
    </text>
</law>