<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40G" order_by="40G" level="3">Massachusetts Technology Development Corporation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Investment Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the proceeds of the investment will only be used to cover the seed capital needs of the enterprise except as hereinafter authorized;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the enterprise has a reasonable chance of success;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     MTDC participation is necessary to the success of the enterprise because funding for the enterprise is unavailable in the traditional capital markets, or because funding has been offered on terms that would substantially hinder the success of the enterprise;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the enterprise has the reasonable potential to create a substantial amount of primary employment within the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the entrepreneur and other founders of the enterprise have already made or are prepared to make a substantial financial and time commitment to the enterprise;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     the securities to be purchased are qualified securities;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     there is a reasonable possibility that the MTDC will recoup at least its initial investment; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     binding commitments have been made to the MTDC by the enterprise for adequate reporting of financial data to the MTDC, which shall include a requirement for an annual or other periodic audit of the books of the enterprise, and for such control on the part of the MTDC as the board shall consider prudent over the management of the enterprise, so as to protect the investment of the MTDC, including, in the discretion of the board and without limitation, right of access to financial and other records of the enterprise.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     a reasonable effort has been made to find a professional investor to make an investment in the enterprise as a co-venture, and that such effort was unsuccessful. Such findings when made by the board shall be conclusive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Not more than $1,000,000 shall be invested in the securities of any one enterprise, except that not more than a total of $2,000,000 may be invested in the securities of any one enterprise, if the board shall find, after the initial investment by the MTDC, that additional investments in such enterprise are required to protect the initial investment of the MTDC. If the additional investment does not meet all the conditions set forth in clauses (1) to (9), inclusive, in the fourth paragraph for initial investments, the additional investment may only be made if the board of directors, after considering the purposes of this chapter, makes a good faith determination that its fiduciary responsibility to protect the initial investment in an entity requires that the additional investment be made. From time to time, the board of directors may adjust these limits to reflect changes in annual inflation of the dollar.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     At least 50 per cent of all MTDC investments shall be made in enterprises that will:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     locate in, or provide substantial employment to residents of, economic target areas as defined in section 3D of chapter 23A or municipalities that satisfy the criteria for economic target areas;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     provide substantial employment opportunities to unskilled or semi-skilled individuals;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     provide substantial employment opportunities for individuals undertaking job retraining as a consequence of technological change or corporate restructuring; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     provide a service that primarily benefits residents of low and moderate income communities.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>