<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="43D" order_by="43D" level="3">Expedited Permitting</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Waiver Or Extension Of Time Period</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        The 180 day time period may be waived or extended for good cause upon written request of the applicant with the consent of the governing body or upon written request of the issuing authority with the consent of the applicant. The 180-day period may be extended for up to 30 days by the governing body in the event an additional permit or other predevelopment review is required in accordance with subsection (c) of section 5, if the requirement for the previously unidentified permit or review has been determined no less than 150 days after the issuance of the notice of completeness. The 180 day time period shall be extended when the issuing authority determines either: (1) that action by another federal, state or municipal government agency is required before the issuing authority may act; (2) that judicial proceedings affect the ability of the issuing authority or applicant to proceed with the application; or (3) that enforcement proceedings that could result in revocation of an existing permit for that facility or activity and denial of the application have been commenced. In those circumstances, the issuing authority shall provide written notification to the secretary. When the reason for the extension is no longer applicable, the issuing authority shall immediately notify the applicant, and shall complete its decision within the time period specified in this section, beginning the day after the notice is issued. An issuing authority may not use lack of time for review as a basis for denial of a permit if the applicant has provided a complete application and met all other obligations in accordance with this chapter. If the Martha’s Vineyard commission as described in chapter 831 of the acts of 1977, or the Cape Cod commission, as described in chapter 716 of the acts of 1989, require or allow referral of a permit application, the 180-day time period as described in this chapter shall be suspended upon receipt of the permit application. The 180-day time period shall recommence at the completion of the regional commission’s review; but if either commission denies a regional permit on a priority development site, section 7 shall not apply and the issuing authority, upon receipt of the denial notice, shall permanently cease the 180 day time period.
    </text>
</law>