<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41" level="3">Officers And Employees Of Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>39A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assistant Treasurer</catch_line>
    <order_by>39A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 29, 2011. For text effective November 29, 2011, see below.]  The treasurer of a city or town may in writing appoint, with the approval of the mayor or the selectmen thereof, an assistant treasurer who may be an employee in the treasurer's department. The assistant treasurer shall be sworn to the faithful performance of his duties, and a record shall be made of his appointment and oath. The assistant treasurer shall be a citizen of the United States and a resident of the commonwealth, and shall give bond annually for the faithful performance of his duties in a form approved, and in an amount determined, by the commissioner of revenue. Unless a temporary treasurer is appointed in accordance with law, the assistant treasurer may, in the absence of the treasurer, perform his duties and when performing such duties shall have the powers and be subject to the requirements and penalties applicable to him. The person appointed as assistant treasurer may receive a salary from the city or town for service as such.
Chapter 41: Assistant treasurer
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 205, Sec. 1 effective November 29, 2011. For text effective until November 29, 2011, see above.]  The treasurer of a city or town may in writing appoint, with the approval of the mayor or the selectmen thereof, an assistant treasurer who may be an employee in the treasurer's department. The assistant treasurer shall be sworn to the faithful performance of his duties, and a record shall be made of his appointment and oath. The assistant treasurer shall be a citizen of the United States and shall give bond annually for the faithful performance of his duties in a form approved, and in an amount determined, by the commissioner of revenue. Unless a temporary treasurer is appointed in accordance with law, the assistant treasurer may, in the absence of the treasurer, perform his duties and when performing such duties shall have the powers and be subject to the requirements and penalties applicable to him. The person appointed as assistant treasurer may receive a salary from the city or town for service as such.
    </text>
</law>