<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40B" order_by="40B" level="3">Regional Planning</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>30</section_number>
    <catch_line>Technical Assistance Center; Permitting Model; Evaluations And Reporting; Regional Planning Districts To Assist Municipalities</catch_line>
    <order_by>30</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be within each regional planning district created under this chapter or by special act, a technical assistance center for the delivery of coordinated, comprehensive, and continuing technical services to and among local governments for the purpose of expediting permitting.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     reduce unnecessary delays and create certainty and predictability as well as promote an efficient and timely appeals process;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     create a positive regulatory culture with a bias toward making decisions;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     conduct on-going staff training to address applicant questions;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     select sites for expedited permitting, while identifying potential issues, concerns, or problem areas;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     prepare applications for approval of the sites;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     establish clear criteria for determining the completeness of permit applications;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     update or eliminate conflicting, cumbersome, and redundant permit processes and procedures;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     examine and redraft zoning by-laws to aid in the balanced development of the community; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     develop plans and incentives for residential and commercial development, while taking steps to mitigate the environmental and transportation impacts of new growth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A city or town shall not be required to receive technical assistance from a regional planning agency in order to participate in the expedited permitting process, pursuant to chapter 43D.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>