<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41" level="3">Officers And Employees Of Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>81EE</section_number>
    <catch_line>Recordation; Evidence That Subdivision Control Law Is In Effect;  Suspension</catch_line>
    <order_by>81EE</order_by>
    <text>
        Every board having on the first day of January, nineteen hundred and fifty-four, powers of subdivision control shall, within sixty days thereafter transmit to the register of deeds and the recorder of the land court a statement stating that in the opinion of such board the subdivision control law is in effect in such city or town, including a copy certified by the clerk of such city or town of the vote of the city council or of the town meeting under which the subdivision control law in the opinion of such board went into effect, together with the date thereof, or a reference to any special statute under which subdivision control was established, in such city or town. The register of deeds and the recorder of the land court shall enter such statement in the book which he is required to keep under section eighty-one X. Unless such statement is transmitted as herein provided within sixty days after said date, or the clerk of such city or town has previously notified the register of deeds and recorder of the land court of the establishment of a planning board under the provisions of law in effect prior to said date, and included in his notice a statement of the date of such establishment, the operation of the subdivision control law in and in respect to such city or town shall be suspended until the clerk of such city or town has notified the register of deeds and recorder of the land court that the subdivision control law is in effect in his city or town in the manner provided in section eighty-one N. The register of deeds and the recorder of the land court shall each enter such notice in his records in the manner provided in section eighty-one X. Any planning board having powers of subdivision control on the first day of January, nineteen hundred and fifty-four, shall, within sixty days thereafter, transmit to the register of deeds and recorder of the land court a certified copy of its rules and regulations relating to subdivision control, which shall be kept by him in the same manner as copies of rules and regulations thereafter adopted, and unless such copy is so transmitted, the operation of the subdivision control law in and with respect to such city or town shall be suspended until the board so transmits such copy.
    </text>
</law>