<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41" level="3">Officers And Employees Of Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>99D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Town Elections For Acceptance; Ballots</catch_line>
    <order_by>99D</order_by>
    <text>
        In towns using official ballots at town elections, acceptance of the provisions of the regional police district law shall be by vote in answer to the following questions to be placed on the official ballot at an annual town election as hereinafter provided, and in towns not using official ballots at town elections such acceptance shall be by vote at an annual town meeting. Upon the filing, with the clerk of any town using official ballots at town elections, of a petition signed by the board of selectmen requesting that the question of accepting the provisions of the regional police district law be placed upon the official ballot, the clerk shall place such questions on the official ballot for the next town election occurring more than thirty days after the filing of such petition. The questions to be voted on shall be:— 
A. Shall the town accept the provisions of sections ninetynine B to ninety-nine K, inclusive, of chapter forty-one of the General Laws, providing for the establishment of a regional police district, together with the town (towns) of? 
B. Shall the police department provided for in question A be under the control and supervision of the regional police district commission and otherwise be governed by section ninety-seven of chapter forty-one of the General Laws governing local police department? 
C. Shall the police department provided for in question A be under the sole control and supervision of the chief of police appointed by the regional police district commission and otherwise be governed by section ninety-seven A of chapter forty-one of the General Laws governing local police departments? 
If a majority of the voters in each town voting on question A is in the affirmative, the proposed regional police district shall be deemed to be established. 
If a majority of all the votes cast in the affirmative in the towns voting on question B is greater than the majority voting in the affirmative on question C, then the police department so established will be governed by section ninety-seven of said chapter forty-one; however, if a majority of all the votes cast in the affirmative in the towns voting on question C is greater than the majority voting in the affirmative on question B, the police department so established will be governed by the provisions of section ninety-seven A of said chapter forty-one.
    </text>
</law>