<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41" level="3">Officers And Employees Of Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>69D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Public Works; Membership; Election; Tenure; Powers And Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>69D</order_by>
    <text>
        Any town which has accepted the provisions of sections sixty-nine C to sixty-nine F, inclusive, shall elect in the following manner a board of public works, hereinafter called the board, to consist of three members. The initial members thereof shall be elected, one to serve for one year, one for two years, and one for three years, from the date of the annual meeting at which they are elected, and thereafter when the term of any member expires, his successor shall be elected to serve for three years. In all cases the members shall serve until their successors are elected and qualified. The members of the board shall, after each election, elect one of their members to act as chairman for the ensuing year. 
Upon the election and qualification of the members of the board, the board shall have all the powers and duties now or from time to time vested by general law or special act in the following boards, departments and offices, or in boards, departments and offices having corresponding powers and duties in said town, to wit:—road commissioners, surveyors of highways, superintendent of streets, water commissioners, sewer commissioners, municipal light board or commissioners, park commissioners, cemetery commissioners, tree warden, moth superintendent and forestry department, and such boards, departments and offices shall thereupon be abolished. No contracts or liabilities then in force shall be affected by such abolition, but the board of public works shall in all respects be the lawful successor of the boards, departments and offices so abolished. 
The board shall have such additional powers with respect to the furnishing of engineering services, the collection and disposal of garbage and refuse, the maintenance and repair of town buildings and property, and the performance of such duties of any other boards, departments and offices of the town as may be reasonably related to the duties and responsibilities of a board of public works, as the town may, from time to time, by by-law provide, any other provisions of law to the contrary notwithstanding.
    </text>
</law>