<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40W" order_by="40W" level="3">Massachusetts Growth Capital Corporation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Criteria For Participation In Certain Projects</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The corporation may participate in a project; provided that, the corporation shall find and incorporate in the official records of the corporation that the project will be of a public benefit such that the project is reasonably expected to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     support or promote economic development, revitalization or stability;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     promote employment opportunities for residents of the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     promote the creation or retention of jobs; or,
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     support the creation or expansion of a business sector whose success would enhance the economic development of the commonwealth, enhance the quality of life of residents of the commonwealth or enhance the employment opportunities for residents of the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The corporation shall not participate in a project unless it determines, in writing, that its participation is necessary because funding for the project is not available in the traditional capital markets or that credit has been offered on terms that would preclude the success of the project.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The corporation shall endeavor to participate in projects each year that provide financial products, which in the aggregate total not less than 30 percent of the total capital committed by the corporation over a 3 year period, to projects which enhance the economic development of a target area, as defined in section 2 of chapter 40H, or enhance the quality of life and promote employment opportunities for low and moderate income residents of the commonwealth. If a certified CDC requests that the corporation participate in a project, the corporation shall make a determination of whether the project: (i) is likely to provide employment opportunities to low and moderate income residents of the commonwealth; (ii) is likely to enhance the quality of life of low and moderate income residents of the commonwealth; or (iii) supports the creation or expansion of the business sector in the region served by the CDC. If the corporation enters into an agreement to participate in such a project, the terms of the financial products made available shall favorably reflect the economic and social benefits which inures to the commonwealth from the project.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Each contract shall include a requirement for adequate reporting of financial and other data to the corporation. The contract shall require that a business receiving financial products shall participate in financial and managerial consulting services and the contract shall include a requirement for an annual or other periodic audit of the project books.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>