<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44" level="3">Municipal Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Construction Contracts; Certificate As To Availability Of Funds;  Effect Of Certificate Upon Defense Of Insufficiency Of Appropriations</catch_line>
    <order_by>31C</order_by>
    <text>
        No contract for the construction, reconstruction, alteration, remodeling, repair or demolition of any public building or public work by any city or town costing more than two thousand dollars shall be deemed to have been made until the auditor or accountant or other officer of the city or town having similar duties has certified thereon that an appropriation in the amount of such contract is available therefor and that an officer or agent of the city, town or awarding authority has been authorized to execute said contract and approve all requisitions and change orders. No order to the contractor for a change in or addition to the work to be performed under a contract subject to this section, whether in the form of a drawing, plan, detail or any other written instruction, unless it is an order which the contractor is willing to perform without any increase in the contract price, shall be deemed to have been given until the auditor or accountant, or other officer of the city or town having similar duties, has certified thereon that an appropriation in the amount of such order is available therefor; but such certificate shall not be construed as an admission by the city or town of its liability to pay for such work. The certificate of the auditor or accountant or other officer of the city or town having similar duties, that an appropriation in the amount of such contract or order is available shall bar any defense by the city or town on the grounds of insufficient appropriation; and any law barring payment in excess of appropriations shall not apply to amounts covered by any certificate under this section.
    </text>
</law>