<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40" level="3">Powers And Duties Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Youth Commission; Establishment; Powers And Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>8E</order_by>
    <text>
        A city or town which accepts this section may establish a youth commission, hereinafter called the commission, for the purpose of carrying out programs which may be designed or established to meet the opportunities, challenges and problems of youth of said city or town and in conjunction with any similar or related programs of any agency of the commonwealth or any agency of the federal government. It shall keep accurate records of its meetings and actions and shall file an annual report which shall be printed in the case of towns in the annual town report. The commission may appoint such clerks and other employees as it may from time to time require. The commission shall consist of not less than three nor more than twenty-one members. In cities the members shall be appointed by the mayor, subject to the provisions of the city charter, except that in cities having or operating under a plan D or plan E form of city charter, said appointments shall be by the city manager, subject to the provisions of the charter; and in towns they shall be appointed by the selectmen, excepting towns having a manager form of government, in which towns appointments shall be made by the town manager, subject to the approval of the selectmen. When a commission is first established, the terms of the members shall be for one, two or three years and so arranged that the terms of approximately one third of the members will expire each year, and their successors shall be appointed for a term of three years each. Any member of a commission so appointed may, after a public hearing, if requested, be removed for cause by the appointing authority. A vacancy occurring otherwise than by expiration of a term shall in a city or town be filled for the unexpired term in the same manner as an original appointment. Said commission may receive gifts of property, both real and personal, in the name of the city or town, subject to the approval of the city council in a city or the selectmen in a town, such gifts to be managed and controlled by the commission for the purposes of this section.
    </text>
</law>