<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40D" order_by="40D" level="3">Industrial Development Of Cities And Towns</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of Bonds; Conditions</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The governing body of the municipality or in case of a consolidated authority the governing bodies of the constituent municipalities shall by vote approve the project (which shall be described in general terms), the estimated cost thereof and the financing thereof by bonds to be issued pursuant to this chapter. In any city a vote required under this section shall be deemed an emergency matter and may be passed in such manner as is provided for emergency orders or ordinances in its charter, and shall be in full force and effect immediately upon final favorable action thereon by its city council or the mayor, as the case may be, or upon the expiration of any period specified by such charter for the approval or disapproval of such orders if no action is taken to approve or disapprove such an order within such period, notwithstanding any provision of general or special law or ordinance to the contrary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The board of directors of the Massachusetts Industrial Finance Agency, hereinafter called the MIFA board, shall have approved the bonds to be issued under this chapter. To obtain such approval, an authority shall first submit to the MIFA board an application therefor in such form and containing such information, data and exhibits as may from time to time be prescribed by the MIFA board, to which application shall be appended as part thereof, in substantially the form proposed to be executed, copies of the trust indenture or agreement, including the form of bonds, securing the bonds which are the subject of the petition, the resolution of the authority authorizing the issuance of the bonds in question and the financing document.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     the user is a responsible party;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     the provisions of the financing document are reasonable and proper, and in making such determination the MIFA board may take into account such factors as it deems relevant including, without limitation, the remedies of the municipality upon default of the user;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     in the case of the lease or sale of a project by the municipality to a user, the provisions of the lease or installment sale agreement relative to the rights of the municipality and the lessee or purchaser, as the case may be respecting the disposition of the project upon payment in full with interest of all the bonds are in the public interest;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     the trust agreement protects the public interest affected by its provisions;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     the project will provide employment, or security against loss of employment, having a reasonable relationship to the principal amount of the bonds to be issued therefor, taking into account, among other things, the investment per employee of comparable industrial facilities;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     adequate provision is being or will be made to meet any increased demand upon community public facilities that might result from the project;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     the size and scope of the project is such that a definite benefit to the economy of the commonwealth may reasonably be expected to result from the construction or improvement thereof;
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     the bonds, the trust agreement and the financing document comply with the provisions of this chapter;
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     in cases where the project consists of or includes the acquisition, equipping or improvement of existing facilities and such acquisition, equipping or improvement is not incidental to the construction and equipping of entirely new facilities, the completed project will be of suitable type and scope for its intended purpose;
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     the payments under the financing document are adequate to pay the current expenses of the authority in connection with the project and the principal of the bonds as they come due and interest thereon;
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     the project has, so far as feasible, been located in a low income area of a municipality so that employment opportunities will become available to residents of such area, and, in the case of a project including a commercial enterprise or incidental thereto for use by a governmental or nonprofit entity, the project is located in a predominantly commercial area for which a commercial area revitalization plan has been adopted by the governing body of the municipality and approved by the director of housing and community development and the project is consistent with the plan. The purposes of a commercial area revitalization plan shall be to prevent or arrest and reverse the decay of the area covered by the plan. The plan shall describe the area and set forth the development or redevelopment, including public improvements, proposed to carry out the purposes of the plan. Nothing herein shall preclude the undertaking of such development or redevelopment through urban renewal or an economic development and industrial corporation or by other means, subject to the laws applicable thereto. In exercising the power of approval granted by this clause, said director shall, among other lawful and relevant considerations, seek to avoid and correct the deterioration of older commercial centers which result from the movement of commercial enterprise to previously noncommercial areas;
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     the sponsor of the project does not do business in the Union of South Africa absent compliance with the platform of guiding principles as defined in subdivision (5) of section twenty-three of chapter thirty-two.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The bonds, the financing document, the trust agreement and the bond issue resolution, as executed or adopted as the case may be, are substantially in the form submitted to the finance board.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>