<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="40B" order_by="40B" level="3">Regional Planning</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Executive Committees; Establishment; Membership; Powers And Duties;  Reports</catch_line>
    <order_by>4A</order_by>
    <text>
        Upon a two-thirds vote of all of the members of the district planning commission there may be established an executive committee, elected annually from the membership of the commission, and consisting of the chairman, vice chairman, if one is elected annually by the commission, the clerk, the assistant clerk, if one is elected annually, the treasurer and at least one but no more than seven members elected at large from the commission membership annually, so that there shall be an uneven number of members of said committee. Actions taken by said executive committee shall be in the name of and on behalf of the commission. Such actions may include one or more of the following listed functions, but only if authorized by a two-thirds vote of the commission’s total membership:—employment of technical staff members, and other professional and clerical assistants; retention of consultants; the disbursement of commission funds based upon a warrant approved by a majority of the executive committee; the borrowing of funds in anticipation of receipt of revenue; applications for federal, state and local aid; the preparation of reviews and comments on proposals of a regional or intercommunity nature, including those referred to the district planning commission under the provisions of Said executive committee shall report its actions to the full commission at least quarterly, and its authority to exercise such functions heretofore authorized shall be reconfirmed by a two-thirds vote of all of the members annually. Additional functions may be authorized for the executive committee from time to time. Such additions shall also be by a two-thirds vote of the district planning commission membership. The authority given to the executive committee to act on behalf of the commission may be terminated for any function by a majority vote of the commission members and thirty days’ notice to said executive committee.
    </text>
</law>