<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="43D" order_by="43D" level="3">Expedited Permitting</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
          As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:--  "Governing body'', in a city having a Plan D or Plan E charter the city manager and the city council and in any other city the mayor and city council, and in towns the board of selectmen.  "Interagency permitting board'', the board, as described in section 62 of chapter 23A, established to review and approve or deny municipal priority development site proposals and to grant and administer technical assistance grants.  "Issuing authority'', a local board, commission, department or other municipal entity that is responsible for issuing permits, granting approvals or otherwise involved in land use development including redevelopment of existing buildings and structures.  "Permit'', a permit formal determination, order of conditions, license, certificate, authorization, registration, plan approval, zoning relief or other approval or determination with respect to the use or development of land, buildings, or structures required by any issuing authority including but not limited to those under statutory authorities contained in chapter 40A, sections 81A to 81J, inclusive, and sections 81X to 81GG, inclusive, of chapter 41, sections 40 and 40A of chapter 131, sections 26 to 32, inclusive, of chapter 111, chapter 40C, sections 13 and 14 of chapter 148, chapter 772 of the acts of 1975, or otherwise under state law or local by-law or ordinance, and all associated regulations, by-laws and rules, but not including building permits or approvals pursuant to sections 81O to 81W, inclusive, of chapter 41. "Permit'' shall not include the decision of an agency to dispose of property under its management or control; predevelopment reviews conducted by the municipal office of permit coordination or a technical review team; or permits granted by the Massachusetts Water Resources Authority.[ Definition of "Priority development site'' effective until August 7, 2012. For text effective August 7, 2012, see below.]  "Priority development site'', a privately or publicly owned property that is: (1) commercially or industrially zoned; (2) eligible under applicable zoning provisions, including special permits or other discretionary permits, for the development or redevelopment of a building at least 50,000 square feet of gross floor area in new or existing buildings or structures; and (3) designated as a priority development site by the board. Several parcels or projects may be included within a single priority development site. Wherever possible, priority development sites should be located adjacent to areas of existing development or in under utilized buildings or facilities, or close to appropriate transit services.[ Definition of "Priority development site'' as amended by 2012, 238, Sec. 25 effective August 7, 2012. For text effective until August 7, 2012, see above.]  "Priority development site'', a privately or publicly owned property that is: (1) eligible under applicable zoning provisions, including special permits or other discretionary permits, for the development or redevelopment of a building at least 50,000 square feet of gross floor area in new or existing buildings or structures; and (2) designated as an appropriate priority development site by the board. Several parcels or projects may be included within a single priority development site. Wherever possible, priority development sites should be located adjacent to areas of existing development or in underutilized buildings or facilities or close to appropriate transit services.  "Secretary'', the secretary of the executive office of economic development.  "Technical review team'', an informal working group consisting of representatives of the various issuing authorities designed by the head of their issuing authority to review requests submitted under this chapter. The technical review team shall not include members of the zoning board of appeals.
    </text>
</law>