<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="2">Cities, Towns And Districts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44" level="3">Municipal Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>54</section_number>
    <catch_line>Investment Of Trust Funds</catch_line>
    <order_by>54</order_by>
    <text>
        Trust funds, including cemetery perpetual care funds, unless otherwise provided or directed by the donor thereof, shall be placed at interest in savings banks, trust companies incorporated under the laws of the commonwealth, banking companies incorporated under the laws of the commonwealth which are members of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or national banks, or invested by cities or towns in participation units in a combined investment fund under section thirty-eight A of chapter twenty-nine, or in paid-up shares and accounts of and in co-operative banks, or in shares of savings and loan associations or in shares or savings deposits of federal savings and loan associations doing business in the commonwealth to an amount not exceeding one hundred thousand dollars, or in bonds or notes which are legal investments for savings banks. Cities and towns having such funds in the custody of the treasurer in an aggregate amount in excess of two hundred and fifty thousand dollars may also invest such funds in securities, other than mortgages or collateral loans, which are legal for the investment of funds of savings banks under the laws of the commonwealth; provided, that not more than fifteen per cent of any such trust funds shall be invested in bank stocks and insurance company stocks, nor shall more than one and one-half per cent of such funds be invested in the stock of any one bank or insurance company. This section shall not apply to the city of Boston.
    </text>
</law>