<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="209C" order_by="209C" level="3">Children Born Out Of Wedlock</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Award Of Custody; Criteria</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Upon or after an adjudication or voluntary acknowledgment of paternity, the court may award custody to the mother or the father or to them jointly or to another suitable person as hereafter further specified as may be appropriate in the best interests of the child.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Prior to or in the absence of an adjudication or voluntary acknowledgment of paternity, the mother shall have custody of a child born out of wedlock. In the absence of an order or judgment of a probate and family court relative to custody, the mother shall continue to have custody of a child after an adjudication of paternity or voluntary acknowledgment of parentage.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     If either parent is dead, unfit or unavailable or relinquishes care of the child or abandons the child and the other parent is fit to have custody, that parent shall be entitled to custody.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     If a person who is not a parent of the child requests custody, the court may order custody to that person if it is in the best interests of the child and if the written consent of both parents or the surviving parent is filed with the court. Such custody may also be ordered if it is in the best interests of the child and if both parents or the surviving parent are unfit to have custody or if one is unfit and the other files his written consent in court.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     In issuing any temporary or permanent custody order, the probate and family court shall consider evidence of past or present abuse toward a parent or child as a factor contrary to the best interest of the child. For the purposes of this section, “abuse” shall mean the occurrence of one or more of the following acts between a parent and the other parent or between a parent and child: (a) attempting to cause or causing bodily injury; or (b) placing another in reasonable fear of imminent bodily injury. “Serious incident of abuse” shall mean the occurrence of one or more of the following acts between a parent and the other parent or between a parent and child: (a) attempting to cause or causing serious bodily injury; (b) placing another in reasonable fear of imminent serious bodily injury; or (c) causing another to engage involuntarily in sexual relations by force, threat or duress. For purposes of this section, “bodily injury” and “serious bodily injury” shall have the same meanings as provided in section 13K of chapter 265.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     ordering an exchange of the child to occur in a protected setting or in the presence of an appropriate third party;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     ordering visitation supervised by an appropriate third party, visitation center or agency;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     ordering the abusive parent to attend and complete, to the satisfaction of the court, a certified batterer’s treatment program as a condition of visitation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     ordering the abusive parent to abstain from possession or consumption of alcohol or controlled substances during the visitation and for 24 hours preceding visitation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     ordering the abusive parent to pay the costs of supervised visitation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     prohibiting overnight visitation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     requiring a bond from the abusive parent for the return and safety of the child;
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     ordering an investigation or appointment of a guardian ad litem or attorney for the child; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     imposing any other condition that is deemed necessary to provide for the safety and well-being of the child and the safety of the abused parent.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>