<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="209A" order_by="209A" level="3">Abuse Prevention</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Remedies; Period Of Relief</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     ordering the defendant to refrain from abusing the plaintiff, whether the defendant is an adult or minor;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     ordering the defendant to refrain from contacting the plaintiff, unless authorized by the court, whether the defendant is an adult or minor;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     ordering the defendant to vacate forthwith and remain away from the household, multiple family dwelling, and workplace. Notwithstanding the provisions of section thirty-four B of chapter two hundred and eight, an order to vacate shall be for a fixed period of time, not to exceed one year, at the expiration of which time the court may extend any such order upon motion of the plaintiff, with notice to the defendant, for such additional time as it deems necessary to protect the plaintiff from abuse;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     awarding the plaintiff temporary custody of a minor child; provided, however, that in any case brought in the probate and family court a finding by such court by a preponderance of the evidence that a pattern or serious incident of abuse, as defined in section 31A of chapter 208, toward a parent or child has occurred shall create a rebuttable presumption that it is not in the best interests of the child to be placed in sole custody, shared legal custody or shared physical custody with the abusive parent. Such presumption may be rebutted by a preponderance of the evidence that such custody award is in the best interests of the child. For the purposes of this section, an “abusive parent” shall mean a parent who has committed a pattern of abuse or a serious incident of abuse;
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     ordering an exchange of the child to occur in a protected setting or in the presence of an appropriate third party;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     ordering visitation supervised by an appropriate third party, visitation center or agency;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     ordering the abusive parent to attend and complete, to the satisfaction of the court, a certified batterer’s treatment program as a condition of visitation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     ordering the abusive parent to abstain from possession or consumption of alcohol or controlled substances during the visitation and for 24 hours preceding visitation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     ordering the abusive parent to pay the costs of supervised visitation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     prohibiting overnight visitation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     requiring a bond from the abusive parent for the return and safety of the child;
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     ordering an investigation or appointment of a guardian ad litem or attorney for the child; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     imposing any other condition that is deemed necessary to provide for the safety and well-being of the child and the safety of the abused parent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     ordering the defendant to pay temporary support for the plaintiff or any child in the plaintiff’s custody or both, when the defendant has a legal obligation to support such a person. In determining the amount to be paid, the court shall apply the standards established in the child support guidelines. Each judgment or order of support which is issued, reviewed or modified pursuant to this chapter shall conform to and shall be enforced in accordance with the provisions of section 12 of chapter 119A;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     ordering the defendant to pay the person abused monetary compensation for the losses suffered as a direct result of such abuse. Compensatory losses shall include, but not be limited to, loss of earnings or support, costs for restoring utilities, out-of-pocket losses for injuries sustained, replacement costs for locks or personal property removed or destroyed, medical and moving expenses and reasonable attorney’s fees;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     ordering information in the case record to be impounded in accordance with court rule;
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     ordering the defendant to refrain from abusing or contacting the plaintiff’s child, or child in plaintiff’s care or custody, unless authorized by the court;
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     the judge may recommend to the defendant that the defendant attend a batterer’s intervention program that is certified by the department of public health.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>