<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="209A" order_by="209A" level="3">Abuse Prevention</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Powers Of Police</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     remain on the scene of where said abuse occurred or was in danger of occurring as long as the officer has reason to believe that at least one of the parties involved would be in immediate physical danger without the presence of a law officer. This shall include, but not be limited to remaining in the dwelling for a reasonable period of time;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     assist the abused person in obtaining medical treatment necessitated by an assault, which may include driving the victim to the emergency room of the nearest hospital, or arranging for appropriate transportation to a health care facility, notwithstanding any law to the contrary;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     assist the abused person in locating and getting to a safe place; including but not limited to a designated meeting place for a shelter or a family member’s or friend’s residence. The officer shall consider the victim’s preference in this regard and what is reasonable under all the circumstances;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     give such person immediate and adequate notice of his or her rights. Such notice shall consist of handing said person a copy of the statement which follows below and reading the same to said person. Where said person’s native language is not English, the statement shall be then provided in said person’s native language whenever possible.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     assist such person by activating the emergency judicial system when the court is closed for business;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     inform the victim that the abuser will be eligible for bail and may be promptly released; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     arrest any person a law officer witnesses or has probable cause to believe has violated a temporary or permanent vacate, restraining, or no-contact order or judgment issued pursuant to section eighteen, thirty-four B or thirty-four C of chapter two hundred and eight, section thirty-two of chapter two hundred and nine, section three, three B, three C, four or five of this chapter, or sections fifteen or twenty of chapter two hundred and nine C or similar protection order issued by another jurisdiction. When there are no vacate, restraining, or no-contact orders or judgments in effect, arrest shall be the preferred response whenever an officer witnesses or has probable cause to believe that a person:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     has committed a felony;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     has committed a misdemeanor involving abuse as defined in section one of this chapter;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     has committed an assault and battery in violation of section thirteen A of chapter two hundred and sixty-five.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>