<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="209B" order_by="209B" level="3">Massachusetts Child Custody Jurisdiction Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Jurisdiction; Determination Of Appropriate Forum; Factors</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A court which has jurisdiction pursuant to section two may decline to exercise its jurisdiction at any time prior to making a custody determination upon finding that its assumption of jurisdiction would be (i) violative of the purposes of this chapter; or (ii) would be based upon the illegal or otherwise wrongful conduct of a party; or (iii) would constitute an inconvenient forum and that a court of another state would constitute a more convenient forum.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A court may decline jurisdiction for any of the reasons set forth in paragraph (a) upon motion of a party or of any representative of the child entitled to appear before the court or upon the court’s own motion.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In order to determine whether it is the appropriate forum, a court of the commonwealth may, in its discretion, at any time during the pendency of the custody proceeding, communicate and exchange information with a court or courts of any other relevant jurisdiction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     For the purposes of this section, a court may consider the following factors:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     whether another state is or recently was the child’s home state;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     whether another state has a closer connection with the child and his family or with the child and one or more of the contestants;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     whether more substantial evidence concerning the child’s present or future care, protection, training, and personal relationships is available or whether such evidence is more readily available in another state;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     whether the parties have agreed on another forum which is not less appropriate; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     whether the exercise of jurisdiction by a court of the commonwealth would contravene any of the purposes of this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     If a court shall find that a court of another jurisdiction is or may be a more appropriate forum under the terms of this chapter for the adjudication of the custody proceeding, it may do one or more of the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     dismiss the proceeding with or without prejudice;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     vacate any order or judgment already entered;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     stay the proceeding upon condition that a custody proceeding be initiated or prosecuted in another state in a timely manner or upon any other condition that the court might deem just;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     retain jurisdiction over any action to which the custody proceeding is incident, while declining to render a custody determination;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     enter such temporary order or orders as may be required, in the court’s discretion, pursuant to clause (ii) of paragraph (3) of section two;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     assess any or all of the costs of the custody proceeding in this state, having due regard for the purposes of this chapter, including the reasonable travel and other expenses of any party and his or her witnesses, the reasonable attorneys’ fees of any party, the costs of the court’s communications and information exchanges with other courts and the fees and costs of any person entitled to appear before the court as the representative of a child;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     assess sanctions against any party whom the court finds has engaged in illegal or otherwise wrongful conduct;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     enter any other order or judgment which may be meet and just under the circumstances of the case.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A court shall communicate to the court of any other relevant jurisdiction any determination or finding made pursuant to this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>