<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210" level="3">Adoption Of Children And Change Of Names</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Agreement For Post Adoption Contact Or Communication</catch_line>
    <order_by>6C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Prior to the entry of an adoption decree, prospective adoptive parents and a birth parent may enter into an agreement for post-adoption contact or communication between or among a minor to be adopted, the prospective adoptive parents and the birth parents. Such agreement may be approved by the court issuing the termination decree under section 3; provided, however, that an agreement under this section shall be finally approved by the court issuing the adoption decree. Any breach, modification or invalidation of the agreement, or any part of it, shall not affect the validity of the adoption. The adoption shall be final.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The court shall approve an agreement for post-adoption contact or communication if the court finds that such agreement:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     is in the best interests of the child;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     contains terms that are fair and reasonable; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     has been entered knowingly and voluntarily by all parties to the agreement. This requirement may be satisfied by an affidavit executed by all parties, either jointly or separately, that is filed with the court. The affidavit shall state that the agreement is entered into knowingly and voluntarily and is not the product of coercion or duress. The court may hear testimony from the parties to the agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     To be approved by the court, an agreement for post-adoption contact or communication shall contain the following statements:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     This agreement is entered into pursuant to the provisions of section 6C of chapter 210 of the General Laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     Any breach, modification or invalidation of the agreement or any part of it shall not affect the validity of the adoption. The adoption shall be final.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     The parties acknowledge that either the birth or adoptive parents who have entered into the agreement have the right to seek enforcement as set forth in section 6D of chapter 210 of the General Laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     The parties have not relied on any representations other than those contained in this agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     To be enforceable, an agreement for post-adoption contact or communication shall be: (i) in writing; (ii) approved by the court prior to the date for entry of the adoption decree; and (iii) incorporated but not merged into the adoption decree, and shall survive as an independent contract.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     An agreement under this section need not disclose the identity of the parties to be enforceable; but if an identity is not disclosed, the unidentified person shall designate an agent for the purpose of service of process.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     An agreement for post-adoption contact or communication shall cease to be enforceable on the date the adopted person turns 18 years of age.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>