<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="276" order_by="276" level="3">Search Warrants, Rewards, Fugitives From Justice, Arrest, Examination, Commitment And Bail. Probation Officers And Board Of Probation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>98A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Board To Commissioner Of Probation And Chief Justice For Administration And Management</catch_line>
    <order_by>98A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 93, Sec. 98A effective July 1, 2011 until the appointment of a court administrator. See 2011, 93, Secs. 133 and 138. For text effective upon the appointment of a court administrator, see below.]  There shall be a board to advise the commissioner of probation and the chief justice for administration and management. The board shall make recommendations on the management of the office of probation. The board shall consist of 9 members to be appointed by the supreme judicial court: 2 persons who have significant experience in criminal justice, 2 persons who have significant experience in public policy, 2 persons who have significant experience in management, 1 person who has significant experience in human resources management, 1 person who is a member of the Massachusetts bar with active status and 1 person with significant experience as a probation officer. Upon the expiration of the term of any appointive member, the member's successor shall be appointed in a like manner for a term of 3 years. In making their initial appointments, the supreme judicial court shall appoint 2 members to serve for a term of 1 year, 4 members to serve for a term of 2 years and 3 members to serve for a term of 3 years.  A person appointed to fill a vacancy on the board shall be appointed in like manner and shall serve for only the unexpired term of the former member. No member shall serve for more than 2 full terms. The board shall annually elect 1 of its members to serve as chair and 1 of its members to serve as vice-chair. The chair shall hold regular meetings and shall notify the board members of the time and place of the meetings.  Members of the board shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for their expenses actually and necessarily incurred in the discharge of their official duties. The chief justice for administration and management shall serve as the executive secretary of the board and the office of probation shall provide, at the request of the board, detailed reports regarding the work of probation in the court.  The board shall advise the commissioner of probation and the chief justice for administration and management on all matters of probation reform. The board shall make recommendations to the commissioner of probation and the chief justice for administration and management and shall forward such recommendations to the house and senate committees on ways and means.
Chapter 276: Advisory board to commissioner of probation and court administrator
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 124B effective upon the appointment of a court administrator. See 2011, 93, Sec. 132. For text effective until the appointment of a court administrator, see above.]  There shall be a board to advise the commissioner of probation and the court administrator. The board shall make recommendations on the management of the office of probation. The board shall consist of 9 members to be appointed by the supreme judicial court: 2 persons who have significant experience in criminal justice, 2 persons who have significant experience in public policy, 2 persons who have significant experience in management, 1 person who has significant experience in human resources management, 1 person who is a member of the Massachusetts bar with active status and 1 person with significant experience as a probation officer. Upon the expiration of the term of any appointive member, the member's successor shall be appointed in a like manner for a term of 3 years. In making their initial appointments, the supreme judicial court shall appoint 2 members to serve for a term of 1 year, 4 members to serve for a term of 2 years and 3 members to serve for a term of 3 years.  A person appointed to fill a vacancy on the board shall be appointed in like manner and shall serve for only the unexpired term of the former member. No member shall serve for more than 2 full terms. The board shall annually elect 1 of its members to serve as chair and 1 of its members to serve as vice-chair. The chair shall hold regular meetings and shall notify the board members of the time and place of the meetings.  Members of the board shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for their expenses actually and necessarily incurred in the discharge of their official duties. The court administrator shall serve as the executive secretary of the board and the office of probation shall provide, at the request of the board, detailed reports regarding the work of probation in the court.  The board shall advise the commissioner of probation and the court administrator on all matters of probation reform. The board shall make recommendations to the commissioner of probation and the court administrator and shall forward such recommendations to the house and senate committees on ways and means.
    </text>
</law>