<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="276" order_by="276" level="3">Search Warrants, Rewards, Fugitives From Justice, Arrest, Examination, Commitment And Bail. Probation Officers And Board Of Probation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>28</section_number>
    <catch_line>Arrest Without Warrant</catch_line>
    <order_by>28</order_by>
    <text>
        Any officer authorized to serve criminal process may arrest, without a warrant, and detain a person found in the act of stealing property in the presence of the officer regardless of the value of the property stolen and may arrest, without a warrant, and detain a person whom the officer has probable cause to believe has committed a misdemeanor by violating a temporary or permanent vacate, restraining, suspension and surrender,, or no-contact order or judgment issued pursuant to section eighteen, thirty-four B or thirty-four C of chapter two hundred and eight, section three, three B, three C, four or five of chapter two hundred and nine A, section thirty-two of chapter two hundred and nine, or section fifteen or twenty of chapter two hundred and nine C. Said officer may arrest, without a warrant, and detain a person whom the officer has probable cause to believe has committed a misdemeanor involving abuse as defined in section one of chapter two hundred and nine A or has committed an assault and battery in violation of section thirteen A of chapter two hundred and sixty-five against a family or household member as defined in section one of chapter two hundred and nine A. Said officer may arrest and detain a person charged with a misdemeanor, without having a warrant for such arrest in his possession, if the officer making such arrest and detention shall have actual knowledge that a warrant then in full force and effect for the arrest of such person has in fact issued.
    </text>
</law>