<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="277" order_by="277" level="3">Indictments And Proceedings Before Trial</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>79</section_number>
    <catch_line>Application Of Annexed Forms; Schedule</catch_line>
    <order_by>79</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. did fraudulently and deceitfully entice (and take away) C.D. from his house (or, if a minor, from his father’s or guardian’s house; or if elsewhere, state it as the case may be), for the unlawful purpose of prostitution (or for the purpose of unlawful sexual intercourse).
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B., with intent to procure the miscarriage of C.D., did unlawfully use a certain instrument upon the body of said C.D., and in consequence thereof said C.D. died.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     That A.B., with intent to procure the miscarriage of C.D., did unlawfully do certain things (naming them) to (or upon the body of) said C.D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B., an unmarried person, did commit adultery with C.D., a married person.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B., while committing the crime of (here state crime), was lawfully arrested by C.D., sheriff of said county, and when so arrested was armed with, and had on his person, a certain dangerous weapon (a slung shot, etc., as the case may be).
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. wilfully and maliciously did burn a building adjoining the dwelling house of C.D. in            in said county.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     That A.B. wilfully and maliciously did set fire to a building in             by the burning whereof the dwelling house of C.D. was burned.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     That A.B. wilfully and maliciously, in the night time, did burn            
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A meeting house (or church, town house, etc.) in             in said county, erected for public use.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A banking house (or warehouse, etc.) of C.D. in             in said county, of the value, with the property therein, of one thousand dollars and not the property of (the defendant).
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A barn (or stable or shop or office) of C.D., in             in said county, the same being there within the curtilage of the dwelling house of said C.D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     That A.B. wilfully and maliciously did burn a building, by the burning whereof [(a), (b), or (c)] was burned in the night time.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     That A.B. wilfully and maliciously did burn a banking house (or other structure mentioned in the statute, as the case may be) of C.D., in             in said county.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. did assault C.D., a child under the age of sixteen years, with intent unlawfully and carnally to know and abuse.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. did break and enter (or entered in the night time without breaking) a building (or ship or vessel) of one X., in said (Boston), with intent (as above), the said X. (or other person), who was lawfully therein, being put in fear.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     That A.B. did break and enter (or entered in the night time without breaking) a railroad car situated in said (Boston), of the (name of the railroad), with intent therein to commit larceny (or murder, etc., as the case may be).
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     That A.B. did enter in the night time the dwelling house of one X., in said (Boston), with intent therein to commit larceny (or murder, etc., as the case may be).
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     That A.B. did break and enter a building (or ship or vessel) of one X., in said (Boston), with intent therein (etc. as above).
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. did enter the dwelling house of one X., situated in said (Boston), with intent therein to commit larceny, and after having so entered with said intent did break said dwelling house in the night time, X. being lawfully therein, and said A.B. being armed with a dangerous weapon at the time of such entry (or such breaking) (or arming himself with a dangerous weapon in said house) (or did make an assault on said X., who was lawfully therein).
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     That A.B. did break and enter the dwelling house of one X., in said (Boston), in the night time, with intent therein to commit larceny (or murder, etc., as the case may be).
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. and C.D. conspired together to commit rape upon E.F.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     That A.B. and C.D. conspired together to steal the property, money, etc., of E.F.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. did cause and procure one C.D. to overdrive (etc.) a certain horse (etc.).
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     That A.B., having the charge and custody of a certain horse (etc.), did inflict unnecessary cruelty upon it.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     That A.B., having the charge and custody of a certain horse (etc.), did unnecessarily fail to provide it with proper food (or drink or shelter or protection from the weather).
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. did steal six cows, each of the value of twenty dollars, of the property of C.D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. was concerned in the setting up (or managing or drawing) of a certain lottery for money.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     That A.B. did dispose of a certain horse of the value of ten dollars to C.D., by way of a lottery.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     That A.B., under the pretext of the sale of certain property, to wit: (state the property) to C.D., did dispose of to said C.D. certain other personal property, to wit: (state the property), with intent of said A.B. to make the said disposal of said (property) dependent upon a chance by lot, and that such chance was made an additional inducement to the disposal and sale of said (property).
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B., having a lawful spouse living, to wit: X., did at (state place) unlawfully marry and have for his spouse one C.D., after which the said A.B. did, while said X., was still living, on, at, etc., unlawfully cohabit and continue to cohabit in (Boston) with the said C.D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     That A.B. did assault C.D., a child under the age of sixteen years, with the intent to unlawfully have sexual intercourse or unnatural sexual intercourse with and abuse said C.D.; and did unlawfully have sexual intercourse or unnatural sexual intercourse with and abuse said C.D.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>