<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="276" order_by="276" level="3">Search Warrants, Rewards, Fugitives From Justice, Arrest, Examination, Commitment And Bail. Probation Officers And Board Of Probation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>88</section_number>
    <catch_line>Clerical Assistance</catch_line>
    <order_by>88</order_by>
    <text>
          Every court appointing probation officers may employ such clerical assistance as it deems necessary to keep, index and consolidate the records required to be kept by probation officers and for such other work in connection with its probation service as the court may determine. The compensation for such service, together with such other necessary expenses as the court shall incur in connection with such work, shall be paid by the commonwealth upon vouchers approved by said court.[ Second paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The administrative justices for the district court and juvenile court departments, in consultation with the commissioner of probation, may designate and redesignate such divisions thereof, including in such term the Boston juvenile court, the Worcester juvenile court, the Bristol county juvenile court and the Springfield juvenile court, within each of the counties of the commonwealth as in the opinion of said administrative justices should join in the establishment of a probation district office for the clerical service of the probation officers of the divisions thereof so designated or redesignated and said divisions so designated or redesignated shall thereupon consult with the chief administrative justice of the trial court and the commissioner of probation as to the establishment of such a probation district office, and shall join in the employment of such clerical assistance as is necessary to keep, index and consolidate the records in such form as may be required by the commissioner of probation in connection with the probation service of the said courts. The compensation for such service, together with such other necessary expenses as the courts shall incur in connection with such work, shall be paid by the commonwealth upon vouchers approved by one of the justices of said courts, designated by said administrative justices.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 122 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The administrative justices for the district court and juvenile court departments, in consultation with the commissioner of probation, may designate and redesignate such divisions thereof, including in such term the Boston juvenile court, the Worcester juvenile court, the Bristol county juvenile court and the Springfield juvenile court, within each of the counties of the commonwealth as in the opinion of said administrative justices should join in the establishment of a probation district office for the clerical service of the probation officers of the divisions thereof so designated or redesignated and said divisions so designated or redesignated shall thereupon consult with the court administrator of the trial court and the commissioner of probation as to the establishment of such a probation district office, and shall join in the employment of such clerical assistance as is necessary to keep, index and consolidate the records in such form as may be required by the commissioner of probation in connection with the probation service of the said courts. The compensation for such service, together with such other necessary expenses as the courts shall incur in connection with such work, shall be paid by the commonwealth upon vouchers approved by one of the justices of said courts, designated by said administrative justices.
    </text>
</law>