<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="277" order_by="277" level="3">Indictments And Proceedings Before Trial</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>70C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Civil Infractions</catch_line>
    <order_by>70C</order_by>
    <text>
        Upon oral motion by the commonwealth or the defendant at arraignment or pretrial conference, or upon the court’s own motion at any time, the court may, unless the commonwealth objects, in writing, stating the reasons for such objection, treat a violation of a municipal ordinance, or by-law or a misdemeanor offense as a civil infraction. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the offenses in sections 22F, 24, 24D, 24G, 24L, and 24N of chapter 90, sections 8, 8A, and 8B of chapter 90B, chapter 119, chapter 119A, chapter 209, chapter 209A, chapter 265, sections 1, 2, 3, 6, 6A, 6B, 8B, 13, 13A, 13B, 13B1/2, 13B3/4, 13C, 14, 14B, 15, 15A, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 22A, 22B, 22C, 23, 23A, 23B, 28, 31 and 36 of chapter 268, chapter 268A, sections 10, 10A, 10C, 10D, 10E, 11B, 11C, 11E, 12, 12A, 12B, 12D and 12E of chapter 269 and sections 1, 2, 3, 4, 4A, 4B, 6, 7, 8, 12, 13, 16, 28, 29A and 29B of chapter 272. If a motion to proceed civilly is allowed, the court shall not appoint counsel. If counsel has already been appointed, the court shall revoke the appointment. A person complained of for such civil infraction shall be adjudicated responsible upon such finding by the court and shall not be sentenced to any term of incarceration. The commonwealth shall maintain a copy of all objections filed under this section and shall report the number of such objections, delineated by divisions of the district court, every 6 months to the house and senate committees on ways and means. 
When the court has treated a violation of a municipal ordinance or by-law or a misdemeanor offense as a civil infraction under this section and the ordinance, by-law or misdemeanor in question does not set forth a civil fine as a possible penalty, the court may impose a fine of not more than $5,000. An adjudication of responsibility shall neither be used in the calculation of second and subsequent offenses under any chapter, nor as the basis for the revocation of parole or of a probation surrender. An adjudication of responsibility under this section may include an order of restitution.
    </text>
</law>