<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="280" order_by="280" level="3">Fines And Forfeitures</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Payment Of Certain Fines And Forfeitures; Apportionment Among Beneficiaries</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        A fine or forfeiture imposed by a court shall, except as otherwise provided, be paid over to the state treasurer. Twenty per cent of the fines imposed under the provisions of chapter three hundred and fifty-four of the acts of nineteen hundred and fifty-two shall be paid over to the state treasurer. If the whole or any part of a fine is by law payable to a complainant or informant or to a person or corporation as beneficiary, the court may apportion the fine or forfeiture between such complainant, informant or other beneficiary and the commonwealth, respectively. 
Fines imposed under the provisions of chapters eighty-nine and ninety, including fines, penalties and assessments imposed under the provisions of chapter ninety C for the violation of the provisions of chapters eighty-nine and ninety, fines assessed by a hearing officer of a city or town as defined in sections twenty A and twenty A1/2 of chapter ninety and forfeitures imposed under the provisions of section one hundred and forty-one of chapter one hundred and forty, shall be paid over to the treasury of the city or town wherein the offense was committed; provided, however, that only fifty per cent of the amount of fines, penalties and assessments collected for violations of section seventeen of chapter ninety or of a special speed regulation lawfully made under the authority of section eighteen of said chapter ninety shall be paid over to the treasury of the city or town wherein the offense was committed and the remaining fifty per cent shall be paid over to the state treasurer and credited to the Highway Fund.
    </text>
</law>