<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="276" order_by="276" level="3">Search Warrants, Rewards, Fugitives From Justice, Arrest, Examination, Commitment And Bail. Probation Officers And Board Of Probation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>42A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Personal Recognizance; Terms And Conditions To Protect Persons Suffering Physical Abuse</catch_line>
    <order_by>42A</order_by>
    <text>
        Whenever a court issues a criminal complaint and the crime involves assault and battery, trespass, threat to commit a crime, nonsupport, or any other complaint which involves the infliction, or the imminent threat of infliction, of physical harm upon a person by such person’s family or household member as defined in section one of chapter two hundred and nine A, the court may, in lieu of or in addition to any terms of personal recognizance, and after a hearing and finding, impose such terms as will insure the safety of the person allegedly suffering the physical abuse or threat thereof, and will prevent its recurrence. 
Such terms and conditions shall include reasonable restrictions on the travel, association or place of abode of the defendant as will prevent such person from contact with the person abused. 
As part of the disposition of any criminal complaint, the court may establish such terms and conditions of probation as will insure the safety of the person who has suffered such abuse or threat thereof, and will prevent the recurrence of such abuse or threat thereof. 
Such terms and conditions shall include reasonable restrictions on the travel, association or place of abode of the defendant as will prevent such person from all contact with the person abused; or the payment by the defendant to the person abused of monetary compensation for losses suffered as a direct result of the crime. Compensatory loss shall include, but not be limited to, loss of earnings or support, out-of-pocket losses for injuries sustained, moving expenses and reasonable attorneys fees. 
In addition, the terms and conditions of either the probation or the disposition of the complaint may include, but not be limited to, referral of the defendant to a clinic, facility or professional for one or more examinations, diagnoses, counseling or treatment; requiring the defendant to report periodically to a probation officer; or release of the defendant to the custody of a residential treatment facility.
    </text>
</law>