<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="276" order_by="276" level="3">Search Warrants, Rewards, Fugitives From Justice, Arrest, Examination, Commitment And Bail. Probation Officers And Board Of Probation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>86</section_number>
    <catch_line>Appointment Of Deputy Probation Officers By Boston Juvenile Court;  Creditable Service</catch_line>
    <order_by>86</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. Repealed by 2011, 93, Sec. 121. See 2011, 93, Sec. 138.]  The justice of the Boston juvenile court subject to the approval of the commissioner of probation may appoint as many deputy probation officers, without salary, as he may deem desirable, who shall assist probation officers in such way as the court may direct in making investigations of cases of children against whom complaints have been made, and in the care of children placed on probation.  Subject to the provisions and limitations of sections one to twenty-eight, inclusive, of chapter thirty-two, any member in service of a retirement system established under said sections, and any person who has been retired under any such system, shall be credited with all service rendered by him as a deputy probation officer under this section; provided that before any retirement allowance becomes effective for him or, in the case of any person already retired, before January first, nineteen hundred and sixty-seven, he pays into the annuity savings fund of such system, with regular interest as defined in said sections, in one sum, or in instalments, upon such terms and conditions as the board managing such system may prescribe, an amount equal to that which would have been withheld as regular deductions from the minimum annual salary payable to a probation officer of said court during the period that such member in service or person so retired served as such deputy probation officer.
    </text>
</law>