<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="276" order_by="276" level="3">Search Warrants, Rewards, Fugitives From Justice, Arrest, Examination, Commitment And Bail. Probation Officers And Board Of Probation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>98</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commissioner Of Probation;  Appointment</catch_line>
    <order_by>98</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. For text effective July 1, 2011, see below.]  There shall be a commissioner of probation, who shall have executive control and supervision of the probation service. The commissioner shall be appointed by the chief justice for administration and management for a term of 5 years and shall devote his full-time during business hours to the duties of his office. Subject to the approval and consent of the chief justice for administration and management, the commissioner may appoint deputies, supervisors and assistants necessary for the performance of his duties. Said commissioner, deputies, supervisors and assistants, shall receive a salary to be fixed by the chief justice for administration and management and subject to appropriation. Subject to the approval and direction of the chief justice for administration and management, the commissioner shall perform such duties and responsibilities as otherwise provided by law or as designated from time to time by the chief justice for administration and management, and shall be responsible for: making recommendations to the first justice and the chief justice for administration and management on the appointment of chief probation officers, assistant chief probation officers and probation officers; the supervision and evaluation of all probation programs within the trial court; the evaluation of the probation service in each court of the commonwealth; the compilation, evaluation, and dissemination of statistical information on crime, delinquency, and appropriate family service matters available in his records; the recruitment, training, and educational development of probation officers; the evaluation of the work performance of probation officers; planning, initiating, and developing volunteer, diversion, and other programs in consultation with probation officers throughout the commonwealth.
Chapter 276: Office of probation; commissioner of probation
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 124A effective July 1, 2011 until the appointment of a court administrator. See 2011, 93, Secs. 133 and 138. For text effective until July 1, 2011, see above. For text effective upon the appointment of a court administrator, see below]  There shall be an office of probation which shall be under the supervision, direction and control of a commissioner of probation. The commissioner shall be appointed, and may be removed, by the chief justice for administration and management, with the advice of the chief justice of the juvenile court, the chief justice of the superior court, the chief justice of the district court, the chief justice of the probate and family court and the chief justice of the Boston municipal court. The commissioner shall be a person of skill and experience in the field of criminal justice. The commissioner shall be the executive and administrative head of the office of probation and shall be responsible for administering and enforcing the laws relative to the office of probation and to each administrative unit of the office. The commissioner shall serve a term of 5 years and may be reappointed. The commissioner shall receive such salary as may be determined by law and shall devote full time to the duties of the office. In the case of an absence or vacancy in the office of the commissioner or in the case of disability as determined by the chief justice for administration and management, the chief justice may designate an acting commissioner to serve as commissioner until the vacancy is filled or the absence or disability ceases. The acting commissioner shall have all of the powers and duties of the commissioner and shall have similar qualifications as the commissioner.  Subject to the approval and consent of the chief justice for administration and management, the commissioner may appoint such deputies, supervisors and assistants as may be necessary for the performance of the commissioner's duties. The deputies, supervisors and assistants shall, subject to appropriation, receive salaries to be fixed by the chief justice for administration and management. The commissioner shall perform such duties and responsibilities as otherwise provided by law or as designated from time to time by the chief justice for administration and management. The commissioner shall make recommendations to the chief justice for administration and management on:  (i) the supervision and evaluation of all probation programs within the trial court;  (ii) the evaluation of the probation service in each court of the commonwealth;  (iii) the compilation, evaluation and dissemination of statistical information on crime, delinquency and appropriate probate and family court matters available in the commissioner's records;  (iv) the recruitment, training and educational development of probation officers;  (v) the evaluation of the work performance of probation officers; and  (vi) planning, initiation and development of volunteer, diversion and other programs in consultation with probation officers throughout the commonwealth.
Chapter 276: Office of probation; commissioner of probation
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 124B effective upon the appointment of a court administrator. See 2011, 93, Sec. 132. For text effective until the appointment of a court administrator, see above.]  There shall be an office of probation which shall be under the supervision, direction and control of a commissioner of probation. The commissioner shall be appointed, and may be removed, by the chief justice of the trial court and the court administrator, with the advice of the chief justice of the juvenile court, the chief justice of the superior court, the chief justice of the district court, the chief justice of the probate and family court and the chief justice of the Boston municipal court. The commissioner shall be a person of skill and experience in the field of criminal justice. The commissioner shall be the executive and administrative head of the office of probation and shall be responsible for administering and enforcing the laws relative to the office of probation and to each administrative unit tof the office. The commissioner shall serve a term of 5 years and may be reappointed. The commissioner shall receive such salary as may be determined by law and shall devote full time to the duties of the office. In the case of an absence or vacancy in the office of the commissioner, or in the case of disability as determined by the chief justice of the trial court, said chief justice may designate an acting commissioner to serve as commissioner until the vacancy is filled or the absence or disability ceases. The acting commissioner shall have all of the powers and duties of the commissioner and shall have similar qualifications as the commissioner.  Subject to the approval and consent of the court administrator, the commissioner may appoint such deputies, supervisors and assistants as may be necessary for the performance of the commissioner's duties. The deputies, supervisors and assistants shall, subject to appropriation, receive salaries to be fixed by the court administrator. Subject to the approval and direction of the court administrator, the commissioner shall perform such duties and responsibilities as otherwise provided by law or as designated from time to time by the chief justice of the trial court and the court administrator. The commissioner shall make recommendations to the chief justice of the trial court and the court administrator on:  (i) the supervision and evaluation of all probation programs within the trial court;  (ii) the evaluation of the probation service in each court of the commonwealth;  (iii) the compilation, evaluation and dissemination of statistical information on crime, delinquency and appropriate probate and family court matters available in the commissioner's records;  (iv) the recruitment, training and educational development of probation officers;  (v) the evaluation of the work performance of probation officers; and  (vi) planning, initiation and development of volunteer, diversion and other programs in consultation with probation officers throughout the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>