<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="276" order_by="276" level="3">Search Warrants, Rewards, Fugitives From Justice, Arrest, Examination, Commitment And Bail. Probation Officers And Board Of Probation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Written Demand; Allegations; Accompanying Papers; Charge Of Crime; Authentication Of Copies Of Papers</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        No demand for the interstate rendition of a person charged with crime in another state shall be recognized by the governor unless it be in writing alleging either that the person demanded was present in the demanding state at the time of the commission of the alleged crime, or that such person committed in this commonwealth or in a third state an act intentionally resulting in a crime in the demanding state, or that such person has escaped from confinement or has broken the terms of his bail, probation or parole, nor unless such demand is accompanied by a copy of an indictment found, or of an information supported by affidavit, in the demanding state, or by a copy of an affidavit made before a magistrate of such state, and by a copy of the warrant which was issued thereon, or by a copy of a judgment of conviction or of a sentence imposed in execution thereof in the demanding state. The indictment or information, or the affidavit made before the magistrate who issued the warrant, shall substantially charge the person demanded with having committed a crime under the law of the demanding state, and the copy of the indictment, information, affidavit, judgment of conviction or sentence shall be authenticated by the executive authority of such state.
    </text>
</law>