<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="276" order_by="276" level="3">Search Warrants, Rewards, Fugitives From Justice, Arrest, Examination, Commitment And Bail. Probation Officers And Board Of Probation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20K</section_number>
    <catch_line>Warrant To Receive Accused And Convey Him To Proper County;  Proceedings Pending In Another State</catch_line>
    <order_by>20K</order_by>
    <text>
        Whenever the governor shall demand a person charged with crime in this commonwealth, or one charged with having been convicted in this commonwealth and having escaped from confinement or having broken the terms of his bail, probation or parole, from the chief executive of any other state, or from the chief justice or an associate justice of the supreme court of the District of Columbia authorized to receive such demand under the laws of the United States, he may issue a warrant, under the seal of this commonwealth, to some agent, commanding him to receive the person so charged if delivered to him, and convey him to the proper officer of the county in which the crime was committed. 
Whenever it is desired to have returned to this commonwealth a person charged herein with a crime, or with having been convicted in this commonwealth and having escaped from confinement or having broken the terms of his bail, probation or parole, and such person is imprisoned or is held under criminal proceedings then pending against him in another state, the governor may agree with the executive authority of such other state for the interstate rendition of such person before the conclusion of such proceedings or of his term of sentence in such other state, upon such conditions relative to the return of such person to such other state at the expense of this commonwealth as may be agreed upon between the governor and the executive authority of such other state.
    </text>
</law>