<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Proceedings In Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="280" order_by="280" level="3">Fines And Forfeitures</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Criminal Assessments</catch_line>
    <order_by>6B</order_by>
    <text>
        The court shall impose an assessment of not less than thirty-five dollars nor more than one hundred dollars against any person who has attained the age of seventeen years and who is convicted of a misdemeanor or against whom a finding of sufficient facts for a conviction is made on a complaint charging a misdemeanor under sections thirty-two C, thirty-two D, and thirty-two G and thirty-five of chapter ninety-four C. The court shall impose an assessment of not less than one hundred and fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars against any person who is convicted of a felony or against whom a finding of sufficient facts for a conviction is made on a complaint charging a felony under sections thirty-two, thirty-two A, thirty-two B, thirty-two E, thirty-two F and thirty-four of chapter ninety-four C. When multiple criminal offenses arising from a single incident are charged, the total assessment shall not exceed five hundred dollars. In the discretion of the court, any assessment imposed pursuant to this section which would cause the person against whom the assessment is made an undue hardship may be reduced or waived. 
All such assessments made shall be collected by the court and shall be transmitted monthly to the state treasurer. The assessment from any conviction which is subsequently overturned on appeal shall be refunded by the court to the person whose conviction is overturned. Said court shall deduct such funds from the assessments transmitted to the state treasurer. Assessments pursuant to this section shall be in addition to any other fines or restitution imposed in any disposition.
    </text>
</law>