<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111L" order_by="111L" level="3">Biotechnology</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Information On Choice Of Disposition Of Remaining Embryos Or Gametes;  Informational Pamphlet; Informed Consent Form</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A physician or other health care provider who provides a patient with in vitro fertilization therapy shall provide the patient with timely, relevant and appropriate information sufficient to allow that patient to make an informed and voluntary choice regarding the disposition of any pre-implantation embryos or gametes remaining following treatment. The physician shall present the patient with the options of storing, donating to another person, donating for research purposes or otherwise disposing of or destroying any unused pre-implantation embryos, as appropriate. The department shall prescribe and provide for use by physicians and other health care providers who treat patients for infertility through in vitro or any other process where an egg is extracted from a woman the following 2 documents, in multiple languages as determined by the department:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     an informational pamphlet, describing the procedure by which an egg is extracted from the patient, including all short and long-term potential health impacts of the procedure on the patient, any drugs or devices to be used, including whether they have received approval from the United States Food and Drug Administration, the risks involved, any discomfort and side effects that may be experienced, any alternatives which the patient may have and their attendant risks and benefits, medical treatment available to the patient should complications arise, and that the particular treatment may involve currently unforeseeable risks to the patient, embryo or fetus. A physician or other health care provider treating a woman with a procedure by which an egg is intended to be extracted shall provide the patient with this pamphlet or a legible copy thereof, and provide any other treatment information which may be specific to the patient’s treatment; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     an informed consent form, stating that the patient has been given and has reviewed and understands the informational pamphlet described in clause (1), has consulted with her physician or health care provider concerning the general procedures and her specific medical situation, and understanding the procedure, process and risks, consents to proceed with the procedure or process. The informed consent form shall also contain a “Notes” section, to be completed by the physician or health care provider. This notes section shall contain any medical information, alternative procedures, medicines, devices, considerations or risks relevant to the specific patient’s informed consent to proceed and shall be completed by the physician or health care provider in each case. A physician or other health care provider treating a woman by a procedure by which an egg is intended to be extracted shall provide the patient with this form or a legible copy thereof, and shall keep a signed copy of this document in the patient’s medical file.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No physician or other health care provider shall provide this treatment before providing the patient with both the informational pamphlet and the informed consent form and without receiving, in return, a complete and fully executed informed consent form from the patient. A physician or other health care provider shall seek such informed consent only under circumstances that provide the prospective patient reasonable opportunity to consider whether or not to receive such treatment and that minimize the possibility of coercion or undue influence. The information that is given to the patient shall be in language understandable to the patient.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>