<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="113" order_by="113" level="3">Promotion Of Anatomical Science</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Acceptance Or Rejection Of Gift By Donee;  Disposition Or Disposal Of Bodies And Tissues;  Determination Of Time Of Death;  Criminal And Civil Liability</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until February 22, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 39, Sec. 2.]  (a) The donee may accept or reject the gift. If the donee accepts a gift of the entire body, he may, subject to the terms of the gift, authorize embalming and the use of the body in funeral services. If the gift is of a part of the body, the donee, upon the death of the donor and prior to embalming, shall cause the part to be removed without unnecessary mutilation. After removal of the part, custody of the remainder of the body vests in the surviving spouse, next of kin or other persons under obligation to dispose of the body. If the donee is responsible for the disposition of the body, he shall dispose of it in accordance with the terms specified by the donor, or if no such terms are specified, he shall have said body decently buried or cremated.  (b) The time of death shall be determined by a physician who attends the donor at his death, or, if none, the physician who certifies the death. This physician shall not participate in the procedures for removing or transplanting a part.  (c) A person who acts in good faith in accordance with the terms of sections seven to thirteen, inclusive, or under the anatomical gift laws of another state or a foreign country shall not be liable for damages in any civil action or be subject to prosecution in any criminal proceeding for his act.  (d) The provisions of sections seven to thirteen, inclusive, shall be subject to the laws of the commonwealth relative to autopsies.
    </text>
</law>