<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>190</section_number>
    <catch_line>Statewide Program; Director; Advisory Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>190</order_by>
    <text>
        Subject to appropriation, the department shall establish a statewide program for the prevention, screening, diagnosis and treatment of lead poisoning, including elimination of the sources of such poisoning, through such research, educational, epidemiologic and clinical activities as may be necessary. 
The commissioner shall appoint a lead poisoning control director, who shall serve at the pleasure of the commissioner. The director shall be responsible, subject to the authority of the commissioner, for carrying out and administering all programs created pursuant to this section and sections one hundred and ninety-one to section one hundred and ninety-nine B, inclusive, except as otherwise indicated herein. The director may contract with any agencies, individuals or groups for the provision of necessary services, subject to appropriation; and shall issue and from time to time, amend, such rules and regulations as may be necessary; provided, however, that such rules, regulations or amendments shall be filed with the joint committee on health care and the joint committee on housing and urban development at least thirty days before the effective date of such rules, regulations and amendments. 
The governor shall appoint an advisory committee for the lead poisoning prevention program, which shall consist of fourteen members who shall serve at the pleasure of the governor. At least four of said fourteen members shall be physicians or persons active in the field of public health; at least one of said members shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Association of Community Development Corporations; at least two of said members shall be parents of children under six years of age who reside in lower-income urban areas; at least one of said members shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Rental Housing Association; at least one of said members shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Bankers Association; at least one of said members shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Association of Realtors; and at least one of said members shall be a representative of the property and casualty insurance industry. The committee shall advise the director on matters of policy; shall be consulted by the director prior to the issuance of rules and regulations; and shall perform such other duties as the director may request. The members of the advisory committee shall not be paid for their services, but they may be reimbursed for travel and other expenses necessary for the performance of their duties.
    </text>
</law>