<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>87F</order_by>
    <text>
        The following words, as used in the following thirteen sections, unless the context otherwise requires, shall have the following meanings:— 
“Barber”, any person who, personally or by any other person, for compensation, shaves or trims the beard, cuts the hair, gives facial and scalp massaging, facial and scalp treatments with oils and creams and other preparations made for that purpose, either by hand or mechanical appliances, singes and shampoos the hair or applies any make of hair tonics, or dyes the hair, of any person; or any person who, without compensation, performs or offers to perform any of the above mentioned services for the public generally. 
“Instructor”, any registered barber who teaches all branches of barbering in a barber school or barber college approved by the board of registration of barbers. 
“Apprentice”, any person who is engaged in barbering or any of its branches under the supervision of a registered barber. 
“Board”, board of registration of barbers. 
“Cosmetologist”, any person who, with hands or mechanical or electrical apparatus or appliances, or by the use of cosmetic preparations, antiseptics, tonics, lotions or creams, engages for compensation in any one or any combination of the following practices, to wit:— Massaging, cleansing, stimulating, manipulating, exercising, beautifying the scalp, face, neck, arms, bust or upper part of the body, manicuring the nails, or removing of superfluous hair, by the use of electricity or otherwise, about the body of any person, or any person who is registered to practice hairdressing, aesthetics or manicuring pursuant to the requirements of the board; provided, however, that cosmetologist shall not mean any person who engages in the practice of make-up artistry only.
    </text>
</law>