<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificate Of Result Of Analysis Of Narcotic Drugs, Poisons, Drugs, Medicines Or Chemicals;  Evidence</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 139, Sec. 107. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229.]  The analyst or an assistant analyst of the department or of the University of Massachusetts medical school shall upon request furnish a signed certificate, on oath, of the result of the analysis provided for in the preceding section to any police officer or any agent of such incorporated charitable organization, and the presentation of such certificate to the court by any police officer or agent of any such organization shall be prima facie evidence that all the requirements and provisions of the preceding section have been complied with. This certificate shall be sworn to before a justice of the peace or notary public, and the jurat shall contain a statement that the subscriber is the analyst or an assistant analyst of the department. When properly executed, it shall be prima facie evidence of the composition, quality, and the net weight of the narcotic or other drug, poison, medicine, or chemical analyzed or the net weight of any mixture containing the narcotic or other drug, poison, medicine, or chemical analyzed, and the court shall take judicial notice of the signature of the analyst or assistant analyst, and of the fact that he is such. A signed certificate of drug analysis furnished by an analyst, assistant analyst or other designated employee of the Drug Enforcement Administration of the United States Department of Justice, which conforms with the requirements of this section, shall be prima facie evidence of the composition, quality, and when appropriate, the net weight of the narcotic or other drug, poison, medication or chemical analyzed or the net weight of any mixture containing the narcotic or other drug, poison, medicine or chemical analyzed and the court shall take judicial notice of the signature of the analyst, assistant analyst or other designated employee and the fact that he is such.
    </text>
</law>