<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>199A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Unlawful Practices In Selling, Renting, Or Leasing Premises Containing Lead In Paint, Plaster Or Materials</catch_line>
    <order_by>199A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     It shall be an unlawful practice for purposes of chapter one hundred and fifty-one B for the owner, lessee, sublessee, real estate broker, assignee, or managing agent of any premises to refuse to sell, rent, lease or otherwise deny to or withhold from any person or to discriminate against any person in the terms, conditions or privileges of the sale, rental or lease of such premises, because such premises do or may contain paint, plaster or accessible structural materials containing dangerous levels of lead, or because the sale, rental or lease would trigger duties under sections one hundred and eighty-nine A to one hundred and ninety-nine B, inclusive, or regulations promulgated thereunder, or because a person chooses to exercise any right under said sections one hundred and eighty-nine A to one hundred and ninety-nine B, inclusive, or regulations promulgated thereunder. Any person claiming to be aggrieved by an alleged unlawful practice as herein defined may file a complaint pursuant to section five of chapter one hundred and fifty-one B and all provisions of said chapter shall be applicable to such complaints.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Refusing to rent to families with children in violation of paragraph eleven of section four of chapter one hundred and fifty-one B shall not constitute compliance with the lead law and regulations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Refusing to renew the lease of or evicting families with children shall not constitute compliance with the lead law and regulations. Such evictions shall also constitute a violation of section two of chapter ninety-three A and section eighteen of chapter one hundred and eighty-six.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>