<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>178</section_number>
    <catch_line>Classification Of Real Estate Appraisers; Applications</catch_line>
    <order_by>178</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The state-certified general real estate appraiser classification, which shall consist of persons meeting the requirements for certification relating to the appraisal of all types of real property and passing a state administered examination, which requirements and examination are, at a minimum, consistent with the requirements and examination of the Appraisal Qualifications Board of the Appraisal Foundation for that category.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The state-certified residential real estate appraiser classification, which shall consist of persons meeting the requirements for certification relating to the appraisal of certain residential real property and passing a state administered examination, which requirements and examination are, at a minimum, consistent with the requirements and examination of the Appraisal Qualifications Board of the Appraisal Foundation for that category.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The state-licensed real estate appraiser classification, which shall consist of persons meeting the requirements established by the board for licensing pursuant to this chapter and passing a state administered examination, which requirements and examination are, at a minimum, consistent with and equivalent to the requirements of Title XI and any guidelines issued thereunder by the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council or its Federal Appraisal Subcommittee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Real estate appraisal trainee classification, which shall consist of persons authorized only to assist a state-certified general real estate appraiser, state-certified residential real estate appraiser or state-licensed real estate appraiser in the performance of an appraisal assignment. Such real estate appraisal trainee shall obtain a trainee license and shall perform such functions as are consistent with regulations established by the board governing this category of licensure; provided, however, that such regulations are not inconsistent with the requirements of Title XI and any guidelines issued thereunder by the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council or its Federal Appraisal Subcommittee.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>