<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>233</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing Of Massage Therapy Schools</catch_line>
    <order_by>233</order_by>
    <text>
        The board shall, upon the application of any school desiring to teach massage therapy, inspect the school and notify the governing body thereof in writing if the school is approved for licensure by the board or, if not, what action the school must take in order to be licensed by the board. The application shall be on a form furnished by the board, which application shall be signed and sworn to by the applicant. Each application shall be accompanied by a fee as prescribed by the secretary of administration and finance in accordance with section 3B of chapter 7. Licenses to operate a massage school shall be valid for a period determined by the director of professional licensure and may be renewed for a like period upon application therefor on forms to be furnished by the board. The fee for each renewal shall be determined under the aforementioned provision. The board shall further establish standards to be met by the massage therapy school and shall require the school to maintain a curriculum that meets the criteria established by the board. When in the opinion of the board the standards have been met by the school, the school shall be licensed. No school or entity may teach massage therapy unless licensed by the board. No person may instruct in a massage school unless he is licensed by the board. If at any time a licensed school has in the opinion of the board lowered its standards below those established by the board or violated any law, rule or regulation of the board, the license may, after notice and an opportunity for hearing, be revoked by the board. Any applicant aggrieved by the refusal of the board to license a massage school may seek review in the superior court under chapter 30A.
    </text>
</law>