<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>220</section_number>
    <catch_line>Multidisciplinary Advisory Board; Training And Examination Of Sexual Assault Nurse Examiners</catch_line>
    <order_by>220</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commissioner of public health shall establish a multi-disciplinary advisory board to assist with the development of a statewide program for the training and certification of sexual assault nurse examiners to conduct comprehensive forensic exams for the purpose of collection, preservation and documentation of forensic evidence for use in civil or criminal proceedings. The advisory board shall include, but not be limited to, a representative from the executive office of public safety, Jane Doe Inc., the office of the attorney general, the Massachusetts office for victim assistance, the disabled persons protection commission, the Massachusetts Nurses Association, the American Academy of Pediatricians, the Massachusetts Children’s Alliance, the Massachusetts District Attorney’s Association, the department of children and families, the Massachusetts Medical Society, the Massachusetts Hospital Association, the Massachusetts College of Emergency Physicians, the Emergency Nurses Association, the Boston police department crime laboratory and the state police crime laboratory.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In consultation with the advisory board, the commissioner shall establish requirements for certification and recertification for sexual assault nurse examiners. An applicant for certification at minimum shall be licensed to practice in the commonwealth as a registered nurse or medical doctor; shall have successfully completed a department approved training program, a written examination, and a pelvic and sexual assault clinical preceptorship; and shall satisfy all requirements that the commissioner may establish for certification.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     In consultation with the advisory board, the commissioner shall establish specialized requirements for certification and recertification for pediatric sexual assault nurse examiners to conduct forensic exams of patients under 12 years of age.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     In consultation with the advisory board, the commissioner shall establish uniform standards and protocols for certified sexual assault nurse examiners and certified pediatric sexual assault nurse examiners to use in conducting forensic exams.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The department shall operate a program to deliver sexual assault nurse examiner services at designated sites throughout the commonwealth. In consultation with the advisory board, the commissioner shall establish guidelines for site designation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The department may enter into agreements with hospitals, other health, welfare and social service agencies, other government agencies, and not-for-profit organizations necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     The department may adopt regulations to implement this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>