<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>71C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Minimum Safety And Quality Of Services Standards For Dementia Special Care Units;  Compliance By Providers Of Specialized Services Or Programming Licensed Under Sec. 71;  Training</catch_line>
    <order_by>71C</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 142, Sec. 1 effective July 8, 2012.]  (a) The department, in consultation with the Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders Association, Massachusetts/New Hampshire Chapter, Inc. and representatives from the nursing home provider community shall promulgate regulations to establish minimum standards for dementia special care units to ensure safety and quality of services including:  (1) dementia-specific training for all direct care workers, activities directors and supervisors of direct care workers in both traditional nursing homes and dementia special care units;  (2) activities programs in dementia special care units that provide dementia-specific activities; and  (3) guidelines for dementia special care unit physical design including, but not limited, to anti-wandering methods and promoting a therapeutic environment.  (b) A licensee under section 71 that holds itself out to the public or advertises that it is a provider of specialized services and programming for dementia special care units in long-term care facilities shall meet the standards set forth under this section in order to provide those services. A nursing home that operates a dementia special care unit shall disclose to consumers and to the department the specialized services the dementia special care unit provides for patients affected by alzheimer's and related dementias.  (c) A licensee of the department under section 71 shall provide dementia-specific training for direct care workers, activities directors and supervisors of direct care workers in a facility that does not hold itself out to the public or advertise that it is a provider of specialized services and programming for dementia special care units in long-term care facilities.
    </text>
</law>