<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>81E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Examination Of Applicants; Rules And Regulations Of Board; Seal</catch_line>
    <order_by>81E</order_by>
    <text>
        The board shall examine applicants for registration as professional engineers and as professional land surveyors and applicants desiring to take written or oral examinations to evidence qualification for registration as professional engineers or professional land surveyors. It shall make such rules and regulations as are necessary or proper for the conduct of its duties. The board may adopt and shall use an official seal. 
If any person, firm, co-partnership, corporation or joint stock association refuses to obey any decision, rule or order, or any part thereof, issued by the board pursuant to its powers, the attorney general of the commonwealth shall, upon request of the board, file a petition in equity for the enforcement of such decision, rule or order in the superior court for Suffolk county or for the county in which such person, firm, co-partnership, corporation or joint stock association resides or has a place of business. After due hearing, with such notice as the court may direct, the court shall order the enforcement of such decision, rule or order, or any part thereof, to the extent that such decision, rule or order, or any part thereof, has been legally and properly made by the board. 
The board, for the purposes of registration of professional engineers, shall recognize all the fundamental branches of engineering which shall include, without limiting the generality thereof by specific enumeration, the following fields:— aeronautical, chemical, civil, electrical, heating and ventilating, and air conditioning, industrial, mechanical, metallurgical, mining, safety, fire protection, sanitary and structural.
    </text>
</law>