<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Schools For Training Medical X Ray Technicians; Approval;  Inspection; Approving Authority</catch_line>
    <order_by>2C</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall operate or maintain a school for training medical X-ray technicians unless such school has been approved by the approving authority established by section two; provided, however, that for the purposes of this section only, the membership of said authority shall be increased by three members to be appointed for a term of three years each by the governor with the advice and consent of the council, one member to be a radiologist who is a member of the section on radiology of the Massachusetts Medical Society; one member to be a member of the Massachusetts Hospital Association; and one member to be an X-ray technician who is a member of the Massachusetts Society of X-ray technicians and certified by the American Registry of X-ray Technicians of Minneapolis, Minnesota. Said additional members shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for their travel and other reasonable expenses incidental to the performance of their duties. The provisions of section two relating to the inspection and approval of colleges, universities and medical schools by the approving authority shall apply to schools for the training of medical X-ray technicians. A school for training medical X-ray technicians shall mean a school or classes conducted for the purpose of training two or more individuals to perform various medical X-ray procedures used in the diagnosis, treatment or study of disease. Any person who operates or maintains a school for training medical X-ray technicians and who violates the provisions of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or both.
    </text>
</law>