<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111N" order_by="111N" level="3">Pharmaceutical And Medical Device Manufacturer Conduct</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Disclosure Of Data Relating To Provision Of Economic Benefits Valuing Fifty Dollars Or Greater</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Subsection (1) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (1) By July 1 of each year, every pharmaceutical or medical device manufacturing company that employs a person to sell or market a drug, medicine, chemical, device or appliance in the commonwealth shall disclose to the department of public health the value, nature, purpose and particular recipient of any fee, payment, subsidy or other economic benefit with a value of at least $50, which the company provides, directly or through its agents, to any physician, hospital, nursing home, pharmacist, health benefit plan administrator, health care practitioner or other person in the commonwealth authorized to prescribe, dispense, or purchase prescription drugs or medical devices in the commonwealth. The disclosure shall be accompanied by the payment of a fee, to be determined by the department, to pay the costs of administering this section.[ Subsection (1) as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 113 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (1) By July 1 of each year, every pharmaceutical or medical device manufacturing company that employs a person to sell or market a drug, medicine, chemical, device or appliance in the commonwealth shall disclose to the department of public health the value, nature, purpose and particular recipient of any fee, payment, subsidy or other economic benefit with a value of at least $50, which the company provides, directly or through its agents, to any physician, hospital, nursing home, pharmacist, health benefit plan administrator, health care practitioner or other person in the commonwealth authorized to prescribe, dispense, or purchase prescription drugs or medical devices in the commonwealth. The disclosure shall be accompanied by the payment of a fee, to be determined by the department, to pay the costs of administering this section. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the department shall not require a pharmaceutical or medical device manufacturing company to disclose information which has been disclosed to a federal agency pursuant to federal law and which may be obtained by the department from such federal agency.  (2) The department of public health shall make all disclosed data publicly available and easily searchable on its website.  (3) The department of public health shall report to the attorney general any payment, entertainment, meals, travel, honorarium, subscription, advance, services or anything of value provided in violation of the market code of conduct as adopted by the department of public health.
    </text>
</law>