<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>197E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Lead Abatement Loan Program</catch_line>
    <order_by>197E</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a loan program in the department of housing and community development for lead abatement throughout the commonwealth. Said program shall assist residential property owners in financing the abatement and containment of lead paint hazards. The director of housing and community development, in consultation with the commissioner and the lead poisoning control director, shall administer said program and may distribute funds through community action agencies, redevelopment agencies, local nonprofit community and housing agencies and other appropriate municipal and non-profit agencies and organizations. Loans under the program must be used for lead-paint abatement and containment activities. 
Agencies and organizations eligible for loans under this program shall be selected by the director of housing and community development in consultation with the commissioner and the lead poisoning control director. Not less than one-half of funds allocated for this program shall be distributed to agencies and organizations serving high-risk areas and communities. Such high-risk areas and communities shall be chosen by the commissioner based upon the following criteria: the incidence of childhood lead poisoning reported in the previous five years; the proportion of residential housing stock containing lead paint hazards; the proportion of residents of low and moderate income; and the prior efforts of appropriate agencies and organizations to promote and carry out preventive measures designed to alleviate lead hazards. All agencies and organizations wishing to receive funding from this program shall submit to said secretary and the commissioner a report detailing a proposed plan to reduce lead paint hazards. 
The director of housing and community development and the commissioner, subject to the consultation provisions of section one hundred and ninety of this chapter, shall promulgate regulations necessary to administer this program. Said director of housing and community development and the commissioner shall report to the clerks of the house of representatives and the senate not later than October first of each year concerning the distribution of loan funds under this program. Said director of housing and community development shall promulgate regulations which establish reasonable terms and conditions of such loans, including interest rates and maturity dates designed to encourage compliance with this chapter.
    </text>
</law>