<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Apprentices And Students; Report Of Instructor; Examinations And Reexaminations; Registration; Fees; Renewal; Permit</catch_line>
    <order_by>87I</order_by>
    <text>
        Nothing in sections eighty-seven F to eighty-seven R, inclusive, shall prohibit any person sixteen years of age or over from serving in this commonwealth in such occupation therein as a student in any barber school or barber college approved by the board under the instruction of an instructor; provided, that such instructor, or the person owning or operating such barber school or barber college, shall immediately report in writing to the board the name and age of such student working under his direction or training. Thereupon, and upon the payment of a fee, as determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, by the person operating or conducting such school or college, or by such student, as the case may be, the name of such students shall be entered in a register of the board for the registering of apprentices and students, and the board may grant to him a permit to practice as a student in such a barber school or barber college under the instruction of an instructor. Any such student, after having completed a course of at least six months, including at least one thousand hours consisting of not more than eight hours in any one day, of training in barbering in such a barber school or barber college, may apply for an examination, or for a second or subsequent examination, if he has failed to pass an earlier examination. Upon passing an examination satisfactory to the board, he shall be registered by the board as an apprentice, and as such may practice barbering for compensation under the supervision of a registered barber during the period of such original registration, and thereafter, upon payment annually of a renewal fee as provided in this section. After having practiced for two years, six months thereof in a barber school or barber college, approved by the board, under the instruction of an instructor and eighteen months thereof under a registered barber, and upon the payment of the required fee for examination, such apprentice shall be eligible for examination by the board for registration as a barber. An apprentice or student may practice barbering under a permit, or a renewal thereof, granted under this section. Fees, as determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, shall be paid upon filing an application for such permit, and thereafter for each annual renewal thereof. Any such permit not renewed at its expiration date shall become void but shall be reinstated within one year upon the payment of a fee as determined annually under the aforementioned chapter seven provision. If such a permit is not reinstated within one year from its expiration date, it shall be reinstated only after re-examination of the apprentice and the payment of a fee as determined annually under the aforementioned chapter seven provision; provided, however, that if an apprentice fails to pass such examination his permit shall be reinstated upon completion of a refresher course of two hundred and fifty hours in a barber school or barber college approved by the board. Such permit shall be valid for a period of one year from the date of issuance thereof. The board may register as an apprentice any person who has previously been registered as a barber for two or more years in this or any other state; provided, that such person, in registering as an apprentice, files with the board the proper apprentice application and pays a fee as determined annually under the aforementioned chapter seven provision. Such permits issued to applicants upon proof of such former experience shall be in effect for one year only.
    </text>
</law>