<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>70G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Genetic Information And Reports Protected As Private Information;  Prior Written Consent For Genetic Testing</catch_line>
    <order_by>70G</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     as a biopsy, autopsy, or clinical specimen solely for the purpose of conducting an immediate clinical or diagnostic test that is not a test of DNA, RNA, mitochondrial DNA, chromosomes or proteins;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     as a blood sample solely for blood banking;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     as a newborn screening pursuant to section 110A;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     as confidential research information for use in epidemiological and clinical research conducted for the purpose of generating scientific knowledge about genes or learning about genes or learning about the genetic basis of disease or for developing pharmaceutical and other treatments of disease; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     as information pertaining to the abuse of drugs or alcohol which is derived from tests given for the exclusive purpose of determining the abuse of drugs or alcohol.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     a statement of the purpose of the test;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     a statement that prior to signing the consent form, the consenting person discussed with the medical practitioner ordering the test the reliability of positive or negative test results and the level of certainty that a positive test result for that disease or condition serves as a predictor of such disease;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     a statement that the consenting person was informed about the availability and importance of genetic counseling and provided with written information identifying a genetic counselor or medical geneticist from whom the consenting person might obtain such counseling;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     a general description of each specific disease or condition tested for; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the person or persons to whom the test results may be disclosed;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Hospital, dispensary, laboratory, hospital-affiliated registry, physician, insurance institution, insurance support organization, or insurance representative, and commercial genetic testing company, agency, or association reports and records pertaining to any genetic information shall not be public records, and the contents thereof shall not be divulged by any person having charge of or access to the same without informed written consent, except upon proper judicial order or to a person whose official duties, in the opinion of the commissioner, entitle receipt of the information contained therein, or except in connection with life, disability, and long term care insurance as authorized pursuant to chapter 175I or as confidential research information for use in epidemiological or clinical research conducted for the purpose of generating scientific knowledge about genes or learning about the genetic basis of disease or for developing pharmaceutical and other treatments of disease. A laboratory receiving a request to conduct a genetic test from a facility, as defined in section 70E, or a physician or health care provider may conduct the requested test only when the request is accompanied by a signed statement of the medical practitioner ordering the test warranting that the appropriate prior written consent has been obtained from the patient except where the test is conducted as confidential research information for use in epidemiological or clinical research conducted for the purpose of generating scientific knowledge about genes or learning about the genetic basis of disease or for developing pharmaceutical and other treatments of disease. The signed request authorizes the laboratory to perform the test and disclose the results to the medical practitioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No facility, as defined in section 70E, and no physician or health care provider shall: (1) test any person for genetic information without first obtaining the prior written consent; (2) disclose the results of a genetic test to any person other than the subject thereof without first obtaining the informed written consent except where the results disclosed will be used only as is confidential research information for use in epidemiological or clinical research conducted for the purpose of generating scientific knowledge about genes or learning about the genetic basis of disease or for developing pharmaceutical and other treatments of disease; or identify the person being tested to any other person without first obtaining informed written consent or upon proper judicial order. Organizations conducting pharmoco-economic studies in systematic research to determine the cost benefits of specific treatment for genetic based disease shall be exempted from the need to re-obtain informed written consent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Whoever violates any provisions of this section shall be deemed to have violated section 2 of chapter 93A. Any person whose rights under this section have been violated, interfered with, or attempted to be interfered with may institute and prosecute in his own name and on his own behalf, or the attorney general, acting on behalf of the commonwealth, may institute a civil action for injunctive and other equitable relief.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     This section shall not apply to a law enforcement official in the execution of his official duties; to a hospital, laboratory or physician carrying out tests upon proper judicial order; or to law enforcement or health care personnel, or any other person, in the execution of their official duties pursuant to chapter 22E.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>