<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Prevention And Wellness Advisory Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>2H</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 60 effective November 4, 2012.]  There shall be a Prevention and Wellness Advisory Board to make recommendations to the commissioner concerning the administration and allocation of the Prevention and Wellness Trust Fund established in section 2G, establish evaluation criteria and perform any other functions specifically granted to it by law.  The board shall consist of: the commissioner of public health or a designee, who shall serve as chairperson; the executive director of the institute of health care finance and policy established in chapter 12C or a designee; the secretary of health and human services or a designee; and 14 persons to be appointed by the governor, 1 of whom shall be a person with expertise in the field of public health economics; 1 of whom shall be a person with expertise in public health research; 1 of whom shall be a person with expertise in the field of health equity; 1 of whom shall be a person from a local board of health for a city or town with a population greater than 50,000; 1 of whom shall be a person of a board of health for a city or town with a population of fewer than 50,000; 2 of whom shall be representatives of health insurance carriers; 1 of whom shall be a person from a consumer health organization; 1 of whom shall be a person from a hospital association; 1 of whom shall be a person from a statewide public health organization; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the interest of businesses; 1 of whom shall administer an employee assistance program; 1 of whom shall be a public health nurse or a school nurse; and 1 of whom shall be a person from an association representing community health workers.
    </text>
</law>