<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>63B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Medicare Program Billings; Commissioner’S Report</catch_line>
    <order_by>63B</order_by>
    <text>
        The department of public health shall bill the Medicare program established by Title XVIII of the Social Security Act for all patients cared for in hospitals operated by the department who have received or are eligible to receive a Medicare health insurance number. The department shall bill the Medicare program for all services provided to such patients since January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine, the effective date of the Medicare Catastrophic Coverage Act of 1988 (Public Law 100-360), as amended. The department shall make the billings required by this section within the time for billing services which are applicable to the Medicare program for the billing of patient care services which are applicable to the Medicare program. 
By February first, nineteen hundred and ninety-one, the commissioner of public health shall issue a report to the house and senate committees on ways and means which shall provide the following information with respect to each hospital operated by the department: (a) the number and percentage of patients billed to the Medicaid program since January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine; (b) the number and percentage of patients who by reason of age or disability are entitled to Medicare claim identification numbers; (c) whether any of the individuals identified in subsection (b) are not entitled to Medicare benefits and the reasons therefor; (d) whether any practice of the department of public welfare or department of public health has resulted in patients admitted to public health hospitals with or entitled to Medicare identification numbers not being entitled to benefits under the Medicare program; and (e) the cost savings and revenue which will be generated from the billings required by this section.
    </text>
</law>