<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87XX</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of License; Term; Renewal Licenses; Records By Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>87XX</order_by>
    <text>
        The board shall issue a license to an applicant who has complied with all pertinent requirements which shall entitle him to act as a broker or a salesman, as the case may be; provided, however, that a license issued to a corporation, society, association or partnership shall not authorize any unlicensed individual connected therewith to act as broker or salesman except as expressly provided in section eighty-seven UU. Such license shall be in such form as the board may determine, shall set forth the name and address of the licensee, shall specify the nature of the license, whether for a broker or salesman, the date of issuance, and shall bear a facsimile of the seal of the board. Except as otherwise provided in section eighty-seven UU in the case of a license issued to a corporation, society, association or partnership, a license shall be valid for a period of two years from the date of issue unless sooner suspended or revoked and shall be renewed by the board biennially thereafter, without examination, upon payment of the fee prescribed in section eighty-seven ZZ; provided, that the applicant, if an individual, or, if a corporation, society, association or partnership, each officer and director or holder of similar position or each partner, of whom evidence of good moral character is required in connection with the application for an original license in section eighty-seven TT, has not been found to be disqualified because of lack of good moral character, or for any ground set forth in sections eighty-seven PP to eighty-seven DDD, inclusive; and, provided, further, that the license of a corporation, society, association or partnership shall be renewed only upon the renewal of the individual license of at least one of its designated officers or partners, as the case may be. No fee shall be required of a corporation, society, association or partnership for the renewal of its license. Applications for renewals of licenses shall be signed and sworn to by the applicant and shall be made on forms furnished by the board. Such application forms shall be mailed by the board to each broker and salesman registered with the board, together with notice of the expiration of his license, not less than thirty days prior to such expiration. Renewal licenses shall be in such form as the board may determine. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the license originally issued to an individual shall be valid until the anniversary of the licensee’s date of birth next occurring more than twenty-four months after the date of issuance. The board shall keep a record of all licensed brokers and salesmen which shall be open to inspection by the public and shall, from time to time, cause to be printed a new or revised publication containing an alphabetical list of such brokers and salesmen, together with their addresses, accompanied by such other information relative to the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter as it may deem of interest to the public.
    </text>
</law>