<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Limited Registration Of Podiatrists</catch_line>
    <order_by>16A</order_by>
    <text>
        An applicant for limited registration under this section may, upon payment of a fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, be registered by the board as an intern, resident, fellow, extern, preceptor or podiatric medical officer for such time as it may subscribe if he furnishes the board with satisfactory proof that he is eighteen years of age or over and of good moral character, he has creditably completed two years of a pre-podiatric medical course of study in a college or university and not less than three and one-half years of study or the comparable requisite years of study at a legally chartered podiatric medical school offering an accelerated course or two years in a podiatry program at a medical school chartered in the commonwealth, followed by one and one-half years at a legally chartered podiatric medical school having the power to grant a degree in podiatric medicine, and that he has been appointed a resident, fellow, intern, extern, preceptor or podiatric medical officer in a health care program. All such schools and programs must be approved by the board of registration in podiatry pursuant to section sixteen and leading toward certification by speciality boards recognized by the American Podiatry Association. 
Such limited registration shall entitle said applicant to practice podiatric medicine only in the hospital, institution, clinic or program designated on his certificate of limited registration, or outside such hospital, institution, clinic or program for the treatment, under supervision of one of its medical officers who is a duly registered physician, or one of its podiatric medical officers who is a duly registered podiatric physician, of persons accepted as patients, by any hospital, institution, clinic or program affiliated for training purposes with the hospital, institution, clinic or program designated on such certificate, which affiliation is approved by the board, and in any case, under regulations established by such hospital, institution, clinic or program. The name of any hospital, institution, clinic or program so affiliated and so approved shall also be indicated on such certificate. Limited registration under this section may be revoked at any time by the board.
    </text>
</law>