<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25M</section_number>
    <catch_line>Healthcare Workforce Advisory Council</catch_line>
    <order_by>25M</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  (a) There shall be a healthcare workforce advisory council within, but not subject to the control of, the health care workforce center established by section 25L. The council shall advise the center on the capacity of the healthcare workforce to provide timely, effective, culturally competent, quality physician and nursing services.  (b) The council shall consist of 16 members who shall be appointed by the governor: 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Extended Care Federation; 1 of whom shall be a physician with a primary care specialty designation who practices in a rural area; 1 of whom shall be a physician with a primary care specialty who practices in an urban area; 1 of whom shall be a physician with a medical subspecialty; 1 of whom shall be an advanced practice nurse, authorized under section 80B of said chapter 112, who practices in a rural area; 1 of whom shall be an advanced practice nurse, authorized under said section 80B of said chapter 112, who practices in an urban area; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Organization of Nurse Executives; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Academy of Family Physicians; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Workforce Board Association; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts League of Community Health Centers, Inc.; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Medical Society; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Center for Nursing, Inc.; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Nurses Association; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Association of Registered Nurses; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Hospital Association, Inc.; and 1 of whom shall be a representative of Health Care For All, Inc. Members of the council shall be appointed for terms of 3 years or until a successor is appointed. Members shall be eligible to be reappointed and shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses reasonably incurred in the performance of their duties. Vacancies of unexpired terms shall be filled within 60 days by the appropriate appointing authority.  The members of the council shall annually elect a chair, vice chair and secretary and may adopt by-laws governing the affairs of the council.  The council shall meet at least bimonthly, at other times as determined by its rules, and when requested by any 8 members.  (c) The council shall advise the center on: (i) trends in access to primary care and physician subspecialties and nursing services; (ii) the development and administration of the loan repayment program, established under section 25N, including criteria to identify underserved areas in the commonwealth; (iii) solutions to address identified health care workforces shortages; and (iv) the center's annual report to the general court.
Chapter 111: Healthcare workforce advisory council
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 72 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  (a) There shall be a healthcare workforce advisory council within, but not subject to the control of, the health care provider workforce center established by section 25L. The council shall advise the center on the capacity of the healthcare workforce to provide timely, effective, culturally competent, quality physician, nursing, physician assistant, behavioral, substance use disorder and mental health services.  (b) The council shall consist of: 19 members to be appointed by the governor: 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Extended Care Federation; 1 of whom shall be a physician with a primary care specialty designation who practices in a rural area; 1 of whom shall be a physician with a primary care specialty who practices in an urban area; 1 of whom shall be a physician with a medical subspecialty; 1 of whom shall be an advanced practice nurse, authorized under section 80B of said chapter 112, who practices in a rural area; 1 of whom shall be an advanced practice nurse, authorized under said section BOB of said chapter 112, who practices in an urban area; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Organization of Nurse Executives; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Academy of Family Physicians; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Workforce Board Association; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts League of Community Health Centers, Inc.; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Medical Society; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Center for Nursing, Inc.; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Nurses Association; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Association of Registered Nurses; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Hospital Association, Inc.; 1 of whom shall be a representative from the Massachusetts Association of Physician Assistants; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Chiropractic Society; 1 of whom shall be a representative of Health Care For All, Inc.; and 1 of whom shall be a behavioral, substance use disorder and mental health professional. Members of the council shall be appointed for terms of 3 years or until a successor is appointed. Members shall be eligible to be reappointed and shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses reasonably incurred in the performance of their duties. Vacancies of unexpired terms shall be filled within 60 days by the appropriate appointing authority.  The council shall meet at least bimonthly, at other times as determined by its rules and when requested by any 8 members.  (c) The council shall advise the center on: (1) trends in access to primary care and physician subspecialties, nursing, physician assistant and behavioral, substance use disorder and mental health services; (2) the development and administration of the loan repayment program, established under section 25N, including criteria to identify underserved areas in the commonwealth; and (3) solutions to address identified health care workforces shortages; and (iv) the center's annual report to the general court.
    </text>
</law>