<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="114" order_by="114" level="3">Cemeteries And Burials</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>29</section_number>
    <catch_line>Indivisible Character Of Lots; Vesting; Limitations And Conditions;  Right Of Interment; Designation Of Representation Of Lot; Record</catch_line>
    <order_by>29</order_by>
    <text>
        Lots in cemeteries incorporated under section one, tombs in public cemeteries in cities and lots and tombs in public cemeteries in towns, shall be held indivisible, and upon the decease of a proprietor of such lot the title thereto shall vest in the heirs at law or devisees of the deceased subject to the following limitations and conditions: If the deceased leaves a spouse and children, they shall have the possession, care and control of said lot or tomb in common during the life of such surviving spouse. If the deceased leaves a spouse and no children, said spouse shall have possession, care and control of such lots or tombs during life. If the deceased leaves children and no spouse, they shall have in common the possession, care and control of such lots or tombs during their joint lives, and the survivor of them during his life. The persons in possession, care and control of such lots or tombs may erect a monument and make other permanent improvements thereon. The surviving spouse shall have a right of permanent interment for his own body in such lot or tomb, but it may be removed therefrom to some other family lot or tomb with the consent of the heirs. If two or more persons are entitled to the possession, care and control of such lot or tomb, they shall designate in writing to the clerk of the corporation, or if it is a tomb or lot in a public cemetery, to the board of cemetery commissioners, if any, or to the town clerk, which of their number shall represent the lot; and in default of such designation, the board of trustees or directors of the corporation, the board of cemetery commissioners, if any, or the board of health if such lots or tombs are in public cemeteries in towns, shall enter of record which of said persons shall represent the lot during such default. The surviving spouse may release his right in such lot, but no conveyance or devise by any other person shall deprive him of such right.
    </text>
</law>