<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>227</section_number>
    <catch_line>Palliative Care And End Of Life Options;  Distribution Of Information Regarding Availability</catch_line>
    <order_by>227</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 103 effective November 4, 2012.]  (a) As used in this section the following terms shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:  "Appropriate'', consistent with applicable legal, health and professional standards, the patient's clinical and other circumstances and the patient's reasonably known wishes and beliefs.  "Attending health care practitioner'', a physician or nurse practitioner who has primary responsibility for the care and treatment of the patient; provided that if more than 1 physician or nurse practitioner share that responsibility, each of them shall have a responsibility under this section, unless there is an agreement to assign that responsibility to 1 such person.  "Palliative care'', a health care treatment, including interdisciplinary end-of-life care and consultation with patients and family members, to prevent or relieve pain and suffering and to enhance the patient's quality of life, including hospice care.  "Terminal illness or condition'', an illness or condition which can reasonably be expected to cause death within 6 months, whether or not treatment is provided.  (b) The commissioner shall adopt regulations requiring each licensed hospital, skilled nursing facility, health center or assisted living facility to distribute to appropriate patients in its care information regarding the availability of palliative care and end-of-life options.  (c) If a patient is diagnosed with a terminal illness or condition, the patient's attending health care practitioner shall offer to provide the patient with information and counseling regarding palliative care and end-of-life options appropriate for the patient, including, but not limited to: (i) the range of options appropriate for the patient; (ii) the prognosis, risks and benefits of the various options; and (iii) the patient's legal rights to comprehensive pain and symptom management at the end-of-life. The information and counseling may be provided orally or in writing. Where the patient lacks capacity to reasonably understand and make informed choices relating to palliative care, the attending health care practitioner shall provide information and counseling under this section to a person with authority to make health care decisions for that patient. The attending health care practitioner may arrange for information and counseling under this section to be provided by another professionally qualified individual.  If the attending health care practitioner is not willing to provide the patient with information and counseling under this section, the attending health care practitioner shall arrange for another physician or nurse practitioner to do so or shall refer or transfer the patient to another physician or nurse practitioner willing to do so.  Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit a healthcare professional to offer to provide information about assisted suicide or the prescribing of medication to end life.  (d) The department shall consult with the Hospice and Palliative Care Federation of Massachusetts in developing educational documents, rules and regulations related to this section.
    </text>
</law>