<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87Z</section_number>
    <catch_line>Reciprocity Registration; Fees; Temporary License</catch_line>
    <order_by>87Z</order_by>
    <text>
        The board may register, without examination, any hairdresser, operator, manicurist or aesthetician who has been registered as such under the laws of another state, which, in the opinion of the board, maintains a standard substantially equivalent to that of the commonwealth, and in which hairdressers, operators, manicurists or aestheticians registered in the commonwealth are given like recognition, upon payment of the fee prescribed in section eighty-seven CC. Any person who has completed in another state, or in a school in the commonwealth supported by public funds, a course of professional training, substantially equivalent to that required by section eighty-seven V, and who, after application accompanied by an examination fee as prescribed in section eighty-seven CC for a first examination, or a fee as prescribed in said section eighty-seven CC for a second or subsequent examination, passes an examination satisfactory to the board, may be registered by the board as an operator. 
Any hairdresser operator, manicurist or aesthetician who has been registered as such under the laws of another state which, in the opinion of the board, maintains a standard substantially equivalent to that of the commonwealth but does not have a reciprocal registration agreement with the commonwealth, and who has filed an application for registration under sections eighty-seven T to eighty-seven JJ, inclusive, may, upon request to the board, be granted a temporary license authorizing him to practice as such hairdresser, operator, manicurist or aesthetician, as the case may be. Such temporary license shall bear an expiration date of six months from date of issuance and the address where such temporary licensee is employed. Only one such temporary license shall be granted to such applicant. The fees for such temporary licenses shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven. If an applicant fails to appear for examination in accordance with the provisions of section eighty-seven KK he shall forfeit such temporary license, as well as the fee for examination. There shall be no refund once a temporary license has been issued to the applicant. 
The word “state” as used in this section shall include the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States or foreign country, state or province.
    </text>
</law>