<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Limited Registration; Fees; Qualifications; Revocation</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        An applicant for limited registration under this section may, upon payment of a fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, be registered by the board as an intern, fellow or medical officer for such time as it may subscribe if he furnishes the board with satisfactory proof of the following:— 
1. He is eighteen or over and of good moral character. 
2. (a) He has creditably completed two years of a premedical course of study in a college or university and not less than three and one-half years of study in a legally chartered medical school having the power to grant degrees in medicine; or (b) if he is not enrolled in or a graduate of a legally chartered medical school in the United States or Canada, he is the holder of a standard certificate granted after an examination by the Education Council for Foreign Medical Graduates, unless granted an exemption by the board; or (c) he has completed two years of premedical education in a college or university of the United States, Canada or Puerto Rico and if he has studied medicine in a medical school outside the United States, Canada or Puerto Rico which is recognized by the World Health Organization, has completed all the formal requirements for the degree corresponding to doctor of medicine, except internship and social service, and has completed a year of clinical clerkship approved by the liaison committee on medical education of the American Medical Association. 
3. He has been appointed an intern, fellow or medical officer in a hospital or other institution of the commonwealth, or of a county or municipality thereof, or in a hospital or clinic which is incorporated under the laws of the commonwealth or in a clinic which is affiliated with a hospital licensed by the department of public health under authority of section seventy-one of chapter one hundred and eleven, or in an out-patient clinic operated by the department of mental health, or in the department of public health for duty in clinics or in programs operated or approved by the department of public health, or in programs approved by the board of registration in medicine in the commonwealth and leading toward certification by specialty boards recognized by the American Medical Association. 
Such limited registration shall entitle the said applicant to practice medicine only in the hospital, institution, clinic or program designated on his certificate of limited registration, or outside such hospital, institution, clinic or program for the treatment, under supervision of one of its medical officers who is a duly registered physician, of persons accepted by it as patients, or in any hospital, institution, clinic or program affiliated for training purposes with the hospital, institution, clinic or program designated on such certificate, which affiliation is approved by the board and in any case under regulations established by such hospital, institution, clinic or program. The name of any hospital, institution, clinic or program so affiliated and so approved shall also be indicated on such certificate. Limited registration under this section may be revoked at any time by the board.
    </text>
</law>