<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24B1/2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Pharmacist Collaborative Practice Agreements; Collaborative Drug Therapy Management</catch_line>
    <order_by>24B1/2</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section and section 24B3/4 the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     In order for a pharmacist to enter into a collaborative practice agreement, the pharmacist shall: (1) hold a current license to practice pharmacy in the commonwealth and currently be engaged in pharmacy practice in the commonwealth; (2) have at least $1,000,000 of professional liability insurance; (3) have earned a doctor of pharmacy degree or have completed 5 years of experience as a licensed pharmacist or the equivalent; (4) agree to devote a portion of his practice to the defined drug therapy area that the pharmacist shall co-manage; and (5) agree to complete, in each year of the agreement, at least 5 additional contact hours or 0.5 continuing education units of board-approved continuing education that addresses areas of practice generally related to collaborative practice agreements.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Collaborative drug therapy management shall only be allowed in the following settings: (1) hospitals licensed pursuant to section 51 of chapter 111, subject to approval by the medical staff executive committee at a licensed hospital or designee; (2) long-term care facilities licensed pursuant to section 71 of chapter 111, subject to approval by the long-term care facilities’ medical director or designee; (3) inpatient or outpatient hospice settings licensed pursuant to section 57D of chapter 111, subject to approval by the hospice’s medical director or designee; (4) ambulatory care clinics licensed pursuant to section 51 of chapter 111, with on-site supervision by the attending physician and a collaborating pharmacist, subject to approval by the ambulatory care clinic’s medical staff executive committee or designee, or medical director or designee; (5) a collaborating pharmacist in a retail drug business, as registered in section 38 of chapter 112 and limited by this section, with supervision by a physician according to the terms of his collaborative practice agreement and limited to the following: patients 18 years of age or older; an extension by 30 days of current drug therapy prescribed by the supervising physician; and administration of vaccines or the modification of dosages of medications prescribed by the supervising physician for asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, congestive heart failure, HIV or AIDS, osteoporosis and co-morbidities identified by the supervising physician for the individual patient along with the primary diagnosis. The collaborative practice agreement shall specifically reference each disease state being co-managed. A patient shall be referred by a supervising physician to that physician’s collaborating pharmacist and shall be given notice of the collaboration and shall consent to the collaboration. No collaborative practice agreement in the retail drug business setting may permit the prescribing of schedule II through V controlled substances, as defined in section 3 of chapter 94C. A pharmacist in the retail setting, who has a collaborative practice agreement with a supervising physician which specifically allows initial prescriptions for referred patients of the supervising physician, may issue prescriptions for schedule VI controlled substances, as defined in clause 6 of section 3 of chapter 94C. Such prescriptions shall be for a patient diagnosis specified in the supervising physician’s individual referral of that patient. A copy of the prescription shall be sent to the supervising physician within 24 hours.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A retail drug business practicing in collaborative drug therapy management under this section shall not be required to register as a Health Facility under 105 CMR 700.004(A)(2)(d).
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A physician or a physician group may hire pharmacists for the purpose of practicing collaborative drug therapy management under a collaborative practice agreement, as defined in subsection (a), for the benefit of a patient of that physician or physician group. No retail pharmacy may employ a physician for the purpose of maintaining, establishing or entering into a collaborative practice agreement with a patient. Nothing shall prohibit a retail pharmacy from hiring a physician or licensed medical practitioner for the purpose of conducting quality assurance reviews of its pharmacists that are engaged in the practice of collaborative drug therapy.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>