<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>192A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Field Testing And Approval Of New Methods Of Removing Paint And Other Materials</catch_line>
    <order_by>192A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  The director shall investigate, field test and approve new methods of removing or covering paint, plaster, or other materials containing dangerous levels of lead that facilitate compliance with section one hundred and ninety-seven with greater efficiency, safety or economy. The director shall consult with the department of labor and workforce development prior to field testing or approval of new methods of removal or covering to ensure that these methods are consistent with regulations and laws concerning the occupational safety and health of workers engaged in deleading operations. The director shall establish a task force composed of appropriate representatives of the public and private sectors to review, evaluate and recommend such new methods. The director may contract with persons to support research and development of such new methods.
Chapter 111: Field testing and approval of new methods of removing paint and other materials
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 115 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  The director shall investigate, field test and approve new methods of removing or covering paint, plaster, or other materials containing dangerous levels of lead that facilitate compliance with section one hundred and ninety-seven with greater efficiency, safety or economy. The director shall consult with the department of labor standards prior to field testing or approval of new methods of removal or covering to ensure that these methods are consistent with regulations and laws concerning the occupational safety and health of workers engaged in deleading operations. The director shall establish a task force composed of appropriate representatives of the public and private sectors to review, evaluate and recommend such new methods. The director may contract with persons to support research and development of such new methods.
    </text>
</law>