<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23S</section_number>
    <catch_line>Examination Of Candidates; Application For License; Renewal Of License</catch_line>
    <order_by>23S</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The board shall examine applicants for licensure at such times and places as it may determine and shall conduct at least two such examinations in each calendar year. The board shall establish examination and testing procedures to enable the board to ascertain the competency of persons wishing to be licensed as qualified respiratory therapists and may utilize any existing national examinations that meet such requirements. Applications for such licenses, signed and sworn by the applicants, shall be made on forms furnished by the board. An applicant who furnished satisfactory proof that he is of good moral character and that he has met the educational and clinical requirements set forth in sections twenty-three T to twenty-three X, inclusive, shall upon payment of a fee determined by the secretary of administration and finance, be examined by the board, and if found qualified, and if he passes the examination, shall be licensed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Every person licensed shall, at such times as determined by the board, apply to the board for renewal of his license, document continuing education as may be required by the board, and pay a fee determined by the secretary of administration and finance to the board and thereupon the board shall issue a license showing the holder is entitled to practice for the period covered by said payment. The board may provide for the late renewal of a license which has lapsed and may require the payment of a late fee, or an examination, or continuing education, or supervised experience prior to issuing said late renewal license.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>