<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Application Of Secs. 2 To 6 And Sec. 8</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        Sections two to six, inclusive, and section eight shall not be held to discriminate against any particular school or system of medicine, to prohibit medical or surgical service in a case of emergency, or to prohibit the domestic administration of family remedies. They shall not apply to a professional nurse with appropriate education in the practice of the profession as defined by section eighty B; to a student of medicine as provided in section nine A, while engaged in the practice of medicine as authorized by said section; to a physician or surgeon resident in another state who is a legal practitioner therein, when in actual consultation with a legal practitioner of the commonwealth; to a physician authorized to practice medicine in another state, when he is called as the family physician to attend a person temporarily abiding in the commonwealth; to a physician authorized to practice medicine in another state or country, when he is providing medical services only to athletes or team personnel attending a sporting event sponsored by the United States Olympic Committee or a World Cup Organizing Committee; nor to registered pharmacists in prescribing gratuitously, clairvoyants or persons practicing hypnotism, magnetic healing, mind cure, massage, Christian Science or cosmopathic method of healing, if they do not violate any provisions of section six. Sections two and eight shall not apply to an intern or medical officer registered as provided in section nine, while engaged in the practice of medicine as authorized by said section.
    </text>
</law>