<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>89</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>89</order_by>
    <text>
        For the purposes of this section and sections ninety to ninety-seven, inclusive, the following words shall, unless the context requires otherwise, have the following meanings:— 
“Board”, the board of registration of chiropractors established by section sixty-four of chapter thirteen. 
“Chiropractic”, the science of locating, and removing interference with the transmission or expression of nerve force in the human body, by the correction of misalignments or subluxations of the bony articulation and adjacent structures, more especially those of the vertebra column and pelvis, for the purpose of restoring and maintaining health. It shall exclude operative surgery, prescription or use of drugs or medicines, the practice of obstetrics, the treatment of infectious diseases, and internal examinations whether or not diagnostic instruments are used except that the X-ray and analytical instruments may be used solely for the purposes of chiropractic examinations. Nothing in this definition shall exclude the use of supportive procedures and therapy, including braces, traction, heat, cold, sound, electricity, and dietary and nutritional advice, as treatment supplemental to a chiropractic adjustment. 
“Chiropractic facility”, a place, office, clinic or establishment in which chiropractic treatment is provided or in which business and patient records related to chiropractic treatment are used or stored which has been registered by the board pursuant to section 94A. 
“Chiropractor”, a person who lawfully practices chiropractic. 
“License renewal certificate,” a certificate issued annually by the board to a registered chiropractor upon payment of the license fee as provided in section ninety-six, and upon presentation of satisfactory evidence to the board that said chiropractor has completed the prescribed educational requirements for renewal.
    </text>
</law>