<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>138</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>138</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this section and sections one hundred and thirty-nine to one hundred and forty-seven, inclusive, the following words shall have the following meanings, unless the context clearly indicates a different meaning: 
“Audiologist”, any person who is duly licensed as an audiologist in the commonwealth and who engages in the practice of audiology. 
“Audiology”, the application of principles, methods and procedures of measurement, prediction, evaluation, testing, counseling, consultation and remediation related to the development and disorders of speech, language and learning for the purposes of identifying, evaluating or modifying an individual’s hearing and the planning, direction or participation in identification and hearing conservation programs. Any representation to the public by title or by description of services, methods or procedures for the evaluation, examination, counseling or remediation of persons suffering or suspected of suffering from conditions or disorders affecting hearing shall be considered to be the practice of audiology. Remediation includes, but is not limited to, hearing aid evaluation, recommendation, fitting and dispensing and aural habilitation or rehabilitation. 
“Audiology assistant”, a person duly certified in accordance with section 139 who assists in the practice of audiology and who works under the supervision and direction of a duly licensed audiologist. 
“Board”, the board of licensure for speech-language pathology and audiology. 
“Speech-language pathologist”, any person who is duly licensed as a speech-language pathologist in the commonwealth and who engages in the practice of speech-language pathology. 
“Speech-language pathology”, the application of principles, methods and procedures of measurement, prediction, evaluation, testing, counseling, consultation and remediation related to the development and disorders of speech and language. Any representation to the public by title or by description of services, methods or procedures for the evaluation, examination, counseling or remediation of persons suffering or suspected of suffering from conditions or disorders affecting speech and language shall be considered to be the practice of speech-language pathology. 
“Speech-language pathology assistant”, a person duly certified in accordance with section 139 who assists in the practice of speech-language pathology and who works under the supervision and direction of a duly licensed speech-language pathologist.
    </text>
</law>