<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>56D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Schools Of Veterinary Medicine; Institutional License</catch_line>
    <order_by>56D</order_by>
    <text>
        The board shall have the authority to grant to any school of veterinary medicine located in the commonwealth an institutional license, upon the payment of an annual fee of twenty-five dollars, under which veterinarians, who are not otherwise licensed as herein provided, may practice veterinary medicine if such practice is conducted in conjunction with their full-time employment by such school. An institutional license shall be renewed yearly and shall be issued and renewed upon the determination by the board that the school meets the recording and reporting requirements contained herein and as may be further defined by rules adopted by the board pursuant to its authority under section fifty-four. 
The board shall review the credentials of any person who applies to practice under an institutional license, and if such person is a graduate of a school or college of veterinary medicine accredited or approved in any state or country and is otherwise approved by the board, the board shall then register the name of such approved applicant upon its public record and notify the licensed school of such approval. A licensed school shall annually submit to the board a list of the names of persons who are practicing, or who seek to practice, under its institutional license. 
An applicant aggrieved by the refusal of the board to act favorably on his credentials, or a school aggrieved by the refusal of the board to issue or renew an institutional license, shall be entitled to have a review of such action by a justice of the superior court, whose decision shall be final. 
The board, after notice and hearing, may, by a vote of the majority of its membership, for any cause set forth in section fifty-nine, revoke or suspend the privilege of a veterinarian to practice under an institutional license.
    </text>
</law>