<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87OOO</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing Without Examination</catch_line>
    <order_by>87OOO</order_by>
    <text>
        The board may, upon the payment of a fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, grant, without examination, a license to practice electrolysis, and issue a certificate, to any person licensed or registered under the laws of any other state, which state, in the opinion of the board, shall require a degree of competency equal to that required of applicants for licensure as electrologists in this commonwealth, and which extends a like courtesy to electrologists licensed in this commonwealth. 
The board shall, upon the payment of a fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, examine any person who makes application, upon a form furnished by the board, for a license to practice electrolysis, provided such applicant furnishes the board with satisfactory proof that he is eighteen years of age or over, of good moral character, and a citizen of the United States or has filed a declaration of intention to become a citizen of the United States, and furnishes the board with documentary proof that he has been actively engaged in the practice of electrolysis in another state for not less than ten years immediately preceding the date of his application. If such person passes such examination, the board shall grant him a license to practice electrolysis and shall issue him a certificate signed by the chairman and secretary of the board in testimony thereof. Such license shall be valid until August first of the next odd year and may be renewed for a two year period upon application thereof upon a form furnished by the board. The fee for such renewal shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven.
    </text>
</law>