<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Council On Radiation Protection</catch_line>
    <order_by>4F</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be an advisory council on radiation protection consisting of the commissioners of public health, labor and industries, public safety, and administration, the personnel administrator, the director of civil defense, and six persons to be appointed by the governor, of whom two shall hold the degree of doctor in medicine or dental medicine and shall be specialists in the field of ionizing radiation injuries, one shall have training or experience in radiology, one in radiation or health physics, one in radiation law, and one in nuclear engineering or in the industrial application of ionizing radiation. Upon the expiration of the term of office of an appointive member, his successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of six years. One of the appointive members shall be designated chairman of the council by the governor. The members of the council shall serve without compensation and shall not be reimbursed for any expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties. 
The advisory council shall meet at least twice a year at the call of the chairman or by vote of a majority of the members of the council. It may hold public hearings but shall not have the power to summon witnesses nor to require the production of books, records and papers. It shall consider and make recommendations to the governor, the general court, and the various departments of the executive branch as to the development, growth, and status of all substances, things, and apparatus within the commonwealth capable of emitting ionizing radiation.
    </text>
</law>