<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111" order_by="111" level="3">Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>142M</section_number>
    <catch_line>Motor Vehicle Emissions Inspection And Repair; Definitions; Rules And Regulations; Inspection Facilities; Waivers; Quality Assurance Program; Violations</catch_line>
    <order_by>142M</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall have the following meanings unless the context clearly requires otherwise:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Pursuant to this section, the department shall develop the standards, requirements and rules and regulations for the emissions component of the periodic staggered inspection program established pursuant to section 7A of chapter 90. It shall be the responsibility of the department, under authority of this chapter, to provide the direct primary oversight of the operational and environmental aspects of the emissions component of the inspection program. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the leasing or purchasing of a dynamometer, an emissions analyzer or any necessary computer hardware or software by an emissions inspection facility from the network contractor; provided, however, the network contractor shall provide access to the data acquisition and management network to any emissions inspection facility who purchases or leases a dynamometer, emissions analyzer or necessary computer hardware or software through sources other than the network contractor so long as such equipment complies with testing equipment specifications as established by the commissioner in consultation with the registrar. Any requests for proposals for contracting with a network contractor shall require that the commissioner, in consultation with the registrar, shall have oversight over the charge assessed by the network contractor for access to the data acquisition and management network to emissions inspection facilities who purchased equipment through sources other than the network contractor; provided, however, that notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the commissioner and the registrar may require emissions inspection facilities to obtain, lease or purchase such equipment from the network contractor upon the determination that allowing emissions inspection facilities to lease or purchase such equipment through sources other than the network contractor would result in an increase in the inspection fee. Said determination shall be made by the commissioner and registrar, in consultation with the secretary of administration and finance, only upon a finding that no feasible option exists by which emissions inspection facilities may obtain such equipment through sources other than the network contractor without increasing the inspection fee. The amount of said fee for said inspection shall be uniform statewide. It shall be the responsibility of the registrar, under authority of chapter 90, to license inspection facilities and inspectors and to register vehicles complying with the inspection program requirements and to conduct audit and enforcement activities related thereto. The department, on behalf of the commonwealth, shall be responsible for submitting all appropriate and required program regulations on the motor vehicle emissions component of the inspection and maintenance program and applicable revisions to the state implementation plan to the United States Environmental Protection Agency, in accordance with the requirements of the federal Clean Air Act. The department, in conjunction with the registry, may develop and implement a demonstration or pilot of the motor vehicle emissions inspection program or elements of such program to evaluate the effectiveness of such program, or elements of such program, in successfully reducing air contaminants emitted by motor vehicles in the commonwealth as required by federal law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The commissioner shall establish rules and regulations implementing the motor vehicle emissions component of the inspection program required by section 7A of chapter 90. Such rules and regulations may reflect a phased-in schedule for the motor vehicles subject to the emissions component of the inspection program; provided, however, that such phase-in shall not begin prior to July 1, 1998. The department may continue to implement the motor vehicle emissions inspection program established pursuant to section 142J of chapter 111 while phasing-in the new requirements of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The commissioner and the registrar shall establish programs for public information and consumer protection. The commissioner shall establish procedures and requirements for the network contractor to ensure maximum convenience to the motorist.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The commissioner, in consultation with the registrar, shall develop, establish and implement a quality control program to ensure the accuracy and integrity of the emissions component of the inspection program. Such quality control program may include, but not be limited to, procedures for: (i) calibrating, operating and maintaining emissions inspection equipment; (ii) documenting the results from the performance of such calibration, operation and maintenance; and (iii) transmitting such documentation to the department.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The commissioner and the registrar or their designees shall have the authority to enforce any provision of this section and may establish rules and regulations pursuant to such authority. Such enforcement authority shall permit officers or agents of the department or the registry to enter the premises of any motor vehicle inspection facility or any contractor to protect the public health and the environment, implement the quality control and quality assurance requirements of this section and for any other reasonable purpose related to implementation and enforcement of the motor vehicle inspection and maintenance program as determined by the commissioner and the registrar.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>