<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="111J" order_by="111J" level="3">Alcohol And Drug Counselors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Duties Of Department</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        The department shall establish the requirements for the licensing of alcohol and drug counselors practicing in the commonwealth, evaluate the qualifications of applicants, supervise licensing examinations, collect fees established for licensing and examination, grant and issue licenses to alcohol and drug counselors who satisfy the department’s requirements for licensing, require and establish continuing education requirements, investigate complaints and take appropriate disciplinary action to protect the public health, safety and welfare. 
The department shall establish requirements for licensed alcohol and drug counselors I and II and may establish other reasonable classifications for alcohol and drug counselors as it finds necessary and appropriate, taking into consideration different levels of education, training and work experience. 
The department shall approve and issue certificates of approval of programs for the training of alcohol and drug counselors. The department shall maintain a list of approved programs as well as a current roster of persons serving as licensed alcohol and drug counselors in the commonwealth. 
The department shall promulgate such rules and regulations as it deems necessary to implement the provisions of this chapter including rules and regulations establishing the educational and professional requirements for licensing alcohol and drug counselors, establishing fees for licensing and examination and governing the practice and employment of licensed alcohol and drug counselors to promote the public health, safety and welfare.
    </text>
</law>