<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="16" order_by="16" level="2">Public Health</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="112" order_by="112" level="3">Registration Of Certain Professions And Occupations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Schools For Training Medical Laboratory Technologists; Inspection;  Approval; Approving Authority</catch_line>
    <order_by>2B</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall operate or maintain a school for training medical laboratory technologists unless such school has been approved in writing by the approving authority established by section two, provided, however, that for the purposes of this section only, the membership of said authority shall be increased by three members to be appointed for a term of three years each by the governor with the advice and consent of the council, one member to be a hospital administrator or hospital trustee, who shall be a member of the Massachusetts Hospital Association; one member to be a medical laboratory technologist meeting the training and experience requirements of the American Medical Association, to be appointed from a list submitted by the Massachusetts Association of Technologists and Laboratory Technicians, Incorporated; and one member to be a physician, appointed from a list submitted by the section of physiology and pathology of the Massachusetts Medical Society. Said additional members shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for their travel and other reasonable expenses incidental to the performance of their duties. 
A school for training of medical laboratory technologists shall mean a school maintained or classes conducted for the purpose of training two or more individuals to perform or assist in the performance of various medical laboratory procedures used in the diagnosis, treatment and study of disease, but shall not be construed to apply to duly accredited colleges and graduate schools teaching courses in physiology, biochemistry, bacteriology, clinical pathology or the various other medical sciences. 
The provisions of section two relating to the inspection and approval of colleges, universities and medical schools by the approving authority shall apply to schools for the training of medical laboratory technologists. 
Whoever being the educational director or the business director of a school for training of medical laboratory technologists violates the provisions of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
    </text>
</law>