<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Counties And County Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35" level="3">County Treasurers, State Supervision Of County Accounts And County Finances</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Accumulated Vacation Allowance; Payment Upon Death Or Separation From Service</catch_line>
    <order_by>19A</order_by>
    <text>
        In any county which accepts this section by vote of the county commissioners, advances of pay may be made to any county officer or employee in advance of his regular vacation to the extent of the pay to which he is about to be entitled during such vacation period under such regulations as the county treasurer may prescribe. 
Upon the death of a county employee who is eligible for vacation under the rules of the county personnel board, payment shall be made in an amount equal to the vacation allowance as earned in the vacation year prior to the employee’s death but which had not been granted, and, in addition, that portion of the vacation allowance earned in the vacation year during which the employee died, up to the time of his separation from the payroll; provided, that no monetary or other allowance has already been made therefor. The county commissioners, upon request of the appointing officer of the deceased employee, shall authorize the payment of such compensation upon the establishment of a valid claim therefor, in the following order of precedence:— First: To the surviving beneficiary or beneficiaries, if any, lawfully designated by the employee under the employee’s retirement system; Second: If there be no such designated beneficiary, to the estate of the deceased. 
Employees who are eligible for vacation under the rules of said county personnel board whose services terminated by dismissal, through no fault or delinquency of their own, or by retirement, shall be paid an amount equal to the vacation allowance as earned in the vacation year prior to such dismissal or retirement which had not been granted, and, in addition, that portion of the vacation allowance earned in the vacation year during which such dismissal or retirement occurred, up to the time of separation; provided, that no monetary or other allowance has already been made therefor.
    </text>
</law>