<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Counties And County Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="38" order_by="38" level="3">Medical Examiners And Inquests</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2A</section_number>
    <catch_line>State And Local Multidisciplinary Child Fatality Review Teams</catch_line>
    <order_by>2A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall have the following meanings:-
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     There shall be a state child fatality review team within the office of the chief medical examiner. Notwithstanding section 172 of chapter 6, members of the state team shall be subject to criminal offender record checks to be conducted by the colonel of the state police, on behalf of the chief medical examiner. All members shall serve without compensation for their duties associated with membership on the state team.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     develop model investigative and data collection protocols for local teams;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     provide information to local teams and law enforcement agencies for the purpose of the protection of children;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     provide training and written materials to local teams to assist them in carrying out their duties;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     review reports from local teams;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     study the incidence and causes of child fatalities and near fatalities in the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     analyze community, public and private agency involvement with the children and their families prior to and subsequent to fatalities or near fatalities;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     develop a protocol for the collection of data regarding fatalities and near fatalities and provide training to local teams on the protocol;
        </section>
        <section prefix="viii">
    	     develop and implement rules and procedures necessary for its own operation; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="ix">
    	     provide the governor, the general court and the public with annual written reports, subject to confidentiality restrictions, which shall include, but not be limited to, the state team’s findings and recommendations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     There shall be a local child fatality review team in each of the 11 districts headed by a district attorney. Notwithstanding section 172 of chapter 6, members of a local team shall be subject to criminal offender record checks to be conducted by the district attorney. All members shall serve without compensation for their duties associated with membership on a local team.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     review, establish and implement model protocols from the state team;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     review, subject to the approval of the local district attorney, all individual fatalities and near fatalities in accordance with the established protocol;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     meet periodically, but at least 4 times per calendar year, to review the status of fatality and near fatality cases and recommend methods of improving coordination of services between member agencies;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     collect, maintain and provide confidential data as required by the state team; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     provide law enforcement or other agencies with information for the purposes of the protection of children.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     information and records relevant to the cause of the fatality or near fatality maintained by providers of medical or other care, treatment or services, including dental and mental health care;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     information and records relevant to the cause of the fatality or near fatality maintained by any state, county or local government agency including, but not limited to, birth certificates, medical examiner investigative data, parole and probation information records, and law enforcement data post-disposition, except that certain law enforcement records may be exempted by the local district attorney;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     information and records of any provider of social services, including the state department of children and families, relevant to the child or the child’s family, that the local team deems relevant to the review; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     demographic information relevant to the child and the child’s immediate family, including but not limited to, address, age, race, gender, and economic status. The district attorney may enforce this paragraph by seeking an order of the superior court.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Any privilege or restriction on disclosure established pursuant to chapter 66A, section 70 of chapter 111, section 11 of chapter 111B, section 18 of 111E, chapters 112, 123, or sections 20B, 20J or 20K of chapter 233 or any other law relating to confidential communications shall not prohibit the disclosure of this information to the chair of the state team or a local team. Any information considered to be confidential pursuant to the aforementioned statutes may be submitted for a team’s review upon the determination of that team’s chair that the review of this information is necessary. The chair shall ensure that no information submitted for a team’s review is disseminated to parties outside the team. Under no circumstances shall any member of a team violate the confidentiality provisions set forth in the aforementioned statutes.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Members of a team, persons attending a team meeting and persons who present information to a team may not be questioned in any civil or criminal proceeding regarding information presented in or opinions formed as a result of a team meeting.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Information, documents and records of the state team or of a local team shall not be subject to subpoena, discovery or introduction into evidence in any civil or criminal proceeding; provided, however, that information, documents and records otherwise available from any other source shall not be immune from subpoena, discovery or introduction into evidence through these sources solely because they were presented during proceedings of a team or are maintained by a team.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Nothing in this section shall limit the powers and duties of the chief medical examiner or district attorneys.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>