<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="258D" order_by="258D" level="3">Compensation For Certain Erroneous Felony Convictions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Receipt Of Chapter</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Subsection (A) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (A) A court granting judicial relief consistent with the criteria set forth in subclause (a) of clause (ii) of subsection (B) of section 1 shall provide a copy of this chapter to an individual seeking such relief at the time the criteria of said subclause (a) of said clause (ii) of said subsection (B) of said section 1 are satisfied. Such individual shall be required to acknowledge receipt of a copy of this chapter in writing on a form established by the chief justice for administration and management of the trial court. This acknowledgement shall be entered on the docket by the court and shall be admissible in any proceeding filed by a claimant under this chapter.[ Subsection (A) as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 112 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (A) A court granting judicial relief consistent with the criteria set forth in subclause (a) of clause (ii) of subsection (B) of section 1 shall provide a copy of this chapter to an individual seeking such relief at the time the criteria of said subclause (a) of said clause (ii) of said subsection (B) of said section 1 are satisfied. Such individual shall be required to acknowledge receipt of a copy of this chapter in writing on a form established by the chief justice of the trial court. This acknowledgement shall be entered on the docket by the court and shall be admissible in any proceeding filed by a claimant under this chapter.  (B) The parole board, upon the issuance of a full pardon under section 152 of chapter 127, shall provide a copy of this chapter to an individual granted clemency at the time warrants necessary to grant the pardon are issued. Such individual shall be required to acknowledge receipt of a copy of this chapter in writing on a form established by the parole board, which shall be retained on file by the parole board as part of its official records and shall be admissible in any proceeding filed by a claimant under this chapter.  (C) If a claimant granted judicial relief or a full pardon shows he did not properly receive a copy of the information required by this section, he shall receive a 1 year extension on the 2 year time limit provided in section 8.
    </text>
</law>