<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255E" order_by="255E" level="3">Licensing Of Certain Mortgage Lenders And Brokers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Information On License; Changes; Notice Requirements</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        Each license shall state the address at which the business is to be conducted and shall state the name of the licensee. If a licensee intends to carry on such business at any place in addition to the address on the license, he shall so notify the commissioner, in writing, at least 30 days prior thereto, and he shall pay a fee for such additional location at a reasonable cost as determined by the commissioner. Such notice shall contain the address of any such additional location and such other information as the commissioner may require; provided, however, that any such business shall at all times be conducted in the name of the licensee as it appears on the license. A copy of such license shall be prominently posted in each place of business of the licensee. Such copies for places of business at addresses other than that appearing on the license may be obtained at a reasonable cost, as determined by the commissioner. Such license shall not be transferable or assignable and shall expire annually on a date determined by the commissioner. Any change of location or closing of a place of business of the licensee, either at the address stated on the license or at a place other than said address stated on the license, shall require prior written notice thereof to the commissioner. Such notice shall be in writing setting forth the reason therefor and shall be filed with the commissioner at least thirty days prior to any such relocation or closing. If there shall be any change among the members, officers, partners or directors of any licensee, the licensee shall notify the commissioner in a timely manner of the name, address and occupation of each new member, officer, partner or director, and provide such other information as the commissioner may require.
    </text>
</law>