<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255E" order_by="255E" level="3">Licensing Of Certain Mortgage Lenders And Brokers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Written Notice Of Intention To Prohibit; Statement Of Facts; Order Of Prohibition; Service</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Whenever the commissioner determines that any person has, directly or indirectly, violated any section of this chapter or any rule or regulation adopted thereunder, applicable to the conduct of the business of making or brokering mortgage loans on residential property in the commonwealth, or any order issued by the commissioner under this chapter or any written agreement entered between the licensee and the commissioner, the commissioner may serve upon that person a written notice of intention:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     to prohibit the person from performing in the capacity of a principal employee on behalf of any licensee for a period of time that the commissioner considers necessary;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     to prohibit the person from applying for or obtaining a license from the commissioner for a period up to 36 months following the effective date of an order issued under subsection (b) or (c); or
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     to prohibit the person from any further participation, in any manner, in the conduct of the affairs of a mortgage lender or mortgage broker in Massachusetts or to prohibit the person from being employed by, an agent of, or operating on behalf of a licensee under this chapter or any other business which requires a license from the commissioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A written notice issued under subsection (a) shall contain a written statement of the facts that support the prohibition and shall give notice of an opportunity for a hearing to be held thereon. The hearing shall be fixed for a date not more than 30 days after the date of service upon the commissioner of the request for a hearing. If the person fails to submit a request for a hearing within 20 days of service of notice under subsection (a), or otherwise fails to appear in person or by a duly authorized representative, the party shall be considered to have consented to the issuance of an order of prohibition in accordance with the notice.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In the event of the consent under subsection (b), or if after a hearing the commissioner finds that any of the grounds specified in the notice have been established, the commissioner may issue an order of prohibition in accordance with subsection (a) as the commissioner finds appropriate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     An order issued under subsection (b) or (c) shall be effective upon service upon the person. The commissioner shall also serve a copy of the order upon the licensee of which the person is an employee or on whose behalf the person is performing. The order shall remain in effect and enforceable until it is modified, terminated, suspended, or set aside by the commissioner or a court of competent jurisdiction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Except as consented to in writing by the commissioner, any person who, pursuant to an order issued under subsection (b) or (c), has been prohibited from participating in whole or in part in the conduct of the affairs of a mortgage lender or mortgage broker in Massachusetts may not, while the order is in effect, continue or commence to perform in the capacity of a principal employee, or otherwise participate in any manner, if so prohibited by order of the commissioner, in the conduct of the affairs of:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     any licensee under this chapter;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     any other business which requires a license from the commissioner; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     any bank, as defined under section 1 of chapter 167 or any subsidiary thereof.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>