<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255F" order_by="255F" level="3">Licensing Of Mortgage Loan Originators</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>License Or Exemption Required; Registration With Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System And Registry</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     No individual shall act as a mortgage loan originator with respect to any dwelling unless such person has first obtained a mortgage loan originator license from the commissioner or is exempt from the licensure requirement under subsection (b). No person shall knowingly employ or retain a mortgage loan originator unless the mortgage loan originator is licensed under this chapter or is exempt from the licensure requirement under subsection (b). Each licensed mortgage loan originator shall register with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry and shall maintain a valid unique identifier issued by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The following shall not be required to obtain a license pursuant to subsection (a): (i) registered mortgage loan originators; (ii) any person offering or negotiating a residential mortgage loan with or on behalf of an immediate family member; (iii) any person offering or negotiating a residential mortgage loan secured by a dwelling that served as the individual’s primary residence; (iv) any person admitted to practice law in the commonwealth negotiating the terms of a residential mortgage loan on behalf of a client as an ancillary matter to the person’s representation of the client, unless the person is compensated by a lender, a mortgage broker, or other mortgage loan originator or by any agent of such lender, mortgage broker, or other mortgage loan originator; (v) any person engaged solely as a loan processor or underwriter unless said person is acting as an independent contractor; (vi) any person that performs only real estate brokerage activities and is licensed or registered pursuant to sections 87PP to 87DDD1/2, inclusive, of chapter 112, unless the person is compensated by a lender, a mortgage broker, or other mortgage loan originator or by any agent of such lender, mortgage broker, or other mortgage loan originator; and (vii) any person solely involved in extensions of credit relating to timeshare plans, as that term is defined in 11 U.S.C. section 101(53D).
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The commissioner may promulgate rules and regulations for the administration and enforcement of this chapter.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>