<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="254" order_by="254" level="3">Liens On Buildings And Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25</section_number>
    <catch_line>Estate Less Than Fee Simple; Effect Of Sale</catch_line>
    <order_by>25</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. For text effective July 1, 2011, see below.] 
If the person for whom the labor has been performed or with whom the original contract has been entered into for the whole or any part of the erection, alteration, repair or removal of a building or structure upon land, or for furnishing material therefor, has an estate less than a fee simple in the land or if the property is subject to a mortgage or other encumbrance, the lien shall bind such person’s whole estate and interest in the property, and such estate or interest may be sold and the proceeds applied according to this chapter. 
Chapter 254: Estate less than fee simple; effect of sale [Text of section as amended by 2010, 424, Sec. 17 effective July 1, 2011 applicable as provided by 2010, 424, Sec. 20. See 2010, 424, Sec. 21. For text effective until July 1, 2011, see above.] 
If the person for whom the labor has been performed or with whom the original contract has been entered into for the whole or any part of the erection, alteration, repair or removal of a building or structure upon land, or for furnishing material or performing professional services therefor, has an estate less than a fee simple in the land or if the property is subject to a mortgage or other encumbrance, the lien shall bind such person’s whole estate and interest in the property, and such estate or interest may be sold and the proceeds applied according to this chapter.
    </text>
</law>