<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255F" order_by="255F" level="3">Licensing Of Mortgage Loan Originators</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Application For License; Furnishing Of Information To Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System And Registry; Waiver Or Modification Of Requirements Of Chapter</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Any person seeking a mortgage loan originator’s license pursuant to this chapter shall file an application, accompanied by the appropriate fee, with the division. Said application shall be made on a form to be furnished by the division, and shall require the applicant to state his name, the name and address of his employer, if any, and such other information as the division may require. The applicant shall, at a minimum, furnish to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry information concerning the applicant’s identity, including: (i) fingerprints for submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and any governmental agency or entity authorized to receive such information for a state, national and international criminal history background check; and (ii) personal history and experience in a form prescribed by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, including the submission of authorization for the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry and the commissioner to obtain: (1) an independent credit report obtained from a consumer reporting agency described in section 603(p) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act; and (2) information related to any administrative, civil or criminal findings by any governmental entity.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commissioner may enter into agreements with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry or other entities designated by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry to collect and maintain records and process transaction fees or other fees related to licensees or other persons subject to this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The commissioner may, for the purpose of participating in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, waive or modify any requirement of this chapter and may establish new requirements as reasonably necessary to participate in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The commissioner may use the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as a channeling agent for requesting information from the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the purposes of clause (i) and subclause (2) of clause (ii) of subsection (a) and distributing information to the Department of Justice or any governmental agency.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The commissioner may use the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as a channeling agent for requesting and distributing information to and from any source for the purposes of subclauses (1) and (2) of clause (ii) of subsection (a) as so directed by the commissioner.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>