<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255E" order_by="255E" level="3">Licensing Of Certain Mortgage Lenders And Brokers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of License By Commissioner; Notice Of License Denial;  Appeal</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        Upon the filing of an application for a license, if the commissioner finds that the financial responsibility, character, reputation, integrity and general fitness of the applicant, and of the partners or members thereof if the applicant is a partnership or association, and of the officers, directors and principal employees if the applicant is a corporation, are such as to warrant belief that the business will be operated honestly, fairly, soundly and efficiently in the public interest consistent with the purposes of this chapter, he shall thereupon issue the applicant a license to engage in the business of a mortgage lender or mortgage broker. If the commissioner shall not so find, he shall not issue a license and he shall notify the applicant of the denial. Within twenty days thereafter, he shall enter upon his records a written decision and findings containing the reasons supporting the denial and shall forthwith give written notice thereof by registered mail to the applicant. Within thirty days after the date of such notice, the applicant may appeal from such denial to the superior court for Suffolk county, sitting in equity. The court shall hear all pertinent evidence and determine the facts and upon the facts as so determined, review said denial and, as justice and equity may require, affirm the same or order the commissioner to issue such license. The commissioner shall approve or deny every application for a license within ninety days after the filing thereof, but any failure of the commissioner to act within such period shall not be deemed to be an approval of any such application.
    </text>
</law>