<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255F" order_by="255F" level="3">Licensing Of Mortgage Loan Originators</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Qualified Written Examination</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     An applicant for a mortgage loan originator’s license shall pass, in accordance with the standards established under this section, a qualified written examination developed by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry and administered by a test provider approved by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry based upon reasonable standards.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A written examination shall not be considered a qualified written examination for purposes of this section unless the test adequately measures the applicant’s knowledge and comprehension in appropriate subject areas, including, but not limited to: (i) ethics; (ii) federal law and regulation pertaining to mortgage origination; (iii) state law and regulation pertaining to mortgage origination; and (iv) federal and state law and regulation, including instruction on fraud, consumer protection, the nontraditional mortgage marketplace, and fair lending issues.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No person shall be considered to have passed the qualified written examination unless the person achieves a test score of not less than 75 per cent correct answers to questions. A person may retake the qualified written examination 3 consecutive times with each consecutive taking occurring at least 30 days after the preceding examination. Upon failing 3 consecutive written examinations, a person shall not be eligible to sit for another written examination for a period of at least 6 months. A licensed mortgage loan originator who fails to maintain a valid license for a period of 5 years or longer shall retake the test, not taking into account any time during which such individual is a registered mortgage loan originator.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>