<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="254" order_by="254" level="3">Liens On Buildings And Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Dissolution By Bond Recording; Labor And Materials; Form Of Bond</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person in interest may dissolve a lien under this chapter by recording or causing to be recorded in the registry of deeds in the county or district where the land lies, a bond of a surety company authorized to do business in Massachusetts and in a penal sum equal to the amount of the lien sought to be dissolved conditioned for the payment of any sum which the claimant may recover on his claim for labor or labor and materials. Upon the recording of the bond, the lien shall be dissolved. Notice of the recording shall be given to the claimant by serving on the claimant a copy of the notice of recording together with a copy of the bond by an officer qualified to serve civil process or by delivering same to the claimant. The claimant may enforce the bond by a civil action commenced within ninety days after the later of the filing of the statement required by section 8 or receipt of notice of recording of the bond, but such bond shall not create any rights which the claimant would not have had, or impair any defense which the obligors would have had, in an action to enforce a lien. 
The bond shall be in the following form: 
Know All Men By These Presents: 
That we, ___ as principal and ___ duly organized to transact business as a surety within the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, as surety, are holden and stand firmly bound and obliged unto ___ in the penal sum of ___ Dollars ($___), to the payment of which we bind ourselves, our heirs, successors and assigns, jointly and severally by these presents. 
Whereas, under date of , the said obligee recorded a notice of contract in the registry of deeds, as Instrument #, in Book ___ at Page ___ upon premises more fully described in said notice, and 
Whereas, the principal desires to dissolve said lien in accordance with the provisions of section fourteen of chapter two hundred and fifty-four of the General Laws. 
Now, therefore, the condition of this obligation is such that if the said principal shall pay to the said obligee all sums which shall be adjudged in favor of the said obligee in an action brought under the provisions of said section fourteen, this obligation shall be void, otherwise to remain in full force and effect. 
In witness whereof, the aforesaid principal and surety have executed this instrument under seal this ___ day of ___ (insert year). 
Principal 
by___________________________________________________________________
Surety 
by ___________________________________________________________________
___.
    </text>
</law>