<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255F" order_by="255F" level="3">Licensing Of Mortgage Loan Originators</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of License; Maintenance Of License By Employing Entity;  Return Of License Upon Termination Of Employment</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The commissioner shall issue a mortgage loan originator license to an applicant therefore unless the applicant: (i) has had a mortgage loan originator license revoked in any governmental jurisdiction; provided, however, that a subsequent formal vacation of such revocation shall not be deemed a revocation; (ii) has been convicted of, or pled guilty, admitted to sufficient facts or nolo contendere to, a felony in a domestic, foreign, or military court: (a) during the 7-year period preceding the date of the application for licensing and registration; (b) at any time preceding such date of application, if such felony involved an act of fraud, dishonesty, or a breach of trust, or money laundering; or (c) has other convictions or admissions to sufficient facts involving fraud, dishonesty, or a breach of trust, or that the applicant has had any adverse civil judgments involving fraudulent dealings; provided, however, that a pardon of a conviction shall not be a conviction for purposes of this subsection; (iii) has failed to demonstrate financial responsibility, character, reputation, integrity and general fitness such as to command the confidence of the community and to warrant a determination that such applicant will operate honestly, fairly, soundly and efficiently in the public interest, consistent with the purposes of this chapter if the applicant is granted a license; provided, however, that for purposes of this clause a person shall have shown that he or she is not financially responsible when he or she has shown a disregard in the management of his or her own financial condition; and provided further, that a determination that an individual has not shown financial responsibility may include, but shall not be limited to: (a) current outstanding judgments, except judgments solely as a result of medical expenses; (b) current outstanding tax liens or other government liens and filings; (c) foreclosure within the past 3 years; or (d) a pattern of seriously delinquent accounts within the past 3 years; (iv) failure to complete the pre-licensing education requirement described in section 5; (v) failure to pass a written test that meets the test requirement described in section 6; or (vi) has failed to meet the surety bond requirement as required pursuant to section 12. The commissioner shall either grant or deny an application within a reasonable period of such filing. If the commissioner denies an application for licensure, he shall notify the applicant of the denial, in writing, within 10 days of such denial. Within 20 days thereafter, the commissioner shall enter upon the division’s records a written decision and findings containing the reasons supporting the denial and shall forthwith give written notice thereof by registered mail to the applicant. Within 30 days after receipt of such notice, the applicant may seek judicial review of the denial in accordance with section 14 of chapter 30A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A mortgage loan originator may be employed by no more than 1 entity. Each license issued to a mortgage loan originator shall be provided to, and maintained by, the employing entity at the employing entity’s main office. If the employment of a mortgage loan originator is terminated, the employing entity shall return the mortgage loan originator’s license to the division within 5 business days after termination. The reason for termination shall be provided to the commissioner. For a period of 1 year after the termination of employment, the mortgage loan originator may request the re-assignment of the license to another employing entity by submitting an application, together with a re-assignment fee as established by the commissioner, to the division. The return of the license of any mortgage loan originator to the division that is not re-assigned to another employing entity shall terminate the right of the mortgage loan originator to engage in any residential mortgage loan origination activity until reactivation of said license. The license of any mortgage loan originator that has been returned to the division and not re-assigned to another employing entity within 1 year of termination of employment shall be cancelled; provided, however, that the person holding the license may reapply to the division for licensure pursuant to this chapter. Each license shall state the name of the mortgage loan originator licensee and the name and main office address of the entity employing such mortgage loan originator.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>