<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255" order_by="255" level="3">Mortgages, Conditional Sales And Pledges Of Personal Property, And Liens Thereon</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Jewelers</catch_line>
    <order_by>31C</order_by>
    <text>
        A person engaged in performing work upon any watch, clock, silverware or jewelry for a price shall have a lien upon such watch, clock, silverware or jewelry for the amount of any account that may be due for such work; provided, however, that he gives to the person delivering to him such watch, clock, silverware or jewelry a receipt for the same having printed thereon in clear legible type the following: 
“Items receipted pursuant to section thirty-one C of chapter two hundred and fifty-five of the General Laws, must be claimed within one year of such receipt, may be subject to sale”. 
The place of business or person performing such work shall post this section in a clear and conspicuous manner that may be easily read by the public and a copy thereof shall be made available upon request to any person delivering a watch, clock, silverware or jewelry. Such lien shall also include the value or agreed price, if any, of all materials furnished by the lienor in connection with such work, whether added to such article or articles or otherwise. If any such account remains unpaid for one year after the completion of the work, the lienor may, upon thirty days’ notice in writing to the owner specifying the amount due and informing him that payment of such amount within thirty days will entitle him to redeem the article or articles covered by such lien, sell the same at public or bona fide private sale to satisfy the account. The proceeds of the sale, after paying the expenses thereof, shall be applied in satisfaction of the indebtedness secured by such lien and the balance, if any, shall be paid over to the owner. Such notice may be served by mail, directed to the owner’s last known address, or, if the owner or his address be unknown, it may be posted in two public places in the town where the property is located. The remedy herein provided to enforce such lien shall be in addition to any other provided by law.
    </text>
</law>