<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255C" order_by="255C" level="3">Insurance Premium Finance Agencies</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Necessity Of License</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 12, 2012. For text effective July 12, 2012, see below.]  No person, except a credit union, a bank as defined in section 1 of chapter 167, a national banking association, or a federal savings and loan association, a federal savings bank, a sales finance company as defined in section 1 of chapter 255B, and a company licensed to carry on the business of making small loans, shall engage in the business of a premium finance agency unless licensed by the commissioner, as provided in section 3; provided, however, that no property and casualty insurance agent or broker, including an insurance agent or insurance broker conducting an insurance premium financing agency business under a subsidiary or different company name, who provides premium financing only to his own customers for purposes of financing payment of premiums on contracts of insurance, which contracts of insurance are exclusively limited to commercial insurance policies, shall be required to be licensed pursuant to this section or any other section of this chapter. Such license shall allow the holder to maintain only one office from which said business may be conducted, but more than one license may be issued to any person. Any change of location of an office of a licensee shall require the prior approval of the commissioner. Such request for relocation shall be in writing setting forth the reason or reasons for the request, and shall be accompanied by a relocation investigation fee of $50. If an applicant has more than one office, he may obtain a license for each office from which he intends to conduct said business.
Chapter 255C: Necessity of license
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 144, Sec. 11 effective July 12, 2012. For text effective until July 12, 2012, see above.]  No person, except a credit union, a bank as defined in section 1 of chapter 167, a national banking association, or a federal savings and loan association, a federal savings bank, a sales finance company as defined in section 1 of chapter 255B, and a company licensed to carry on the business of making small loans, shall engage in the business of a premium finance agency unless licensed by the commissioner, as provided in section 3; provided, however, that no property and casualty insurance agent or broker, including an insurance agent or insurance broker conducting an insurance premium financing agency business under a subsidiary or different company name, who provides premium financing only to his own customers for purposes of financing payment of premiums on contracts of insurance, which contracts of insurance are exclusively limited to commercial insurance policies, shall be required to be licensed pursuant to this section or any other section of this chapter. Such license shall allow the holder to maintain only one office from which said business may be conducted, but more than one license may be issued to any person. Any change of location of an office of a licensee shall require the prior approval of the commissioner. Such request for relocation shall be in writing setting forth the reason or reasons for the request, and shall be accompanied by an investigation fee to be determined annually by the secretary of administration and finance under section 3B of chapter 7. If an applicant has more than one office, he may obtain a license for each office from which he intends to conduct said business.
    </text>
</law>