<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="255" order_by="255" level="3">Mortgages, Conditional Sales And Pledges Of Personal Property, And Liens Thereon</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Aircraft Facilities; Aircraft Repairs; Filing Of Lien</catch_line>
    <order_by>31E</order_by>
    <text>
        Persons, including but not limited to the commonwealth and any department, commission, division, agency, or branch thereof, maintaining public landing, parking, storage, and tie-down facilities for the landing, parking, storage, and tie-down of aircraft brought to their premises on an airport or placed in their care by or with the consent of the owners thereof, shall have a lien upon such aircraft for proper charges due them for the landing, parking, storage, and tie-down and care of the same, which lien may be enforced as provided in sections twenty-six to thirty-one, inclusive. 
Any person who lawfully repairs an aircraft within the commonwealth shall have a lien upon such aircraft for proper charges due to him, which lien may be enforced as provided in sections twenty-six to thirty-one, inclusive. 
Any person entitled to a lien under this section, shall within sixty days after last furnishing of labor, money, material or supplies for the production of, altering or repairing of said personal property, file in the office of the federal aviation administration aircraft registry, a statement in writing verified by oath, showing the amount of labor, money, material or supplies furnished for the producing, storage, parking, servicing, altering or repairing of said personal property, the name of the person for, and by whom labor, money, material or supplies, was furnished, and specifying the registration number of said aircraft. Unless the person entitled to such lien shall file such statement within the time aforesaid, he shall be deemed to have waived his rights thereto; provided, however, that the lien provided for in this section shall not attach to any personal property after it has been purchased by an innocent purchaser for value, and has passed into his possession unless the lien shall have been filed with the federal aviation administration aircraft registry before the property was purchased by such purchaser, or he shall have received written notice, from the party entitled to the lien, of his intention to file the same.
    </text>
</law>