<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="258E" order_by="258E" level="3">Harassment Prevention Orders</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Filing Of Complaint; Impounding Of Case Record Information; Filing Fee; Expiration Of Order; Modification Of Order; Time For Filing;  Nonexclusivity Of Remedy</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A person suffering from harassment may file a complaint in the appropriate court requesting protection from such harassment. A person may petition the court under this chapter for an order that the defendant:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     refrain from abusing or harassing the plaintiff, whether the defendant is an adult or minor;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     refrain from contacting the plaintiff, unless authorized by the court, whether the defendant is an adult or minor;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     remain away from the plaintiff’s household or workplace, whether the defendant is an adult or minor; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     pay the plaintiff monetary compensation for the losses suffered as a direct result of the harassment; provided, however, that compensatory damages shall include, but shall not be limited to, loss of earnings, out-of-pocket losses for injuries sustained or property damaged, cost of replacement of locks, medical expenses, cost for obtaining an unlisted phone number and reasonable attorney’s fees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The court may order that information in the case record be impounded in accordance with court rule.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No filing fee shall be charged for the filing of the complaint. The plaintiff shall not be charged for certified copies of any orders entered by the court, or any copies of the file reasonably required for future court action or as a result of the loss or destruction of plaintiff’s copies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Any relief granted by the court shall not extend for a period exceeding 1 year. Every order shall, on its face, state the time and date the order is to expire and shall include the date and time that the matter will again be heard. If the plaintiff appears at the court at the date and time the order is to expire, the court shall determine whether or not to extend the order for any additional time reasonably necessary to protect the plaintiff or to enter a permanent order. When the expiration date stated on the order is on a date when the court is closed to business, the order shall not expire until the next date that the court is open to business. The plaintiff may appear on such next court business day at the time designated by the order to request that the order be extended. The court may also extend the order upon motion of the plaintiff, for such additional time as it deems necessary to protect the plaintiff from harassment. The fact that harassment has not occurred during the pendency of an order shall not, in itself, constitute sufficient ground for denying or failing to extend the order, or allowing an order to expire or be vacated or for refusing to issue a new order.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The court may modify its order at any subsequent time upon motion by either party; provided, however, that the non-moving party shall receive sufficient notice and opportunity to be heard on said modification. When the plaintiff’s address is inaccessible to the defendant as provided in section 10 and the defendant has filed a motion to modify the court’s order, the court shall be responsible for notifying the plaintiff. In no event shall the court disclose any such inaccessible address.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The court shall not deny any complaint filed under this chapter solely because it was not filed within a particular time period after the last alleged incident of harassment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     An action commenced under this chapter shall not preclude any other civil or criminal remedies. A party filing a complaint under this chapter shall be required to disclose any prior or pending actions involving the parties; including, but not limited to, court actions, administrative proceedings and disciplinary proceedings.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>