<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Certain Writs And Proceedings In Special Cases</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="254" order_by="254" level="3">Liens On Buildings And Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>30</section_number>
    <catch_line>Recording; Duty Of Register Of Deeds</catch_line>
    <order_by>30</order_by>
    <text>
        All liens for labor and notices of contract, and instruments pertaining thereto, filed as provided for in this chapter, shall be recorded by the register of deeds, who shall enter the names of the parties affected thereby in the grantor and grantee indexes. 
Any notice or other instrument required or permitted to be filed or recorded by this chapter in the registry of deeds or in the land registration district of the land court that is in the form required by this chapter and executed before a notary public, justice of the peace or other officer entitled by law to take acknowledgements with respect to instruments, whether executed within or without the commonwealth, by a person purporting to hold the position of president, vice president, treasurer, clerk, secretary, or any assistant to the foregoing, principal, partner, proprietor, trustee, attorney or other similar position, of the entity entitled to record or file such instruments on behalf of such entity acting in its own capacity or as a general partner or co-venturer, or as assignee, agent or authorized representative, shall be binding upon such entity and shall be entitled to be recorded or filed, and no vote of the entity affirming such authority shall be required to permit recording or filing. A certificate of the acknowledgement or other proof of due execution shall be endorsed upon or annexed to such instrument, and filed or recorded with it. 
Such notices, and all other instruments required or permitted by this chapter to be filed or recorded in the registry of deeds, affecting registered land shall be filed and registered in the manner prescribed by section seventy-eight of chapter one hundred and eighty-five. Such notices, and all other instruments required or permitted by this chapter to be filed or recorded in the registry of deeds, affecting unregistered land shall be indexed in a separate book to be kept for that purpose. 
If registered land is included with unregistered land in any such notice or other instrument, an attested copy thereof shall be filed with the assistant recorder and registered.
    </text>
</law>