<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="69" order_by="69" level="3">Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Elementary And Secondary Education</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Vocational Technical Education And School To Work Transition Programs; Standards; Grants</catch_line>
    <order_by>1F</order_by>
    <text>
        The board shall set standards for vocational-technical education and programs for school-to-work transition. The board shall give particular emphasis for setting standards for the integration of academic and vocational education and to the progress in educating students for all aspects of a chosen industry. 
The board shall assess progress in the areas of integration of academic and vocational education, and education for all aspects of an industry by assessing curriculum plans, staffing patterns, and other factors the board deems pertinent to said assessment. 
The board shall, subject to appropriation, establish demonstration grants to develop alternative education program models. Said grants shall be awarded to public or public/private entities in an effort to design programs for students who may be identified as having difficulty achieving a certificate of initial mastery, and which assist students in achieving said certificate or moving directly into the work force. 
The board shall, subject to appropriation, establish a grant program to create job compacts for communities to coordinate summer and after school employment opportunities for students. Eligible districts shall demonstrate private sector participation in the compact which helps to provide work opportunities for students. 
The board shall, with the assistance of the board of higher education and subject to appropriation, establish grants for technology preparation programs. Said grants shall be available to all public secondary schools in the commonwealth and public institutions of higher education for the purposes of improving collaboration between secondary and post-secondary technology programs. 
The board shall, with the assistance of the board of higher education and subject to appropriation, establish four demonstration grants to consortia of vocational schools, comprehensive secondary schools, and community colleges to promote further collaboration between grades nine through twelve and higher education institutions. 
For the purpose of this chapter, Technology Education shall mean organized education programs in the K-12 comprehensive schools which offer courses instructing all students how to use and apply technology through critical and creative thinking and problem solving. These programs shall provide all students with activities concentrated in an action-based, problem solving, solution seeking format in the areas of communication, construction, manufacturing, power, energy, transportation, and biotechnology. 
Technology Education shall also mean an integrated approach to education through organized programs K-12 comprehensive schools which emphasizes career awareness, consumer knowledge, impacts and consequences of technology, and understanding of technical systems through the application of science, mathematics, language arts educational technology.
    </text>
</law>