<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="71" order_by="71" level="3">Public Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>71E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Appropriations For And Expenditure Of Receipts From Adult Education And Continuing Education Programs</catch_line>
    <order_by>71E</order_by>
    <text>
        In any city or town which accepts this section, all moneys received by the school committee in connection with the conduct of adult education and continuing education programs, including, but not limited to adult physical fitness programs conducted under section seventy-one B, summer school programs and programs designated by prior vote of said committee as community school programs, and in connection with the use of school property under section seventy-one, shall be deposited with the treasurer of the town or city and held as separate accounts. The receipts held in such a separate account may be expended by said school committee without further appropriation for the purposes of the program or programs from which the receipts held in such account were derived or, in the case of the use of school property account, for expenses incurred in making school property available for such use, notwithstanding the provisions of section fifty-three of chapter forty-four of the General Laws. A city or town may appropriate funds for the conduct of any such program or for expenses incurred in making school property available for such use, which funds shall be expended by the school committee in addition to funds provided from other sources. Three years from the date a city or town accepts the provisions of this paragraph, and every third year thereafter, said city or town may act to rescind its original acceptance.
    </text>
</law>