<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="78" order_by="78" level="3">Libraries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Library Commissioners; Members; Appointment; Term;  By Laws; Reimbursement; Officers; Staff</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board of library commissioners for the commonwealth, in this section and in sections fifteen to thirty, inclusive, called the board, consisting of nine residents of the commonwealth appointed by the governor. Upon the expiration of the term of office of a member of the board, his successor shall be appointed for a term of five years. 
No person shall be appointed to serve more than two consecutive terms. Prior service on the board for a period of less than three years resulting from an initial appointment or an appointment for the remainder of an unexpired term shall not be considered a full term. The board shall prepare and adopt by-laws for the conduct of its business. Said by-laws shall provide for the election of one of its members to be chairman of the board, establish the term of office, and provide for the ways and means for the election of other officers and their terms of office as deemed necessary by the board. 
The members of the board shall be reimbursed for their necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. 
The board shall appoint a director and determine his duties and responsibilities and may at its discretion remove him. The board shall, upon recommendation of the director, appoint a deputy director and determine his duties and responsibilities and may at its discretion remove him. The director and deputy director shall be classified in accordance with section forty-five of chapter thirty and the salary shall be determined in accordance with section forty-six C of said chapter thirty. The director and deputy director shall receive such other perquisites as the board may approve. The director and the deputy director shall not be subject to the provisions of section nine A of chapter thirty or of chapter thirty-one. 
Subject to appropriation and to the approval of the board the director shall appoint or release such professional and subprofessional staff as the functions, powers, and duties of the board shall require; provided, however, that the provisions of said section nine A of said chapter thirty and said chapter thirty-one shall not apply to any such appointment or release.
    </text>
</law>