<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="74" order_by="74" level="3">Vocational Education</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
          The following words, as used in this chapter, shall have the following meanings unless the context otherwise requires:  "Commissioner'', the commissioner of education.  "Approved'', the approval of specific vocational-technical programs by the commissioner of education, acting through the division of occupational education, following investigation and determining the appropriateness of programs as to organization, control, location, equipment, courses of study, qualifications of teachers, methods of instruction, conditions of admissions of student, employment of students and expenditures.  "State board'', the board of education.  "Forms of vocational-technical education'', the classification of vocational-technical educational programs which lead employment or continuing preparation for employment associated with agriculture, allied health, automotive, construction, marketing, service occupations, industrial-manufacturing programs and technical programs.  "Agricultural programs'', the preparation of students for occupations connected with agriculture, the care of domestic animals, forestry and other wage earning or productive work on farm land. The term agricultural supplies, horticulture and agricultural and natural resources.  "Allied health programs'', the preparation of students for occupations connected with health, to include direct and indirect care of patients and other wage earning or productive work within the health care area and related services.  "Automotive programs'', the preparation of mechanics and technicians for any type of engine-powered vehicle.  "Construction programs'', the preparation of students for occupations in the areas of carpentry, plumbing, painting, electricity, heating, ventilation and air conditioning and other areas of construction.  "Marketing education programs'', the development of competent workers engaged in marketing, sales and such administrative supporting functions as buying, receiving, storing, shipping, promoting, financing, market research, and management. These activities are found in such areas as retail and wholesale trade, banking, and finance, insurance, real estate, service trades, manufacturing, utilities and communications. Such phrase shall not include the following occupations: stenographer, secretary, typist nor industrial workers in transportation activities.  "Industrial-manufacturing programs'', the development of workers for occupations involving the manufacturing or fabrication of products in either heavy or light industry.  "Technology programs'', the preparation of students for occupations or further education in such areas as: electronics, drafting, computers, electromechanical.[ Definition of "Service programs'' effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  "Service programs'', the preparation of students in the occupational areas of hotel and lodging, cosmetology, child care.[ Definition of "Service programs'' as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 87 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  "Service programs'', the preparation of students in occupational areas such as hotel and lodging, cosmetology, child care or any service occupation that by its nature is characterized as being a service, professional or non-professional; provided, however, that such programs shall be in compliance with the program approval criteria regulations published by the state board.  "Part time class'', towns, cities, regional and county school districts and independent schools may operate part-time and evening vocational-technical classes approved by the commissioner under the state board.  "Cooperative education'', a program of vocational-technical education for persons who, through a cooperative arrangement between the school and employers, receive instruction, including required academic courses and related vocational-technical instruction, by the alternation of study in school with a job in any occupational field. Such instruction shall be planned and supervised by the school and the employer so that each contributes to the student's education and employability. Work periods and school attendance may be on alternate half-days, full days, weeks or other coordinated periods of time.  "Articulation'', is the educational process whereby curricular interaction occurs across grade levels and links programs between educational levels.  Horizontal articulation provides the curricular process which serves to strengthen a student's mastery of interacting concepts and skills across all academic and educational levels.  Vertical articulation provides the curricular vehicle which allows a student to progress by competencies from a vocational-technical program at one educational level to the same program area at a higher educational level, for example, between secondary and postsecondary education.  "Vocational-technical education'', organized education programs offering sequences of courses designed to educate and prepare students for both employment and continuing academic and occupational preparation. Such programs shall integrate academic and vocational education and shall include competency based applied learning which contributes to an individual's academic knowledge, higher order reasoning, and problem solving skills, work attitudes, general employability skills and the occupational-specific skills necessary for economic independence as a productive and contributing member of society. Vocational-technical education shall also include applied technology education to be taught by personnel certified in technology education.
    </text>
</law>