<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="74" order_by="74" level="3">Vocational Education</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Supervision Of Athletic And Other Organizations</catch_line>
    <order_by>31B</order_by>
    <text>
        The boards of trustees of the Bristol county agricultural school, the Essex agricultural and technical institute, and the Norfolk county agricultural school may supervise and control all athletic and other organizations composed of vocational agricultural school pupils and bearing the name of said school or organized in connection therewith. The trustees of each of said county agricultural schools may, directly or through authorized representatives, determine under what conditions the same may compete with similar organizations in other schools. Expenditures by said trustees for the organization and conduct of physical training and exercises, athletics, sports, practice sessions of athletic teams, games and play, for providing proper apparatus, equipment, supplies, athletic wearing apparel, including appropriate souvenir garments and trophies, and facilities for the same in the buildings, yards and playgrounds under the control of said trustees, or upon any other land which they may have the right or privilege to use for this purpose, and for exercises, athletics, sports, practice sessions of athletic teams, games and play, shall be deemed to be for school purposes and shall be considered to be a proper maintenance item for reimbursement purposes. Said trustees shall include in their annual budgets, with the approval of the commissioner, amounts sufficient for the employment of coaches, an athletic director, a faculty manager, and a physician to supervise in said county agricultural schools physical training and exercises, athletics, sports, games and play, and for the transportation of the school athletic teams, coaches, cheerleaders, bands and other groups composed of pupils of the said schools, within the commonwealth to places where athletic contests or physical exercises, sports, games, play, musical festivals, competitions or other events are held, and for the purchase of uniforms and musical instruments for the members of bands composed of pupils of said schools.
    </text>
</law>