<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="71" order_by="71" level="3">Public Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Regional School Districts; Formation; Procedure</catch_line>
    <order_by>14B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The number, composition, method of selection, and terms of office of the members of the regional district school committee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The town or towns in which, or the general area within the regional school district where, the regional district school or schools are to be located.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The type of regional district school or schools. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, the type of regional school may, if it is so stated in the agreement, consist of a vocational school or schools offering such kinds of education as may be provided by towns under the provisions of chapter seventy-four; and any other type of regional school may, if it is so stated in the agreement, offer said kinds of education. A town may simultaneously be a member of a vocational regional school district and any other type of regional school district provided, however, that when a vocational school district is in operation, no member town of such district, and no other type of regional school district of which such a town is a member shall, without the approval of the commissioner of education, offer the same kinds of education as offered by said vocational school district.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The method of apportioning the expenses of the regional school district, and the method of apportioning the costs of school construction, including any interest and retirement of principal of any bonds or other obligations issued by the district among the several towns comprising the district, and the time and manner of payment of the shares of the several towns of any such expense.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The method by which school transportation shall be provided, and if such transportation is to be furnished by the district, the manner in which the expenses shall be borne by the several towns.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     the terms by which any city or town may be admitted to or separated from the regional school district; provided, however, that in the case of admission such terms shall not be inconsistent with the provisions of section sixteen of chapter six hundred and forty-five of the acts of nineteen hundred and forty-eight.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The method by which the agreement may be amended.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     The detailed procedure for the preparation and adoption of an annual budget.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Any other matters, not incompatible with law, which the said board may deem advisable.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>