<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="74A" order_by="74A" level="3">Independent Agricultural And Technical Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Trustees; Members</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until July 1 preceding the opening of the Essex North Shore agricultural and technical school. Repealed by 2004, 463, Sec. 1. See 2004, 463, Sec. 18 as amended by 2010, 130, Sec. 7.] 
The powers, duties and liabilities of each school shall be vested in and exercised by a board of trustees. The board of trustees shall consist of nine members appointed by the governor for terms of not more than four years, of which neither more than two nor less than one term shall expire each year. The chairperson of the board of trustees shall be designated by the governor from among the board’s nine members. The term of the board of trustees of the Essex agricultural and technical institute as constituted immediately prior to the transfer date of Essex county pursuant to section 1 of chapter 34B shall expire on January 1, 2001. 
For the Essex independent agricultural and technical institute, members of said board shall be selected by the governor from nominations submitted by the mayors and boards of selectmen of the cities and towns having students enrolled in the institute. At least three of said members shall reside in the municipalities of Lynn, Peabody, Salem, Methuen, Gloucester, Haverhill or Lawrence and shall be selected from a list of nominations submitted by the mayors of such cities. At least one candidate shall reside in the municipalities of Danvers, Amesbury, Middleton, Newburyport or Beverly and shall be selected from a list of nominations submitted by the mayors or boards of selectmen in such municipalities. 
The remaining five members shall reside in one of the remaining municipalities in which a student of said school resides and shall be selected from a list of nominations submitted by the mayors and boards of selectmen in each such municipality. Said remaining members shall be nominated from communities based on the percentage of students enrolled, which shall be recalculated every three years. The municipalities shall be ranked according to enrollment, then separated into three categories based on enrollment. Two members shall be selected from municipalities with enrollments in the top third, two members shall be selected from municipalities with enrollment in the middle third and one shall be selected from municipalities with enrollments in the lower third; provided, however, that no person shall be nominated from a municipality that does not enroll students at the institute; and provided, further, that no municipality shall have more than one seat on the board.
    </text>
</law>