<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="70B" order_by="70B" level="3">School Building Assistance Program</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3A</section_number>
    <catch_line>School Building Advisory Board; Establishment; Members</catch_line>
    <order_by>3A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be a school building advisory board comprised of the state auditor or his designee, the inspector general or his designee, and the executive director of the authority, who shall serve as the secretary to the advisory board and shall be a nonvoting member of the board, and 15 members to represent the following nongovernmental organizations, to be appointed by those organizations: the Massachusetts Municipal Association, the Massachusetts Association of School Committees, the Massachusetts Mayors Association, the Massachusetts Association of School Superintendents, the Massachusetts Association of Regional Schools, the Massachusetts Building Trades Council, the Massachusetts chapter of the Associated Builders and Contractors, the Massachusetts Alliance of Small Contractors, the American Council of Engineering Companies of Massachusetts, the Associated Subcontractors of Massachusetts, the American Institute of Architects-Massachusetts, the Massachusetts Smart Growth Alliance, the Massachusetts Taxpayers Foundation, Associated General Contractors of Massachusetts and acting jointly, the Massachusetts Teachers Association and Massachusetts Federation of Teachers. The advisory board shall assist the authority in the development of general policy regarding school building construction, renovation, reconstruction, maintenance and facility space, preservation of open space and minimization of loss of open space, thoughtful community development, cost management and shall provide technical advice and input to the authority. The advisory board shall meet at least quarterly.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>