<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="71" order_by="71" level="3">Public Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>42B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Rights Of School Employees In Regional Districts</catch_line>
    <order_by>42B</order_by>
    <text>
        The provisions of this chapter relating to school personnel granted certificates in accordance with section thirty-eight G shall apply to all such school personnel employed by regional school districts. Any such school personnel who have professional teacher status or other rights under section forty-one in a particular school district, whose positions are superseded by reasons of the establishment and operation of a regional school district, shall be employed with the same status by the regional school district. 
All such school personnel employed by regional school districts shall initially be placed on the salary schedule of the district so that compensation to be paid to such school personnel shall not be less than the compensation received by such school personnel while previously employed with the same status. 
Such school personnel shall also be given credit by the regional school district committee for all accumulated sick leave and accumulated sabbatical leave years of service while employed with such status and for terminal compensation due such school personnel on the termination of such service. 
All such personnel without such status in a city or town in the district whose positions are superseded by reason of the establishment and operation of a regional school district shall be elected to serve in such district by the regional school district committee; provided, however, that there is an available position which such person is certified to fill. All such personnel employed by regional school district committees shall initially be placed on the salary schedule of the regional school district so that the compensation paid to such school personnel shall not be less than the compensation received by such school personnel while previously employed by a local school committee. Such school personnel shall also be given credit by the regional school district committee for all accumulated sick leave, accumulated time towards service with such status, and accumulated sabbatical leave years of service, and for terminal compensation due such school personnel on the termination of such service. 
Any employee subject to the provisions of chapter thirty-one, employed by the school committee of a town, whose position is superseded by reason of the establishment and operation of a regional school district shall be employed by the regional school district without loss of any civil service or other rights previously acquired by him. 
This section shall also apply to all school personnel with such status of local trustees for vocational education, and any such school personnel whose positions are superseded by reason of the establishment and operation of a regional school district shall be employed by the regional school district with the same status. 
Any such school personnel, employed by a regional school district, whose position is abolished or eliminated by reason of the disestablishment and discontinuance of the regional school district or the withdrawal of a member community from such district shall be employed by one of the withdrawing city or town school committees, and if any such personnel have such status, such personnel shall be employed by such city or town, school committee with the same status. In the event that there are not sufficient teaching positions available in the withdrawing city or town school systems, such personnel shall be offered the available positions for which they are currently certified in the order of their seniority in the regional school district. All such personnel so employed by a city or town school district shall initially be placed on the salary schedule of such city or town school district so that the compensation paid to such school personnel shall not be less than the compensation received by such school personnel while previously employed by the regional school district. Such school personnel also shall be given credit by the city or town school committee for all accumulated sick time, accumulated time towards service with such status, and accumulated sabbatical leave years of service, and for terminal compensation due such school personnel on the termination of such service.
    </text>
</law>