<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="69" order_by="69" level="3">Powers And Duties Of The Department Of Elementary And Secondary Education</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1J</section_number>
    <catch_line>Underperforming Or Chronically Underperforming Schools; Creation And Submission Of Turnaround Plan; Appointment Of Receiver; Annual Review</catch_line>
    <order_by>1J</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The commissioner of elementary and secondary education may, on the basis of student performance data collected pursuant to section 1I, a school or district review performed under section 55A of chapter 15, or regulations adopted by the board of elementary and secondary education, designate 1 or more schools in a school district other than a Horace Mann charter school as underperforming or chronically underperforming. The board shall adopt regulations establishing standards for the commissioner to make such designations on the basis of data collected pursuant to section 1I or information from a school or district review performed under section 55A of chapter 15. Upon the release of the proposed regulations, the board shall file a copy thereof with the clerks of the house of representatives and the senate who shall forward the regulations to the joint committee on education. Within 30 days of the filing, the committee may hold a public hearing and issue a report on the regulations and file the report with the board. The board, pursuant to applicable law, may adopt final regulations making revisions to the proposed regulations as it deems appropriate after consideration of the report and shall forthwith file a copy of the regulations with the chairpersons of the joint committee on education and, not earlier than 30 days of the filing, the board shall file the final regulations with the state secretary. Schools that score in the lowest 20 per cent statewide among schools serving common grade levels on a single measure developed by the department that takes into account student performance data and, beginning on July 1, 2011, improvement in student academic performance, shall be deemed eligible for designation as underperforming or chronically underperforming. Not more than 4 per cent of the total number of public schools may be designated as underperforming or chronically underperforming at any given time.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Upon the designation of a school as an underperforming school in accordance with regulations developed pursuant to this section, the superintendent of the district, with approval by the commissioner, shall create a turnaround plan for the school, under subsections (b) to (e), inclusive. The commissioner may allow for an expedited turnaround plan for schools that have been previously designated as underperforming and where the district has a turnaround plan that has had a public comment period and approval of the local school committee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In creating the turnaround plan in subsection (b) the superintendent shall include, after considering the recommendations of the local stakeholder group, provisions intended to maximize the rapid academic achievement of students at the school and shall, to the extent practicable, base the plan on student outcome data, including, but not limited to: (1) data collected pursuant to section 1I or information from a school or district review performed under section 55A of chapter 15; (2) student achievement on the Massachusetts Comprehensive Assessment System; (3) other measures of student achievement, approved by the commissioner; (4) student promotion and graduation rates; (5) achievement data for different subgroups of students, including low-income students as defined in chapter 70, limited English-proficient students and students receiving special education; and (6) student attendance, dismissal rates and exclusion rates.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, in creating the turnaround plan required in subsection (b), the superintendent may, after considering the recommendations of the group of stakeholders: (1) expand, alter or replace the curriculum and program offerings of the school, including the implementation of research-based early literacy programs, early interventions for struggling readers and the teaching of advanced placement courses or other rigorous nationally or internationally recognized courses, if the school does not already have such programs or courses; (2) reallocate the uses of the existing budget of the school; (3) provide additional funds to the school from the budget of the district, if the school does not already receive funding from the district at least equal to the average per pupil funding received for students of the same classification and grade level in the district; (4) provide funds, subject to appropriation and following consultation with applicable local unions, to increase the salary of any administrator, or teacher in the school, to attract or retain highly-qualified administrators, or teachers or to reward administrators, or teachers who work in underperforming schools that achieve the annual goals set forth in the turnaround plan; (5) expand the school day or school year or both of the school; (6) for an elementary school, add pre-kindergarten and full-day kindergarten classes, if the school does not already have such classes; (7) following consultation with applicable local unions, require the principal and all administrators, teachers and staff to reapply for their positions in the school, with full discretion vested in the superintendent regarding his consideration of and decisions on rehiring based on the reapplications. (8) limit, suspend or change 1 or more provisions of any contract or collective bargaining agreement, as the contract or agreement applies to the school; provided, that the superintendent shall not reduce the compensation of an administrator, teacher or staff member unless the hours of the person are proportionately reduced; (9) limit, suspend or change 1 or more school district policies or practices, as such policies or practices relate to the school; (10) include a provision of job-embedded professional development for teachers at the school, with an emphasis on strategies that involve teacher input and feedback; (11) provide for increased opportunities for teacher planning time and collaboration focused on improving student instruction; (12) establish a plan for professional development for administrators at the school, with an emphasis on strategies that develop leadership skills and use the principles of distributive leadership; (13) establish steps to assure a continuum of high-expertise teachers by aligning the following processes with a common core of professional knowledge and skill: hiring, induction, teacher evaluation, professional development, teacher advancement, school culture and organizational structure; (14) develop a strategy to search for and study best practices in areas of demonstrated deficiency in the school; (15) establish strategies to address mobility and transiency among the student population of the school; and (16) include additional components based on the reasons why the school was designated as underperforming and the recommendations of the group of stakeholders in subsection (b).
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Within 30 days of the local stakeholder group making recommendations under subsection (b), the superintendent shall submit a turnaround plan to the local stakeholder group, the school committee and the commissioner, all of whom may propose modifications to the plan. The superintendent shall make such plan immediately available to the public upon the submission. The stakeholder group, the school committee and the commissioner shall submit any proposed modifications to the superintendent not more than 30 days after the date of submission of the turnaround plan and the proposed modifications shall be made public immediately upon their submission to the superintendent. The superintendent shall consider and may incorporate the modifications into the plan if the superintendent determines that inclusion of the modifications would further promote the rapid academic achievement of students at the school or may alter or reject the proposed modifications submitted under this subsection. Within 30 days of receiving any proposed modifications under this subsection, the superintendent shall issue a final turnaround plan for the school and the plan shall be made publicly available.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Within 30 days of the issuance of a final turnaround plan under subsection (e) a school committee or local union may appeal to the commissioner regarding 1 or more components of the plan, including the absence of 1 or more modifications proposed under subsection (e). The commissioner may, in consultation with the superintendent, modify the plan if the commissioner determines that: (1) such modifications would further promote the rapid academic achievement of students in the applicable school; (2) a component of the plan was included, or a modification was excluded, on the basis of demonstrably-false information or evidence; or (3) the superintendent failed to meet the requirements of subsections (b) to (e), inclusive. The decision of the commissioner regarding an appeal under this subsection shall be made within 30 days and shall be final. (g) If, after considering the recommendations of the group of stakeholders, the superintendent considers it necessary to maximize the rapid academic achievement of students at the applicable school by altering the compensation, hours and working conditions of the administrators, teachers, principal and staff at the school or by altering other provisions of a contract or collective bargaining agreement applicable to the administrators, teachers, principal and staff, the superintendent may request that the school committee and any union bargain or reopen the bargaining of the relevant collective bargaining agreement to facilitate such achievement. The bargaining shall be conducted in good faith and completed not later than 30 days from the point at which the superintendent requested that the parties bargain. The agreement shall be subject to ratification within 10 business days by the bargaining unit members in the school. If the parties are unable to reach an agreement within 30 days or if the agreement is not ratified within 10 business days by the bargaining unit members of the school, the parties shall submit remaining unresolved issues a joint resolution committee for dispute resolution process on the next business day following the end of the 30-day bargaining period or failure to ratify.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     The superintendent may select an external receiver to operate the school and implement the turnaround plan or to assist the superintendent with the implementation. The superintendent may appoint the receiver if the superintendant determines that conditions exist in the district that are likely to negatively affect his ability to implement the plan successfully. A school committee may appeal to the commissioner the decision of the superintendent to appoint an external receiver. The commissioner may reverse such decision only if he determines that the superintendent made the decision on the basis of demonstrably-false information or evidence. A receiver shall be a non-profit entity or an individual with a demonstrated record of success in improving low-performing schools or the academic performance of disadvantaged students. A receiver shall be subject to section 11A 1/2 of chapter 30A and chapter 66. A receiver who is an individual shall also be subject to chapter 268A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     An external receiver selected by the superintendent to operate a school shall have full managerial and operational control over the school as provided in the turnaround plan. For all other purposes, the school district in which the school is located shall remain the employer of record.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Each turnaround plan shall be authorized for a period of not more than 3 years, subject to subsection (k). The superintendent or external receiver, as applicable, may develop additional components of the turnaround plan pursuant to subsections (b) to (g) inclusive and shall develop annual goals for each component of the plan, in a manner consistent with subsections (b) to (g), inclusive. The superintendent or external receiver, as applicable, shall be responsible for meeting the goals of the plan.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     Each school designated by the commissioner as underperforming under subsection (a) shall be reviewed by the superintendent, in consultation with the principal of the school, at least annually. The purpose of the review shall be to determine whether the school has met the annual goals in its turnaround plan and to assess the overall implementation of the turnaround plan. The review shall be in writing and shall be submitted to the commissioner and the relevant school committee not later than July 1 for the preceding school year. The review shall be submitted in a format determined by the department of elementary and secondary education.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     Upon the expiration of a turnaround plan, the commissioner shall conduct a review of the school to determine whether the school has improved sufficiently, requires further improvement or has failed to improve. On the basis of such review, the commissioner may determine that: (1) the school has improved sufficiently for the designation of the school as underperforming to be removed; (2) the school has improved, but the school remains underperforming, in which case the superintendent may, with the approval of the commissioner, renew the plan or create a new or modified plan for an additional period of not more than 3 years, consistent with the requirements of subsections (a) to (g); or (3) consistent with the requirements of subsection (a),the school is chronically underperforming. The commissioner may recommend the appointment of an external receiver by the superintendent if the commissioner believes that a new or modified turnaround plan implemented by the superintendent will not result in rapid improvement. In carrying out this subsection, the superintendent shall: (1) in the case of a renewal of a turnaround plan, determine subsequent annual goals for each component of the plan with the input of the local stakeholder group as defined in subsection (b); or (2) create a new or modified turnaround plan as necessary, consistent with the requirements of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     Upon the designation of a school as a chronically underperforming school in accordance with the regulations developed under this section, the commissioner shall create a turnaround plan for the school under this subsection and subsections (n) to (p), inclusive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="n">
    	     In creating the turnaround plan required in subsection (m), the commissioner shall include, after considering the recommendations of the local stakeholder group, provisions intended to maximize the rapid academic achievement of students at the school and shall, to the extent practicable, base the plan on student outcome data, including, but not limited to: (1) data collected under section 1I or information from a school or district review performed under section 55A of chapter 15; (2) student achievement on the Massachusetts Comprehensive Assessment System; (3) other measures of student achievement, approved by the commissioner, as appropriate; (4) student promotion and graduation rates; (5) achievement data for different subgroups of students, including low-income students as defined by chapter 70, limited English-proficient students and students receiving special education; and (6) student attendance ,dismissal rates and exclusion rates.
        </section>
        <section prefix="o">
    	     Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, in creating the turnaround plan required in subsection (m), the commissioner may, after considering the recommendations of the group of stakeholders: (1) expand, alter or replace the curriculum and program offerings of the school, including the implementation of research-based early literacy programs, early interventions for struggling readers and the teaching of advanced placement courses or other rigorous nationally or internationally recognized courses, if the school does not already have such programs or courses; (2) reallocate the uses of the existing budget of the school; (3) provide additional funds to the school from the budget of the district, if the school does not already receive funding from the district at least equal to the average per pupil funding received for students of the same classification and grade level in the district; (4) provide funds, subject to appropriation, to increase the salary of an administrator ,or teacher in the school, in order to attract or retain highly-qualified administrators or teachers or to reward administrators,. or teachers who work in chronically underperforming schools that achieve the annual goals set forth in the turnaround plan; (5) expand the school day or school year or both of the school; (6) for an elementary school, add pre-kindergarten and full-day kindergarten classes, if the school does not already have such classes; (7) limit, suspend, or change 1 or more provisions of any contract or collective bargaining agreement, as the contract or agreement applies to the school; provided, however, that the commissioner shall not reduce the compensation of an administrator, teacher or staff member unless the hours of the person are proportionately reduced; and provided further, that the commissioner may require the school committee and any applicable unions to bargain in good faith for 30 days before exercising authority pursuant to this clause; (8) following consultation with applicable local unions, require the principal and all administrators, teachers and staff to reapply for their positions in the school, with full discretion vested in the superintendent regarding his consideration of and decisions on rehiring based on the reapplications; (9) limit, suspend or change 1 or more school district policies or practices, as such policies or practices relate to the school; (10) include a provision of job-embedded professional development for teachers at the school, with an emphasis on strategies that involve teacher input and feedback; (11) provide for increased opportunities for teacher planning time and collaboration focused on improving student instruction; (12) establish a plan for professional development for administrators at the school, with an emphasis on strategies that develop leadership skills and use the principles of distributive leadership; (13) establish steps to assure a continuum of high expertise teachers by aligning the following processes with the common core of professional knowledge and skill: hiring, induction, teacher evaluation, professional development, teacher advancement, school culture and organizational structure; (14) develop a strategy to search for and study best practices in areas of demonstrated deficiency in the school; (15) establish strategies to address mobility and transiency among the student population of the school; and (16) include additional components, at the discretion of the commissioner, based on the reasons the school was designated as chronically underperforming and the recommendations of the local stakeholder group in subsection (m).
        </section>
        <section prefix="p">
    	     Within 30 days of the local stakeholder group making recommendations under subsection (m), the commissioner shall submit a turnaround plan to the local stakeholder group, the superintendent and the school committee, all of whom may propose modifications to the plan. The commissioner shall make the plan immediately available to the public upon submission. The stakeholder group, the superintendent and the school committee shall submit any proposed modifications to the commissioner within 30 days after the date of submission of the turnaround plan and the proposed modifications shall be made public immediately upon their submission to the commissioner. The commissioner shall consider and incorporate the modifications into the plan if the commissioner determines that inclusion of the modifications would further promote the rapid academic achievement of students at the applicable school. The commissioner may alter or reject modifications submitted pursuant to this subsection. Within 30 days of receiving any proposed modifications, the commissioner shall issue a final turnaround plan for the school and the plan shall be made publicly available.
        </section>
        <section prefix="q">
    	     Within 30 days of the issuance of a final turnaround plan under subsection (p), a superintendent, school committee or local union may appeal to the board of elementary and secondary education regarding 1 or more components of the plan, including the absence of 1 or more modifications proposed under subsection (p). A majority of the board, may vote to modify the plan if the board determines that: (1) such modifications would further promote the rapid academic achievement of students in the applicable school; (2) a component of the plan was included, or a modification was excluded, on the basis of demonstrably-false information or evidence; or (3) the commissioner failed to meet the requirements of subsections (m) to (p), inclusive. The decision of the board regarding an appeal under this subsection shall be made within 30 days and shall be final.
        </section>
        <section prefix="r">
    	     In the case of a chronically underperforming school, the commissioner may, under the circumstances described in this subsection, send a targeted assistance team to the school to assist the superintendent with the implementation of the turnaround plan, require the superintendent to implement the turnaround plan, or select an external receiver to operate the school and implement the turnaround plan. The commissioner may appoint such receiver if the commissioner determines that: (1) the superintendent is unlikely to implement the plan successfully; or (2) conditions exist in the district that are likely to negatively affect the ability of the superintendent to implement such plan successfully. A receiver shall be a non-profit entity or an individual with a demonstrated record of success in improving low performing schools or the academic performance of disadvantaged students. A receiver shall be subject to section 11A1/2 of chapter 30A and chapter 66. A receiver who is an individual shall also be subject to chapter 268A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="s">
    	     An external receiver selected by the commissioner to operate a chronically underperforming school shall have full managerial and operational control over the school as provided in the turnaround plan. For all other purposes, the school district in which the school is located shall remain the employer of record.
        </section>
        <section prefix="t">
    	     Each turnaround plan shall be authorized for a period of not more than 3 years, subject to subsection (v). The superintendent or external receiver, as applicable, may develop additional components of the plan and shall develop annual goals for each component of the plan in a manner consistent with subsection (n), all of which must be approved by the commissioner. The superintendent or external receiver, as applicable, shall be responsible for meeting the goals of the turnaround plan.
        </section>
        <section prefix="u">
    	     The commissioner or external receiver, as applicable, shall provide a written report to the school committee on a quarterly basis to provide specific information about the progress being made on the implementation of the school’s turnaround plan. One of the quarterly reports shall be the annual evaluation under subsection (v).
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     The commissioner shall evaluate each chronically underperforming school at least annually. The purpose of the evaluation shall be to determine whether the school has met the annual goals in its turnaround plan and assess the implementation of the plan at the school. The review shall be in writing and shall be submitted to the superintendent and the school committee not later than July 1 for the preceding school year. The review shall be submitted in a format determined by the department of elementary and secondary education.
        </section>
        <section prefix="w">
    	     Upon the expiration of a turnaround plan for a chronically underperforming school, the commissioner shall conduct a review of the school to determine whether the school has improved sufficiently, requires further improvement or has failed to improve. On the basis of such review, the commissioner may: (1) on the basis of a superintendent’s or external receiver’s success in meeting the terms of the plan, renew the plan with the superintendent or external receiver for an additional period of not more than 3 years; (2) if a school that is operated by a superintendent and remains chronically underperforming, appoint an external receiver, as defined in subsection (r), to operate the school; (3) if a chronically underperforming school that is operated by an external receiver and remains chronically underperforming, transfer the operation of the school from the receiver to the applicable superintendent or to another external receiver; or (4) determine that the school has improved sufficiently for the designation of chronically underperforming to be removed. The commissioner shall: (1) in the case of a renewal of an turnaround plan, jointly determine subsequent annual goals for each component of the plan with the superintendent or external receiver, as applicable; or (2) create a new or modified turnaround plan as necessary, consistent with the requirements of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="x">
    	     Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, any underperforming or chronically underperforming school operating a limited-English proficient program or programs for limited English proficient students in any 1 language group shall establish a limited English proficient parent advisory council. The parent advisory council shall be comprised of parents or legal guardians of students who are enrolled in limited English proficient programs within the school. Each parent advisory council shall have at least 1 representative from every language group in which a program is conducted in a given school. Membership shall be restricted to parents or legal guardians of students enrolled in limited English proficient programs within the school. The duties of the parent advisory council shall include, but not be limited to, advising the school on matters that pertain to the education of students in limited English proficient programs, meeting regularly with school officials to participate in the planning and development of a plan to improve educational opportunities for limited English proficient students, and to participate in the review of school improvement plans established under section 59C of chapter 71 as they pertain to limited English proficient students. Any parent advisory council may, at its request, meet at least once annually with the school council. The parent advisory council shall establish by-laws regarding officers and operational procedures. In the course of its duties under this section, the parent advisory council shall receive assistance from the director of limited English proficient programs for the district or other appropriate school personnel as designated by the superintendent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="y">
    	     The board of elementary and secondary education shall adopt regulations regarding: (1) the conditions under which an underperforming or chronically underperforming school shall no longer be designated as an underperforming or chronically underperforming school; and (2) the transfer of the operation of an underperforming or a chronically underperforming school from a superintendent or an external receiver, as applicable, to the school committee. The regulations shall include provisions to allow a school to retain measures adopted in an turnaround plan for a transitional period if, in the judgment of the commissioner, the measures would contribute to the continued improvement of the school. Such regulations shall also include provisions that clearly identify the conditions under which such a transitional period shall end and the powers granted to the commissioner and board under this section shall cease to apply to a district previously designated as chronically underperforming.
        </section>
        <section prefix="z">
    	     The commissioner shall report annually to the joint committee on education, the house and senate committees on ways and means, the speaker of the house of representatives and the senate president on the implementation and fiscal impact of this section and section 1K. The report shall include, but not be limited to, a list of all schools currently designated as underperforming or chronically underperforming, a list of all districts currently designated as chronically underperforming, the plans and timetable for returning the schools and districts to the local school committee and strategies used in each of the schools and districts to maximize the rapid academic achievement of students.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>