<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="71" order_by="71" level="3">Public Schools</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>91</section_number>
    <catch_line>Recovery High School;  Definition;  Enrollment;  Student Performance;  Rules And Regulations;  Deduction Of Home School District Allotment For Failure To Transfer Funds As Required</catch_line>
    <order_by>91</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) The term "Recovery High School'' shall mean a public school or collaborative program for students diagnosed with substance use disorder or dependency, as defined by the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders IV-TR, that provides: (1) a comprehensive 4-year high school education, and (2) a structured plan of recovery.  (b) A school district shall transfer the state average foundation budget per pupil to a Recovery High School for a student meeting the following criteria: (1) the student is currently enrolled in the district or currently resides in the municipality in which the district is located; (2) the student is considered by a clinician, as defined by 105 CMR 164.006, to be clinically appropriate, using the criteria for Substance Use Disorders as defined in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders IV-TR; and (3) the student meets all matriculation criteria as outlined by the sending district and the department of elementary and secondary education, with determination of academic eligibility based on existing documentation provided by the district. The district and the Recovery High School shall arrange to confer a diploma when a student completes state and district-mandated graduation requirements.  (c) A Recovery High School shall submit to the board of elementary and secondary education data considered necessary by the board to provide information regarding each student's academic performance. A Recovery High School shall also submit to the department of public health data regarding each student's recovery.  (d) The board of elementary and secondary education, in consultation with the department of public health and the department of mental health, shall promulgate rules and regulations, as necessary to implement this section.[ Subsection (e) added by 2011, 68, Sec. 73 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221.]  (e) Failure by a school district to transfer funds to a Recovery High School as required in subsection (b) shall result in a deduction of the amount therein from the home school district's chapter 70 per pupil allotment for the following fiscal year.
    </text>
</law>