<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="70B" order_by="70B" level="3">School Building Assistance Program</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15</section_number>
    <catch_line>Sale Or Lease Of School Buildings For Which School Facilities Project Applicant Receives Grant Payments</catch_line>
    <order_by>15</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     In the event that an eligible applicant sells or leases an assisted structure or facility, or a portion of that structure or facility, on account of which it is receiving grant payments for an approved school project or, in the case of an approved school project approved on or after July 1, 2004, on account of which it has received at least 1 grant payment in the preceding 20 years, under this chapter or under chapter 645 of the acts of 1948, the sale or lease of the assisted structure or facility, or portion of that structure or facility, shall be for no less than fair market value as determined by independent appraisal, unless the eligible applicant receives prior written approval from the authority to do otherwise, and the proceeds from the sale or lease shall be divided between the authority and the general funds of the applicable eligible applicant in proportion to the commonwealth’s and authority’s prior investments in the assisted structure or facility under this chapter or said chapter 645, as applicable. In the case of an approved school project approved before July 1, 2004, the authority’s share of the proceeds shall reduce the balance of outstanding grant payments that would otherwise be payable except for this section and shall not exceed that amount. An eligible applicant which sells, leases or otherwise removes from use by the eligible applicant as a schoolhouse an approved school project on account of which it is receiving grant payments or, in the case of an approved school project approved on or after July 1, 2004, on account of which it has received at least 1 grant payment in the preceding 20 years, under this chapter or under said chapter 645, shall report the sale, lease or removal to the authority in the form and manner and within the time prescribed by the authority. The authority may issue regulations to recapture commonwealth and authority assistance for an approved school facilities projects for school buildings that are removed from service.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     In the event an eligible applicant sells or leases an assisted structure or if the assisted structure was not used as a schoolhouse for at least half of the preceding fiscal year, the amount of outstanding grant payments remaining after reductions under the provisions of subsection (a), shall be deducted from each city, town or regional school district’s cherry sheets, so-called, as an assessment in accordance with the provisions of section 21 of chapter 59, according to a schedule agreed to between the city or town and the authority; provided, however, that at the discretion of the authority, deductions authorized from said cherry sheets under the provisions of this subsection may be waived for an assisted structure or facility which has been removed from use as a schoolhouse by a city, town or regional school district, pursuant to a plan approved by said city, town or regional school district and the authority, which provides for the reuse of the assisted structure or facility as a schoolhouse within two years of the adoption of the plan or prior to the expiration of the term of any bonds or notes issued to finance the project for which the grant was approved, whichever is the earliest.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Any eligible applicant which applies for a grant pursuant to this chapter and which has, prior to such application, sold, leased or otherwise removed from service any schoolhouse operated by said eligible applicant shall be eligible for such grant only if the board determines either that the grant is not for the purpose of replacing a schoolhouse sold, leased or otherwise removed from service in the past ten years or that the need for the project covered by the grant could not have reasonably been anticipated at the time that such schoolhouse was sold, leased or otherwise removed from service.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The provisions of this section, at the discretion of the authority, shall not apply to sales or leases of such assisted structures or facilities for nonprofit public purposes.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>