<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="2">Education</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="74" order_by="74" level="3">Vocational Education</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Establishment By Districts</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  Independent vocational-technical schools may be established and maintained by districts composed of two or more towns, through boards to be known as district trustees for vocational-technical education, consisting either of the chairman and two other members of the school committees of each town, to be appointed by such committees, or of three residents of each, to be elected by the town.
Chapter 74: Establishment by districts
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 88 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  Independent vocational-technical schools may be established and maintained by districts composed of two or more towns, through boards to be known as district trustees for vocational-technical education, consisting either of the chairman and two other members of the school committees of each town, to be appointed by such committees, or of three residents of each, to be elected by the town. Pursuant to section 21 of chapter 15A, 1 member of said board shall be designated by the district trustees to serve as a non-voting member of the board of trustees for any community college that shares the same geographic region as the independent vocational-technical school. The designated member shall serve as a liaison between the 2 boards for the purposes of sharing information and developing policies that will promote greater interaction between the vocational-technical school and the community college while maximizing the educational resources available to individuals seeking to learn a trade or develop targeted employment skills.
    </text>
</law>