<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2GGG</section_number>
    <catch_line>Civil Monetary Penalties Fund;  Nursing Home Facilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>2GGG</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the division of medical assistance and the department of public health shall deposit all monies collected as civil monetary penalties from nursing homes participating in the Medicaid program authorized by Title XIX of the Social Security Act into a separate expendable trust fund which shall be designated and known as the Commonwealth of Massachusetts Civil Monetary Penalties Fund. Monies collected as civil monetary penalties from nursing homes shall include both monies collected from Medicaid-only facilities, known as nursing facilities, and the commonwealth portion of funds collected from dually participating facilities, known as skilled nursing facilities or nursing facilities, for noncompliance with sections 1919(b), 1919(c) and 1919(d) of the Social Security Act and monies collected from individuals pursuant to sections 1919(b)(3)(B)(ii)(I), 1919(b)(3)(B)(ii)(II) and 1919(g)(2)(A)(i) of the Social Security Act. The department may expend monies from this fund without further appropriation in accordance with this section. The department shall administer the fund in accordance with law including, without limitation, section 1919(h)(2)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act. The department shall expend monies in the fund for measures to protect the health and property of nursing home residents in nursing home facilities found by the department or the secretary of health and human services to be deficient including, without limitation, the following: (i) nursing facility staff training and education; (ii) technical assistance for troubled facilities; (iii) dissemination of best practice models for quality of care issues, such as malnutrition and dehydration; (iv) state operation of facilities pending correction of deficiencies or closure; (v) reimbursement of facility residents for lost personal funds or property; and (vi) costs of relocating residents from 1 facility to another. No expenditure shall cause the fund to be in deficit at the end of the fiscal year.
Chapter 29: Civil Monetary Penalties Fund; nursing home facilities
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the executive office of health and human services and the department of public health shall deposit all monies collected as civil monetary penalties from nursing homes participating in the Medicaid program authorized by Title XIX of the Social Security Act into a separate expendable trust fund which shall be designated and known as the Commonwealth of Massachusetts Civil Monetary Penalties Fund. Monies collected as civil monetary penalties from nursing homes shall include both monies collected from Medicaid-only facilities, known as nursing facilities, and the commonwealth portion of funds collected from dually participating facilities, known as skilled nursing facilities or nursing facilities, for noncompliance with sections 1919(b), 1919(c) and 1919(d) of the Social Security Act and monies collected from individuals pursuant to sections 1919(b)(3)(B)(ii)(I), 1919(b)(3)(B)(ii)(II) and 1919(g)(2)(A)(i) of the Social Security Act. The department may expend monies from this fund without further appropriation in accordance with this section. The department shall administer the fund in accordance with law including, without limitation, section 1919(h)(2)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act. The department shall expend monies in the fund for measures to protect the health and property of nursing home residents in nursing home facilities found by the department or the secretary of health and human services to be deficient including, without limitation, the following: (i) nursing facility staff training and education; (ii) technical assistance for troubled facilities; (iii) dissemination of best practice models for quality of care issues, such as malnutrition and dehydration; (iv) state operation of facilities pending correction of deficiencies or closure; (v) reimbursement of facility residents for lost personal funds or property; and (vi) costs of relocating residents from 1 facility to another. No expenditure shall cause the fund to be in deficit at the end of the fiscal year.
    </text>
</law>