<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="30A" order_by="30A" level="3">State Administrative Procedure</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Regulations Not Requiring Hearings;  Small Business Impact Statement;  Adoptions, Amendments Or Repeals</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
          Prior to the adoption, amendment, or repeal of any regulation for which a public hearing is not required under section two, the agency shall give notice and afford interested persons an opportunity to present data, views, or arguments as follows:  The agency shall, within the time specified by law, or, if no time is specified, then at least twenty-one days prior to its proposed action: (a) publish notice of its proposed action in such manner as is specified by any law, or, if no manner is specified, then in such newspapers, and, where appropriate, in such trade, industry or professional publications as the agency may select; (b) notify any person to whom specific notice must be given, such notice to be given by delivering or mailing a copy of the notice to the last known address of the person required to be notified; (c) notify any person or group filing written request for notice of agency rule making proceedings, such request to be renewed annually in December, such notice to be given by delivering or mailing a copy of the notice to the last known address of the person or groups required to be notified; and (d) file a copy of such notice with the state secretary.  The notice shall refer to the statutory authority under which the action is proposed; give the time and place of any public hearing or state the anticipated time of agency action; state the manner in which data, views, or arguments may be submitted to the agency by any interested person; either state the express terms or describe the substance of the proposed action; and include any additional matter required by any law.[ Third paragraph effective until February 17, 2012 applicable to regulations proposed after August 1, 2010. See 2010, 240, Secs. 194 and 206. For text effective February 17, 2012, see below.]  The notice shall also include a small business impact statement considering the impact of the proposed action on small businesses with the state secretary. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 6, the state secretary shall include the small business impact statement on the electronic website of the state secretary; provided, however, that the full text of the small business impact statement may be inspected and copied in the office of the state secretary during business hours.[ Third paragraph as amended by 2012, 36, Sec. 5 effective February 17, 2012 until January 1, 2013. For text effective until February 17, 2012, see above. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  A small business impact statement shall be filed with the state secretary on the same day the notice is filed and shall accompany the notice. Notwithstanding section 6, the state secretary shall include the small business impact statement on the electronic website of the state secretary and the statement may be inspected and copied in the office of the state secretary during business hours.[ Third paragraph as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 115 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  A small business impact statement shall be filed with the state secretary on the same day the notice is filed and shall accompany the notice. Notwithstanding section 6, the state secretary shall include the full text of said small business impact statement on the electronic website of the state secretary; provided, however, that the full text of the small business impact statement may also be inspected and copied in the office of the state secretary during business hours.[ Fourth paragraph applicable to regulations proposed after August 1, 2010. See 2010, 240, Secs. 194 and 206.]  That small business impact statement shall include, but not be limited to, the following:  (1) an estimate of the number of small businesses subject to the proposed regulation;  (2) projected reporting, recordkeeping and other administrative costs required for compliance with the proposed regulation;  (3) the appropriateness of performance standards versus design standards;  (4) an identification of regulations of the promulgating agency, or of another agency or department of the commonwealth, which may duplicate or conflict with the proposed regulation; and  (5) an analysis of whether the proposed regulation is likely to deter or encourage the formation of new businesses in the commonwealth;  The agency shall afford interested persons an opportunity to present data, views or arguments in regard to the proposed action orally or in writing. If the agency finds that oral presentation is unnecessary or impracticable, it may require that presentation be made in writing.  If the agency finds that the immediate adoption, amendment or repeal of a regulation is necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety or general welfare, and that observance of the requirements of notice and affording interested persons an opportunity to present data, views, or arguments would be contrary to the public interest, the agency may dispense with such requirements and adopt, amend or repeal the regulation as an emergency regulation. The agency's finding and a brief statement of the reasons for its finding shall be incorporated in the emergency regulation as filed with the state secretary under section five. An emergency regulation shall not remain in effect for longer than three months unless, during that time, the agency gives notice and affords interested persons an opportunity to present data, views, or arguments as required in this section, and files notice of compliance with the state secretary.  This section does not relieve any agency from compliance with any law requiring that its regulations be approved by designated persons or bodies before they may become effective.
    </text>
</law>