<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>29E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Maximum Reimbursement For Project Costs</catch_line>
    <order_by>29E</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the comptroller may enter into contracts or interdepartmental service agreements for the purpose of identifying and pursuing increased revenue collection, cost avoidance, the maximum reimbursement opportunities for certain federally assisted and other programs of the commonwealth and any other reimbursements of overpayments or other revenues. The contractor payments, or oversight costs or fees related to this section shall be paid from the revenues or reimbursements collected, or as otherwise considered appropriate by the comptroller, without further appropriation, and the comptroller shall establish accounts and procedures within the affected departments as he considers appropriate and necessary to accomplish the revenue generation purposes of this section. The comptroller shall notify, in writing, the house and senate committees on ways and means 60 days before entering into any contract authorized pursuant to this section. The comptroller shall report on said projects as a part of his annual report under section twelve of chapter seven A.
Chapter 29: Maximum reimbursement for project costs
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the comptroller may enter into contracts or interdepartmental service agreements for the purpose of identifying and pursuing increased revenue collection, cost avoidance, the maximum reimbursement opportunities for certain federally assisted and other programs of the commonwealth and any other reimbursements of overpayments or other revenues. The contractor payments, or oversight costs or fees related to this section shall be paid from the revenues or reimbursements collected, or as otherwise considered appropriate by the comptroller, without further appropriation, and the comptroller shall establish accounts and procedures within the affected departments as the comptroller considers appropriate and necessary to accomplish the revenue generation purposes of this section. The comptroller shall notify, in writing, the house and senate committees on ways and means 60 days before entering into any contract authorized under this section. The comptroller shall report on said projects as a part of the comptroller's annual report under section 12 of chapter 7A.
    </text>
</law>