<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Voluntary Services At Public Schools By State Employees;  Effect On Salaries</catch_line>
    <order_by>31E</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law to the contrary, a state employee, during working hours and at such times as are approved by his supervisor and in accordance with regulations promulgated hereunder, may, without loss of salary, provide voluntary services at a public elementary, secondary, or vocational-technical school to assist the improvement of a student's or school's educational program; provided, however, that said voluntary services do not exceed the equivalent of one work day per month. There shall be no requirement that the employee have a child as a student in the school or school district. Said services shall not be compensated by a school.
Chapter 29: Voluntary services at public schools by state employees; effect on salaries
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, a state employee, during working hours and at such times as are approved by the employee's supervisor and under regulations promulgated hereunder, may, without loss of salary, provide voluntary services at a public elementary, secondary, or vocational-technical school to assist the improvement of a student's or school's educational program; provided, however, that said voluntary services do not exceed the equivalent of 1 work day per month. There shall be no requirement that the employee have a child as a student in the school or school district. Said services shall not be compensated by a school.
    </text>
</law>