<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2VVV</section_number>
    <catch_line>International Education And Foreign Language Grant Program Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2VVV</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  (a) There shall be established and set upon the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the international education and foreign language grant program fund, hereinafter referred to as the international education fund, to which shall be credited any appropriations, bond proceeds or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited thereto and additional funds designated for deposit to the international education fund, including any pension funds, federal grants or loans, or private donations made available to the commissioner of education for such purpose. The Commissioner of Education shall hold the international education fund in an account or accounts separate from other funds or accounts. Amounts credited to the international education fund shall be used by the commissioner of education, in consultation with the chairman of the board of higher education, and the global education advisory council to carry out the purposes of subsection (b).  (b) The public purpose of the international education fund shall be to increase the number of Massachusetts students, teachers, administrators and education policymakers participating in international studies, international exchange programs, and other activities that advance cultural awareness and promote mutual understanding and respect for citizens of other countries. In furtherance of this public purpose and in consultation with the chairman of the board of higher education and the global education advisory council, the Commissioner of Education shall employ the international education fund in support of programs and activities that advance cultural awareness, including the awarding of grants to local or regional school districts that use the funds to support international education programs and promote the study of foreign languages, including programs that establish foreign language and two-way bi-lingual education classes, teacher training, and curriculum development to encourage students, teachers, administrators and educational policy makers to participate in international studies, international exchange programs and other activities.
Chapter 29: International education and foreign language grant program fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  (a) There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the international education and foreign language grant program fund, hereinafter referred to as the international education fund, to which shall be credited any appropriations, bond proceeds or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited thereto and additional funds designated for deposit to the international education fund, including any pension funds, federal grants or loans, or private donations made available to the commissioner of education for such purpose. The commissioner of education shall hold the international education fund in an account or accounts separate from other funds or accounts. Amounts credited to the international education fund shall be used by the commissioner of education, in consultation with the chairman of the board of higher education, and the global education advisory council to carry out the purposes of subsection (b).  (b) The public purpose of the international education fund shall be to increase the number of Massachusetts students, teachers, administrators and education policymakers participating in international studies, international exchange programs, and other activities that advance cultural awareness and promote mutual understanding and respect for citizens of other countries. In furtherance of this public purpose and in consultation with the chairman of the board of higher education and the global education advisory council, the commissioner of education shall employ the international education fund in support of programs and activities that advance cultural awareness, including the awarding of grants to local or regional school districts that use the funds to support international education programs and promote the study of foreign languages, including programs that establish foreign language and two-way bi-lingual education classes, teacher training and curriculum development to encourage students, teachers, administrators and educational policy makers to participate in international studies, international exchange programs and other activities.
    </text>
</law>