<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2W</section_number>
    <catch_line>Water Pollution Abatement And Drinking Water Projects Administration Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2W</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Water Pollution Abatement and Drinking Water Projects Administration Fund. There shall be credited to said fund any amounts transferred pursuant to sections 5 and 18 of chapter 29C and any income derived from the investment of amounts credited to said fund. Amounts credited to said fund shall be held in an expendable trust and the department of environmental protection shall report monthly all amounts credited to said fund and all expenditures by subsidiary on the Massachusetts management and accounting reporting system, so-called. Said amounts shall be used solely for the administration of the provisions of section 27A of chapter 21 and section 18 of said chapter 29C.
Chapter 29: Water Pollution Abatement and Drinking Water Projects Administration Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Water Pollution Abatement and Drinking Water Projects Administration Fund. There shall be credited to said fund any amounts transferred under sections 5 and 18 of chapter 29C and any income derived from the investment of amounts credited to said fund. Amounts credited to said fund shall be held in an expendable trust and the department of environmental protection shall report monthly all amounts credited to said fund and all expenditures by subsidiary on the Massachusetts management and accounting reporting system, so-called. Said amounts shall be used solely for the administration of section 27A of chapter 21 and section 18 of said chapter 29C.
    </text>
</law>