<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31</section_number>
    <catch_line>Salaries;  Advances;  Teachers;  Centralized Payroll System;  Direct Credit To Bank Accounts;  Wage Garnishments</catch_line>
    <order_by>31</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Salaries payable by the commonwealth shall for all classified services, unless otherwise provided, be paid monthly through the last Saturday of each month, and shall be in full for all services rendered to the commonwealth by the persons to whom they are paid. Salaries payable by the commonwealth to persons in statutory positions shall be payable in equal monthly payments. Advances on account of salaries may be made upon request of any employee, under such regulations as the state treasurer may prescribe, not exceeding the proportion of salary then due. No salary shall be paid to any person for a longer period than that during which he has been actually employed in the duties of his office. If a salary shall be diminished, no greater rate shall be paid because of any previous appropriation therefor. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section, the annual salary of each teacher and each supervisor employed in any school or college within any department of the commonwealth shall be the weekly rate set out in the job group to which his position has been allocated in the general salary schedule times the number of Saturdays in the fiscal year established by law for the payment of salaries and if the regular services of such teacher or supervisor are rendered from September first to June thirtieth, said salary shall be for his service for the number of weeks established by the department for such school to be in session during said period, payable, however, monthly through the last Saturday of each month and the amount earned and unpaid at the time of his resignation, retirement, death or entry on leave of absence shall be paid forthwith to the persons entitled thereto, and advances of pay may be made to any state officer or employee in advance of his regular vacation to the extent of the pay to which he is about to become entitled during such vacation period under such regulations as the state treasurer may prescribe. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the payment of premiums for the purchase of an individual or group annuity contract for any employee of the department of education or of any educational institution within any department of the commonwealth as provided in section eighteen A of chapter fifteen.  Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section or any other provisions of law, the commissioner of administration may establish a centralized payroll system and may include therein salaries payable by the commonwealth, for all classified services in any agency of the commonwealth and for teachers and supervisors employed in any school or college in any department of the commonwealth and any salary payable by the commonwealth to a person holding a statutory position.  Such centralized payroll system shall conform to such rules and regulations as the commissioner of administration, with the approval of the state treasurer, the comptroller, and the personnel administrator, may from time to time make. Such rules and regulations shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter thirty A. Notwithstanding any other general or special law to the contrary, and in accordance with section 148 of chapter 149, to ensure the timely payment of wages and related payroll charges for work authorized by a spending authority and performed by employees, the comptroller shall have full authority to mandate the payment of such wages and payroll charges and prescribe, regulate and direct any spending authority to take the appropriate actions necessary to properly account for payroll charges, to ensure that payroll accounts are not in deficit at the close of the fiscal year and any other actions necessary to support sound fiscal management including appropriation, allotment or other funding limits.  The comptroller shall prepare and submit to the governor and council, for their approval, a weekly warrant which shall include a sum sufficient in each item of appropriation to meet the total current weekly cost of salaries included within such centralized payroll system. The comptroller shall require certification from each spending authority that each employee receiving a salary under the warrant is being paid for duties performed directly for the employing agency and not for duties performed for another state agency. The treasurer shall pay such salaries from the amounts approved by the governor and council in said warrant and shall, within five days after such payment, provide a detailed record thereof to the comptroller. The comptroller, no later than twenty working days after the close of each monthly pay period, shall provide the house and senate committees on ways and means with a record of full and part-time personnel who were paid during the most recently completed monthly pay period. Said report shall identify for each state agency all positions, their position titles and monthly salaries by account, whether appropriation account for ordinary maintenance, federal grant account, revolving account, retained revenue expenditure account, trust account, bond fund account, or any other type of account maintained or established by the comptroller. The provisions of this section shall not be construed so as to prohibit the payment of premiums for the purchase of a life insurance contract, annuity contract or other deferred compensation program for state employees under section sixty-four.  The state treasurer or other state official authorized to expend money on behalf of the commonwealth may pay any salary, wages or other compensation to any person in the service of the commonwealth by means of deposits to employee bank accounts, provided, employees have expressly authorized said deposits.  The state treasurer or other state official authorized to expend money on behalf of the commonwealth may pay any retirement benefit due to any retired employee in the state system or retired teachers in the teachers retirement system by means of deposits to such retired person's bank account, provided, the retired persons have expressly authorized said deposits.  The state treasurer or other state official authorized to expend money on behalf of the commonwealth may comply with administrative wage garnishments issued by the federal government for nonpayment of student loans by employees of the commonwealth, by paying to the federal government not more than 10 per cent of the employee's salary or wages. For the purposes of this section, the term "employee'' shall mean "employee'' as defined in section 1 of chapter 32.
Chapter 29: Centralized payroll system; duties of comptroller; authorized payments; wage garnishments
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The comptroller, in consultation with the personnel administrator and the secretary of administration and finance, may establish a centralized payroll system and may include salaries payable by the commonwealth in that system, for all classified services in any agency of the commonwealth and for teachers and supervisors employed in any school or college in any department of the commonwealth and any salary payable by the commonwealth to a person holding a statutory position.  Such centralized payroll system shall conform to such rules and regulations as the secretary of administration and finance, with the approval of the state treasurer, the comptroller and the personnel administrator, may from time to time make. Such rules and regulations shall not be subject to chapter 30A. Notwithstanding any other general or special law to the contrary, and under section 148 of chapter 149, to ensure the timely payment of wages and related payroll charges for work authorized by a spending authority and performed by employees, the comptroller shall have full authority to mandate the payment of such wages and payroll charges and prescribe, regulate and direct any spending authority to take the appropriate actions necessary to properly account for payroll charges, to ensure that payroll accounts are not in deficit at the close of the fiscal year and any other actions necessary to support sound fiscal management including appropriation, allotment or other funding limits.  The comptroller shall require certification from each spending authority that each employee receiving a salary under the warrant is being paid for duties performed directly for the employing agency and not for duties performed for another state agency or other legal entity.  The state treasurer or other state official authorized to expend money on behalf of the commonwealth may pay any salary, wages or other compensation to any person in the service of the commonwealth by means of deposits to employee bank accounts, provided, employees have expressly authorized said deposits.  The state treasurer or other state official authorized to expend money on behalf of the commonwealth may pay any retirement benefit due to any retired employee in the state system or retired teachers in the teachers retirement system by means of deposits to such retired person's bank account, provided, the retired persons have expressly authorized said deposits.  The comptroller or other state official authorized to expend money on behalf of the commonwealth may comply with administrative wage garnishments for child support, student loans, state or federal tax liens, court order bankruptcy orders or other garnishments as determined by the comptroller which name the commonwealth as employer and mandating deductions under state or federal law for employees of the commonwealth in amounts not more than the percentage allowable under state or federal law or a greater amount as authorized by the employee, provided that the commonwealth shall not use state resources or be compelled to comply with voluntary private garnishments or trustee process orders. For the purposes of this section, the term "employee'' shall mean "employee'' as defined in section 1 of chapter 32.
    </text>
</law>