<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Requests And Recommendations For Appropriations Or Authorizations For Expenditures;  Review Of Proposed Legislation Providing For Capital Facility Projects</catch_line>
    <order_by>7I</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  All requests and recommendations for appropriations or authorizations for expenditures by the commonwealth, other than those submitted by the governor to the general court pursuant to section two of Article LXIII of the Amendments to the Constitution, shall be submitted by the governor to the general court; shall be classified to show the request of each officer having charge of an office, department or undertaking, including the priorities assigned to each program by said officer, the recommendation of the secretary of the executive office within which such office, department or undertaking shall be, the recommendation of the governor, and the prior year appropriation, if any; and shall indicate the number, if any, of permanent positions proposed to be authorized for an office, department or undertaking and the number of persons to be served or the number of actions to be taken by such office, department or undertaking.  All such requests and recommendations as they pertain to capital facility projects shall also be studied by the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance with reference to any current long range capital facility development plans proposed in accordance with the requirements of sections seven A, seven B, seven C and seven D. The commissioner in his study shall consider the effects upon the policies, programs, and priorities with regard to which he is required to report in accordance with section seven J and with reference to any other matters which the commissioner requires to be reported to him in his review and evaluation of capital facility budget requests by public agencies in accordance with the provisions of sections seven A, seven B, seven C, seven D and seven E. After such review and study, the commissioner shall promptly prepare and submit his recommendations to the general court.  The commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall promptly review any petition, motion or amendment introduced in either chamber of the general court which makes a provision for a capital facility project. During such review the commissioner shall study the necessity, desirability, and relative priority of such capital facility project by reference to any current long range capital facilities development plans proposed in accordance with the requirements of sections seven A, seven B, seven C, seven D, and seven E. The commissioner in his study shall consider the effects upon the policies, programs, and priorities with regard to which he is required to report in accordance with section seven J, and with reference to any other matters which the commissioner requires to be reported to him in his review and evaluation of capital facility budget requests by public agencies in accordance with the provisions of sections seven A, seven B, seven C, seven D, and seven E. After such review and study the commissioner shall promptly prepare and forward his recommendation on the petition, motion, or amendment to the chamber in which it was introduced and where it is pending.
Chapter 29: Requests and recommendations for appropriations or authorizations for expenditures; review relating to capital facilities projects
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  All requests and recommendations for appropriations or authorizations for expenditures by the commonwealth, other than those submitted by the governor to the general court under section 2 of Article LXIII of the Amendments to the Constitution, shall be submitted by the governor to the general court; shall be classified to show the request of each officer having charge of an office, department or undertaking, including the priorities assigned to each program by said officer, the recommendation of the secretary of the executive office within which such office, department or undertaking shall be, the recommendation of the governor, and the prior year appropriation, if any; and shall indicate the number, if any, of permanent positions proposed to be authorized for an office, department or undertaking and the number of persons to be served or the number of actions to be taken by such office, department or undertaking. Requests and recommendations as they pertain to capital facilities projects shall be studied by the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance under chapter 7C.
    </text>
</law>