<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2OOO</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commonwealth Care Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2OOO</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until June 19, 2012. For text effective June 19, 2012, see below.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Commonwealth Care Trust Fund, in this section called the trust fund. There shall be credited to the trust fund: (a) all contributions collected under section 188 of chapter 149, (b) all revenue from surcharges imposed under section 18B of chapter 118G, (c) any transfers from the Health Safety Net Trust Fund, established by section 57 of chapter 118E, (d) revenue deposited from penalties collected under chapter 111M. Amounts credited to the trust fund shall be expended without further appropriation for programs designed to increase health coverage, including a program of subsidized health insurance provided to low-income residents of the commonwealth under chapter 118H and rate increases to certain Medicaid providers and supplemental payments to certain publicly operated or public-service hospital entities, as determined by law. Money from the trust fund may be transferred to the Uncompensated Care Trust Fund, established by section 18 of chapter 118G, or any successor fund, as necessary to provide payments to acute hospitals and community health centers for reimbursable health services. Not later than January 1, the comptroller shall report an update of revenues for the current fiscal year and prepare estimates of revenues to be credited to the trust fund in the subsequent fiscal year. The comptroller shall file this report with the secretary of administration and finance, the office of Medicaid, the joint committee on health care financing, and the house and senate committees on ways and means. If revenues credited to the trust fund are less than the amounts estimated to be credited to the trust fund, the comptroller shall duly notify the secretary, office and committees that this revenue deficiency shall require proportionate reductions in expenditures from the revenues available to support programs appropriated from the trust fund.
Chapter 29: Commonwealth Care Trust Fund
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 118, Sec. 8 effective June 19, 2012 until November 4, 2012. For text effective until June 19, 2012, see above. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Commonwealth Care Trust Fund. The secretary of administration and finance shall be the trustee of the fund and shall expend money in the fund for the purposes described herein.  There shall be credited to the trust fund: (a) all contributions collected under section 188 of chapter 149; (b) all revenue from surcharges imposed under section 18B of chapter 118G; (c) any transfers from the Health Safety Net Trust Fund established in section 36 of said chapter 118G; (d) revenues deposited from penalties collected under chapter 111M; and (e) any revenue from appropriations or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited to the fund. Amounts credited to the fund shall be expended without further appropriation for programs administered by the commonwealth health insurance connector authority pursuant to chapter 176Q that are designed to increase health coverage for residents of the commonwealth. Money from the fund may be transferred to the Health Safety Net Trust Fund or any successor fund, as necessary to provide payments to acute hospitals and community health centers for reimbursable health services. Not later than January 1, the comptroller shall report an update of revenues for the current fiscal year and prepare estimates of revenues to be credited to the fund in the subsequent fiscal year. The comptroller shall file this report with the secretary of administration and finance, the secretary of health and human services, the joint committee on health care financing and the house and senate committees on ways and means. Monies remaining in the fund at the end of a fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund; provided, however, that the comptroller shall report the amount remaining in the fund at the end of each fiscal year to the house and senate committees on ways and means.
Chapter 29: Commonwealth Care Trust Fund
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 24 effective November 4, 2012 until January 1, 2013. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Commonwealth Care Trust Fund. The secretary of administration and finance shall be the trustee of the fund and shall expend money in the fund for the purposes described herein.  There shall be credited to the trust fund: (a) all contributions collected under section 188 of chapter 149; (b) all revenue from surcharges imposed under section 18 of chapter 176Q; (c) any transfers from the Health Safety Net Trust Fund established in section 36 of said chapter 118G; (d) revenues deposited from penalties collected under chapter 111M; and (e) any revenue from appropriations or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited to the fund. Amounts credited to the fund shall be expended without further appropriation for programs administered by the commonwealth health insurance connector authority pursuant to chapter 176Q that are designed to increase health coverage for residents of the commonwealth. Money from the fund may be transferred to the Health Safety Net Trust Fund or any successor fund, as necessary to provide payments to acute hospitals and community health centers for reimbursable health services. Not later than January 1, the comptroller shall report an update of revenues for the current fiscal year and prepare estimates of revenues to be credited to the fund in the subsequent fiscal year. The comptroller shall file this report with the secretary of administration and finance, the secretary of health and human services, the joint committee on health care financing and the house and senate committees on ways and means. Monies remaining in the fund at the end of a fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund; provided, however, that the comptroller shall report the amount remaining in the fund at the end of each fiscal year to the house and senate committees on ways and means.
Chapter 29: Commonwealth Care Trust Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Commonwealth Care Trust Fund. The secretary of administration and finance shall be the trustee of the fund and shall expend money in the fund for the purposes described herein.  There shall be credited to the trust fund: (a) all contributions collected under section 188 of chapter 149; (b) all revenue from surcharges imposed under section 18B of chapter 118G; (c) any transfers from the Health Safety Net Trust Fund established in section 36 of said chapter 118G; (d) revenues deposited from penalties collected under chapter 111M; and (e) any revenue from appropriations or other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited to the fund. Amounts credited to the fund shall be expended without further appropriation for programs administered by the commonwealth health insurance connector authority pursuant to chapter 176Q that are designed to increase health coverage for residents of the commonwealth. Money from the fund may be transferred to the Health Safety Net Trust Fund or any successor fund, as necessary to provide payments to acute hospitals and community health centers for reimbursable health services. Not later than January 1, the comptroller shall report an update of revenues for the current fiscal year and prepare estimates of revenues to be credited to the fund in the subsequent fiscal year. The comptroller shall file this report with the secretary of administration and finance, the secretary of health and human services, the joint committee on health care financing and the house and senate committees on ways and means. Monies remaining in the fund at the end of a fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund; provided, however, that the comptroller shall report the amount remaining in the fund at the end of each fiscal year to the house and senate committees on ways and means.
    </text>
</law>