<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2LLL</section_number>
    <catch_line>Firearms Fingerprint Identity Verification Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2LLL</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Firearms Fingerprint Identity Verification Trust Fund. Amounts credited to such fund shall be available, without further appropriation, to the department of state police for the purposes of financing fingerprint identification verifications with the fingerprint records maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigations or any other federal agency for the verification of firearms license applicant identities. $25 of the fee assessed under sections 122, 122B, 129B, 131, 131A, 131F, and 131H of chapter 140 of the General Laws shall be deposited into the fund. The funds shall be utilized for the sole purpose of making payments charged to the department by the Federal Bureau of Investigations or other entity for fingerprint identification verification.
Chapter 29: Firearms Fingerprint Identity Verification Trust Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Firearms Fingerprint Identity-Verification Trust Fund. Amounts credited to such fund shall be available, without further appropriation, to the department of state police to finance fingerprint identification verifications with the fingerprint records maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigations or any other federal agency for the verification of firearms license applicant identities. $25 of the fee assessed under sections 122, 122B, 129B, 131, 131A, 131F, and 131H of chapter 140 shall be deposited into the fund. The funds shall be utilized for the sole purpose of making payments charged to the department by the Federal Bureau of Investigations or other entity for fingerprint identification verification.
    </text>
</law>