<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Proposed Legislation Affecting Agencies;  Estimate Of Costs</catch_line>
    <order_by>3A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Any officer having charge of any state agency which receives a periodic appropriation from the commonwealth, or any officer of a state authority or commission, shall upon the request of any standing committee of the house or senate, or of any joint standing committee of the general court, furnish in writing to such committee, in a format prescribed by such committee, any information requested by such committee that is necessary for the committee to perform its duties. The information shall include, but not be limited to, historical, current or proposed operational costs funded through any appropriation, capital accounts, federal grants, trust funds or other funding sources, the officer's estimate of the cost of proposed legislation affecting activities which are or would be under his supervision, estimates of and reasons for any supplemental funding that is projected to be needed during the fiscal year, estimates of revenue collections, estimates of proposed changes in fees or taxes, and any other such information as may be required by the committee. Such estimates shall be provided to such committee within 10 days of the receipt of such a request by the officer. If the officer fails to respond within 10 days, the matter shall be referred to the house or senate committee on post audit and oversight which shall, in conjunction with the committee that originally requested the information, determine if further action is necessary.
Chapter 29: Information to be provided by agency or authority receiving periodic appropriation upon request by committees
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Any officer having charge of any state agency which receives a periodic appropriation from the commonwealth, or any officer of a state authority, shall upon the request of any standing committee of the house or senate, or of any joint standing committee of the general court, furnish in writing to such committee, in a format prescribed by such committee, any information requested by such committee that is necessary for the committee to perform its duties. The information shall include, but not be limited to, historical, current or proposed operational costs funded through any appropriation, bond authorizations, federal grants, trust funds or other funding sources, the officer's estimate of the cost of proposed legislation affecting activities which are or would be under the officer's supervision, estimates of and reasons for any supplemental funding that is projected to be needed during the fiscal year, estimates of revenue collections, estimates of proposed changes in fees or taxes, and any other such information as may be required by the committee. Such estimates shall be provided to such committee within 10 days of the receipt of such a request by the officer. If the officer fails to respond within 10 days, the matter shall be referred to the house or senate committee on post audit and oversight which shall, in conjunction with the committee that originally requested the information, determine if further action is necessary.
    </text>
</law>