<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>59</section_number>
    <catch_line>Lost Or Destroyed Interest Bearing Bonds;  Duplicates</catch_line>
    <order_by>59</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  If it appears to the governor and council that any interest-bearing bond of the commonwealth identified by number and description has, without bad faith upon the part of the owner, been lost or destroyed, wholly or in part, they shall, under regulations and with restrictions as to time and retention for security or otherwise prescribed by them, order the state treasurer to issue a registered duplicate of such bond, payable at the same time, bearing the same rate of interest as the bond lost or destroyed, and so marked as to show the number and date of the original bond. If such bond was of a class or series which has been called in for redemption before the application for a reissue, it shall be paid, with such interest only as would have been paid if the bond had been presented in accordance with such call.
Chapter 29: Lost or destroyed interest-bearing bonds; duplicates
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  If it appears to the governor and council that any interest-bearing bond of the commonwealth identified by number and description has, without bad faith upon the part of the owner, been lost or destroyed, wholly or in part, they shall, under regulations and with restrictions as to time and retention for security or otherwise prescribed by them, order the state treasurer to issue a registered duplicate of such bond, payable at the same time, bearing the same rate of interest as the bond lost or destroyed, and so marked as to show the number and date of the original bond. If such bond was of a class or series which has been called in for redemption before the application for a reissue, it shall be paid, with such interest only as would have been paid if the bond had been presented under such call.
    </text>
</law>