<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Annual Statement Of Planned Expenditures And Employment For Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority And Regional Transit Authorities</catch_line>
    <order_by>3B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority and the several regional transit authorities shall annually, on or before September fifteenth, submit to the state budget director, the joint committee on transportation, the house and senate committees on ways and means, and the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority advisory board (1) statements showing planned expenditures for the current fiscal year and the subsequent fiscal year; provided, however, that said statements shall detail planned expenditures according to the expenditure classification plan promulgated by the state comptroller pursuant to the provisions of section twenty-seven and also by program; and (2) a statement detailing the number of full time equivalent employees of the authority for the current fiscal year and an estimate of the number of full time equivalent employees for the subsequent fiscal year. The state budget director and the state comptroller are hereby authorized and directed to establish such procedures as they deem necessary to implement and enforce the provisions of this section.
Chapter 29: Annual statement of planned expenditures and employment for Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority and regional transit authorities
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority and the several regional transit authorities shall annually, on or before September 15, submit to the state budget director, the joint committee on transportation, the house and senate committees on ways and means and the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority advisory board (1) statements showing planned expenditures for the current fiscal year and the subsequent fiscal year; provided, however, that said statements shall detail planned expenditures according to program and to the expenditure classification plan promulgated by the state comptroller under section 27; and (2) a statement detailing the number of full time equivalent employees of the authority for the current fiscal year and an estimate of the number of full time equivalent employees for the subsequent fiscal year. The state budget director and the state comptroller shall establish such procedures as they deem necessary to implement and enforce this section.
    </text>
</law>