<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="30" order_by="30" level="3">General Provisions Relative To State Departments, Commissions, Officers And Employees</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>62I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Environmental Notification Forms Filed On Or After November 15, 2007; Requirements</catch_line>
    <order_by>62I</order_by>
    <text>
        A person who is proposing a new use or structure or modification of an existing use or structure within landlocked tidelands as defined in section 1 of chapter 91 that is otherwise required to file an environmental notification form pursuant to section 62A and files an environmental notification form on or after November 15, 2007, shall comply with the requirements of this paragraph. The environmental notification form, and an environmental impact report required pursuant to section 62B, if applicable, shall include an explanation of the project’s impact on the public’s right to access, use and enjoy tidelands that are protected by chapter 91, and identify measures to avoid, minimize, or mitigate any adverse impact on such rights set forth herein. If the project is located in an area where low groundwater levels have been identified by a municipality or by a state or federal agency as a threat to building foundations, the environmental notification form and an environmental impact report if the latter is required, shall also include an explanation of the project’s impact on groundwater levels, and identification and commitment to taking measures to avoid, minimize, or mitigate any adverse impact on groundwater levels. Any measures identified by the secretary under this section shall be set forth in a certificate on the environmental notification form or a certificate on the environmental impact report, if the latter is applicable. Within 30 days after a certificate is issued under this paragraph, the proponent of the project shall file with the department of environmental protection a completed form notifying the department that work will be conducted within landlocked tidelands, and shall attach the Massachusetts environmental policy act certificate to the form. The person who is proposing shall comply with all obligations set forth in the certificate under this section, and the department shall have the authority to enforce such conditions consistent with this chapter.
    </text>
</law>