<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2L</section_number>
    <catch_line>Water Pollution Abatement Revolving Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2L</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund, to be known as the Water Pollution Abatement Revolving Fund, consisting of amounts credited to the fund in accordance with chapter twenty-nine C. The fund shall be administered in accordance with the provisions of said chapter twenty-nine C by the board of trustees of the water pollution abatement trust created thereunder and shall be held in trust exclusively for the purposes and the beneficiaries described therein. The state treasurer shall be treasurer-custodian of the fund and shall have the custody of its monies and securities.
Chapter 29: Water Pollution Abatement Revolving Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund, to be known as the Water Pollution Abatement Revolving Fund, consisting of amounts credited to the fund under chapter 29C. The fund shall be administered under said chapter 29C by the board of trustees of the water pollution abatement trust created under that chapter and shall be held in trust exclusively for the purposes and the beneficiaries described in that chapter. The state treasurer shall be treasurer-custodian of the fund and shall have the custody of its monies and securities.
    </text>
</law>