<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>48B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bonds And Notes;  Official Statements;  Advertising;  Collateral Tax Consequences To Social Security Recipients</catch_line>
    <order_by>48B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Any official statement prepared in connection with the sale of any bonds or notes of the commonwealth and all advertising of such bonds and notes, the interest on which is excludable from gross income for federal income tax purposes under the provisions of section 103 of the Internal Revenue Code (26 USC 103), shall include a reference to the collateral tax consequences which may result under section 86 of said Code (26 USC 86) to the holders of such bonds or notes who are recipients of social security benefits.
Chapter 29: Bonds and notes; official statements; advertising; collateral tax consequences to social security recipients
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Any official statement prepared in connection with the sale of any bonds or notes of the commonwealth and all advertising of such bonds and notes, the interest on which is excludable from gross income for federal income tax purposes under section 103 of the Internal Revenue Code (26 USC 103), shall include a reference to the collateral tax consequences which may result under section 86 of said Code (26 USC 86) to the holders of such bonds or notes who are recipients of social security benefits.
    </text>
</law>