<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>38B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Deferred Compensation Committee;  State Treasurer's Office</catch_line>
    <order_by>38B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There shall be in the office of the state treasurer a deferred compensation committee, consisting of three members, one of whom shall be appointed by the governor, shall represent the employees who contract with the state treasurer for a deferred compensation program under section sixty-four, and shall be chairman, one of whom shall be appointed by the commissioner of insurance, and one of whom shall be appointed by the state treasurer. Said committee shall meet from time to time and shall oversee the operation of the day to day operation of the deferred compensation program. The members of said committee shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties.
Chapter 29: Deferred compensation committee
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There shall be in the office of the state treasurer a deferred compensation committee, consisting of 3 members; 1 of whom shall be appointed by the governor, shall represent the employees who contract with the state treasurer for a deferred compensation program under section 64 and shall be chairman; 1 of whom shall be appointed by the commissioner of insurance; and 1 of whom shall be appointed by the state treasurer. Said committee shall meet from time to time and shall oversee the day to day operation of the deferred compensation program. The members of said committee shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties.
    </text>
</law>