<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2YYY</section_number>
    <catch_line>Courts Capital Project Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2YYY</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund, to be known as the Courts Capital Project Fund, hereinafter in this section referred to as the fund. The fund shall be credited: (i) the portion of any net cash proceeds from the conveyance, lease or other disposition of any surplus court facilities vacated and determined to be surplus by the commissioner of the division of capital asset management and maintenance as a result of or in anticipation of the construction of new court facilities or the consolidation of court facilities in the cities of Cambridge, Lowell, Salem and Worcester; (ii) any appropriations; (iii) bond proceeds; or (iv) other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited thereto. The comptroller shall disburse amounts in the fund at the direction of the secretary of administration and finance, without further appropriation, for the purpose of paying costs of, or paying down any portion of the debt incurred to pay costs related to the acquisition, temporary leasing or the construction of any replacement court facilities. The inspector general of the commonwealth shall make an annual oversight inquiry and report on the Capital Courts Project Fund and its disbursements. Said report shall be provided to the clerks of the house of representatives and senate, chairs of house and senate committees on ways and means and chairs of the joint committee on bonding, capital expenditures, and state assets.
Chapter 29: Courts Capital Project Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund, to be known as the Courts Capital Project Fund, in this section referred to as the fund. The fund shall be credited: (i) the portion of any net cash proceeds from the conveyance, lease or other disposition of any surplus court facilities vacated and determined to be surplus by the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance as a result of or in anticipation of the construction of new court facilities or the consolidation of court facilities in the cities of Cambridge, Lowell, Salem and Worcester; (ii) any appropriations; (iii) bond proceeds; or (iv) other monies authorized by the general court and specifically designated to be credited to the fund. The comptroller shall disburse amounts in the fund at the direction of the secretary of administration and finance, without further appropriation, for the purpose of paying costs of, or paying down any portion of the debt incurred to pay costs related to the acquisition, temporary leasing or the construction of any replacement court facilities. The inspector general of the commonwealth shall make an annual oversight inquiry and report on the Capital Courts Project Fund and its disbursements. Said report shall be provided to the clerks of the house of representatives and senate, chairs of house and senate committees on ways and means and chairs of the house and senate committees on bonding, capital expenditures and state assets.
    </text>
</law>