<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>27B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Expenditure Of Funds For Lease Or Purchase Of Data Processing Or Reproduction Equipment Restricted</catch_line>
    <order_by>27B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  No state agency, excepting the departments of the attorney general, state auditor, state secretary, and state treasurer, shall initiate any encumbrance or make any expenditure of funds, whether appropriated or not, for the lease or purchase of date processing or reproduction equipment or systems unless:  (1) if appropriated funds are to be used, a prior request therefor has been made to the budget director under sections three or four, and at least 30 days written notification has been given to the house and senate committees on ways and means;  (2) the officer in charge of the agency has certified that funds are specifically available for the purpose;  (3) in the case of a department, office, commission, board or institution within any of the executive offices established by chapters six A and seven, the secretary having charge of such executive office has approved in writing the encumbrance or expenditure, and  (4) the commissioner of administration has approved in writing said encumbrance or expenditure.  The commissioner of administration shall establish rules and regulations governing the lease or purchase of data processing or reproduction equipment or systems and the procedure for requesting approval thereof as required by this section.  The commissioner of administration shall notify the house and senate committees on ways and means and joint legislative committee on post audit and oversight of the general court of any approval granted by him under this section.
Chapter 29: Expenditure of funds for lease or purchase of data processing or reproduction equipment restricted
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  No state agency, excepting the departments of the attorney general, state auditor, state secretary and state treasurer, shall initiate any encumbrance or make any expenditure of funds, whether appropriated or not, for the lease or purchase of data processing or reproduction equipment or systems unless:  (1) if appropriated funds are to be used, a prior request therefor has been made to the budget director under sections 3 or 4, and at least 30 days written notification has been given to the house and senate committees on ways and means;  (2) the officer in charge of the agency has certified that funds are specifically available for the purpose;  (3) in the case of a department, office, commission, board or institution within any of the executive offices established by chapters 6A and 7, the secretary having charge of such executive office has approved in writing the encumbrance or expenditure, and  (4) the secretary of administration and finance has approved in writing said encumbrance or expenditure.  The secretary of administration and finance shall establish rules and regulations governing the lease or purchase of data processing or reproduction equipment or systems and the procedure for requesting approval thereof as required by this section.  The secretary of administration and finance shall notify the house and senate committees on ways and means and the house and senate committees on post audit and oversight of the general court of any approval granted by the secretary under this section.
    </text>
</law>