<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Laws Relating To State Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29" level="3">State Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2III</section_number>
    <catch_line>Agricultural Resolve And Security Fund; Gifts, Grants, Donations, Annual Audit And Report</catch_line>
    <order_by>2III</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Agricultural Resolve and Security Fund, the funds of which shall be expended for the purpose of fostering agriculture in the commonwealth, as the term "agriculture'' is defined pursuant to section 1A of chapter 128, and for furthering other purposes of the department of food and agriculture as set forth in any general or special law. These purposes may include, but shall not be limited to, agricultural education, support for sustainable agriculture and pollution prevention, agricultural integrated pest management programs, agricultural land preservation, control of animal diseases and emergency preparedness.  The Agricultural Resolve and Security Fund shall receive monies from: (1) gifts, grants and donations from public or private sources; (2) federal reimbursements and grants-in-aid; and (3) any interest earned from the fund. The state treasurer shall receive, deposit and invest funds held in such a manner as to ensure the highest interest rate available consistent with the safety of the fund. The books and records of the fund shall be subject to an annual audit by the state auditor. The department may expend such funds, subject to appropriation, and no expenditure from the fund shall cause it to be in deficiency at the close of a fiscal year. The commissioner of food and agriculture shall report annually to the house and senate committees on ways and means and the joint committee on natural resources and agriculture on income received into the fund and the sources of that income, any expenditures from the fund and their purposes and fund balances.
Chapter 29: Agricultural Resolve and Security Fund
[ Text of section as recodified by 2012, 165, Sec. 112 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Agricultural Resolve and Security Fund, the funds of which shall be expended to foster agriculture, as defined in section 1A of chapter 128, in the commonwealth and for furthering other purposes of the department of agricultural resources as set forth in any general or special law including, but not limited to, agricultural education, support for sustainable agriculture and pollution prevention, agricultural integrated pest management programs, agricultural land preservation, control of animal diseases and emergency preparedness.  The Agricultural Resolve and Security Fund may receive monies from: (1) gifts, grants and donations from public or private sources; (2) federal reimbursements and grants-in-aid; and (3) any interest earned from the fund. The state treasurer shall receive, deposit and invest funds held in such a manner as to ensure the highest interest rate available consistent with the safety of the fund. The books and records of the fund shall be subject to an annual audit by the state auditor. The department may expend such funds, subject to appropriation, and no expenditure from the fund shall cause it to be in deficiency at the close of a fiscal year. The commissioner agricultural resources shall report annually to the house and senate committees on ways and means and the joint committee on environment, natural resources and agriculture on income received into the fund and sources of that income, any expenditure from the fund and their purposes and fund balances.
    </text>
</law>