<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>21</section_number>
    <catch_line>Training Of Hunting Dogs; Field Trials</catch_line>
    <order_by>21</order_by>
    <text>
        Except as provided in sections 21A, 70, 81 and 82, nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the training of hunting dogs, so-called, or conducting or engaging in a field trial with such dogs; provided, however, that except during other open seasons promulgated by the director, no firearms may be carried by any person so training or conducting or engaging in such field trials. A person shall not conduct any field trial where the use of buildings of the division, the services of any personnel of the division are deemed necessary by the director or birds or mammals are provided by the director without first obtaining a permit so to do from the director, which permit may be issued upon payment of a fee, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven for the filing thereof. Such field trials shall be conducted in accordance with such rules and regulations as the director may prescribe, authority to issue such permits and make, alter, amend and rescind such rules and regulations being hereby granted to him. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require a person attending or participating in such a field trial or such training to obtain a hunting or sporting license; provided, that no firearm other than a pistol or revolver and blank cartridges are used or possessed by such person; and provided further, that no birds or mammals are taken or killed.
    </text>
</law>