<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="129" order_by="129" level="3">Livestock Disease Control</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>36B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Vaccination Of Female Calves; Identification Of Positive Reactors;  Transportation Of Unvaccinated Bovine Animals</catch_line>
    <order_by>36B</order_by>
    <text>
        The director shall cause all female calves to be vaccinated against brucellosis, commonly known as bangs disease, when they are from the ages of four to eight months, inclusive. Calves shall be vaccinated by an approved licensed veterinarian designated by the director and only with vaccine produced at establishments licensed under the federal Virus-Serum-Toxin Act, or at establishments in the commonwealth approved by the director, and the expense thereof shall be borne by the commonwealth. The director shall make the necessary rules for the handling of the vaccine and the method of vaccination. Any person refusing to have his calves vaccinated shall not be permitted to move any of his cattle from his premises except for immediate slaughter, unless such cattle react negatively to an approved blood test for brucellosis. Each veterinarian shall make a report of all animals vaccinated by him on forms furnished by the director. The commonwealth shall not be liable for any damages incurred or alleged to have been incurred by the use of vaccine. Whenever any cattle are tested for brucellosis and determined to react positively to such tests, or are vaccinated against brucellosis, the owner of the cattle shall cause them to be permanently identified in accordance with regulations prescribed by the director. It shall be unlawful for a person to transport or offer for transport any unvaccinated bovine animal over six months of age, and any vaccinated bovine animal over eighteen months of age that has been tested for brucellosis and has reacted positive to such tests, except cattle moved under permit issued by the director to slaughtering establishments under state or federal inspection. Any person, firm or corporation who buys, sells or transports any cattle known to be positive to an approved test for brucellosis, except animals under eighteen months of age and accompanied by a certificate of vaccination or except unvaccinated animals less than six months of age or except animals for immediate slaughter, shall be fined not more than two hundred dollars for each animal bought, sold or transported.
    </text>
</law>