<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16</section_number>
    <catch_line>Loss Or Destruction Of License; Duplicates</catch_line>
    <order_by>16</order_by>
    <text>
        Whoever loses or by mistake or accident destroys his license, permit, or certificate issued under this chapter may, upon application to the director, clerk of the city or town or any person duly authorized under the provisions of section twelve issuing the same, and upon payment of a fee, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, receive a duplicate license, permit or certificate; provided, that such application is accompanied by an affidavit setting forth the circumstances of said loss, and also, if application is made to the director in any case where he did not issue the original license, permit or certificate, by a statement from the person who issued the original license, permit or certificate, or his successor in office, which statement shall contain the number and form of the license, permit or certificate, the date of its issue, and a personal description of the licensee. A person shall not, while he knowingly has a valid license, permit or certificate, obtain, have in possession or use any duplicate license, permit or certificate. A person shall not, while he knowingly has a valid fishing, hunting, sporting or trapping license, obtain for himself, have in possession or use any license which purports to afford him any of the privileges of the original license for any part of the period for which such original license was valid.
    </text>
</law>