<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132" level="3">Forestry</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>41</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Forestry Committee; Members; Forest Cutting Practices And Guidelines</catch_line>
    <order_by>41</order_by>
    <text>
        The governor shall appoint a state forestry committee, to consist of eight members representing, respectively: forest land owners; primary woodusing industries; licensed timber harvesters; consulting foresters; environmental organizations; water supply agencies; fisheries and wildlife; and one member representing the public at large. The director of the division of forests and parks, hereinafter referred to as the director, shall be an ex officio member of the committee and shall vote only in case of a tie. 
In the initial appointments of said committee members, three shall be appointed for a one year term, three for a two year term, and two for a three year term. Thereafter, as the term of a committee member expires, his successor, with like qualifications as his predecessor, shall be appointed for a term of three years. Said committee shall select its own chairman. The members of said committee shall serve without pay, but shall be reimbursed for actual travelling expenses within the commonwealth, when approved by said director. 
The state forestry committee, with recommendations of such other advisory committees as the director in his discretion may appoint, shall prepare tentative minimum forest cutting practices and guidelines. Before recommending any forest practices, said committee shall hold hearings, with due notice being given, in conformance with chapter thirty A, in at least three places conveniently located throughout the commonwealth. Said committee may thereafter recommend such practices or modifications thereof and submit them to the director of forests and parks. Said director shall, subject to the approval by the commissioner of environmental management, thereupon adopt the practices and place them in effect, by posting in all city and town halls in the region affected and by publication in at least one daily newspaper in every county affected. Such approved practices may be amended at any time by said committee in the same manner, on its own motion or upon the petition of not less than twenty-five forest owners or licensed timber harvesters of the commonwealth or upon petition of any person authorized under section four of chapter thirty A.
    </text>
</law>