<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132A" order_by="132A" level="3">State Recreation Areas Outside Of The Metropolitan Parks District</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Development And Improvement; Powers Of Commissioner</catch_line>
    <order_by>2D</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     To impose and collect such charges and fees for the use of the lands, buildings, facilities and equipment enumerated in subdivision (1) as may be necessary to defray in so far as practicable the cost of such developments and improvements, including costs of maintenance and operation and bond amortization and interest and to revise said fees and charges from time to time. A disabled veteran or a handicapped person whose vehicle bears the distinctive type number plate authorized by section two of chapter ninety shall not be required to pay the charges or fees imposed under the provisions of this subdivision.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     To designate such areas as may be used in season for hunting and fishing.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     To effect improvements at public recreation facilities, including improvements through the commonwealth’s shared energy savings program and to expend, without further appropriation, monies received as a result of the improvements from a trust for facilities, the costs associated with said improvements, including contingency costs authorized under section forty-three F of chapter seven. The department shall develop and submit to the secretary of administration and finance and the house and senate committees on ways and means an analysis of all expenditures from said trust on or before each September first for the prior fiscal year.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>