<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132B" order_by="132B" level="3">Massachusetts Pesticide Control Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Adjudicatory Hearings</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person aggrieved by a determination by the department to register or not to register a pesticide, to suspend a pesticide registration, to issue, not issue or revoke an experimental use permit, to issue, deny, revoke or suspend any certification or license, or to issue an order, made under the provisions of this chapter, may request an adjudicatory hearing before the board under the provisions of chapter thirty A. Said determination shall contain a notice of a right to request a hearing and may specify a time limit, not to exceed twenty-one days, within which said persons may request a hearing before the board under the provisions of said chapter thirty A. If no such request is timely made, the determination shall be deemed assented to. If a timely request is received, the board shall within a reasonable time hold a hearing and comply with the provisions of said chapter thirty A. In hearings so held the board shall designate a hearing officer to preside over the hearing, to assemble an official record thereof, and to render a tentative decision as provided in paragraph (7) of section eleven of said chapter thirty A. The board shall make the final decision on the basis of the official record and tentative decision so rendered. 
If, in making a determination which under the provisions of the preceding paragraph may be the subject of an adjudicatory hearing, the department finds that an imminent hazard or an unreasonable adverse effect on the environment could result pending the conclusion of the adjudicatory hearing requested thereon, the department may order that the determination shall become provisionally effective and enforceable immediately upon issuance, and shall remain so notwithstanding and until the conclusion of any adjudicatory hearing procedures timely requested. In the event that the department has thus made a determination provisionally effective, it may later, at its discretion, shorten the duration of or waive such order. 
As part of a final decision in an adjudicatory proceeding held under the provisions of this section, the board may specify a reasonable time period within which the matter may be barred from further proceedings before the department or the board. In the event that the board has so specified a time period, the board may later, at its discretion, shorten or waive such period. 
A person aggrieved by a final adjudicatory determination of the board may obtain judicial review thereof pursuant to the provisions of chapter thirty A.
    </text>
</law>