<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>65A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Online Shooting Or Spearing</catch_line>
    <order_by>65A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purposes of this section, “online shooting or spearing” means the use of a computer or any other device, equipment, software or technology, to remotely control the aiming and discharge of any weapon including, but not limited to, any firearm, bow and arrow, spear, slingshot, harpoon or any other projectile device or any other weapon capable of killing or capable of inflicting injury capable of killing any bird, mammal, reptile or fish.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Whoever:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     engages in online shooting or spearing of any bird, mammal, reptile or fish;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     owns or operates a shooting range, site, gallery or other facility in the commonwealth utilized for online shooting or spearing;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     creates, maintains or utilizes an Internet Web site, or a service or business via any other means, from any location within the commonwealth for the operation of online shooting or spearing;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     possesses or confines any bird, mammal, reptile or fish to promote or for use in online shooting or spearing; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     imports into or exports out of the commonwealth any bird, mammal, reptile or fish, or the remains thereof, injured or killed by online shooting or spearing, shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 2 1/2 years or by a fine of not more than $2,500, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The department shall revoke any license issued pursuant to section 12 to any person who violates this section. The department shall not issue nor renew a license under said section 12 to any person who violates this section for not less than 3 years nor more than 5 years from the date of such violation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     This section shall apply to any person, firm, corporation, partnership, limited liability company, association or other business entity.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Any bird, mammal, reptile or fish, or the remains thereof, possessed in violation of this section shall be subject to seizure by the department.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>