<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Nature Preserve Council</catch_line>
    <order_by>10B</order_by>
    <text>
        A nature preserve council, hereinafter referred to as the council, shall be established and shall consist of seven members who shall be appointed by the secretary of the executive office of environmental affairs, four of whom shall be members of the natural heritage and endangered species advisory committee, appointed pursuant to section five B, two of whom shall be trained in plant ecology and shall represent colleges, universities, outdoor education programs, primary and secondary schools, science museums, and arboreta, and one of whom shall be knowledgeable in natural history and shall represent the general public. The members of the council shall be reimbursed for their necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. Each member shall be appointed for a term of three years, except that for the initial term, three members shall be appointed for one year, two members shall be appointed for two years and two members shall be appointed for three years. Any person appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the unexpired term. Any member shall be eligible for reappointment. 
The council shall annually select from among its members a chairman. The council shall hold meetings at least quarterly. Special meetings may be called by the chairman and shall be called by him upon written request of at least two members of the council. A written notice of the time and place of each meeting shall be sent to each member. 
The council’s duties shall include advising the division on policies and rules and regulations concerning nature preserves, consulting with the division regarding the nomination of potential nature preserves, assisting in the preparation of a plan for each nature preserve, and advising the division on budgetary matters related to such nature preserves. The council shall submit a biennial report to the governor on or before May first of such year, describing the condition of each nature preserve, outlining any actions taken by the council since the last report, and making any recommendations related to the nature preserve program which the council deems necessary.
    </text>
</law>