<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20</section_number>
    <catch_line>Field Trials For Retriever Or Bird Dogs</catch_line>
    <order_by>20</order_by>
    <text>
        Upon application to the director by an incorporated or unincorporated club or organization having a membership of citizens who have been residents of the commonwealth for at least six consecutive months immediately prior to making application, and upon payment of a fee by the applicant, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven for the filing thereof, the director may issue a license to such club or organization to hold a field trial under the rules and regulations of the American Kennel Club, Inc., American Field or other bird dog or kennel association as recognized by the director for retriever or bird dogs at the time and place stated in the license. The license shall authorize members of the licensee to shoot and kill with firearms, under the supervision of an environmental police officer of the division of law enforcement except that, in the case of such a field trial conducted on property under the ownership or control of the division, under the supervision of an employee of the division, pheasants, quail, chukar partridge, mallard ducks, or other species authorized by the director, which are propagated or legally acquired by members of the licensee, and released by members of the licensee at the field trial held at the time and place specified in the license. The license shall be valid only during the daylight hours, and the written consent of the owner of or the person having legal control of, the land on which such field trial is held shall first be obtained. Before any pheasant, quail, chukar partridge, mallard duck, or other species so shot is removed from the premises, the environmental police officer of the division of law enforcement or the employee of the division, as the case may be, shall attach to it a tag, which shall be furnished by the director for a reasonable fee, and which shall remain attached to the bird until the bird is prepared for consumption. A licensee shall pay to the environmental police officer of the division of law enforcement or the employee of the division, as the case may be, a fee for services rendered at such a field trial, the amount of which shall be determined pursuant to the aforementioned chapter seven provision. Such environmental police officer shall be designated by the director of the division of law enforcement or such employee of the division shall be designated by the director, as the case may be, to supervise such a field trial. Persons participating in any such field trial pursuant to the provisions of this section shall not be required to secure hunting or sporting licenses for this purpose.
    </text>
</law>