<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="128A" order_by="128A" level="3">Horse And Dog Racing Meetings</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Stewards To Conduct Racing Meetings;  Representatives;  Access;  Authority;  Reports;  Violations</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 31, 2014. Repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 39. See 2011, 194, Sec. 112.]  The commission shall appoint two stewards to each track licensed to conduct racing meetings, who shall not be subject to chapter thirty-one or section nine A of chapter thirty. The commission shall assign, by regulation, duties to be performed by him. The compensation of the commission-appointed steward shall be fixed by the commission.  The commission may also appoint one or more other representatives to attend each racing meeting held or conducted under a license issued under this chapter, and the appointment of said representatives shall not be subject to chapter thirty-one or section nine A of chapter thirty. The compensation and duties of each such representative shall be fixed by the commission.  Each such representative appointed by the commission to attend a racing meeting shall have full and free access to the space or enclosure where the pari-mutuel or certificate system of wagering is conducted or supervised for the purpose only of ascertaining whether or not the provisions of this chapter are being properly observed. He shall also, for the same purpose only, have full and free access to the books, records and papers pertaining to such pari-mutuel or certificate system of wagering. All employees of the commission assigned to the tracks for security purposes and all police officers assigned to the commission shall be under the control and authority of one of the representatives of the commission at each track. Said representative shall have full and free access to any other areas used in connection with the conduct of racing. He shall investigate, ascertain and report to the commission in writing under oath as to whether or not he has discovered any violation at such meeting of any of the provisions of this chapter, and, if so, the nature and character of such violations. Such report shall be made within ten days after the termination of the duties of such representative at any racing meeting.  If any such report shows any violation of this chapter, the commission shall transmit a copy of such report to the attorney general for such action as he shall deem proper.
    </text>
</law>