<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132" level="3">Forestry</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>34</section_number>
    <catch_line>Rules And Regulations Relative To Use Of State Forests; Enforcement</catch_line>
    <order_by>34</order_by>
    <text>
        The commissioner may make rules and regulations relative to hunting and fishing or other uses of any such land, provided that such rules and regulations shall be consistent with all laws in relation to the protection of fish, birds and quadrupeds. Whoever violates any provision of any such rule or regulation shall be punished by a fine of not more than twenty-five dollars. 
In addition to the officers required by section seven of chapter one hundred and twenty-nine A to enforce throughout the commonwealth the provisions of law relating to fish, birds and mammals, the forester, state fire warden and any duly authorized forest warden or deputy forest warden shall enforce said provisions within the limits of state forests and shall enforce throughout the commonwealth the provisions of section eighty-one of chapter one hundred and thirty-one; and said forester and wardens shall enforce the provisions of all rules and regulations relating to state forests and state reservations made under authority of this chapter and chapter one hundred and thirty-two A. With respect to violations of all the provisions aforesaid, said forester and wardens shall have and exercise all the powers conferred by law upon the officers described in said section seven for the enforcement of the laws relating to fish, birds and mammals. The officers mentioned in said section seven shall take cognizance of violations of said rules and regulations and prosecute the same; and for such purpose shall have and exercise all said powers.
    </text>
</law>