<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="128C" order_by="128C" level="3">Simulcast Wagering Of Horse And Dog Racing</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Records Regarding Injuries Incurred By Racing Greyhounds;  Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>7A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 31, 2014. Repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 41. See 2011, 194, Sec. 112. See, also, 2001, 139, Sec. 45 as amended by 2005, 176, Sec. 13; 2006, 54, Sec. 12; 2006, 449, Secs. 19 and 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 12; 2009, 167, Sec. 12; 2010, c. 203, Sec. 12; 2011, 77, Sec. 12 and 2011, 194, Sec. 84. Expiration of section does not take effect. See 1992, 101, Sec. 13 as amended by 2001, 139, Sec. 39; 2005, 176, Sec. 12; 2006, 54, Sec. 11; 2006, 449, Secs. 18 and 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 11; 2009, 167, Sec. 11; 2010, 203, Sec. 11 and 2011, 77, Sec. 11 and as repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 83.]  The racing commission shall adopt regulations governing injuries incurred by racing greyhounds while they are racing in the commonwealth, including schooling races. The commission shall maintain accurate records and statistics regarding the injuries. The records shall include the following:--  (1) the greyhound's registered name and right and left ear tattoo numbers;  (2) the owner, trainer and kennel operator's name, business address and telephone number;  (3) the color, weight, and sex of the greyhound;  (4) where the injury took place on a race track or other area;  (5) if the injury occurred while the greyhound was racing, the race track where the injury occurred, along with the distance, grade, race and post position when the injury occurred; the weather conditions, time, temperature, and track condition when the injury occurred; the specific type of injury, the cause of the injury, the estimated recovery time, and the location of injury on the greyhound.  All injury forms shall be completed and signed under the pains and penalties of perjury by the race track veterinarian, whose signature shall be witnessed by a designated representative of the state racing commission. Whoever knowingly makes a false written statement on an injury form shall be punished by imprisonment for up to 2 years and by a fine of up to $2,500, or both. A person found guilty of knowingly violating this section for a second or subsequent offense shall be punished by imprisonment for not less than 1, nor more than 5 years, or a fine of not less than $5,000, or both such fine and imprisonment. Disposition and injury records created and maintained under this section shall be maintained by the state racing commission for a period of 7 years and shall be made readily available to the public upon oral or written request.  The department of food and agriculture may certify entities of any kind which provide humane disposition and cremation, or adoption services, including proper implementation of neutering and spaying of all greyhounds prior to adoption, for greyhounds bred for racing who never qualify for pari-mutuel races or for racing greyhounds who have reached the end of their racing career.
    </text>
</law>