<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="128C" order_by="128C" level="3">Simulcast Wagering Of Horse And Dog Racing</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Simulcast Wagering At Guest Track For Greyhound Races From Host Track;  Payments To Winning Patrons, Commission And Greyhound Promotional Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 31, 2014. Repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 41. See 2011, 194, Sec. 112. Expiration of section does not take effect. See 1992, 101, Sec. 13 as amended by 1995, 268, Sec. 20; 1999, 163, Sec. 12; 2000, 354, Sec. 14; 2001, 25, Sec. 1; 2001, 54, Sec. 4; 2001, 70, Sec. 4; 2001, 95, Sec. 4; 2001, 108, Sec. 4; 2001, 121, Sec. 4; 2001, 139, Sec. 39; 2005, 176, Sec. 12; 2006, 54, Sec. 11; 2006, 449, Secs. 18 and 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 11; 2009, 167, Sec. 11; 2010, 203, Sec. 11 and 2011, 77, Sec. 11 and as repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 83.][ First paragraph effective until July 31, 2014. See 2001, 139, Sec. 45 as amended by 2005, 176, Sec. 13; 2006, 54, Sec. 12; 2006, 449, Secs. 19 and 21; 2008, 290, Sec. 12; 2009, 167, Sec. 12; 2010, 203, Sec. 12; 2011, 77, Sec. 12 and 2011, 194, Sec. 84. For text effective July 31, 2014, see below.]  Each racing meeting licensee within the commonwealth acting as a guest track and simulcasting a live greyhound race from a host track within the commonwealth shall return to the winning patrons wagering on such simulcast race all sums so deposited as an award or dividend, according to the acknowledged and recognized rules and methods under which such pari-mutuel or certificate system has been operated, less the breaks and less an amount not to exceed nineteen percent of the total amount so deposited; provided, however, that a sum equal to two and one-half percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid daily to the commission on behalf of the commonwealth; a sum equal to one-quarter of one percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid to the Greyhound Promotional Trust Fund under the direction and supervision of the state racing commissioners; a sum equal to one-quarter of one percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid to the Greyhound Capital Improvements Trust Fund under the direction and supervision of the state racing commissioners; a sum equal to two and one-half percent shall be paid as purses to the dog owners at the host track in accordance with the rules and established customs of conducting greyhound racing meetings; a sum equal to four and one-quarter percent shall be paid to the racing meeting licensee at the host track; a sum equal to nine and one-quarter percent shall be retained by the racing meeting licensee at the guest track; provided, however, that not less than three and one-half percent shall be paid to the dog owners for purses, said percentages to be paid from the nineteen percent withheld as provided in this section.[ First paragraph effective July 31, 2014 does not take effect. See 2011, 194, Secs. 41 and 112. For text effective until July 31, 2014, see above.]  Each racing meeting licensee within the commonwealth acting as a guest track and simulcasting a live greyhound race from a host track within the commonwealth shall return to the winning patrons wagering on such simulcast race all sums so deposited as an award or dividend, according to the acknowledged and recognized rules and methods under which such pari-mutuel or certificate system has been operated, less the breaks, as defined in section five of chapter one hundred and twenty-eight A, and less an amount not to exceed nineteen percent of the total amount so deposited; provided, however, that a sum equal to two and one-half percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid daily to the commission on behalf of the commonwealth; a sum equal to one-quarter of one percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid to the Greyhound Promotional Trust Fund under the direction and supervision of the state racing commissioners; a sum equal to one-quarter of one percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid to the Greyhound Capital Improvements Trust Fund under the direction and supervision of the state racing commissioners; a sum equal to two and one-half percent shall be paid as purses to the dog owners at the host track in accordance with the rules and established customs of conducting greyhound racing meetings; a sum equal to four and one-quarter percent shall be paid to the racing meeting licensee at the host track; a sum equal to nine and one-quarter percent shall be retained by the racing meeting licensee at the guest track; provided, however, that not less than three and one-half percent shall be paid to the dog owners for purses, said percentages to be paid from the nineteen percent withheld as provided in this section.  Each racing meeting licensee within the commonwealth acting as a guest track and simulcasting a live greyhound race from a host track from outside the commonwealth shall return to the winning patrons all sums so deposited less such breaks and less either an amount not to exceed nineteen percent of the total amount so deposited or an amount which would be paid under the laws of the jurisdiction exercising regulatory authority over such host track; provided, however, that a sum equal to two and one-half percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid daily to the commission on behalf of the commonwealth; a sum equal to one-quarter of one percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid to the Greyhound Promotional Trust Fund under the direction and supervision of the state racing commissioners; a sum equal to one-quarter of one percent of the total amount wagered shall be paid to the Greyhound Capital Improvement Trust Fund under the direction and supervision of the state racing commissioners; and the remaining percentages shall be retained by the racing meeting licensee as his commission; provided, however, that not less than three and one-half percent shall be paid to the dog owners for purses, and the remaining portion shall be applied to the expenses as the racing meeting licensee is required to pay pursuant to contracts negotiated with the host track. All such contracts shall be subject to the approval of the recognized greyhound owners association of the most recent live racing performance at the guest track.  In no case shall a person or association licensed to conduct a dog racing meeting serve as a guest or host track for the purpose of simulcasting a race unless the licensee has received the prior approval of the greyhound owners association at the licensees facility and such approval is on file with the commission.
    </text>
</law>