<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131" level="3">Inland Fisheries And Game And Other Natural Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23</section_number>
    <catch_line>Propagation, Dealing, Etc., In Fish, Birds, Mammals, Reptiles Or Amphibians; Rules And Regulations; Licenses; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>23</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     To any individual, a special propagator’s license to possess, propagate and maintain fish at any time for the personal use of himself, his immediate family or guests; or to any club or association, or its members or guests; a special propagator’s license to possess, propagate and maintain fish at any time for the purpose of fishing within waters under the control of such club or association for the personal use of the members and guests thereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     To any individual, club or association, a special propagator’s license to possess, propagate and maintain fish for the purpose of liberation into public waters, for which there shall be no fee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     To any individual, club or association, a propagator’s license to possess, propagate, maintain, buy, sell or otherwise dispose of fish at any season of the year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     To any individual, a propagator’s license to possess, maintain, buy, sell, offer for sale or have in possession for the purpose of sale, birds, mammals, reptiles or amphibians.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     To any individual, club or association, a special propagator’s license to possess birds or mammals to propagate for the purpose of liberation into covers open to public hunting, for which there shall be no fee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     To any individual, a dealer’s license to possess, buy, sell, or offer for sale, fish, birds or mammals lawfully taken or lawfully propagated outside the commonwealth or lawfully propagated within the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     To any individual, a license to possess but not to sell except under authority of a permit from the director, authority to issue such permits being hereby granted to the director, a bird or mammal as a pet, or for the purpose of training dogs, or a reptile or amphibian.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     To any individual, a license to possess, liberate and recapture, but not to sell except under authority of a permit from the director, authority to issue such permit being hereby granted to the director, up to twenty-five quail for the purpose of training dogs.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     To any person who successfully fulfills the license requirements as established by the director, a falconry license, for either an apprentice falconer, general or master falconer, depending upon the applicant’s qualifications and testing, to keep, train and hunt with raptors in accordance with the rules and regulations established therefor, provided that when hunting, the licensee shall also possess a valid hunting or sporting license.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     To any person fulfilling the requirements of this license as established by the director, a raptor breeding license to possess and propagate birds of the families Accipitridae, Falconidae, Tytonidae, and Strigidae in accordance with the rules and regulations established therefor. The sport of falconry shall be permitted under this license only for the purposes of conditioning and training propagated raptors prior to their release to the wild or transfer to a falconry permittee or other use as authorized by the director.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     To any person fulfilling the requirements of this license as established by the director, a raptor salvage license to possess, transport, rehabilitate and release to the wild, transfer to a falconry permittee, or other use as authorized by the director, birds of the order Falconiformes, except species prohibited by federal regulations, in accordance with the rules and regulations established therefor. The sport of falconry shall be permitted under this license only for the purposes of conditioning and training rehabilitated raptors prior to their release to the wild, transfer to a falconry permittee or other use as authorized by the director.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>