<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132B" order_by="132B" level="3">Massachusetts Pesticide Control Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Violations; Penalties; Injunctions</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person who knowingly violates any provision of section six shall be punished by a fine of not more than twenty-five thousand dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both such fine and imprisonment, for each such violation, or shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed twenty-five thousand dollars for each such violation, which may be assessed in an action brought on behalf of the commonwealth in any court of competent jurisdiction. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate offense. 
Any person who violates any provision of section 6A to 6I, inclusive, or section 7A or who violates any regulation adopted under the provisions of this chapter, (a) shall be punished by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars, or imprisonment for not more than six months, or both such fine and imprisonment, for the second and each subsequent offense knowingly committed, or (b), shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed ten thousand dollars for any offense, which may be assessed in an action brought on behalf of the commonwealth in any court of competent jurisdiction. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate offense. 
Any person who violates any order issued under the provisions of this chapter, (a) shall be punished by a fine of not more than twenty-five thousand dollars or imprisonment for not more than two years, or both such fine and imprisonment, for each violation knowingly committed, or (b) shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed twenty-five thousand dollars for each violation, which may be assessed in an action brought on behalf of the commonwealth in any court of competent jurisdiction. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate offense. 
The superior court shall have jurisdiction to enjoin violations of, or grant such relief as it deems necessary or appropriate to secure compliance with, any provision of this chapter or the terms of an order, license, certification, registration, permit or regulation issued or adopted thereunder.
    </text>
</law>