<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="130" order_by="130" level="3">Marine Fish And Fisheries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>21</section_number>
    <catch_line>Compilation Of Statistical Information Useful To Marine Fish Industries; Confidentiality; False Reports; Refusal Or Failure</catch_line>
    <order_by>21</order_by>
    <text>
        The director shall devise a system of statistical information useful to the commercial and recreational fishing industry of the commonwealth and may collect and compile fishery statistics obtained thereunder. He may require for such purposes statistical reporting from all fishermen, wholesale and retail fish dealers and fish processors on such forms and at such time to be determined by him. Said statistical reports shall be signed and submitted under the pains and penalties of perjury and subject to chapter sixty-six and chapter sixty-six A, shall be held strictly confidential by the director and shall not be disclosed except in compliance with a valid court order. The director may, by regulation, prescribe such procedures as may be necessary to preserve such confidentiality, except that the director may release or make public any such statistics in any aggregate or summary form which does not directly or indirectly disclose the identity or business of any person who submits such statistics. 
Any license, permit or certificate issued by the division to any person who refuses or fails to submit, or knowingly submits a false statistical report shall be suspended and surrendered to the director. Persons who fail to submit, or knowingly file a false report shall not have issued to them a new license, permit or certificate until an accurate statistical report is submitted to the director. 
The director may enter into cooperative agreements with local, state or federal authorities for the purpose of joint conservation and management of marine fisheries and for the implementation and enforcement of rules and regulations relative thereto, and may, subject to chapter thirty A, implement any regulations as developed and recommended by the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission. 
The director shall, from to time, prepare and distribute bulletins and reports embodying statistical and other information relative to marine fisheries. He shall also assist and cooperate with local authorities in the promulgation of rules and regulations for the protection and conservation of marine fisheries. 
Whoever violates any provisions of this act shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars.
    </text>
</law>