<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="132B" order_by="132B" level="3">Massachusetts Pesticide Control Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Programs Director</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        The pesticide regulatory functions conferred upon the department under the provisions of this chapter shall be under the administrative supervision of a pesticide programs director who shall be qualified by training and experience to perform such duties. Said director shall be appointed by the commissioner with the approval of the board for a term of five years. Said person shall be eligible for reappointment, but may be removed by the commissioner for cause. The position of director shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter thirty-one or the provisions of section nine A of chapter thirty. If an employee serving in a position which is classified under chapter thirty-one or in which he has tenure by reason of section nine A of chapter thirty shall be appointed director, he shall upon termination of his service as director be restored to the position which he held immediately prior to such appointment or to a position equivalent thereto in salary grade in the same state department; provided, however, that his service in such unclassified position shall be determined by the civil service commission in administering chapter thirty-one. Such restoration shall be made without impairment of his civil service status or tenure under section nine A of chapter thirty and without loss of seniority, retirement, or other rights to which uninterrupted service in such prior position would have entitled him. During the period of such appointment, the person so appointed from a position in the classified service shall be eligible to take any competitive promotional examination for which he would otherwise have been eligible.
    </text>
</law>