<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="19" order_by="19" level="2">Agriculture And Conservation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="129" order_by="129" level="3">Livestock Disease Control</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Feeding Garbage To Swine</catch_line>
    <order_by>14B</order_by>
    <text>
        The word “garbage” means any meat waste, or meat waste combined with any other food waste, resulting from handling, preparation, cooking and consumption of foods, including animal carcasses or parts thereof. 
The word “person” means the state, any municipality, political subdivision, institution, public or private corporation, individual, partnership, or other entity, except that it shall not mean a person who feeds garbage to swine which are raised for such person’s own use. 
No person shall feed garbage to swine without first securing a permit therefor from the director. Such permits shall be secured before January first, nineteen hundred and fifty-four, and shall be renewed on the first day of January of each year thereafter. 
Any person desiring to obtain a permit to feed garbage to swine shall make written application therefor to the director in accordance with the requirements of the division of animal health. At the time of filing such application the applicant shall pay to the division of animal health a permit fee, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provisions of section three B of chapter seven for the filing thereof. 
Upon determination that any person having a permit issued under this section, or who has applied for a permit hereunder, has violated or failed to comply with any of the provisions of this section, or any of the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder, the director, subject to the approval of the commissioner of agriculture, may revoke such permit or refuse to issue a permit to an applicant therefor. 
On and after January first, nineteen hundred and fifty-four, all garbage, regardless of previous processing, shall, before being fed to swine, be thoroughly heated to at least 212° F for at least thirty minutes, unless treated in some other manner which shall be approved in writing by the director as being equally effective. 
The director shall cause the premises of all permit holders to be inspected semi-monthly for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this and the preceding sections. 
Any authorized representative of the division of animal health shall have the power to enter at reasonable times upon any private or public property for the purposes of inspection and investigating conditions relating to the treating of garbage to be fed to swine as required by this section. 
Any authorized representative of the division of animal health may examine any records or memoranda pertaining to the feeding of garbage to swine. The division of animal health may require maintenance of records relating to the operation of equipment for and procedure of treating garbage to be fed to swine. Copies of such records shall be submitted to the division of animal health on request.
    </text>
</law>