<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Remedies Relating To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244" level="3">Foreclosure And Redemption Of Mortgages</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Foreclosure Under Power Of Sale;  Procedure;  Notice;  Form</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 1, 2012. For text effective November 1, 2012, see below.]  The mortgagee or person having his estate in the land mortgaged, or a person authorized by the power of sale, or the attorney duly authorized by a writing under seal, or the legal guardian or conservator of such mortgagee or person acting in the name of such mortgagee or person, may, upon breach of condition and without action, do all the acts authorized or required by the power; but no sale under such power shall be effectual to foreclose a mortgage, unless, previous to such sale, notice thereof has been published once in each of three successive weeks, the first publication to be not less than twenty-one days before the day of sale, in a newspaper, if any, published in the town where the land lies or in a newspaper with general circulation in the town where the land lies and notice thereof has been sent by registered mail to the owner or owners of record of the equity of redemption as of thirty days prior to the date of sale, said notice to be mailed at least fourteen days prior to the date of sale to said owner or owners to the address set forth in section sixty-one of chapter one hundred and eighty-five, if the land is then registered or, in the case of unregistered land, to the last address of the owner or owners of the equity of redemption appearing on the records of the holder of the mortgage, if any, or if none, to the address of the owner or owners as given on his deed or on the petition for probate by which he acquired title, if any, or if in either case no address appears, then to the address to which the tax collector last sent the tax bill for the mortgaged premises to be sold, or if no tax bill has been sent for the last preceding three years, then to the address of any of the parcels of property in the name of said owner of record which are to be sold under the power of sale and unless a copy of said notice of sale has been sent by registered mail to all persons of record as of thirty days prior to the date of sale holding an interest in the property junior to the mortgage being foreclosed, said notice to be mailed at least fourteen days prior to the date of sale to each such person at the address of such person set forth in any document evidencing the interest or to the last address of such person known to the mortgagee. Any person of record as of thirty days prior to the date of sale holding an interest in the property junior to the mortgage being foreclosed may waive at any time, whether prior or subsequent to the date of sale, the right to receive notice by mail to such person under this section and such waiver shall be deemed to constitute compliance with such notice requirement for all purposes. If no newspaper is published in such town, or if there is no newspaper with general circulation in the town where the land lies, notice may be published in a newspaper published in the county where the land lies, and this provision shall be implied in every power of sale mortgage in which it is not expressly set forth. A newspaper which by its title page purports to be printed or published in such town, city or county, and having a circulation therein, shall be sufficient for the purpose.  The following form of foreclosure notice may be used and may be altered as circumstances require; but nothing herein shall be construed to prevent the use of other forms.(Form.)MORTGAGEE'S SALE OF REAL ESTATE.  By virtue and in execution of the Power of Sale contained in a certain mortgage given by .......... to .......... dated .......... and recorded with .................Deeds, Book .........., page .........., of which mortgage the undersigned is the present holder, ...........  (If by assignment, or in any fiduciary capacity, give reference.).........................for breach of the conditions of said mortgage and for the purpose of foreclosing the same will be sold at Public Auction at .......... o'clock, ....M. on the .......... day of .......... A.D. (insert year), .......... (place) .......... all and singular the premises described in said mortgage,  (In case of partial releases, state exceptions.)  To wit: "(Description as in the mortgage, including all references to title, restrictions, encumbrances, etc., as made in the mortgage.)''  Terms of sale: (State here the amount, if any, to be paid in cash by the purchaser at the time and place of the sale, and the time or times for payment of the balance or the whole as the case may be.)  Other terms to be announced at the sale.(Signed) ..........................................................Present holder of said mortgage.  A notice of sale in the above form, published in accordance with the power in the mortgage and with this chapter, together with such other or further notice, if any, as is required by the mortgage, shall be a sufficient notice of the sale; and the premises shall be deemed to have been sold, and the deed thereunder shall convey the premises, subject to and with the benefit of all restrictions, easements, improvements, outstanding tax titles, municipal or other public taxes, assessments, liens or claims in the nature of liens, and existing encumbrances of record created prior to the mortgage, whether or not reference to such restrictions, easements, improvements, liens or encumbrances is made in the deed; but no purchaser at the sale shall be bound to complete the purchase if there are encumbrances, other than those named in the mortgage and included in the notice of sale, which are not stated at the sale and included in the auctioneer's contract with the purchaser.
Chapter 244: Foreclosure under power of sale; procedure; notice; form
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 194, Sec. 1 effective November 1, 2012. See 2012, 194, Sec. 9. For text effective until November 1, 2012, 2013, see above.]  The mortgagee or person having estate in the land mortgaged, or a person authorized by the power of sale, or the attorney duly authorized by a writing under seal or the legal guardian or conservator of such mortgagee or person acting in the name of such mortgagee or person, may, upon breach of condition and without action, perform all acts authorized or required by the power of sale; provided, however, that no sale under such power shall be effectual to foreclose a mortgage, unless, previous to such sale, notice of the sale has been published once in each of 3 successive weeks, the first publication of which shall be not less than 21 days before the day of sale, in a newspaper published in the city or town where the land lies or in a newspaper with general circulation in the city or town where the land lies and notice of the sale has been sent by registered mail to the owner or owners of record of the equity of redemption as of 30 days prior to the date of sale, said notice to be mailed by registered mail at least 14 days prior to the date of sale to said owner or owners to the address set forth in section 61 of chapter 185, if the land is then registered or, in the case of unregistered land, to the last address of the owner or owners of the equity of redemption appearing on the records of the holder of the mortgage, if any, or if none, to the address of the owner or owners as given on the deed or on the petition for probate by which the owner or owners acquired title, if any, or if in either case no owner appears, then mailed by registered mail to the address to which the tax collector last sent the tax bill for the mortgaged premises to be sold, or if no tax bill has been sent for the last preceding 3 years, then mailed by registered mail to the address of any of the parcels of property in the name of said owner of record which are to be sold under the power of sale and unless a copy of said notice of sale has been sent by registered mail to all persons of record as of 30 days prior to the date of sale holding an interest in the property junior to the mortgage being foreclosed, said notice to be mailed at least 14 days prior to the date of sale to each such person at the address of such person set forth in any document evidencing the interest or to the last address of such person known to the mortgagee. Any person of record as of 30 days prior to the date of sale holding an interest in the property junior to the mortgage being foreclosed may waive at any time, whether prior or subsequent to the date of sale, the right to receive notice by mail to such person under this section and such waiver shall constitute compliance with such notice requirement for all purposes. If no newspaper is published in such city or town, or if there is no newspaper with general circulation in the city or town where the land lies, notice may be published in a newspaper published in the county where the land lies, and this provision shall be implied in every power of sale mortgage in which it is not expressly set forth. A newspaper which by its title page purports to be printed or published in such city, town or county, and having a circulation in that city, town or county, shall be sufficient for the purposes of this section.  The following form of foreclosure notice may be used and may be altered as circumstances require; but nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the use of other forms.(Form.)  MORTGAGEE'S SALE OF REAL ESTATE.  By virtue and in execution of the Power of Sale contained in a certain mortgage given by .......... to .......... dated .......... and recorded with..........  Deeds, Book .........., page .........., of which mortgage the undersigned is the present holder, ...........  (If by assignment, or in any fiduciary capacity, give reference to the assignment or assignments recorded with .......... Deeds, Book .........., page .........., of which mortgage the undersigned is the present holder, ...........  for breach of the conditions of said mortgage and for the purpose of foreclosing the same will be sold at Public Auction at .......... o'clock, ..........M. on the .......... day of .......... A.D. (insert year), .......... (place) .......... all and singular the premises described in said mortgage,  (In case of partial releases, state exceptions.)  To wit: "(Description as in the mortgage, including all references to title, restrictions, encumbrances, etc., as made in the mortgage.)''  Terms of sale: (State here the amount, if any, to be paid in cash by the purchaser at the time and place of the sale, and the time or times for payment of the balance or the whole as the case may be.)  Other terms to be announced at the sale.  (Signed) ______________________  Present holder of said mortgage. ________________  A notice of sale in the above form, published in accordance with the power in the mortgage and with this chapter, together with such other or further notice, if any, as is required by the mortgage, shall be a sufficient notice of the sale; and the premises shall be deemed to have been sold and the deed thereunder shall convey the premises, subject to and with the benefit of all restrictions, easements, improvements, outstanding tax titles, municipal or other public taxes, assessments, liens or claims in the nature of liens, and existing encumbrances of record created prior to the mortgage, whether or not reference to such restrictions, easements, improvements, liens or encumbrances is made in the deed; provided, however, that no purchaser at the sale shall be bound to complete the purchase if there are encumbrances, other than those named in the mortgage and included in the notice of sale, which are not stated at the sale and included in the auctioneer's contract with the purchaser.  For purposes of this section and section 21 of chapter 183, in the event a mortgagee holds a mortgage pursuant to an assignment, no notice under this section shall be valid unless (i) at the time such notice is mailed, an assignment, or a chain of assignments, evidencing the assignment of the mortgage to the foreclosing mortgagee has been duly recorded in the registry of deeds for the county or district where the land lies and (ii) the recording information for all recorded assignments is referenced in the notice of sale required in this section. The notice shall not be defective if any holder within the chain of assignments either changed its name or merged into another entity during the time it was the mortgage holder; provided, that recited within the body of the notice is the fact of any merger, consolidation, amendment, conversion or acquisition of assets causing the change in name or identity, the recital of which shall be conclusive in favor of any bona fide purchaser, mortgagee, lienholder or encumbrancer of value relying in good faith on such recital.
    </text>
</law>