<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Remedies Relating To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244" level="3">Foreclosure And Redemption Of Mortgages</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Right Of Residential Real Property Mortgagor To Cure A Default; Good Faith Effort To Negotiate For Commercially Reasonable Alternative To Foreclosure; Response From Borrower; Affidavit Upon Initiation Of Foreclosure Proceedings; Acceleration Of Maturity Of Balance Prohibited;  Notice</catch_line>
    <order_by>35A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A mortgagor of residential property shall have a 150-day right to cure a default of a required payment as provided in the residential mortgage or note secured by the residential property by full payment of all amounts that are due without acceleration of the maturity of the unpaid balance of the mortgage; provided, however, that if a creditor certifies that: (i) it has engaged in a good faith effort to negotiate a commercially reasonable alternative to foreclosure as described in subsection (c); (ii) its good faith effort has involved at least 1 meeting, either in person or by telephone, between a creditor’s representative and the borrower, the borrower’s attorney or the borrower’s representative; and (iii) after such meeting the borrower and the creditor were not successful in resolving their dispute, then the creditor may begin foreclosure proceedings after a right to cure period lasting 90 days. A borrower who fails to respond within 30 days to any mailed communications offering to negotiate a commercially reasonable alternative to foreclosure sent via certified and first class mail or similar service by a private carrier from the lender shall be deemed to have forfeited the right to a 150-day right to cure period and shall be subject to a right to cure period lasting 90 days. The right to cure a default of a required payment shall be granted once during any 3 year period, regardless of mortgage holder.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     For purposes of this section, a determination that a creditor has made a good faith effort to negotiate and agree upon a commercially reasonable alternative to foreclosure shall mean that the creditor has considered: (i) an assessment of the borrower’s current circumstances including, without limitation, the borrower’s current income, debts and obligations; (ii) the net present value of receiving payments pursuant to a modified mortgage loan as compared to the anticipated net recovery following foreclosure; and (iii) the interests of the creditor; provided, however, that nothing in this subsection shall be construed as prohibiting a creditor from considering other factors; provided, further, that the creditor shall provide by first class and certified mail or similar service by a private carrier to a borrower documentation of good faith effort 10 days prior to meeting, telephone conversation or a meeting pursuant to subsection (b).
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A borrower who receives a loan modification offer from the creditor resulting from the lender’s good faith effort to negotiate and agree upon a commercially reasonable alternative to foreclosure shall respond within 30 days of receipt of first class or certified mail. A borrower shall be presumed to have responded if the borrower provides: (i) confirmation of a facsimile transmission to the creditor; (ii) proof of delivery through the United States Postal Service or similar carrier; or (iii) record of telephone call to the creditor captured on a telephone bill or pin register. A borrower who fails to respond to the creditor’s offer within 30 days of receipt of a loan modification offer shall be deemed to have forfeited the 150-day right to cure period and shall be subject to a right to cure period lasting 90 days.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Nothing in this section shall prevent a creditor from offering or accepting alternatives to foreclosure, such as a short sale or deed-in-lieu of foreclosure, if the borrower requests such alternatives, rejects a loan modification offered pursuant to this subsection or does not qualify for a loan modification pursuant to this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A creditor that chooses to begin foreclosure proceedings after a right to cure period lasting less than 150 days that engaged in a good faith effort to negotiate and agree upon a commercially reasonable alternative but was not successful in resolving the dispute shall certify compliance with this section in an affidavit. The affidavit shall include the time and place of the meeting, parties participating, relief offered to the borrower, a summary of the creditor’s net present value analysis and applicable inputs of the analysis and certification that any modification or option offered complies with current federal law or policy. A creditor shall provide a copy of the affidavit to the homeowner and file a copy of the affidavit with the land court in advance of the foreclosure.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, shall not accelerate maturity of the unpaid balance of such mortgage obligation or otherwise enforce the mortgage because of a default consisting of the mortgagor’s failure to make any such payment in subsection (b) by any method authorized by this chapter or any other law until at least 150 days after the date a written notice is given by the mortgagee to the mortgagor; provided, however, that a creditor meeting the requirements of subsection (b) that chooses to begin foreclosure proceedings after a right to cure period lasting less than 150 days may accelerate maturity of the unpaid balance of such mortgage obligation or otherwise enforce the mortgage because of a default consisting of the mortgagor’s failure to make any such payment in subsection (b) by any method authorized by this chapter or any other law not less than 91 days after the date a written notice is given by the creditor to the mortgagor.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     The notice required in subsection (g) shall inform the mortgagor of the following:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the nature of the default claimed on such mortgage of residential real property and of the mortgagor’s right to cure the default by paying the sum of money required to cure the default;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the date by which the mortgagor shall cure the default to avoid acceleration, a foreclosure or other action to seize the home, which date shall not be less than 150 days after service of the notice and the name, address and local or toll free telephone number of a person to whom the payment or tender shall be made unless a creditor chooses to begin foreclosure proceedings after a right to cure period lasting less than 150 days that engaged in a good faith effort to negotiate and agree upon a commercially reasonable alternative but was not successful in resolving the dispute, in which case a foreclosure or other action to seize the home may take place on an earlier date to be specified;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     that, if the mortgagor does not cure the default by the date specified, the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, may take steps to terminate the mortgagor’s ownership in the property by a foreclosure proceeding or other action to seize the home;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the name and address of the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, and the telephone number of a representative of the mortgagee whom the mortgagor may contact if the mortgagor disagrees with the mortgagee’s assertion that a default has occurred or the correctness of the mortgagee’s calculation of the amount required to cure the default;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the name of any current and former mortgage broker or mortgage loan originator for such mortgage or note securing the residential property;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     that the mortgagor may be eligible for assistance from the Homeownership Preservation Foundation or other foreclosure counseling agency, and the local or toll free telephone numbers the mortgagor may call to request this assistance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     that the mortgagor may sell the property prior to the foreclosure sale and use the proceeds to pay off the mortgage;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     that the mortgagor may redeem the property by paying the total amount due, prior to the foreclosure sale;
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     that the mortgagor may be evicted from the home after a foreclosure sale; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     the mortgagor may have the following additional rights, depending on the terms of the residential mortgage: (i) to refinance the obligation by obtaining a loan which would fully repay the residential mortgage debtor; and (ii) to voluntarily grant a deed to the residential mortgage lender in lieu of foreclosure.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     To cure a default prior to acceleration under this section, a mortgagor shall not be required to pay any charge, fee or penalty attributable to the exercise of the right to cure a default. The mortgagor shall pay late fees as allowed pursuant to section 59 of chapter 183 and per-diem interest to cure such default. The mortgagor shall not be liable for any attorneys’ fees relating to the mortgagor’s default that are incurred by the mortgagee or anyone holding thereunder prior to or during the period set forth in the notice required by this section. The mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, may also provide for reinstatement of the note after the 150-day notice to cure has ended.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     A copy of the notice required by this section and an affidavit demonstrating compliance with this section shall be filed by the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, in any action or proceeding to foreclose on such residential real property.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     A copy of the notice required by this section shall also be filed by the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, with the commissioner of the division of banks. Additionally, if the residential property securing the mortgage loan is sold at a foreclosure sale, the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, shall notify the commissioner of the division of banks, in writing, of the date of the foreclosure sale and the purchase price obtained at the sale.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Any mortgagor of residential real property located in the commonwealth, shall have a 90-day right to cure a default of a required payment as provided in such residential mortgage or note secured by such residential real property by full payment of all amounts that are due without acceleration of the maturity of the unpaid balance of such mortgage. The right to cure a default of a required payment shall be granted once during any 5-year period, regardless of the mortgage holder. For the purposes of this section, “residential property”, shall mean real property located in the commonwealth having thereon a dwelling house with accommodations for 4 or less separate households and occupied, or to be occupied, in whole or in part by the mortgagor; provided, however, that residential property shall be limited to the principal residence of a person; provided further, that residential property shall not include an investment property or residence other than a primary residence; and provided further, that residential property shall not include residential property taken in whole or in part as collateral for a commercial loan.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, shall not accelerate maturity of the unpaid balance of such mortgage obligation or otherwise enforce the mortgage because of a default consisting of the mortgagor’s failure to make any such payment in subsection (a) by any method authorized by this chapter or any other law until at least 90 days after the date a written notice is given by the mortgagee to the mortgagor.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The notice required in subsection (b) shall inform the mortgagor of the following:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the nature of the default claimed on such mortgage of residential real property and of the mortgagor’s right to cure the default by paying the sum of money required to cure the default;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the date by which the mortgagor shall cure the default to avoid acceleration, a foreclosure or other action to seize the home, which date shall not be less than 90 days after service of the notice and the name, address and local or toll free telephone number of a person to whom the payment or tender shall be made;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     that, if the mortgagor does not cure the default by the date specified, the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, may take steps to terminate the mortgagor’s ownership in the property by a foreclosure proceeding or other action to seize the home;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the name and address of the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, and the telephone number of a representative of the mortgagee whom the mortgagor may contact if the mortgagor disagrees with the mortgagee’s assertion that a default has occurred or the correctness of the mortgagee’s calculation of the amount required to cure the default;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the name of any current and former mortgage broker or mortgage loan originator for such mortgage or note securing the residential property;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     that the mortgagor may be eligible for assistance from the Massachusetts Housing Finance Agency and the division of banks and the local or toll free telephone numbers the mortgagor may call to request this assistance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     that the mortgagor may sell the property prior to the foreclosure sale and use the proceeds to pay off the mortgage;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     that the mortgagor may redeem the property by paying the total amount due, prior to the foreclosure sale;
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     that the mortgagor may be evicted from the home after a foreclosure sale; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     the mortgagor may have the following additional rights, depending on the terms of the residential mortgage: (i) to refinance the obligation by obtaining a loan which would fully repay the residential mortgage debtor; and (ii) to voluntarily grant a deed to the residential mortgage lender in lieu of foreclosure.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     To cure a default prior to acceleration under this section, a mortgagor shall not be required to pay any charge, fee, or penalty attributable to the exercise of the right to cure a default. The mortgagor shall pay late fees as allowed pursuant to section 59 of chapter 183 and per-diem interest to cure such default. The mortgagor shall not be liable for any attorneys’ fees relating to the mortgagor’s default that are incurred by the mortgagee or anyone holding thereunder prior to or during the period set forth in the notice required by this section. The mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, may also provide for reinstatement of the note after the 90 day notice to cure has ended.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A copy of the notice required by this section and an affidavit demonstrating compliance with this section shall be filed by the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, in any action or proceeding to foreclose on such residential real property.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A copy of the notice required by this section shall also be filed by the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, with the commissioner of the division of banks. Additionally, if the residential property securing the mortgage loan is sold at a foreclosure sale, the mortgagee, or anyone holding thereunder, shall notify the commissioner of the division of banks, in writing, of the date of the foreclosure sale and the purchase price obtained at the sale.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>