<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="2">Remedies Relating To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="239" order_by="239" level="3">Summary Process For Possession Of Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Land Or Tenements Used For Residential Purposes; Action By Lessor Under This Chapter To Recover Possession; Conditions And Restrictions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1A</order_by>
    <text>
        A lessor of land or tenements used for residential purposes may bring an action under this chapter to recover possession thereof before the determination of the lease by its own limitation, subject to the following conditions and restrictions. The tenancy of the premises at issue shall have been created for at least six months duration by a written lease in which a specific termination date is designated, a copy of which, signed by all parties, shall be annexed to the summons. No such action may be initiated before the latest date permitted by the lease for either party to notify the other of his intention to renew or extend the rental agreement, or in any case before thirty days before the designated termination date of the tenancy. The person bringing the action shall notify all defendants by registered mail that he has done so, which notification shall be mailed not later than twenty-four hours after the action is initiated. The person bringing the action shall demonstrate substantial grounds upon which the court could reasonably conclude that the defendant is likely to continue in possession of the premises at issue without right after the designated termination date, which grounds shall be set forth in the writ. No execution for possession may issue in any such action before the day next following the designated termination date of the tenancy. Any action brought pursuant to this section shall conform to and be governed by the provisions of this chapter in all other respects and no remedy or procedure otherwise available to any party, including any stay of execution which the court has discretion to allow, shall be denied solely because the action was brought pursuant to this section.
    </text>
</law>