<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="152" order_by="152" level="3">Workers' Compensation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>52C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Rating Organizations In General; Subscribers; Co Operative Activities; Rates; Freedom Of Contract</catch_line>
    <order_by>52C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A corporation, an unincorporated association, a partnership, or an individual, located within this commonwealth may make application to the commissioner of insurance, hereinafter and in sections fifty-two D to fifty-two F, inclusive, called the commissioner, for license as a rating organization and shall file therewith (1) a copy of its constitution, its articles of agreement or association or its certificate of incorporation, and of its by-laws, rules and regulations governing the conduct of its business, (2) a list of its members and subscribers, (3) the name and address of a resident of this commonwealth upon whom notices or orders of the commissioner or process affecting such rating organization may be served and (4) a statement of its qualifications as a rating organization. If the commissioner finds that the applicant is competent, trustworthy and otherwise qualified to act as a rating organization and that its constitution, articles of agreement or association or certificate of incorporation, and its by-laws, rules and regulations governing the conduct of its business conform to the requirements of law, he shall issue a license authorizing it to act as a rating organization. Every such application shall be granted or denied in whole or in part by the commissioner within sixty days of the date of its filing with him. Licenses issued pursuant to this section shall remain in effect for three years unless sooner suspended or revoked by the commissioner. The fee for said license shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven. Licenses issued pursuant to this section may be suspended or revoked by the commissioner, after hearing upon due notice, in the event the rating organization ceases to meet the requirements of this section. Every rating organization shall notify the commissioner promptly of every change in (1) its constitution, its articles of agreement or association or its certificate of incorporation, and its by-laws, rules and regulations governing the conduct of its business, (2) its list of members and subscribers and (3) the name and address of the resident of this commonwealth designated by it upon whom notices or orders of the commissioner or process affecting such rating organization may be served.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Subject to the rules and regulations which have been approved by the commissioner as reasonable, each rating organization shall permit any insurer not a member to be a subscriber to its rating services. Notice of proposed changes in such rules and regulations shall be given to subscribers. Each rating organization shall furnish its rating services without discrimination to its members and subscribers. The reasonableness of any rule or regulation in its application to subscribers, or the refusal of any rating organization to admit an insurer as a subscriber, shall at the request of any subscriber or any such insurer, be reviewed by the commissioner at a hearing held upon at least ten days’ written notice to such rating organization and to such subscriber or insurer. If the commissioner finds that such rule or regulation is unreasonable in its application to subscribers, he shall order that such rule or regulation shall not be applicable to subscribers. If the rating organization fails to grant or reject an insurer’s application for subscribership within thirty days after it was made, the insurer may request a review by the commissioner as if the application had been rejected. If the commissioner finds that the insurer has been refused admittance to the rating organization as a subscriber without justification, he shall order the rating organization to admit the insurer as a subscriber. If he finds that the action of the rating organization was justified, he shall make an order affirming its action.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No rating organization shall adopt any rule the effect of which would be to prohibit or regulate the payment of dividends, savings or unabsorbed premium deposits allowed or returned by insurers to their policyholders, members or subscribers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Co-operation among rating organizations or among rating organizations and insurers in rate making or in other matters within the scope of this chapter is hereby authorized, provided the filings resulting from such co-operation are subject to all the provisions of this chapter which are applicable to filings generally. The commissioner may review such co-operative activities and practices and if, after due notice and a hearing, he finds that any such activity or practice is unfair or unreasonable or otherwise inconsistent with this section, he may issue a written order specifying in what respects such activity or practice is unfair or unreasonable or otherwise inconsistent with this section, and requiring the discontinuance of such activity or practice.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The commissioner shall, at least once in five years, make or cause to be made an examination of each rating organization licensed in this commonwealth as provided in this section. The reasonable cost of any such examination shall be paid by the rating organization examined upon presentation to it of a detailed account of such costs. The officers, manager, agents and employees of such rating organization may be examined at any time under oath and shall exhibit all books, records, accounts, documents or agreements governing its method of operation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     All rates shall be made in accordance with the following provisions:—(1) Due consideration shall be given to past and prospective loss experience within and outside this commonwealth, to catastrophe hazards, if any, to a reasonable margin for underwriting profit and contingencies, and to past and prospective expenses both countrywide and those specially applicable to this commonwealth, and to all other relevant factors within and outside this commonwealth; (2) the systems of expense provisions included in the rates for use by any insurer or group of insurers may differ from those of other insurers or groups of insurers to reflect the requirements of the operating methods of any such insurer or group of insurers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Nothing in this chapter shall abridge or restrict the freedom of contract between insurers and agents or brokers, or between agents and brokers, nor affect the customary right of insurers, agents or brokers to pay to or receive from each other, commission or brokerage; nor shall it abridge or restrict the freedom of contract between insurers, agents or brokers and their employees with respect to compensation.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>