<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Ropes, Hooks And Cranes; Use And Operation</catch_line>
    <order_by>18D</order_by>
    <text>
        All chains, wire ropes and fiber ropes shall be of sufficient strength to safely lift or otherwise handle the loads. 
The use of deformed hooks or rings shall be discontinued. 
All hooks, slings, bridles and fittings shall be of the correct size for the work to be done, and shall have sufficient strength to sustain the loads imposed upon them. Wire bridles shall have a covering of marlin, rubber hose or other suitable material for the protection of the employee’s hands at the splice. 
A crane, derrick, hoist or winch shall not be loaded beyond the rated capacity or safe working load, whichever is smaller. 
The load shall be attached to the hook by means of slings or other suitable effective means, which shall be properly rigged to insure the safe handling of the load. Slings shall be free of kinks or twists before use. 
No employee shall be required to or shall ride on loads, slings, hooks, buckets or skip boxes, except under conditions or exception covered by other orders of the division. 
Operator shall never leave crane, hoist, derrick or winch while load is suspended unless the load is suspended over water or a barricaded area, or is blocked up or otherwise supported from below during repair or emergency. 
Only qualified employees shall give signals. No one should give signals except employees who are specifically designated and authorized to do so by the employer. Operators shall not accept signals except from those specifically designated and authorized to give same.
    </text>
</law>