<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151" level="3">Minimum Fair Wages</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Overtime Pay; Excluded Employments</catch_line>
    <order_by>1A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     as a janitor or caretaker of residential property, who when furnished with living quarters is paid a wage of not less than thirty dollars per week.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     as a golf caddy, newsboy or child actor or performer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     as a bona fide executive, or administrative or professional person or qualified trainee for such position earning more than eighty dollars per week.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     as an outside salesman or outside buyer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     as a learner, apprentice or handicapped person under a special license as provided in section nine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     as a fisherman or as a person employed in the catching or taking of any kind of fish, shellfish or other aquatic forms of animal and vegetable life.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     as a switchboard operator in a public telephone exchange.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     as a driver or helper on a truck with respect to whom the Interstate Commerce Commission has power to establish qualifications and maximum hours of service pursuant to the provisions of section two hundred and four of the motor carrier act of nineteen hundred and thirty-five, or as employee of an employer subject to the provisions of Part 1 of the Interstate Commerce Act or subject to title II of the Railway Labor Act.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     in a business or specified operation of a business which is carried on during a period or accumulated periods not in excess of one hundred and twenty days in any year, and determined by the commissioner to be seasonal in nature.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     as a seaman.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     by an employer licensed and regulated pursuant to chapter one hundred and fifty-nine A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     in a hotel, motel, motor court or like establishment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     in a gasoline station.
        </section>
        <section prefix="14">
    	     in a restaurant.
        </section>
        <section prefix="15">
    	     as a garageman, which term shall not include a parking lot attendant.
        </section>
        <section prefix="16">
    	     in a hospital, sanitorium, convalescent or nursing home, infirmary, rest home or charitable home for the aged.
        </section>
        <section prefix="17">
    	     in a non-profit school or college.
        </section>
        <section prefix="18">
    	     in a summer camp operated by a non-profit charitable corporation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="19">
    	     as a laborer engaged in agriculture and farming on a farm.
        </section>
        <section prefix="20">
    	     in an amusement park containing a permanent aggregation of amusement devices, games, shows, and other attractions operated during a period or accumulated periods not in excess of one hundred and fifty days in any one year.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>