<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="151A" order_by="151A" level="3">Unemployment Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14L</section_number>
    <catch_line>Work Force Training Contribution Paid By Employers</catch_line>
    <order_by>14L</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Repeal of section by 1998, 175, Sec. 20A does not take effect. See 2011, 68, Sec. 128. See also 1998, 175, Sec. 25 as amended by 1999, 172, Sec. 1, 2002, 184, Sec. 159, 2005, 45, Sec. 8, 2006, 123, Sec. 78 and 2010, 112, Sec. 33 and repealed by 2011, 68, Sec. 129 and 2012, 36, Sec. 21.]  (a) Each employer liable to pay a contribution under subsection (i) of section 14 shall also pay, in the same manner and at the same times as the commissioner prescribes for the contribution required by said section 14, a workforce training contribution of 0.075 per cent of so much of its wages as are subject to contributions pursuant to clause (4) of subsection (a) of said section 14. To the extent consistent with federal law, the commissioner shall adjust the rate of said contribution so that the total amount of said contributions in a year substantially equals $18,000,000, and shall adjust to the same extent the rate of the contribution required by section 14. The commissioner shall deposit the proceeds of said workforce training contributions in the Workforce Training Fund, established by section 2RR of chapter 29.  (b) Except where inconsistent with the provisions of this section, the terms and conditions of this chapter that apply to the payment of and the collection of contributions shall apply to the same extent to the payment of and the collection of the workforce training contribution required by this section; provided, however, that said contributions shall not be credited to the employer's account or the solvency account established pursuant to section 14, 14A or 14C.
    </text>
</law>