<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>52D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Family And Medical Leave; Enforcement</catch_line>
    <order_by>52D</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, terms shall have the meanings assigned to them by the federal act, notwithstanding any contrary provision of section 1 of this chapter. In addition, the following terms shall have the following meanings:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     An eligible employee shall be entitled to a total of 24 hours of leave during any 12-month period, in addition to leave available under the federal act, to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     participate in school activities directly related to the educational advancement of a son or daughter of the employee, such as parent-teacher conferences or interviewing for a new school;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     accompany the son or daughter of the employee to routine medical or dental appointments, such as check-ups or vaccinations; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     accompany an elderly relative of the employee to routine medical or dental appointments or appointments for other professional services related to the elder’s care, such as interviewing at nursing or group homes.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Unless this section provides otherwise, the terms of the federal act shall apply to leave under this section. As provided in section 102(d)(2)(A) of the federal act, 29 U.S.C. section 2612(d)(2)(A), an eligible employee may elect, or an employer may require the employee, to substitute any of the accrued paid vacation leave, personal leave, or medical or sick leave of the employee for any of the leave provided under this section, but nothing in this section shall require an employer to provide paid sick leave or paid medical leave in any situation in which the employer would not normally provide any such paid leave. Leave under this section may be taken intermittently or on a reduced leave schedule.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     If the necessity for leave under this section is foreseeable, the employee shall provide the employer with not less than seven days’ notice before the date the leave is to begin. If the necessity for leave is not foreseeable, the employee shall provide such notice as is practicable.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     An employer may require that a request for leave under this section be supported by a certification issued at such time and in such manner as the attorney general may by regulation require.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The attorney general shall enforce this section, and may obtain injunctive or declaratory relief for this purpose. Violation of this section shall be subject to the second paragraph of section 150 and to section 180.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>