<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>87</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employment Permits In General; Approval; Return Of Evidence Of Age;  Certificate By Town Clerk; Notice Of Child’S Violation Of Statute</catch_line>
    <order_by>87</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     A pledge or promise, signed by the prospective employee and his parent or guardian, and, signed by the employer or by an authorized manager or superintendent, setting forth the character of the specific employment, the number of hours per day during which the child is to be regularly employed, and the name and address of the employer, in which pledge or promise the employer agrees to employ the child in accordance with this chapter which is summarized on the pledge or promise form, and to return the employment permit as provided in section eighty-six.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The school record of a minor under 16 years of age, filled out and signed as provided in section eighty-eight, except when such record may be waived thereunder; and evidence that a minor 16 years of age or older meets the requirements for the completion of the sixth grade of the public schools of the town in which he resides.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     For a minor under 16 years of age, a certificate, signed within the previous 12 months, by a school or family physician, or by a physician appointed by the school committee, stating that the minor has been thoroughly examined by the physician and, in his opinion, is in sound health.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Evidence of age, showing that the child is of the age required for the issuance of the permit, which shall consist of one of the following proofs of age:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A birth certificate, or a duly attested transcript thereof, made by a registrar of vital statistics or other officer charged with the duty of recording births.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A baptismal certificate, or a duly attested transcript thereof, showing the age and date of baptism of the child.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     If none of the aforesaid proofs of age is obtainable, and only in such case, the person issuing employment permits may accept in lieu thereof a passport or a duly attested immigration record, or transcript thereof, showing the age of the child, or other official or religious record of the child’s age; provided, that it shall appear to the satisfaction of said person that the same is good and sufficient evidence of the child’s age.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     If none of the aforesaid proofs of age is obtainable, and only in such case, the person issuing employment permits may accept in lieu thereof a record of age as given on the register of the school which the child first attended in the commonwealth; provided, that such record was kept for at least two years during the time when such child attended school.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     If none of the aforesaid proofs of age is obtainable, and only in such case, the person issuing employment permits may receive the signed statement of the school physician, or of the physician appointed by the school committee, stating that after examination it is the opinion of such physician that the child is at least of the age required for the issuance of the permit. Such physician’s statement shall be accompanied by a statement signed by the child’s parent, guardian or custodian, or, if such child has no parent, guardian or custodian, by the signed statement of the next adult friend. Such signed statement shall contain the name, date and place of birth and residence of the child, and shall certify that the parent, guardian, custodian or next friend signing it is unable to produce any of the proofs of age specified in this section. Such statement shall be so signed in the presence of the person issuing the employment permit. The person issuing employment permits may, before issuing such a permit, require the parent, guardian, custodian, or next adult friend of the child to appear and approve in writing the issuance of such permit.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>