<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>147F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Attendance Of Witnesses And Production Of Books And Papers; Summons And Court Order; Fees; Oaths; Depositions</catch_line>
    <order_by>147F</order_by>
    <text>
        In making any investigation or examination under authority of any provision of sections one hundred and forty-four to one hundred and forty-seven H, inclusive, the attorney general or his duly authorized representative may require the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, papers, contracts and documents relating thereto. Witnesses shall be summoned in the same manner and shall be paid the same fees as witnesses before the superior court in civil cases. The attorney general or any such representative may administer oaths to witnesses or take their affirmation. If any person summoned and paid as a witness refuses to attend, or to be sworn or to affirm, or to answer any question, or to produce any book, contract, document or paper pertinent to the matter before the attorney general or such representative, a justice of the supreme judicial or the superior court, upon application by said attorney general or such representative, may issue an order requiring such person to appear before said attorney general or representative, and to produce his books, contracts, documents and papers and to give evidence relating to the matter in question. Upon application by the attorney general or such representative, commissions to take depositions of persons without the commonwealth may be issued by a justice of the supreme judicial or the superior court, to be used in hearings before the attorney general or such representative, and all laws and rules relating to such commissions in civil actions shall apply to commissions issued hereunder.
    </text>
</law>