<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>147</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employer’S Permit; Person To Whom Materials Or Articles May Be Delivered; Effect Of Strike; Payment Of Fees Into Treasury</catch_line>
    <order_by>147</order_by>
    <text>
        No materials for manufacture or to be worked upon by industrial homework shall be delivered to any person in the commonwealth unless the employer so delivering them, or his agent if the employer is not a resident of or located within this commonwealth, has in his possession a valid permit issued by the attorney general under authority of this section, hereinafter and in sections one hundred and forty-seven A to one hundred and forty-seven H, inclusive, called an employer’s permit. Such permit shall be issued by the attorney general, may be renewed annually by him, and, subject to the last sentence of section one hundred and forty-five, shall be valid for a period of one year from the date of its issuance, unless sooner revoked or suspended. Application for such permit shall be made in such form as the attorney general may from time to time by rule or regulation prescribe. No employer shall deliver or cause to be delivered any materials or articles for manufacture or to be worked upon by industrial homework to a person who is not in possession of a valid employer’s permit, or a homeworker’s certificate issued in accordance with this or the following section. The attorney general may revoke or suspend an employer’s permit if he finds that the employer has violated any provision of sections one hundred and forty-four to one hundred and forty-seven H, inclusive, or has failed to observe or comply with any provision of his permit or has violated any rule or regulation adopted for control of industrial homework. No original permit shall be granted by the attorney general to any employer at whose plant there is a strike, and any permit so issued shall be revoked or suspended, unless the attorney general finds such strike to be unlawful under the provisions of paragraph (e) of section twenty C. 
The attorney general shall collect a fee, as determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, for the original issuance of an employer’s permit, and for each renewal of such permit plus an amount for each homeworker with whom the employer directly or indirectly had business relations during the preceding calendar year. Any such fees received by the attorney general shall be paid into the treasury to the credit of the General Fund.
    </text>
</law>