<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>44E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Filing Of Bids; Forms; Modular Buildings</catch_line>
    <order_by>44E</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Whenever general bids are invited for a contract subject to section 44A and whenever sub-bids are invited in connection with such a contract subject to subsection (1) of section 44F, the awarding authority shall prescribe 1 place for filing the general bids and 1 place for filing the sub-bids, which need not be the same place. Notwithstanding any general or special law, ordinance or by-law to the contrary, a bidder shall not be required to file a duplicate of his bid or sub-bid in any other place. For all projects where prequalification of general contractors is required, or where an awarding authority has elected to prequalify general contractors pursuant to subsection (a) of section 44D1/2, an awarding authority shall request bids only from general contractors who have been so prequalified pursuant to subsections (a) to (j), inclusive, of section 44D1/2. For all projects where prequalification of subcontractors is required, or where an awarding authority has elected to prequalify subcontractors pursuant to subsection (a) of section 44D3/4, an awarding authority shall request bids only from subcontractors who have been so prequalified pursuant to subsections (a) to (j), inclusive, of section 44D3/4.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Every general bid submitted for a contract subject to section forty-four A shall be submitted on a form furnished by the awarding authority and containing the following provisions:
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     General bids shall be for the complete work as specified and shall include the names of sub-bidders and the amounts of their sub-bids; and the general contractor shall be selected on the basis of such general bids. Every general bid which is not accompanied by a bid deposit as prescribed by paragraph (2) of section forty-four B, or which otherwise does not conform with sections forty-four A to forty-four H, inclusive, or which is on a form not completely filled in, or which is incomplete, conditional or obscure, or which contains any addition not called for, shall be invalid; and the awarding authority shall reject every such bid. No such bid shall be rejected because of the failure to submit prices for, or information relating to, any item or items for which no specific space is provided in the bid form furnished by the awarding authority, but this sentence shall not be applicable to any failure to furnish prices or information required by this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     A public agency may procure modular buildings in accordance with the provisions of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the time and date for receipt of proposals, the address of the office to which the proposals are to be delivered, and the maximum time for proposal acceptance by the awarding authority;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the purchase description and all evaluation criteria that will be utilized;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     all contractual terms and conditions applicable to the procurement; provided, however, that the contract may incorporate by reference a plan submitted by the selected offeror for providing the modular buildings;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     a notice that every proposal shall be accompanied by a copy of an appropriate certificate of eligibility issued by the commissioner pursuant to section forty-four D, together with an update statement; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     except where the request for proposals calls for manufacture or delivery to the building site, a notice that every proposal shall be accompanied by a certification that the offeror is able to furnish labor that can work in concert with all other elements of labor employed or to be employed at the site of installation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     for each evaluation criterion, a rating of each proposal as highly advantageous, advantageous, not advantageous, or unacceptable and the reasons for such rating;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     a composite rating for each proposal and the reasons for such rating;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     recommendations for revisions, if any, to each proposed plan for providing the modular buildings which should be obtained by negotiation prior to awarding the contract to the offeror of the proposal; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     whether the modular buildings were manufactured within the commonwealth and whether such modular buildings were manufactured within the United States but outside the commonwealth.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>