<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="151A" order_by="151A" level="3">Unemployment Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>62A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Unemployment Compensation; Orientation; Notice; Initiation Of Claim</catch_line>
    <order_by>62A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The division of unemployment assistance shall provide a minimum level of in-person assistance at the following regional offices: Worcester, Milford, Dudley, Springfield, Gardner, Greenfield, Pittsfield, North Adams, New Bedford, Northampton, Taunton, Brockton, Boston, Lawrence and Framingham.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     In addition to such access by telephone to offices of the division, the deputy director shall maintain walk-in service, including the provision of general information, application assistance, claims information and orientation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The division shall provide an orientation to individuals who have applied for unemployment compensation within 15 days from the date upon which said application was made. At the orientation the claimant shall be informed of the determination process, eligibility criteria and requirements, including those mandated by worker profiling, and the address and telephone number to report to for division services. The division shall also provide claimants with information relative to the medical security plan and training benefit extensions established pursuant to section 30. The orientation may be provided through multilingual audio-visual methods, but the claimant shall have the opportunity for face-to-face interaction with division staff.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The deputy director shall take any such actions as may be necessary to ensure that any notice to an individual issued by the division:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     is written in simple and clear language;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     includes the address and telephone number of the regional office of the division which serves the recipient and the statewide toll free telephone number; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     that not later that January 1, 1998 the division shall issue all notices and materials explaining the provisions of this section in English, Spanish, Chinese, Haitian Creole, Italian, Portuguese, Vietnamese, Laotian, Khmer, Russian and any other language that is the primary language of at least 10,000 or 1/2 of 1\% of all residents of the commonwealth. If the division fails to issue a bilingual notice in the claimant’s primary language and such omission results in the claimant’s failure to meet a deadline or requirement, the division’s omission shall constitute good cause for the claimant’s failure.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A claimant shall be deemed to have initiated a claim for unemployment compensation benefits on the first day that the claimant contacts or attempts to contact the division, whether or not such employee is able to speak with a division representative at the time.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Each employer shall post at each site operated by the employer, in a conspicuous place, accessible to employees, the following information: the name and mailing address of the employer, the identification number assigned to the employer by said division, instructions on how to file a claim for unemployment compensation, the address and telephone number of the regional office of said division located nearest the work site, and the telephone number of the teleclaim information line. Each failure to post the information described herein shall result in a written warning by said division to the employer for a first violation, and thereafter shall result in the assessment of a civil fine of $100 for a second violation, $250 for a third violation, and $500 for a fourth and subsequent violations. Said division shall collect all fines assessed for violations of this subsection for deposit into the General Fund.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>