<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="152" order_by="152" level="3">Workers' Compensation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Failure To Provide For Payment Of Compensation; Stop Work Orders;  Penalties; Liens; Actions Brought By Losing Bidders; Civil Actions For Violations Of Chapter</catch_line>
    <order_by>25C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Whenever the commissioner or his designee determines that an employer who is required to provide for the payment to his employees of the compensation provided for by the chapter has failed to do so, a stop work order shall be served on said employer, requiring the cessation of all business operations at the place of employment or job site. Such order shall take effect immediately upon its service upon said employer, unless such employer provides evidence, satisfactory to the commissioner or his designee, of having secured any necessary insurance or self-insurance and pays a civil penalty into the private employer trust fund in the amount of one hundred dollars per day for each day such employer was not in compliance with this chapter, counting the date of service of the stop work order as the first day and date of payment of the penalty herein provided and of production of evidence of insurance or self-insurance as the final day.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Any employer who is aggrieved by the imposition of a stop work order shall have ten days from the date of its service to appeal such order. Any employer who timely files such appeal shall be granted a hearing by the commissioner or his designee within fourteen days of receipt of appeal. The stop work order shall not be in effect during the pendency of any timely filed appeal. Any stop work order and monetary penalty shall be rescinded if the commissioner or his designee finds at the hearing that the employer has at all times been in compliance with this chapter. If the commissioner or his designee finds at the hearing that the employer did or has not provided for all insurance or self-insurance required by this chapter, the stop work order shall be effective immediately on the conclusion of the hearing and shall remain in effect until such time as the employer provides evidence, satisfactory to the commissioner or his designees, of having secured any necessary insurance or self-insurance and pays a civil penalty into the private employer trust fund in the amount of two hundred and fifty dollars per day for each day such employer was not in compliance with this chapter, counting the date of service of the stop work order as the first day and the date of payment of the penalty herein provided and of production of evidence of insurance or self-insurance as the final day.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Any law enforcement agency in the commonwealth shall, at the request of the commissioner, render any assistance necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, including but not limited to preventing any employee or other persons from remaining at a place of employment or job site after a stop work order has taken effect.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Any employee affected by a stop work order pursuant to this section shall be paid for the first ten days lost pursuant to such order and any time lost pursuant to this section not exceeding ten days shall be considered time worked under the provisions of chapter one hundred and forty-nine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     In addition to being subject to the civil penalties herein provided, an employer who fails to provide for insurance or self-insurance as required by this chapter shall be punished by a fine of not more than one thousand five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both. Failure of an employer, after imposition of such fine or imprisonment, to provide for insurance or self-insurance under this chapter after notice by the department to do so shall, as to each notice, be deemed a further violation in respect thereof, subject to an additional fine and imprisonment. If such employer is a corporation, the president or treasurer or both shall be liable for said punishment. The commissioner or his designee shall have power to bring complaints against employers, including the president and treasurer of a corporation which is an employer, for violations of the provisions of this subsection, and to prosecute the same, and for such purpose may deputize one or more employees of the department to make and prosecute complaints. Complaints under this subsection shall be brought in the district court in which the principal place of business of such employer is situated, or in the district court in whose district such president or treasurer of a corporation resides.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Every state or local licensing agency shall withhold the issuance or renewal of a license or permit to operate a business or to construct buildings in the commonwealth for any applicant who has not produced acceptable evidence of compliance with the insurance coverage required by this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Neither the commonwealth nor any of its political subdivisions shall enter into any contract for the performance of public work until acceptable evidence of compliance with the insurance requirements of this chapter have been presented to the contracting authority.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     Any judgments obtained by the department requiring employer reimbursements or other payments into the private employer trust fund, and any penalties due pursuant to the service of a stop work order under this section shall, until collected, constitute a lien upon the entire interest of the employer, legal or equitable, in any property, real or personal, tangible or intangible; provided, however, that such lien shall be subordinate to claims for unpaid wages and any prior recorded liens; and provided, further, that no lien created by this section shall be valid against a subsequent purchaser or mortgagee in good faith and for value of real or personal property from or of such employer, or against a subsequent attaching creditor, unless, with respect to real estate of the employer, a notice of such lien is recorded in the registry of deeds for the county where such real estate is located, and, with respect to personal property of the employer, said notice is recorded with the clerk of the city or town where such personal property is located.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A person or firm bringing an action under this section must establish a violation of said subsection or chapters by a preponderance of the evidence. Upon establishing that the violation occurred, the person bringing the action shall recover, as liquidated damages, ten percent of the total amount bid on the contract, or fifteen thousand dollars, whichever is lesser.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     An action under this subsection shall be commenced within one year from the date when the contract is awarded.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     No plaintiff shall be allowed to recover any amounts under this subsection if said plaintiff was in violation of sections twenty-five A or twenty-five C at the time of making the bid on the contract.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     In any action under this section, the prevailing party shall be entitled to an award of reasonable attorneys fees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     In addition to being subject to the civil penalties herein provided, an employer who fails to provide for insurance or self insurance as required by this chapter or knowingly misclassifies employees, to avoid higher premium rates, will be immediately debarred from bidding or participating in any state or municipal funded contracts for a period of three years and shall when applicable be subject to penalties provided for in section fourteen.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     Whenever facts exist showing that an employer has failed to comply with this chapter, then any 3 persons may bring a civil action and that civil action shall be deemed a private attorney’s general action. Before bringing a civil action under this subsection, the 3 persons shall provide notice, by certified mail, return receipt requested, of what might become the substance of a complaint to the employer and any insurer that was or is entitled to collect amounts not paid. The notice shall include a statement of intent to file suit under this subsection. After the expiration of 90 days after delivery of the notice to the employer and the insurer, the 3 persons may file a civil action under this subsection, but they shall not be bound by the notice provided to the employer and the insurer.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>