<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="151B" order_by="151B" level="3">Unlawful Discrimination Because Of Race, Color, Religious Creed, National Origin, Ancestry Or Sex</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employers’ Policies Against Sexual Harassment; Preparation Of Model Policy; Education And Training Programs</catch_line>
    <order_by>3A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     All employers, employment agencies and labor organizations shall promote a workplace free of sexual harassment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Every employer shall:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     adopt a policy against sexual harassment which shall include:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     a statement that sexual harassment in the workplace is unlawful;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     a statement that it is unlawful to retaliate against an employee for filing a complaint of sexual harassment or for cooperating in an investigation of a complaint for sexual harassment;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     a description and examples of sexual harassment;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     a statement of the range of consequences for employees who are found to have committed sexual harassment;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     a description of the process for filing internal complaints about sexual harassment and the work addresses and telephone numbers of the person or persons to whom complaints should be made; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     the identity of the appropriate state and federal employment discrimination enforcement agencies, and directions as to how to contact such agencies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     provide annually to all employees an individual written copy of the employer’s policy against sexual harassment; provided, however, that a new employee shall be provided such a copy at the time of his employment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The commission shall prepare and provide to employers subject to this section a model policy and poster consistent with federal and state statutes and regulations, which may be used by employers for the purposes of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     An employer’s failure to provide the information required to be provided by this section shall not, in and of itself, result in the liability of said employer to any current or former employee or applicant in any action alleging sexual harassment. An employer’s compliance with the notice requirements of this section shall not, in and of itself, protect the employer from liability for sexual harassment of any current or former employee or applicant.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Employers and labor organizations are encouraged to conduct an education and training program for new employees and members, within one year of commencement of employment or membership, which includes at a minimum the information set forth in this section. Employers are encouraged to conduct additional training for new supervisory and managerial employees and members within one year of commencement of employment or membership, which shall include at a minimum the information set forth in subsection (b), the specific responsibilities of supervisory and managerial employees and the methods that such employees should take to ensure immediate and appropriate corrective action in addressing sexual harassment complaints. Employers, labor organizations and appropriate state agencies are encouraged to cooperate in making such training available.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>