<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>44A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions; Competitive Bids; Award; Bonds; Extreme Emergency Situations; Records Contracts Not Subjected To Competitive Bid Process</catch_line>
    <order_by>44A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The words defined in this section shall have the meaning set forth below whenever they appear in sections forty-four A through forty-four H, inclusive, of this chapter unless indicated otherwise or unless the context in which they are used clearly requires a different meaning.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     Every contract for the construction, reconstruction, installation, demolition, maintenance or repair of any building estimated to cost not less than $10,000 but not more than $25,000 shall be awarded to the responsible person offering to perform the contract at the lowest price. The public agency shall make public notification of the contract and shall seek written responses from persons who customarily perform such work. The public notification shall include a scope-of-work statement that defines the work to be performed and provides potential responders with sufficient information regarding the objectives and requirements of the public agency and the time period within which the work shall be completed. For the purposes of this paragraph, “public notification” shall include, but need not be limited to, posting at least 2 weeks before the time specified in the notification for the receipt of responses, the contract and scope-of- work statement on the website of the public agency, on the COMPASS system, in the central register published pursuant to section 20A of chapter 9 and in a conspicuous place in or near the primary office of the public agency.
        </section>
        <section prefix="C">
    	     Every contract for the construction, reconstruction, installation, demolition, maintenance or repair of any building by a public agency estimated to cost not less than $25,000 but not more than $100,000, except for a pumping station to be constructed as an integral part of a sewer construction or water construction project bid under the provisions of section 39M of chapter 30, shall be awarded to the lowest responsible and eligible bidder on the basis of competitive bids publicly opened and read in accordance with the procedure set forth in said section 39M of said chapter 30. The term “pumping station” as used in this section shall mean a building or other structure which houses solely pumps and appurtenant electrical and plumbing fixtures.
        </section>
        <section prefix="D">
    	     Every contract for the construction, reconstruction, installation, demolition, maintenance or repair of any building by a public agency estimated to cost more than $100,000, except for a pumping station to be constructed as an integral part of a sewer construction or water construction project bid under the provisions of section 39M of chapter 30, shall be awarded to the lowest responsible and eligible general bidder on the basis of competitive bids in accordance with the procedure set forth in section 44A to 44H, inclusive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="E">
    	     When the general court has approved the use of an alternative mode of procurement of construction for a project pursuant to section 7E of chapter 29, the awarding authority responsible for procuring construction services for the project shall follow the policies and procedures of this section and of section 44B to 44H, inclusive, to the extent compatible with the mode of construction procurement selected.
        </section>
        <section prefix="F">
    	     Notwithstanding paragraph (E), a public agency may undertake the procurement of modular buildings, in accordance with section 44E. A public agency may procure site work for modular buildings, including but not limited to, construction of foundations, installations, and attachment to external utilities, or any portion of site work, either in combination with the procurement of modular buildings pursuant to section 44E or on the basis of competitive bids pursuant to the paragraph (E). Notwithstanding the paragraph (E), a public agency may procure energy management services in accordance with section 11C of chapter 25A and regulations promulgated thereunder.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The award of every such contract in connection with which approval by an officer, board or agency of the federal government is required shall be made within thirty days, Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays excluded, after such approval; and the award of every contract subject to this section in connection with which approval by an officer, board or agency of the federal government is not required shall be made within thirty days, Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays excluded, after the opening of the bids therefor. If the bidder selected as the general contractor fails to perform his agreement to execute a contract in accordance with the terms of his bid and furnish a performance bond and also a labor and materials or payment bond as stated in his bid in accordance with section forty-four E, an award shall be made to the next lowest responsible and eligible bidder, subject to the provisions of sections forty-four A to forty-four H, inclusive, of this chapter. The thirty-day time limit shall not be applicable to a second or subsequent award made after expiration of the time limit with the consent of said next lowest responsible and eligible bidder, and made because the original award made within the time limit was invalid, or because the bidder failed to execute the contract or to provide a performance bond and labor and materials or payment bond.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     In cases of extreme emergency, the awarding authority may, with the prior approval of the commissioner, award a contract for that portion of the work necessary to preserve the health or safety of persons or property or to alleviate an imminent security threat on the basis of such competitive bids or proposals as it can obtain in time to care for the extreme emergency and without public opening of the bids or proposals.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     (a) Notwithstanding the provisions of this section or any other general or special law to the contrary, a municipality may enter into a contract for proprietary environmental technology systems as defined in subsection (1) of this section without said contract being subject to the competitive bid process as set forth in sections thirty-eight A1/2 to thirty-eight O, inclusive, of chapter seven; this section and sections forty-four B to forty-four H, inclusive, of this chapter, and section thirty-nine M of chapter thirty; provided that the awarding authority meets the conditions set forth and receives the approvals required in paragraph (b) of this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Prior to the issuance of any request for proposal with respect to the awarding of any contract pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (a) of this subsection, the awarding authority shall meet or obtain each of the following conditions or required approvals: (1) the municipality shall appoint qualified persons to conduct a thorough review of all available environmental technology, including both proprietary and non-proprietary environmental technology, and if the conclusion of this review is that a contract for proprietary environmental technology systems is in the public interest, such conclusion shall be supported by sound documented reasons in writing available for public inspection; (2) the city council, the board of selectmen, or the town meeting shall take a majority vote finding that it is in the public interest to enter into a contract for proprietary environmental technology systems, as defined in subsection (1) of this section, providing such vote is supported by the conclusion of the review conducted pursuant to condition (1); (3) both the attorney general and the commissioner of the department of environmental protection shall grant written approval; (4) said contract shall be subject to any limitation in the waiver of sections thirty-eight A1/2 to thirty-eight O, inclusive, of chapter seven, sections forty-four A to forty-four H of chapter one hundred and forty-nine, and section thirty-nine M of chapter thirty imposed by either the attorney general or the commissioner of the department of environmental protection as a condition for a grant of approval by said officers; and (5) every proprietary environmental technology systems contract shall be as compatible with sections thirty-eight A to thirty-eight O, inclusive, of chapter seven, sections forty-four A to forty-four H of chapter one hundred and forty-nine, and section thirty-nine M of chapter thirty as is feasible for the procurement of the proprietary environmental technology systems chosen.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>