<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>187</section_number>
    <catch_line>Health Care Providers; Protection From Retaliatory Action By Health Care Facilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>187</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall have the following meanings:-
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A health care facility shall not refuse to hire, terminate a contractual agreement with or take any retaliatory action against a health care provider because the health care provider does any of the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     discloses or threatens to disclose to a manager or to a public body an activity, policy or practice of the health care facility or of another health care facility with whom the health care provider’s health care facility has a business relationship, that the health care provider reasonably believes is in violation of a law or rule or regulation promulgated pursuant to law or violation of professional standards of practice which the health care provider reasonably believes poses a risk to public health;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     provides information to or testifies before any public body conducting an investigation, hearing or inquiry into any violation of a law, or rule or regulation promulgated pursuant to law or activity, policy or professional standards of practice of a health care provider, by the health care facility or by another health care facility with whom the health care provider’s health care facility has a business relationship, which the health care provider reasonably believes poses a risk to public health;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     objects to or refuses to participate in any activity, policy or practice of the health care facility or of another health care facility with whom the health care provider’s health care facility has a business relationship which the health care provider reasonably believes is in violation of a law or rule or regulation promulgated pursuant to law or violation of professional standards of practice which the health care provider reasonably believes poses a risk to public health; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     participates in any committee or peer review process, files a report or a complaint, or an incident report discussing allegations of unsafe, dangerous or potentially dangerous care.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A health care provider shall not be required to comply with paragraph (1) if he: (i) is reasonably certain that the activity, policy or practice is known to one or more managers of the health care facility and the situation is emergent in nature; (ii) reasonably fears physical harm as a result of the disclosure; or (iii) makes the disclosure to a public body for the purpose of providing evidence of what the health care provider reasonably believes to be a crime.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Any health care provider or former health care provider aggrieved by a violation of this section may, within two years, institute a civil action in the superior court. Any party to such action shall be entitled to claim a jury trial. All remedies available in common law tort actions shall be available to prevailing plaintiffs. The remedies shall be in addition to any legal or equitable relief provided herein. The court may:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     issue a temporary restraining order or preliminary or permanent injunction to restrain continued violation of this section;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     reinstate the health care provider to the same position held before the retaliatory action, or to an equivalent position;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     reinstate full fringe benefits and seniority rights to the health care provider;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     compensate the health care provider for lost wages, benefits and other remuneration, and interest thereon; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     order payment by the health care facility of reasonable litigation costs, reasonable expert witness fees and reasonable attorneys’ fees. A health care provider may bring an action in the appropriate superior court or the superior court of the county of Suffolk for the relief provided in this subsection. The health care provider or former health care provider shall deliver a copy of the complaint to the attorney general. The attorney general shall establish and maintain a register of all complaints made by health care personnel under this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A health care provider shall not be assessed attorneys’ fees under paragraph (1) if, upon exercising reasonable and diligent efforts after filing the action, the health care provider moves to dismiss the action against the health care facility, or files a notice agreeing to a voluntary dismissal, within a reasonable time after determining that the health care facility would not be found liable for damages.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Whenever he believes it to be in the public interest, the attorney general may bring an action in the name of the commonwealth against any health care facility violating the provisions of subsection (b) or subsection (h). Such an action may be brought in the superior court and any party thereto may claim trial by jury. In any action under this section, in addition to the remedies the court may provide in accordance with subsection (d), the court may require the health care facility to pay to the commonwealth a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for each violation, as well as the cost of reasonable attorneys’ fees and reasonable expert witness fees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish the rights, privileges or remedies of any health care provider under any other federal or state law or regulation or under any collective bargaining agreement or employment contract.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     A health care facility shall conspicuously display notices reasonably designed to inform its health care providers of their protection and obligations under this section and use other appropriate means to keep its health care providers so informed. Each notice posted pursuant to this subsection shall include the name of the persons the health care facility has designated to receive written notifications pursuant to subsection (c). Any health care facility which violates the provisions of this subsection shall be punished by a fine of not less than $250 nor more than $2,500.  The provisions of this subsection shall be enforced by the attorney general.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     The attorney general may promulgate rules and regulations necessary and appropriate to enforce the provisions of this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>