<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="151D" order_by="151D" level="3">Health, Welfare And Retirement Funds</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Annual Report Or Other Reports By Trustees Or Plan Administrators;  Exemptions; Information Required; Form; Filing; Time; Powers Of Board;  Conflicts Of Interest; Restrictions; Violations; Penalties; Proceedings;  Service Of Process On Nonresidents</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The trustees or plan administrator required to register under section two shall file an annual report with the board within five months after the end of the calendar year, or if the records of the trust or fund are kept on a policy or fiscal year basis then within five months after the end of such policy or fiscal year. Said report shall be in writing upon a form prescribed by the board. It shall be signed and certified under oath as prescribed by the board. It shall contain the following information for the preceding calendar, policy or fiscal year: the value of the trust or fund as of the end of the fiscal year; the amount contributed by the employer or employers, the amount contributed by the employees; the amount of benefits paid for each class of benefits; the number of employees covered; the salaries and fees paid by or charged to the trust or fund, to whom paid, in what amount, and for what purposes. If some or all of the benefits under the trust or fund are provided by an insurance carrier or by a hospital, surgical or medical service or any other similar type of plan, such report shall also include for each such year, with respect to such and for each class of benefits, the following information: the premium rate or subscription charge and the total premium or subscription charges paid to each such insurance carrier or service plan; the number of persons covered by each class of benefits; the total claims incurred and the total claims paid by such insurance carrier or service plan; dividend, commissions and administrative, services or other fees paid by such insurance carrier or service plan; retentions by such insurance carrier or service plan; the names and addresses of the brokers, agents or other persons to whom commissions or fees were paid, the amounts paid to each, and the services rendered for said commissions or fees. Such insurance carrier or service plan shall certify to the trustees or plan administrators of such trust or fund within four months after the end of each policy year, the information necessary to enable such trustees or plan administrators to comply with the requirements of this paragraph. Any insurance carrier or service plan failing to furnish such information within the time specified shall be penalized five dollars for each day during which such failure continues. The board may also request in writing such supplemental information as is necessary to clarify and explain any such annual reports.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The board may examine the books and records and investigate the administration of any trust, pension plan or profit-sharing retirement plan, and the board may require the attendance and testimony of witnesses. Such witnesses shall be duly sworn and shall give their testimony under the penalties of perjury. The board may conduct examinations at such places and take deposition within or without the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No trustee or plan administrator or employer, or labor organization representing any employees eligible for benefits under a trust or fund required to register under this chapter, and no officer, agent or employee of any such trustee or plan administrator, employer or labor organization shall receive directly or indirectly any payment, commission, loan, service, or any other thing of value from any insurance company, insurance agent, insurance broker or any hospital, surgical or medical service plan, in connection with the solicitation, sale, service or administration of a contract providing benefits for such trust or fund, or receive any payment, commission, loan or any other thing of value from such trust or fund, or which is charged against such trust or fund would otherwise be payable to such trust or fund either directly or indirectly, except that any such person may receive any benefits under a trust or fund to which he is otherwise entitled, and any trustee or plan administrator, employer or labor organization, or his or its officer, agent or employee, may receive from such trust or fund reasonable compensation for necessary services and expenses rendered or incurred by him or in connection with the official duties of such trust or fund; provided, however, that nothing in this paragraph shall affect the payment of any dividend or rate credit or any other adjustment due under the terms of any insurance or annuity contract to the policy holder or contract holder.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Any trustee or plan administration subject to the provisions of this chapter, who has a principal place of business located outside the commonwealth shall appoint an agent in the commonwealth for the service of process upon such trustee or plan administrator in his capacity as trustee or plan administrator and register the name and address of such agent with the board. Any such trustee or plan administrator who fails to appoint an agent in the commonwealth shall be deemed and held, in relation to any cause of action or proceeding against him as trustee or plan administrator to have appointed the commissioner of corporations and his successor in office to be his true and lawful attorney and any process in any such action or proceeding against such trustee or plan administrator served upon the commissioner or his successor in office shall be of the same legal force and validity as if served on such trustee or plan administrator personally. When legal process against such trustee or plan administrator is served upon the commissioner, he shall immediately give notice to the trustee or plan administrator of such service by registered mail, postage prepaid, return receipt requested, directed to the trustee or plan administrator and shall, within two days after such service forward in the same manner, a copy of the process served upon him to such trustee or plan administrator.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     If, after notice and a hearing, the board finds that any trust or fund has been depleted by reason of any wrongful or negligent act or omission of a trustee, plan administrator or of any other person, or that any trustee, plan administrator or other person unreasonably fails or refuses to pay or award any benefit to which an employee or beneficiary is entitled, it may bring an action or intervene in an action brought by or on the behalf of an employee, beneficiary or an employer against such trustee, plan administrator or other person who fails or refuses to pay said benefits, or whose act of omission has caused such depletion, for the recovery of such monies, securities, property or thing of value for the benefit of the beneficiaries.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A summary of the report in such form as shall be approved by the board setting forth the information required to be filed under subsection (a) shall be filed annually with the board at the same time as the filing of said report. It shall be kept available for public inspection at the office of the board. The board may, if it deems it necessary for the accomplishment of the purposes of this act in the case of any particular trust, direct the trustees to distribute or appropriately publish copies of such summary to all employees and labor organizations participating in the trust or fund. Except as provided in this subsection, all reports and other information in the possession of the board shall be confidential communications, shall not be subject to subpoena and shall not be made public unless the ends of justice and the public advantage will be subserved by the publication thereof in the case of any particular trust or fund; in which event the board shall publish a copy of such report or other information or any part thereof in such manner as the board may deem proper. Any amendments, modifications or alterations of any kind to plans registered with the board shall be reported on forms acceptable to said board and certified copies of the same shall be filed with said board within thirty days after their effective date.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>