<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>147A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Homeworker’S Certificate; Place Of Work; Work Performed By Others;  Qualifications Of Applicant And Home; Strike Against Employer</catch_line>
    <order_by>147A</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall engage in industrial homework within the commonwealth unless he has in his possession a valid certificate issued to him by the attorney general under authority of this section, hereinafter and in sections one hundred and forty-seven B to one hundred and forty-seven H, inclusive, called a homeworker’s certificate. Such certificate shall be issued by the attorney general without cost and shall be valid for a period of one year from the date of its issuance, unless sooner revoked or suspended. Application for such certificate shall be made in such form as the attorney general may from time to time by rule or regulation prescribe. Such certificate shall be valid only for work performed by the applicant himself in his own home. No homeworker’s certificate shall be issued to any person under the age of sixteen years, or to any person suffering from an infectious, contagious or communicable disease or living in a home that is not clean, sanitary and free from infectious, contagious or communicable disease. The attorney general may revoke or suspend any homeworker’s certificate if he finds that the holder thereof is performing industrial homework contrary to the conditions under which the certificate was issued or in violation of any pertinent provision of sections one hundred and forty-four to one hundred and forty-seven H, inclusive, or has permitted any person not holding a valid homeworker’s certificate to assist him in performing his industrial homework. 
No original certificate shall be granted by the attorney general to any person for work to be done for an employer at whose plant there is a strike, and any certificate so issued shall be revoked or suspended, unless the attorney general finds such strike to be unlawful under the provisions of paragraph (e) of section twenty C.
    </text>
</law>