<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="152" order_by="152" level="3">Workers' Compensation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notice Of Injuries;  Forms;  Additional Reports;  Statistical Summaries</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
          Within seven calendar days, not including Sundays and legal holidays, of receipt of notice of any injury alleged to have arisen out of and in the course of employment which incapacitates an employee from earning full wages for a period of five or more calendar days, the employer shall furnish notice of the injury to the division of administration, the employee and insurer. The notice shall be submitted on a form prescribed by the division and shall contain the name and nature of the business of the employer, the name, age, sex, and occupation of the injured employee, and the date, nature, circumstances and cause of the injury and such additional information as the division shall prescribe.[ Second paragraph effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  The commissioner may require employers with those standard industry codes with the highest number of injuries or claims to provide proof of insurance coverage as required by this chapter. The commissioner may utilize information provided by the division of employment and training and the department of revenue to ascertain the addresses of the employers with such industry codes.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 154 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  The commissioner may require employers with those standard industry codes with the highest number of injuries or claims to provide proof of insurance coverage as required by this chapter. The commissioner may utilize information provided by the department of unemployment assistance and the department of revenue to ascertain the addresses of the employers with such industry codes.  Additional reports may be required from employers, insurers and medical services providers with respect to such injury and of the condition of such employee, including copies of medical, hospital, and rehabilitation reports and records, and the payments made or to be made for compensation shall be filed with the division of administration at such times and in such manner as the division may prescribe.  The division of administration shall prepare statistical summaries of reports filed under this section.  The provisions of this section shall apply also to the head of each employing board, commission and department of the commonwealth and of the several counties, cities, towns and districts subject to the provisions of section sixty-nine and copies of the report hereby required shall be furnished to the appropriate retirement board, if any, and to the agent set forth in section seventy-five or the insurer, if any.  Any person who violates the provision of this section three or more times in any year shall be punished by a fine of one hundred dollars for each such violation. Each failure to pay a fine within thirty days of receipt of a bill from the department shall be considered a separate violation.
    </text>
</law>