<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>104</section_number>
    <catch_line>Children Participants In Public Exhibitions; Violation Of Statute</catch_line>
    <order_by>104</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall employ a child under fifteen years of age, or permit him to appear as a participant in a theater, circus or any other public exhibition as a singer, dancer, acrobat, actor or in any other entertainment capacity; but this section shall not prevent the education of children in vocal and instrumental music or dancing or their participation in any exhibition of dancing conducted as a part of its graduation exercises by a school furnishing them instruction in dancing, or their participation in a church, chapel, school or school exhibition, or prevent their taking part in any festival, concert or other non-commercial exhibition upon the special written permission of the local licensing authority; nor shall it prevent children under fifteen from taking part on the stage for a limited period in a play or musical comedy in a theater wherein not more than two performances are given in any one day and not more than eight performances are given in any one week if the attorney general, after being satisfied that the supervision of such children is adequate, that their living conditions are healthful and that their education is not neglected, gives his written permission to such taking part. This section shall not prevent participation of a child under fifteen years of age in a fashion show, provided such child is accompanied by either one of his parents. Whoever violates this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than two hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not more than six months.
    </text>
</law>