<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>168A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Farm Labor Contracts;  Notice To Department</catch_line>
    <order_by>168A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. Repealed by 2011, 3, Sec. 131.]  Any employer who enters into a farm labor contract with a farm labor contractor for the hire of agricultural and farm workers shall require that said contractor exhibit his certificate of registration issued pursuant to the Farm Labor Registration Act of 1963, 7 U.S.C. sections 2041--2053, prior to entering into any such contract, and shall thereafter notify the department in writing of the execution of the contract, giving the name of the contractor, the number of the certificate, if any, and other data necessary to identify said certificate of registration.  If a worker is not an employee of the farm or farmer and remains on the labor contractor's payroll, each labor contractor shall give to each worker with each payment of wages an itemized statement of his wages and deductions and shall submit to the department of labor and workforce development a copy of his payroll record, on a form prescribed by the commissioner and mailed within forty-eight hours after the close of the weekly pay period.  Said record shall include but not be limited to the following: pay rate, hours worked, incentives, deductions for social security, transportation, housing, food, advances and net pay for the period. The department shall audit the return upon receipt according to departmental procedures.  A farm labor contractor shall file within forty-eight hours with the commissioner any change of his permanent address.
    </text>
</law>