<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="2">Labor And Industries</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149" level="3">Labor And Industries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Safety Devices And Means To Prevent Accidents And Diseases Generally;  Fees For Structural Painting</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        The department shall or the attorney general may investigate, from time to time, employments and places of employment, including, but not limited to, such places where temporary personnel and material elevators are used in construction, reconstruction or renovation of buildings, but excluding places of employment of persons engaged in domestic service in the home of the employer, and determine what suitable safety devices or other reasonable means or requirements for the prevention of accidents shall be adopted or followed in any or all such employments or places of employment; and also shall or the attorney general may determine what suitable devices or other reasonable means or requirements for the prevention of industrial or occupational diseases shall be adopted or followed in any or all such employments or places of employment; and shall make reasonable rules, regulations and orders for the prevention of accidents and the prevention of industrial or occupational diseases, and rules and regulations pertaining to structural painting made hereunder may provide for the payment of reasonable fees. 
The rules and regulations for elevators and for suitable safety devices or other reasonable means or requirements for the prevention of accidents shall also be applicable to self-employed and individual contractors who themselves work at the trade as well as to employees. 
Whoever violates any rule, regulation or requirement made by the department under authority hereof shall be punished by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars for each offense. The department or its representative or any person aggrieved, any interested party or any officer of any labor union or association, whether incorporated or otherwise, may file a written complaint with the district court in the jurisdiction of which the violation occurs. 
The provisions of this section and of sections three and five shall not apply to any employment or place of employment subject to the provisions of section twenty-eight of chapter seven.
    </text>
</law>