<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="3">The General Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advertisement Of Committee Hearings;  Designation Of Newspaper;  Expenses</catch_line>
    <order_by>35</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Advertisements of hearings shall be published only in newspapers designated by the chairman of the committee on the part of the senate or of the house of representatives and the clerk of the committee, subject to the approval of the committees on rules sitting jointly or acting concurrently, and in each case the order for the advertisement shall be signed by the chairman and clerk of the respective committees, who shall designate therein the newspapers in which such advertisement is to be published, designating daily papers whenever such are available, and shall file the same with the comptroller, who shall thereupon forward a copy to the newspapers so designated for publication and shall give the necessary directions to secure uniformity in the style and manner of publication, as provided in the preceding section. The comptroller shall certify all bills for publishing such advertisements, and shall annually, during the first week in April, report in detail to the general court the expenses incurred by the several committees under this section.
Chapter 3: Advertisement of legislative committee hearings; publication
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 6 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Advertisements of hearings of legislative committees shall be published on the official website of the general court and may be published in additional publications if the chairs of the committee determine that additional publication is necessary to reach those with a substantial interest in a matter pending at the hearing.
    </text>
</law>