<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="3">The General Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18</section_number>
    <catch_line>Other Legislative Employees;  Compensation</catch_line>
    <order_by>18</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There shall be two chief general court officers for each branch, each with the title of assistant sergeant-at-arms, and such assistant chief general court officers, general court officers and pages as shall be established by the committees on rules of the two branches of the general court acting concurrently. Such employees shall receive such compensation as may be established by the said committees acting concurrently. There shall be a maintenance superintendent for each branch and such assistants as may be necessary, for whose fitness and good conduct the sergeant-at-arms shall be responsible, and such employees shall receive such compensation as may be established by the said committees acting concurrently.
Chapter 3: Other legislative employees; compensation
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 4 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There shall be 2 chief general court officers for each branch, each with the title of assistant sergeant-at-arms, and such assistant chief general court officers, general court officers and pages as shall be established by the committees on rules of the 2 branches of the general court acting concurrently. Such employees shall receive such compensation as may be established by said committees acting concurrently.
    </text>
</law>