<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="5" order_by="5" level="3">Printing And Distribution Of Laws And Public Documents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18</section_number>
    <catch_line>Preparation And Distribution Of Book Of Biographical Sketches And Portraits Of State Officers;  Report Of Receipts</catch_line>
    <order_by>18</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. Repealed by 2012, 165, Sec. 10. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  The clerks of the two branches shall, in every odd-numbered year, prepare a book containing portraits and biographical sketches of members of the general court and other state officers, and such other information as may be deemed pertinent, of which not more than six hundred copies shall be printed under the direction of said clerks, for the use of the general court. The clerks shall furnish one such copy to each member of the general court and shall distribute the other copies as the committees on rules of the senate and house of representatives may direct.  In addition to the copies of such book printed under authority of the foregoing provisions of this section, there shall be printed such additional copies thereof as said clerks may from time to time determine. Such additional copies shall be delivered to the state secretary, who shall place the same on public sale at a price not less than the cost thereof, as determined by said committees on rules. The state secretary shall annually report to the general court the amount received from the sale of such copies, the amount received from the sale of legislative journals under section ten, and the amount received from the sale of the general court manuals under section eleven.
    </text>
</law>