<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="3">Statutes</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Special Legislative Commissions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2A</order_by>
    <text>
        Unless otherwise provided, the provisions of this section shall apply to each special commission established to make an investigation and study of any matter. 
If it is provided that members of the senate and house of representatives shall be members of such commission, such members shall be designated by the president of the senate and the speaker of the house of representatives, respectively. 
Such commission (1) shall be provided with quarters in the state house or elsewhere; (2) may expend for expenses and for expert, legal, clerical and other assistance such sums as may be appropriated therefor; (3) may travel within the commonwealth; (4) may hold hearings; (5) shall report to the general court the results of its investigation and study and its recommendations, if any, together with drafts of legislation necessary to carry its recommendations into effect by filing the same with the clerk of either branch; and (6) may report from time to time but shall file its final report not later than the last Wednesday in January in the following year, if it is established, continued, or revived and continued, in an odd-numbered year, or not later than the last Wednesday in December in the same year, if it is established, continued, or revived and continued in an even-numbered year. 
Private or executive meetings of each special commission shall be open to the public unless a majority of the members of such commission shall vote otherwise. A notice of each such meeting shall be filed with the clerk of either branch, and the notice or a copy thereof shall be publicly posted in the office of such clerk at least twenty-four hours prior to such meeting, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays. 
If such commission is continued, or revived and continued, it shall continue to exercise and perform all the rights, powers and duties previously conferred or imposed on it.
    </text>
</law>