<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Jurisdiction And Emblems Of The Commonwealth, The General Court, Statutes And Public Documents</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="3">The General Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>65</section_number>
    <catch_line>Senate Art Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>65</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There is hereby established in the senate a senate art committee, hereinafter called the committee, to consist of the president and the minority leader thereof, and seven persons to be appointed by the president, of whom at least three shall be members of The Doric Dames, Inc. Each member shall be appointed for a term coterminous with that of the president, and shall serve at his pleasure.[ First paragraph as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 8 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There is hereby established in the senate a senate art committee, hereinafter called the committee, to consist of the president and the minority leader thereof, and seven persons to be appointed by the president, of whom at least 1 may be a member of The Doric Docents Inc. Each member shall be appointed for a term coterminous with that of the president, and shall serve at his pleasure.[ Second paragraph effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The committee shall consider and advise the senate relative to any matter germane to the upgrading and restoration of the quarters in the state house used by the members of the senate and its employees, with particular attention to the historical and artistic qualities of said quarters. The committee may file recommendations from time to time with the clerk of the senate, but shall file an annual report with the clerk before the first Wednesday in December of each year.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 9 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The committee may consider and advise the senate relative to any matter germane to the upgrading and restoration of the quarters in the state house used by the members of the senate and its employees, with particular attention to the historical and artistic qualities of said quarters. The committee may file recommendations from time to time with the clerk of the senate.
    </text>
</law>