<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>162T</section_number>
    <catch_line>Insurer’S Termination Of Appointment, Contract, Etc. With Producer;  Procedures</catch_line>
    <order_by>162T</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     An insurer or authorized representative of the insurer that terminates the appointment, employment, contract or other insurance business relationship with a producer shall notify the commissioner within 30 days following the effective date of the termination, using a format prescribed by the commissioner, if the reason for termination is one of the reasons set forth in section 162R or the insurer has knowledge the producer was found by a court, government body, or self-regulatory organization authorized by law to have engaged in any of the activities in section 162R. Upon the written request of the commissioner, the insurer shall provide additional information, documents, records or other data pertaining to the termination or activity of the producer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     An insurer or authorized representative of the insurer that terminates the appointment, employment or contract with a producer for any reason not set forth in section 162R shall notify the commissioner within 30 days following the effective date of the termination, using a format prescribed by the commissioner. Upon written request of the commissioner, the insurer shall provide additional information, documents, records or other data pertaining to the termination.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The insurer or the authorized representative of the insurer shall promptly notify the commissioner in a format acceptable to the commissioner if, upon further review or investigation, the insurer discovers additional information that would have been reportable to the commissioner in accordance with subsection (a) had the insurer then known of its existence.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Within 30 days after the producer has received the original or additional notification, the producer may file written comments concerning the substance of the notification with the commissioner. The producer shall, by the same means, simultaneously send a copy of the comments to the reporting insurer, and the comments shall become a part of the commissioner’s file and accompany every copy of a report distributed or disclosed for any reason about the producer as permitted under subsection (f).
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     In any action brought against a person that may have immunity under paragraph (1) for making any statement required by this section or providing any information relating to any statement that may be requested by the commissioner, the party bringing the action shall plead specifically in any allegation that paragraph (1) does not apply because the person making the statement or providing the information did so with actual malice.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Paragraph (1) or (2) shall not abrogate or modify any existing statutory or common law privileges or immunities.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Neither the commissioner nor any person who received documents, materials or other information while acting under the authority of the commissioner shall be permitted or required to testify in any private civil action concerning any confidential documents, materials, or information subject to paragraph (1).
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     In order to assist in the performance of the commissioner’s duties under sections 162H to 162X, inclusive, the commissioner:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     may share documents, materials or other information, including the confidential and privileged documents, materials or information subject to paragraph (1), with other state, federal and international regulatory agencies, with the NAIC, its affiliates or subsidiaries, and with state, federal and international law enforcement authorities, if the recipient agrees to maintain the confidentiality and privileged status of the document, material or other information;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     may receive documents, materials or information, including otherwise confidential and privileged documents, materials or information, from the NAIC, its affiliates or subsidiaries and from regulatory and law enforcement officials of other foreign or domestic jurisdictions, and shall maintain as confidential or privileged any document, material or information received with notice or the understanding that it is confidential or privileged under the laws of the jurisdiction that is the source of the document, material or information; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     may enter into agreements governing sharing and use of information consistent with this paragraph.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     No waiver of any applicable privilege or claim of confidentiality in the documents, materials or information shall occur as a result of disclosure to the commissioner under this section or as a result of sharing as authorized in paragraph (3).
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Nothing in sections 162H to 162X, inclusive, shall prohibit the commissioner from releasing final, adjudicated actions including for cause terminations that are open to public inspection, under clause Twenty-sixth of section 7 of chapter 4 and section 10 of chapter 66, to a database or other clearinghouse service maintained by the NAIC, its affiliates or subsidiaries of the NAIC.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     An insurer, the authorized representative of the insurer, or producer that fails to report as required under this section or that is found to have reported with actual malice by a court of competent jurisdiction may, after notice and hearing, have its license or certificate of authority suspended or revoked and may be fined in accordance with chapter 176D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Nothing in this section shall modify the provisions of section 163.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>