<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176O" order_by="176O" level="3">Health Insurance Consumer Protections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24</section_number>
    <catch_line>Internal Appeals Processes For Risk Bearing Provider Organizations;  Patient's Right To Third Party Advocate;  External Review Process</catch_line>
    <order_by>24</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 206 effective October 1, 2013. See 2012, 224, Sec. 293.]  (a) All risk-bearing provider organizations certified under chapter 176U shall create internal appeals processes. The appeals processes shall be available to the public in written format and, by request, in electronic format.  (b) The internal appeals processes in subsection (a) shall be completed in a period not longer than 14 days; provided, however, that an expedited internal appeal shall be completed in a period not longer that 3 days for a patient with an urgent medical need including, but not limited to, terminal illness or emergency situations, as defined through regulations by the office of patient protection. During the appeals process, the risk-bearing provider organization shall not: (i) prevent a patient from seeking medical opinions outside of that organization; or (ii) terminate any medical services being provided to the patient, including medical services which began prior to the appeal and are the subject of such appeal. The decision on the appeal shall be in writing and shall notify the patient of the right to file a further external appeal.  (c) Risk-bearing provider organizations shall inform any patient of the right to designate a third party to advocate on the patient's behalf during the appeals process including, but not limited to, a spouse or other family member, an attorney of record or a legal guardian. If the patient does not elect a person to serve as his or her advocate such provider organization shall offer to contact the office of patient protection and the office of patient protection may designate an ombudsman to advocate on the patient's behalf.  (d) The office of patient protection shall establish by regulation an external review process for the review of grievances submitted by or on behalf of patients of risk-bearing provider organizations. The process shall specify the maximum amount of time for the completion of a determination and review after a grievance is submitted and shall include the right to have benefits continued pending appeal. The office of patient protection shall establish expedited review procedures applicable to emergency and urgent care situations  (e) The office of patient protection shall promulgate regulations necessary to implement this section.
    </text>
</law>