<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>193P</section_number>
    <catch_line>Fire Insurance Policies;  Nonrenewal Notice Provision;  Requisites Of Notice</catch_line>
    <order_by>193P</order_by>
    <text>
          Except as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, no policy providing protection against loss by reason of fire to a dwelling or contents thereof shall be issued unless it contains a provision that the insurer will give written notice of its intent not to renew or reissue a policy to the insured at least forty-five days prior to the expiration of the policy which notice shall state or be accompanied by a writing stating the specific reasons for such decision.  The notice so required shall, except as hereinafter provided, be sent or delivered either to the named insured at the mailing address shown in the policy or to the insurance agent of the company or the insurance broker who negotiated the issuance of the policy. If the policy was executed on behalf of the company, in whole or in part, by or on behalf of an insurance agent or broker of the company such notice shall be sent to such insurance agent or broker. Every such insurance agent or broker receiving such notice shall, within fifteen days of its receipt, send a copy to the insured or the principal unless such agent or broker has replaced the insurance. Any company which fails to send such notice or which sends such notice and subsequently renews such policy, shall recognize the agent or broker designated by the insured in the same manner as provided by any contract, custom, or usage then in effect between such agent or broker and such company.[ Paragraph added by 2012, 188, Sec. 2 effective October 30, 2012.]  Nothing in this section shall be construed to require notice if an insurer within the same group of insurers issues a succeeding policy to the insured that provides coverage on the same terms and conditions as the preceding policy. Insurers that offer or issue a succeeding policy to the insured through a different company within the same company group shall notify the insured in writing of any changes in coverage from the preceding policy at the time of issuance.
    </text>
</law>