<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176B" order_by="176B" level="3">Medical Service Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4DD</section_number>
    <catch_line>Coverage For Diagnosis And Treatment Of Autism Spectrum Disorder</catch_line>
    <order_by>4DD</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A subscription certificate under an individual or group medical service agreement which is issued or renewed within or without the commonwealth shall provide benefits on a nondiscriminatory basis to residents of the commonwealth and to all policyholders having a principal place of employment in the commonwealth for the diagnosis and treatment of autism spectrum disorder in individuals.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Such certificate shall be in compliance with subsection (b) if the certificate does not contain any annual or lifetime dollar or unit of service limitation on coverage for the diagnosis and treatment of autism spectrum disorders which is less than annual or lifetime dollar or unit of service limitation imposed on coverage for the diagnosis and treatment of physical conditions.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     This section shall not limit benefits that are otherwise available to an individual under a health insurance policy.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Coverage under this section shall not be subject to a limit on the number of visits an individual may make to an autism services provider.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     This section shall not affect an obligation to provide services to an individual under an individualized family service plan, an individualized education program or an individualized service plan. Services related to autism spectrum disorder provided by school personnel pursuant to an individualized education program are not subject to reimbursement under this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     An insurer, corporation or health maintenance organization shall be exempt for a period of 3 years from the requirement to provide coverage for habilitative or rehabilitative care required under this section and not covered by the insurer, corporation or health maintenance organization as of December 31, 2010, if:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     an actuary, affiliated with the insurer, corporation or health maintenance organization certifies in writing to the commissioner of insurance that:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     based on an analysis to be completed not more than once annually by each insurer, corporation or health maintenance organization for the most recent experience period of at least 1 year’s duration, the annual costs associated with coverage of habilitative or rehabilitative care required under this section and not covered as of December 31, 2010, exceeded 1 per cent of the premiums charged over the experience period by the insurer, corporation or health maintenance organization;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     those costs solely would lead to an increase in average premiums charged of more than 1 per cent for all insurance policies, subscription contracts or health care plans commencing on inception or the next renewal date, based on the premium rating methodology and practices the insurer, corporation or health maintenance organization employs; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     the commissioner of insurance approves the certification of the actuary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     An exemption allowed under paragraph (1) shall apply for a 3 year coverage period following inception or next renewal date of all insurance policies, subscription contracts or health care plans issued or renewed during the 1-year period following the date of the exemption, after which the insurer, corporation or health maintenance organization shall again provide coverage for habilitative or rehabilitative care required under this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Notwithstanding the exemption allowed under paragraph (1), an insurer, corporation or health maintenance organization may elect to continue to provide coverage for habilitative or rehabilitative care required under this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>