<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>149N</section_number>
    <catch_line>Service Contracts; Duties Of Provider</catch_line>
    <order_by>149N</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A provider may appoint an administrator or other designee to be responsible for the administration of service contracts executed under sections 149M to 149V, inclusive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Service contracts shall not be issued, sold or offered for sale unless the provider has provided: (1) a receipt for, or other written evidence of, the purchase of the service contract to the contract holder; and (2) a copy of the service contract to the service contract holder within a reasonable period of time from the date of purchase.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A provider of service contracts shall file a registration with the commissioner which shall include, without limitation, the provider’s name, address, phone and contact person and a designated person in the commonwealth for service of process. Each provider shall pay to the commissioner a fee of $600 upon initial registration and upon renewal which shall occur every 3 years thereafter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     In order to assure the faithful performance of a provider’s obligations to its contract holders, each provider shall:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     insure all service contracts under a reimbursement insurance policy issued by an insurer that is authorized, registered or otherwise permitted to transact insurance in the commonwealth or a surplus lines insurer authorized to do business in the commonwealth; provided, that the reimbursement insurance policy shall be obtained from an insurer that: (i) at the time the policy is filed with the commissioner, and continuously thereafter, maintains surplus as to contract holders and paid-in capital of at least $15,000,000 and annually files copies of the insurer’s financial statements, its NAIC annual statement and an actuarial certification if required and filed in the insurer’s state of domicile; or (ii) at the time the policy is filed with the commissioner, and continuously thereafter, maintains surplus as to policyholders and paid-in capital of less than $15,000,000 but at least $10,000,000, demonstrates to the satisfaction of the commissioner that the insurer maintains a ratio of net written premiums, wherever written, to surplus as to contract holders and paid-in capital of not greater than 3 to 1, and annually files copies of the insurer’s financial statements, its NAIC annual statement and an actuarial certification if required and filed in the insurer’s state of domicile;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Except for the requirements specified in subsections (c) and (d), no additional registration submissions or financial security requirements shall be required by the commissioner for service contract providers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Service contracts shall require the provider to permit the service contract holder to return the service contract within 20 days of the date the service contract was mailed to the service contract holder or within 10 days of delivery of the service contract to the service contract holder if the service contract is delivered to the service contract holder at the time of sale or within a longer time period permitted under the service contract. Upon return of the service contract to the provider within the applicable time period, if no claim has been made under the service contract prior to its return to the provider, the service contract shall be void and the provider shall refund to the service contract holder, or credit the account of the service contract holder or other payer of record, if different, the full purchase price of the service contract. The right to void the service contract provided in this subsection shall not be transferable and shall apply only to the original service contract purchaser if no claim has been made prior to its return to the provider. A 10 per cent penalty per month shall be added to a refund that is not paid or credited within 45 days after return of the service contract to the provider.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Provider fees collected on service contracts shall not be subject to premium taxes; provided, however, that premiums for reimbursement insurance policies shall be subject to premium taxes and all other applicable taxes.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Except for the registration requirements in subsection (c), providers and related service contracts sellers, administrators and other persons marketing, selling or offering to sell service contracts shall not be required to hold any other form of license granted by the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Chapter 176D shall apply to all providers and related service contract sellers, administrators and other persons marketing, selling or offering to sell service contracts; provided however, a service contract shall not be considered to be insurance for any purpose under the laws of the commonwealth and the marketing, sale, offering for sale, issuance, making, proposing to make and administration of service contracts by providers and related service contract sellers, administrators and other persons shall be exempt from all other provisions of chapter 175, including any non-consumer commercial service contract.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Service contracts may provide for the service, repair, replacement or maintenance of tangible personal property for damage resulting from power surges and accidental damage from handling and may provide for leak or repair coverage to roofing systems on residential dwellings.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>