<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176S" order_by="176S" level="3">Consumer Choice Of Physician Assistant Services</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 216 effective November 4, 2012.]  As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:--  "Carrier'', (1) an insurer licensed or otherwise authorized to transact accident or health insurance under chapter 175; (2) a nonprofit hospital service corporation organized under chapter 176A; (3) a nonprofit medical service corporation organized under chapter 176B; (4) a health maintenance organization organized under chapter 176G; (5) an organization entering into a preferred provider arrangement under chapter 176I; (6) a contributory group general or blanket insurance for persons in the service of the commonwealth under chapter 32A; (7) a contributory group general or blanket insurance for persons in the service of counties, cities, towns and districts, and their dependents under chapter 32B; (8) the medical assistance program administered by the office of Medicaid pursuant to chapter 118E and in accordance with Title XIX of the Social Security Act or any successor statute; and (9) any other medical assistance program operated by a governmental unit for persons categorically eligible for such program.  "Commissioner'', the commissioner of insurance.  "Insured'', an enrollee, covered person, insured, member, policyholder or subscriber of a carrier.  "Nondiscriminatory basis'', a carrier shall be deemed to be providing coverage on a non-discriminatory basis if its plan does not contain any annual or lifetime dollar or unit of service limitation imposed on coverage for the care provided by a physician assistant which is less than any annual or lifetime dollar or unit of service limitation imposed on coverage for the same services by other participating providers.  "Participating provider'', a provider who, under terms and conditions of a contract with the carrier or with its contractor or subcontractor, has agreed to provide health care services to an insured with an expectation of receiving payment, other than coinsurance, co-payments or deductibles, directly or indirectly from the carrier.  "Physician assistant'', a person who is a graduate of an approved program for the training of physician assistants who is supervised by a registered physician in accordance with sections 9C to 9H, inclusive, of chapter 112, and who has passed the Physician Assistant National Certifying Exam or its equivalent.  "Primary care provider'', a health care professional qualified to provide general medical care for common health care problems who (1) supervises, coordinates, prescribes, or otherwise provides or proposes health care services; (2) initiates referrals for specialist care; and (3) maintains continuity of care within the scope of practice.
    </text>
</law>