<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="161A" order_by="161A" level="3">Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Directors</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until August 9, 2012. For text effective August 9, 2012, see below.]  The authority shall be governed and its corporate powers exercised by a board of directors. The board shall consist of the 5 members appointed by the governor for terms of 4 years, 2 of whom shall be experts in the field of public or private transportation finance, 2 of whom shall have practical experience in transportation planning and policy and 1 of whom shall be a registered civil engineer with at least 10 years experience. One of the members shall be appointed by the governor to serve as chairperson of the board; provided, however, that said designee shall not be an employee of the authority, department or any division thereof. Not more than 3 of the directors shall be members of the same political party. Any person appointed to fill a vacancy in the office of a member of the board shall be appointed in a like manner and shall serve for only the unexpired term of such member. A member shall be eligible for reappointment. A member may be removed from his appointment by the governor for cause. The governor may appoint a designee pursuant to section 6A of chapter 30. A majority of the directors shall constitute a quorum, which shall be required to take any particular action. The directors shall meet monthly; provided, however, that such meeting shall occur no later than the fifteenth day of the month. Each meeting shall provide a sufficient opportunity for public comment.
Chapter 161A: Board of directors
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 242, Sec. 9 effective August 9, 2012. For text effective until August 9, 2012, see above.]  The authority shall be governed and its corporate powers exercised by the board of directors of the Massachusetts Department of Transportation established under chapter 6C.
    </text>
</law>