<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>94D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Domestic Exchange; Certificates And Provisional Certificates To  Transact Business; Applications   </catch_line>
    <order_by>94D</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The name or designation under which the reciprocal or inter-insurance contracts are to be issued, which shall not be so similar to the name of any other insurance company as likely to be mistaken for it, and which, as to domestic exchanges, shall be subject to the approval of the commissioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The location of the office or offices from which such contracts are to be issued.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The classes of insurance to be written.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     An exact copy of the form of agreement or policy contracts to be used in the exchanging of the insurance provided for.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     An exact copy of the form of power of attorney authorizing the attorney in fact to effect the exchanging of insurance provided for and which as to domestic exchanges, shall be subject to the approval of the commissioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The name of the attorney in fact; provided, that the commissioner shall not issue a certificate of authority to transact business to a domestic exchange until he is satisfied, by such examination as he may make and such evidence as he may require, that the attorney in fact is competent, of good repute, and intends in good faith to act as attorney in fact for subscribers at said exchange and has adopted a proper system of accounting and employed a competent accountant, a competent claim manager and a competent and experienced underwriter; and provided, further, that if the commissioner is of the opinion that the granting of such a certificate of authority to transact business to any domestic exchange would, in any case, be prejudicial to the public interest, he may, in his discretion, refuse to issue it.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     That a fund of at least two hundred thousand dollars is in the possession of the attorney in fact or trustees duly authorized for that purpose as a surplus fund for the carrying out of reciprocal or inter-insurance contracts executed by said attorney in fact, said fund to be in cash or invested in such securities as are specified or referred to in sections sixty-three, eighty and ninety for the investment of the surplus of mutual companies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     That, except as to the kinds of insurance hereinafter specifically mentioned in paragraphs (a), (b) and (c) of this subdivision, applications have been made for insurance upon at least fifty separate risks aggregating not less than two and one half million dollars represented by executed contracts or bona fide applications to become concurrently effective upon the issuance of a certificate of authority to transact business.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     That, in the case of employers’ liability or workers’ compensation insurance, applications have been made for insurance upon at least one hundred separate risks covering a total annual pay roll of not less than two and one half million dollars, represented by executed contracts or bona fide applications to become concurrently effective upon the issuance of a certificate of authority to transact business, and arrangements satisfactory to the commissioner for reinsurance in the manner required for domestic mutual companies under section ninety-three have been made, except that a domestic exchange may, for this purpose, reinsure under the provisions of either section twenty or section ninety-four J.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     That, in the case of automobile insurance, whether written by an exchange writing automobile insurance only or in conjunction with other risks on any of the coverages permitted for any one stock or mutual insurance company, applications have been made for insurance upon at least one thousand motor vehicles, represented by executed contracts or bona fide applications to become concurrently effective upon the issuance of a certificate of authority to transact business, the premiums on which shall amount to not less than one hundred thousand dollars, and, in the case of domestic exchanges, that a deposit of not less than two hundred thousand dollars has been made with the state treasurer in the manner provided for domestic mutual companies under section ninety-three.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     That, in the case of an exchange to be authorized to transact business under clause Fifth of section forty-seven, arrangements for its protection from extraordinary losses caused by any one disaster have been made by reinsurance as provided in section twenty or section ninety-four J.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     That every subscription for insurance in the list filed with the commissioner is genuine and that all premium deposits paid thereon have actually been paid to the attorney in fact in full in cash.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     That the attorney in fact will execute no contracts of insurance save upon the express condition that the commissioner shall be the attorney for each subscriber to receive service of process in any action or proceeding against the subscriber, nor unless the subscriber shall have authorized the attorney in fact to designate the commissioner for service of process and shall have ratified any prior designations or appointments for service of process.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     Any reinsurance contracts entered into by such exchanges must be obtained in accordance with the laws of the commonwealth and in amounts adequate to satisfy the commissioner.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>