<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171" level="3">Credit Unions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20</section_number>
    <catch_line>Compensation And Expense Reimbursement; Restrictions On Loans To Directors</catch_line>
    <order_by>20</order_by>
    <text>
        No member of the board of directors shall receive compensation for his services as a member of the board or as a member of any committee. A director may be reimbursed for actual expenses incurred in the performance of responsibilities of director or as a member of any committee; provided, however, that such expenses must be itemized in writing and approved by the board of directors. Such expenses shall be reported to the members at the next annual meeting or at a special meeting called for that purpose. The officers elected by the board shall receive such compensation as it may authorize. No member of said board shall borrow from the corporation, by means of a personal loan upon his note, to an amount in excess of the total of his shares and deposits in said credit union, and the accumulated earnings standing to his credit thereon on the books of the corporation or with sufficient collateral pledged to secure the same made up of negotiable bonds or notes of the United States valued at not more than eighty percent of their market value or by the assignment of his passbook in a savings bank, cooperative bank or a federal savings and loan association, all doing business in the commonwealth or policies issued by life insurance companies authorized to transact business in this commonwealth valued at not more than their cash surrender value, unless approved by vote of two-thirds of the other members of said board.
    </text>
</law>