<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>117C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Premium Rates; Determination; Filing; Reports   </catch_line>
    <order_by>117C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The following method of determination of premium rates with respect to credit life insurance and credit accident and health insurance is required only for such insurance written in connection with obligations, other than loans secured by first liens on real property, which are subject to section twelve G of chapter two hundred and fifty-five, section ten of chapter two hundred and fifty-five B, section fourteen A of chapter two hundred and fifty-five C, or subsection C of section twenty-six of chapter two hundred and fifty-five D, for which an identifiable charge is paid by insured persons.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The following are the procedures for determining the maximum premium rates permitted to be charged any account:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Minimum loss ratio test: Benefits will be considered reasonable in relation to the premium charged if the loss ratio equals or exceeds or is reasonably expected to equal or exceed the minimum loss ratio standard specified below. The minimum loss ratio standard is:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     for credit life insurance, fifty per cent and
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     for credit accident and health insurance, fifty-five per cent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     When deviated rates are in use: If an insurer has deviated rates approved under clauses (1) and (2) of paragraph C, the reasonableness of rates for those accounts will be determined by paragraph C.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Frequency of rate review:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     The rate review will be made each year for all classes of business except for motor vehicle dealers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     The rate review will be made every three years for the motor vehicle dealers class of business.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Use of rates higher than nominal rates:
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Use of rates lower than nominal rates:
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Determination of deviated rates for all classes of business except for motor vehicle dealers:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Applied uniformly to all accounts of the insurer;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     Applied on an equitable basis approved by the commissioner to only one or more accounts of the insurer for which the experience has been more favorable or less favorable than expected; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     Applied according to a case rating procedure on file with the commissioner. An insurer electing to file a case rating procedure may either file its own plan for the approval of the commissioner or may use the standard case rating procedure specified herein by notice to him.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Determination of deviated rates for the motor vehicle dealers class of business:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     The motor vehicle dealers class of business case rate for each plan of insurance shall be the nominal rates until the effective date of the appropriate deviated case rate for each plan of insurance as provided for in subclause (ii).
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     The commissioner shall on or before October first, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine, aggregate the combined experience of all insurers for the motor vehicle dealers class of business for the three preceding calendar years, compute the appropriate deviated case rate according to paragraph D, for each plan of insurance for said class of business for all said insurers combined, according to subclause (ii) of clause (1) of said paragraph D. The commissioner shall send by first class mail, mailed on the same day, written notice to all insurers of said appropriate deviated case rate for each plan of insurance that shall apply to said class of business from ninety days after the date of the mailing of said written notice, but not later than January first, nineteen hundred and ninety, until midnight December thirty-first, nineteen hundred and ninety-two.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     The commissioner shall on or before October first, nineteen hundred and ninety-two, and each three years thereafter on or before October first, aggregate the combined experience of all insurers for the motor vehicle dealer class of business for the three preceding calendar years, compute the appropriate deviated case rate, according to said paragraph D, for each plan of insurance for said class of business for all said insurers combined according to subclause (ii) of clause (1) of said paragraph D and shall send by first class mail written notice to all insurers of said appropriate deviated case rate for each plan of insurance that shall apply to said class of business for the succeeding three calendar years beginning January first, nineteen hundred and ninety-three, and each three years thereafter on January first.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Determination of case rate:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Single account cases and multiple account cases:
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     Pooled account cases:
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     New accounts without experience:
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Calculation of case rate:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Symbols and Definitions
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     New Case Rate
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Minimum changes:
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Case rate period:
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Change of insurers:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Each insurer writing said life insurance and accident and health insurance shall report to the commissioner its claims experience and loss ratio data on said insurance separately for the motor vehicle dealers class of business and for all classes of business combined on the credit insurance supplement forms as specified by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners for inclusion in the annual statement blanks filed pursuant to section twenty-five.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The commissioner shall summarize said insurance claims experience and loss ratio data from said credit insurance supplement forms and submit such summary experience and loss ratio data to the clerk of the house of representatives who shall forward the same to the joint committee on insurance not later than the thirtieth day of September of each year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Each insurer writing said life insurance and accident and health insurance for the motor vehicle dealers class of business shall report to the commissioner its claims experience and loss ratio data on said insurance for motor vehicle dealers on said credit insurance supplement forms for the calendar years nineteen hundred and eighty-five, nineteen hundred and eighty-six, nineteen hundred and eighty-seven and nineteen hundred and eighty-eight, by a date and in a manner to be set by the commissioner, but not later than July first, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     “Account”, the aggregate credit life insurance or credit accident and health insurance coverage for a single plan of insurance and for single class of business written through a single creditor by the insurer. With the approval of the commissioner, the account may also mean the credit life insurance or the credit accident and health insurance of two or more plans of insurance or two or more classes of business of a single creditor.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     “Average Number of Life Years”, the average number of group certificates in force during the experience period, without regard to multiple coverage, times the number of years in the experience period, or some equivalent calculation, which shall be made separately for credit life insurance and for credit accident and health insurance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     “Case” a “Single Account Case”, a “Multiple Account Case” or a “Pooled Account Case” as follows:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     “Single Account Case”, an account that is at least as credible as the minimum level of credibility elected by the insurer for defining a single account case excluding all of these accounts which have been included in multiple account cases.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     “Multiple account case”, with the approval of the commissioner, two or more accounts of the same insurer having similar underwriting characteristics which are combined by the insurer for premium rating purposes, excluding all cases defined in (i) and which, when combined, are at least as credible as the minimum level of credibility elected in (i).
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     “Pooled account case”, a combination of all the insurer’s accounts of the same plan of insurance and class of business which combination has experience in this commonwealth, excluding all defined in (i) and (ii).
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     “Class of business”, a grouping of the classes of business listed below:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     credit unions;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     commercial, cooperative & savings banks;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     finance companies;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     motor vehicle dealers;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     other sales finance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     production credit associations;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     bank—agricultural loans;
        </section>
        <section prefix="viii">
    	     all others
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     “Credibility factor”, the extent to which the past experience of a case can be expected to recur in the future. For the standard case rating procedure, the credibility factor may be based on either the number of claims incurred or on the “average number of life years” for the case during the experience period using the credibility table. The insurer shall notify the commissioner in advance which method it will use to measure the credibility of all its cases in this commonwealth and may not change its method without the prior approval of the commissioner. If “claim count” or “life year” data are not available, reasonable methods of approximation approved by the commissioner may be used until such data are developed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     “Credibility table”, for purposes of the standard case rating procedure means the following table:
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     “Earned premiums at rates in use”, actual earned premiums, that is, the premiums earned at the premium rates actually charged for coverage in force during the experience period.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     “Earned premiums at the nominal rates”, the actual earned premiums adjusted to the amount which would have been earned had the premium rate charged for coverage in force during the experience period been equal to the nominal rate. Reasonable methods of approximation approved by the commissioner may be used.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     “Experience”, earned premiums, incurred claims, incurred claim count, number of life years insured, and average amount of insurance during the experience period.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     “Experience period”, the most recent period of time for which experience is reported, but not a period longer than three full years. Experience period for the motor vehicle dealer pooled account case means the most recent three calendar years for which experience is reported.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     If a case develops one hundred per cent credibility in less than three years, the experience period for that case will be the number of full years needed to develop one hundred per cent credibility.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     If a case develops the minimum credibility elected by the insurer in less than three years, the experience period for that case, at the option of the insurer, will be the number of full years needed to develop minimum credibility or three full years.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     New accounts with experience:
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     Accounts with multi-state experience:
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     “Incurred claims”, total claims paid during the experience period, adjusted for the change in the claim reserve.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     “Incurred claim count”, the number of claims incurred for the case during the experience period. This means the total number of claims reported during the experience period, whether paid or in the process of payment, plus any incurred but not reported at the end of the experience period, less the number of claims incurred but not reported at the beginning of the experience period. If a debtor has been issued more than one certificate for the same plan of insurance, only one claim is counted. If a debtor receives disability benefits, only the initial claim payment for that period of disability is counted.
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     “Loss Ratio”, the ratio of incurred claims to earned premiums at the nominal rate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="14">
    	     “Nominal rates”, the premium rates shown below for credit life insurance and credit accident and health insurance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     For credit life insurance the nominal rates per one thousand dollars of insurance in force per month shall be sixty-nine cents for single life insurance, and one hundred and sixty per cent of said single life insurance rate for joint life insurance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     For credit accident and health insurance, single premium rates for each one hundred dollars of initial insured indebtedness shall be seventy cents per annum for each of the first four years of the term of coverage, fifty cents per annum for each of the next three years of the term of coverage and twenty-five cents per annum for each year of the term of coverage thereafter. The initial insured indebtedness is the total of all monthly insurance benefits provided.
        </section>
        <section prefix="15">
    	     “Plan of insurance” unless otherwise filed and approved means
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     credit life insurance on a flat rated basis other than revolving accounts, e.g. including joint and single life coverage, decreasing and level insurance,
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     credit life insurance on a revolving account basis,
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     credit life insurance on an age-graded basis,
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     credit accident and health insurance other than on revolving accounts combining outstanding balance and single premium,
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     credit accident and health insurance on a revolving account basis.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>