<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25</section_number>
    <catch_line>Stockholders Of Public Service Corporation; Use Of Name Or Title Thereof Prohibited; Violations; Penalty; Proceedings; Injunction;  Exception</catch_line>
    <order_by>25</order_by>
    <text>
        No person owning, holding or controlling shares of stock of any public service corporation shall use any name or title or other words that, in the opinion of the department, might lead the public to believe that such person is a public service corporation or that its business is that of a public service corporation. The department may investigate and determine whether any person is violating this section; and any person violating any provision hereof shall forfeit to the commonwealth one hundred dollars a day for every day or part thereof during which such violation continues after the determination aforesaid. Any such violation shall forthwith be reported by the department to the attorney general, after said determination and notice thereof to such person. The said forfeiture may be recovered by an information or other appropriate proceeding brought in the supreme judicial or superior court in the name of the attorney general. Upon such information or other proceeding the court may issue an injunction restraining such person from further prosecution of his business within the commonwealth during the pendency of such proceeding or for all time, and may make such other order or decree as equity and justice may require. This section shall not apply to the continued use by any person of any name or title adopted prior to April seventeenth, nineteen hundred and thirteen.
    </text>
</law>