<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176Q" order_by="176Q" level="3">Commonwealth Health Insurance Connector</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commonwealth Health Insurance Connector Authority; Board; Meetings;  Executive Director</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be a body politic and corporate and a public instrumentality to be known as the commonwealth health insurance connector authority, which shall be an independent public entity not subject to the supervision and control of any other executive office, department, commission, board, bureau, agency or political subdivision of the commonwealth except as specifically provided in any general or special law. The exercise by the authority of the powers conferred by this chapter shall be considered to be the performance of an essential public function. The purpose of the authority is to implement the commonwealth health insurance connector, the purpose of which is to facilitate the availability, choice and adoption of private health insurance plans to eligible individuals and groups as described in this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     There shall be a board, with duties and powers established by this chapter, that shall govern the connector. The connector board shall consist of 10 members: the secretary for administration and finance, ex officio, who shall serve as chairperson; the director of Medicaid, ex officio; the commissioner of insurance, ex officio; the executive director of the group insurance commission; 3 members appointed by the governor, 1 of whom shall be a member in good standing of the American Academy of Actuaries, 1 of whom shall be a health economist, and 1 of whom shall represent the interests of small businesses; and 3 members appointed by the attorney general, 1 of whom shall be an employee health benefits plan specialist, 1 of whom shall be a representative of a health consumer organization, and 1 of whom shall be a representative of organized labor. No appointee may be an employee of any licensed carrier authorized to do business in the commonwealth. All appointments shall serve a term of 3 years, but a person appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve only for the unexpired term. An appointed member of the board shall be eligible for reappointment. The board shall annually elect 1 of its members to serve as vice-chairperson. Each member of the board serving ex officio may appoint a designee under section 6A of chapter 30.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     There shall be a board, with duties and powers established by this chapter, which shall govern the connector. The connector board shall consist of 11 members: the secretary for administration and finance, or a designee, who shall serve as chairperson; the director of Medicaid or a designee; the commissioner of insurance or a designee; the executive director of the group insurance commission; 4 members appointed by the governor, 1 of whom shall be a member in good standing of the American Academy of Actuaries, 1 of whom shall be a health economist, 1 of whom shall represent the interests of small businesses and 1 of whom shall be a member of the Massachusetts chapter of the National Association of Health Underwriters; and 3 members appointed by the attorney general, 1 of whom shall be an employee health benefits plan specialist, 1 of whom shall be a representative of a health consumer organization and 1 of whom shall be a representative of organized labor. No appointee shall be an employee of any licensed carrier authorized to do business in the commonwealth. All appointments shall serve a term of 3 years, but a person appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve only for the unexpired term. An appointed member of the board shall be eligible for reappointment. The board shall annually elect 1 of its members to serve as vice-chairperson.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Six members of the board shall constitute a quorum, and the affirmative vote of 6 members of the board shall be necessary and sufficient for any action taken by the board. No vacancy in the membership of the board shall impair the right of a quorum to exercise all the rights and duties of the connector. Members shall serve without pay, but shall be reimbursed for actual expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties. The chairperson of the board shall report to the governor and to the general court no less than annually.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Any action of the connector may take effect immediately and need not be published or posted unless otherwise provided by law. Meetings of the connector shall be subject to section 11A1/2 of chapter 30A; but, said section 11A1/2 shall not apply to any meeting of members of the connector serving ex officio in the exercise of their duties as officers of the commonwealth if no matters relating to the official business of the connector are discussed and decided at the meeting. The connector shall be subject to all other provisions of said chapter 30A, and records pertaining to the administration of the connector shall be subject to section 42 of chapter 30 and section 10 of chapter 66. All moneys of the connector shall be considered to be public funds for purposes of chapter 12A. The operations of the connector shall be subject to chapter 268A and chapter 268B.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The chairperson shall hire an executive director to supervise the administrative affairs and general management and operations of the connector and also serve as secretary of the connector, ex officio. The executive director shall receive a salary commensurate with the duties of the office. The executive director may appoint other officers and employees of the connector necessary to the functioning of the connector. Sections 9A, 45, 46, and 46C of chapter 30, chapter 31 and chapter 150E shall not apply to the executive director or any other employees of the connector. The executive director shall, with the approval of the board:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     plan, direct, coordinate and execute administrative functions in conformity with the policies and directives of the board;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     employ professional and clerical staff as necessary;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     report to the board on all operations under his control and supervision;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     prepare an annual budget and manage the administrative expenses of the connector; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     undertake any other activities necessary to implement the powers and duties set forth in this chapter.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>