<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175K" order_by="175K" level="3">Interstate Insurance Compact</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Rules; Uniform Standards; Operating Procedures</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The commission shall promulgate reasonable rules, including uniform standards, and operating procedures in order to effectively and efficiently achieve the purposes of this compact. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event the commission exercises its rulemaking authority in a manner that is beyond the scope of the purposes of this chapter, or the powers granted hereunder, then the action by the commission shall be invalid and have no force and effect.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Rules and operating procedures shall be made pursuant to a rulemaking process that conforms to the Model State Administrative Procedure Act of 1981 as amended, as may be appropriate to the operations of the commission. Before the commission adopts a uniform standard, the commission shall give written notice to the relevant state legislative committee in each compacting state responsible for insurance issues of its intention to adopt the uniform standard. The commission in adopting a uniform standard shall consider fully all submitted materials and issue a concise explanation of its decision.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A uniform standard shall become effective 90 days after its promulgation by the commission or a later date as the commission may determine; but, a compacting state may opt out of a uniform standard as provided in this section. All other rules and operating procedures, and amendments thereto, shall become effective as of the date specified in each rule, operating procedure or amendment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     A compacting state may opt out of a uniform standard, either by legislation or regulation duly promulgated by the insurance department under the compacting state’s administrative procedure act. If a compacting state elects to opt out of a uniform standard by regulation, it must (i) give written notice to the commission no later than 10 business days after the uniform standard is promulgated, or at the time the state becomes a compacting state; and (ii) find that the uniform standard does not provide reasonable protections to the citizens of the state, given the conditions in the state. The commissioner shall make specific findings of fact and conclusions of law, based on a preponderance of the evidence, detailing the conditions in the state which warrant a departure from the uniform standard and determining that the uniform standard would not reasonably protect the citizens of the state. The commissioner shall consider and balance the following factors and find that the conditions in the state and needs of the citizens of the state outweigh: (i) the intent of the legislature to participate in, and the benefits of, an interstate agreement to establish national uniform consumer protections for the products subject to this chapter; and (ii) the presumption that a uniform standard adopted by the commission provides reasonable protections to consumers of the relevant product.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     If a compacting state elects to opt out of a uniform standard, the uniform standard shall remain applicable in the compacting state electing to opt out until the time the opt out legislation is enacted into law or the regulation opting out becomes effective.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     If a compacting state has formally initiated the process of opting out of a uniform standard by regulation, and while the regulatory opt out is pending, the compacting state may petition the commission, at least 15 days before the effective date of the uniform standard, to stay the effectiveness of the uniform standard in that state. The commission may grant a stay if it determines the regulatory opt out is being pursued in a reasonable manner and there is a likelihood of success. If a stay is granted or extended by the commission, the stay or extension thereof may postpone the effective date by up to 90 days, unless affirmatively extended by the commission; but, a stay may not be permitted to remain in effect for more than 1 year unless the compacting state can show extraordinary circumstances which warrant a continuance of the stay, including, but not limited to, the existence of a legal challenge which prevents the compacting state from opting out. A stay may be terminated by the commission upon notice that the rulemaking process has been terminated.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Not later than 30 days after a rule or operating procedure is promulgated, a person may file a petition for judicial review of the rule or operating procedure; but, the filing of the petition shall not stay or otherwise prevent the rule or operating procedure from becoming effective unless the court finds that the petitioner has a substantial likelihood of success. The court shall give deference to the actions of the commission consistent with applicable law and shall not find the rule or operating procedure to be unlawful if the rule or operating procedure represents a reasonable exercise of the commission’s authority.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>