<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>129</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>129</order_by>
    <text>
        The following words, as used in sections one hundred and thirty to one hundred and thirty-two, inclusive, unless the context otherwise requires, or a different meaning is specifically prescribed, shall have the following meanings:— 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of insurance. 
“Fund balance”, a minimum of two hundred and fifty thousand dollars or a lesser or greater amount approved by the commissioner. 
“Municipal light board”, a municipal light board or commission, municipal gas and electric commission or similar body in a city or town having a municipal light board, gas and electric commission or similar body; the mayor or city manager as the case may be, of a city having no municipal light board, municipal gas and electric commission or similar body; or the selectmen of a town having no municipal light board, municipal gas and electric commission or similar body. 
“Municipal electric department”, an electric department or lighting plant of a city or town, which department or plant is subject to the provisions of this chapter, or a municipally or consumer-owned electric utility outside the commonwealth. Except as otherwise specifically provided, a Massachusetts municipal electric department may exercise any of its powers or authority granted in sections one hundred and twenty-nine to one hundred and thirty-two, inclusive, through its municipal light board. 
“Municipal Electric Department Self-insurance Trust Fund” or “Fund”, a trust fund established in accordance with the provisions of section one hundred and twenty-nine to one hundred and thirty-two, inclusive, to provide insurance to a group of two or more participating municipal electric departments. 
“Insurance”, formal self-insurance or commercial insurance or a combination thereof, covering risks including, without limiting the generality of the foregoing, general liability, directors and officers, and fire insurance. Insurance shall include all layers of coverage, on either a claims made or occurrence basis and reinsurance. 
“Participant”, a municipal electric department that is a member of a fund, in accordance with section one hundred and thirty, and has accepted the benefits and detriments of sections one hundred and twenty-nine to one hundred and thirty-two, inclusive; 
“Trustee”, the trustee of a fund.
    </text>
</law>