<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>69H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Energy Facilities Siting Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>69H</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     To adopt and publish rules and regulations consistent with the purposes of sections sixty-nine H to section sixty-nine Q, and to amend the same from time to time. This includes rules and regulations for the conduct of the board’s public hearings under the provisions of sections sixty-nine H1/2, sixty-nine I, sixty-nine J and sixty-nine M.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     To accept petitions for certificates of environmental impact and public need on such forms as it may prescribe, consistent with the provisions of section sixty-nine L; to conduct preliminary investigations thereon and solicit information and recommendations relating thereto; to conduct public hearings in accordance with the provisions of sections sixty-nine M and sixty-nine N and to supervise the enforcement of the terms and conditions of certificates so issued; to approve or reject petitions to construct facilities and notices of intention to construct an oil facility in accordance with the provisions of section sixty-nine J; and to accept for review and approval or rejection any application, petition, or matter related to the need for, construction of, or siting of facilities referred by the chairman of the department pursuant to section four of chapter twenty-five; provided, however, that in reviewing such application, petition, or matter, the board shall apply department and board standards in a consistent manner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Where the applicant has petitioned the board with respect to a national pollutant discharge elimination system permit, the board shall be required to make a tentative determination as to the resolution of that petition, which determination shall be included in the public notice as required by section sixty-nine M.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The board shall have the opportunity to issue orders with respect to any matter over which it has jurisdiction. Any applicant who violates any such order shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $1000 for each violation for each day that the violation persists; provided, however, that the maximum civil penalty shall not exceed $200,000 for any related series of violations.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>