<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="166" order_by="166" level="3">Telephone And Telegraph Companies, And Lines For The Transmission Of Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Underground Construction; Customer Service Facilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>22I</order_by>
    <text>
        All underground construction and conduits, conductors and associated equipment necessary to receive utility service between the utility’s service facilities referred to in section twenty-two H and the service facilities in the building or structure being served shall be deemed “customer’s service facilities”. 
To the extent required by any ordinance or by-law adopted pursuant to section twenty-two D may provide, any utility in providing underground replacement facilities for any poles and overhead wires and associated overhead structures shall install customer’s service facilities. In all other respects the provision of customer’s service facilities shall be the responsibility of the person owning, operating, leasing or renting said property, subject to applicable rules, regulations and tariffs of the utility on file with the department and to the requirements of applicable laws, ordinances and by-laws. If the person owning, operating, leasing or renting said property fails to provide such customer’s service facilities which are his responsibility prior to the time for removal of the poles and overhead wires and associated overhead structures of the utility, the engineer of the municipality shall have the authority to order the disconnection and removal of any and all overhead service wires and associated facilities supplying utility service to said property at the expense of the person owning, operating, leasing or renting said property, and the municipality shall have a claim against said person for the cost thereof and a lien against said property to secure said claim. No utility shall be in violation of any such ordinance or by-law in continuing to maintain overhead facilities necessary to serve such person during the period of such person’s failure to provide customer’s service facilities for which he is responsible and such reasonable time thereafter as may be necessary to remove such overhead facilities. No utility shall be deemed to be in violation of any law, by-law or ordinance or any obligation to the public or to any person by reason of such utility’s discontinuing service to any property in the event of failure of the person owning, operating, leasing or renting said property to provide customer’s service facilities for which he is responsible prior to the removal by any utility of its poles and overhead wires and associated overhead structures as required by any ordinance or by-law adopted pursuant to section twenty-two D of this chapter.
    </text>
</law>