<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>193F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Policy Forms; Filing With Commissioner; Approval</catch_line>
    <order_by>193F</order_by>
    <text>
        The thirty-day period specified in sections two B, twenty-two A, one hundred and eight, one hundred and thirty-two, one hundred and thirty-two B and one hundred and thirty-four may be extended by the commissioner with respect to any form required to be filed with him by said sections for an additional thirty days by giving written notice of such extension to the company filing such form before the expiration of the thirty-day period specified in said sections. At the expiration of the thirty days specified in said sections or of any extension thereof in the manner provided in this section, the form so filed shall be deemed approved unless prior to the applicable period it has been affirmatively approved or disapproved in accordance with the provisions of said sections two B, twenty-two A, one hundred and eight, one hundred and thirty-two, one hundred and thirty-two B or one hundred and thirty-four, whichever is applicable. Approval of any such form by the commissioner during the thirty days specified in said sections or under any extension authorized by this section shall constitute a waiver of any unexpired portion of the period applicable to the filing. 
To the extent that this section is inconsistent with the provisions of chapter one hundred and seventy-six M and any regulations promulgated thereunder, the provisions of said chapter one hundred and seventy-six M and any such regulations shall govern the terms, conditions, rates and all other matters concerning any policy form that is within the definition of a guaranteed issue health plan in said chapter one hundred and seventy-six M.
    </text>
</law>