<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="156D" order_by="156D" level="3">Business Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9.22</section_number>
    <catch_line>Articles Of Domestication</catch_line>
    <order_by>9.22</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     After the domestication of a foreign business corporation has been authorized as required by the laws of the foreign jurisdiction, articles of domestication shall be executed by any officer or other duly authorized representative. The articles shall set forth:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the name of the corporation immediately before the filing of the articles of domestication and, if that name is unavailable for use in the commonwealth or the corporation desires to change its name in connection with the domestication, a name that satisfies the requirements of section 4.01;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the jurisdiction of incorporation of the corporation immediately before the filing of the articles of domestication and the date the corporation was incorporated in that jurisdiction; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     a statement that the domestication of the corporation in the commonwealth was duly authorized as required by the laws of the jurisdiction in which the corporation was incorporated immediately before its domestication in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The articles of domestication shall either contain all of the provisions that subsection (a) of section 2.02 requires to be set forth in articles of organization and other desired provisions that subsection (b) of section 2.02 permits to be included in articles of organization, or shall have attached articles of organization, except that, in either case, provisions that would not be required to be included in restated articles of organization may be omitted.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The articles of domestication shall be delivered by the corporation to the secretary of state for filing and shall take effect at the effective time provided in section 1.23.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The corporation shall file a copy of the articles of domestication certified by the state secretary in the registry of deeds in each district within the commonwealth in which real property of the corporation is situated. The domestication shall not be affected by this requirement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     If the foreign corporation is authorized to transact business in the commonwealth under Part 15, its authority shall be cancelled automatically on the effective date of its domestication.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>