<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171" level="3">Credit Unions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Annual Meetings; Special Meetings; Notice; Voting</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        The annual meeting of the corporation shall be held at such time and place as the by-laws prescribe but not later than one hundred and twenty days after the close of the fiscal year. The fiscal year of every credit union shall end at the close of business on the last business day of December. Special meetings may be called at any time by a majority of the directors and shall be called by the clerk upon written application of ten or more members entitled to vote. Notices of all meetings of the corporation and of all meetings of the board of directors and of committees shall be given in the manner prescribed in the by-laws; provided, however, that all meetings of the shareholders and depositors shall be posted in a conspicuous place, for at least seven days prior to the meeting, within each office or branch office of said corporation. 
A member shall not have more than 1 vote and, after a credit union has been incorporated for a year, no member shall be entitled to vote or be a candidate for director until he has been a member for more than 3 months. An organization member or persons who are parties to a joint account may cast 1 vote on the share or deposit account at any of its meetings by a duly delegated agent or a party to the joint account. A minor shall not have the right to vote. A member may vote in person or by mail. Each credit union shall set forth in its by-laws the method of voting to be used. The voting methods shall be subject to conditions and limitations as the commissioner may establish. 
The members at each annual meeting shall elect directors, fix the maximum amount to be loaned to any one member, vote on any proposed amendment to the by-laws, approve expenses of the auditing and credit committees not otherwise approved at a special meeting and act on such matters as required under law.
    </text>
</law>