<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="166" order_by="166" level="3">Telephone And Telegraph Companies, And Lines For The Transmission Of Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22</section_number>
    <catch_line>Consent Of Municipal Officers To Construct Or Alter Lines</catch_line>
    <order_by>22</order_by>
    <text>
        A company desiring to construct a line for such transmission upon, along, under or across a public way shall in writing petition the board of aldermen of the city or the selectmen of the town where it is proposed to construct such line for permission to erect or construct upon, along, under or across said way the wires, poles, piers, abutments or conduits necessary therefor. A public hearing shall be held on the petition, and written notice of the time and place of the hearing shall be mailed at least seven days prior thereto by the clerk of the city or by the selectmen of the town to all owners of real estate abutting upon that part of the way upon, along, across or under which the line is to be constructed, as such ownership is determined by the last preceding assessment for taxation. After a public hearing as aforesaid, the board of aldermen or the selectmen may by order grant to the petitioner a location for such line, specifying therein where the poles, piers, abutments or conduits may be placed, and in respect to overhead lines may also specify the kind of poles, piers or abutments which may be used, the number of wires or cables which may be attached thereto, and the height to which the wires or cables may run. 
After the erection or construction of such line, the board of aldermen or selectmen may, after giving the company or its agents an opportunity to be heard, or upon petition of the company without notice or hearing, by order permit an increase in the number of wires or cables, and direct an alteration in the location of the poles, piers, abutments or conduits or in the height of the wires or cables. The board of aldermen or selectmen may, on written petition by two or more companies subject to this chapter, and having locations in any of the public ways of such city or town, without notice or hearing, by order transfer any such location from one of such companies to either or any of the other petitioners, or by order authorize any such company to attach its wires and fixtures to existing poles, piers or abutments of either or any of the other petitioners, or to maintain its wires or cables in the conduits of either or any of said other petitioners, or by order grant to said companies joint or identical locations for the maintenance of said existing poles, piers, abutments or conduits, to be used in common by them. The board of aldermen or selectmen may, on written petition by a company subject to this chapter having a location, or by two or more such companies having joint or identical locations, in any of the public ways of a city or town, in any case where a private way has been accepted as a public way, by order, without notice or hearing, grant a location or joint or identical locations to such company or companies for the maintenance of its or their poles, piers, abutments or conduits which were being maintained in such private way at the time of its acceptance as a public way. The board of aldermen or selectmen may, on written petition by two or more companies subject to this chapter, and after notice to abutting land owners and a hearing as hereinbefore provided, by order grant to said companies joint or identical locations for the erection or construction of poles, piers, abutments or conduits, to be owned and used in common by them. No order of the board of aldermen or selectmen shall be required for renewing, repairing or replacing wires, cables, poles, piers, abutments, conduits or fixtures once erected or constructed under the provisions of law, or for making house connections or connections between duly located conduits and distributing poles. 
The order granting a location or an alteration or transfer thereof, or authorizing an increase in the number of wires or cables or attachments, such as are hereinbefore described, shall be recorded by the city or town clerk in books kept exclusively therefor, and where notice has been given as hereinbefore provided the clerk of the city or the chairman or a majority of the selectmen shall certify on said record that the order was adopted after due notice and a public hearing as hereinbefore prescribed, and no such order shall be valid without such certificate. The company or companies in whose favor the order is made shall pay for such record the fees provided by clause (62) of section thirty-four of chapter two hundred and sixty-two. 
The board of aldermen or selectmen may under this section authorize the attachment of the wires and fixtures of a street railway or electric railroad company to the poles, piers and abutments of another owner, or the attachment of the wires and fixtures of another owner to the poles, piers and abutments of such company, and may grant joint or identical locations for the erection or construction of poles, piers, or abutments to be owned and used in common by such company and other owners, and locations for the transmission lines and telephone, signal and feed wires of such company in public ways or parts thereof, other than those public ways in which the tracks of such company are laid, and locations for additional poles to support, or alterations of locations for existing poles supporting, trolley or span wires; and all locations granted to a street railway or electric railroad company hereunder shall be subject only to revocation as provided in sections seventy-seven and eighty-two of chapter one hundred and sixty-one; but nothing contained in this section save as hereinbefore expressly set forth shall be held to apply to the poles, wires and other appliances and equipment which a street railway or electric railroad company, by a grant of location, or extension or alteration thereof, under any general or special law now or hereafter in force relating to street railways or electric railroads may be authorized to construct, maintain and operate in a public way; and no terms, restrictions and obligations, other than those imposed upon a grant of location for a street railway or electric railroad, or an extension or alteration thereof, under any general or special law now or hereafter in force relating thereto, shall be imposed upon locations granted to a street railway or electric railroad company hereunder, save locations for its transmission lines or telephone, signal or feed wires in public ways other than those public ways in which the tracks of such company are laid.
    </text>
</law>