<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175D" order_by="175D" level="3">Massachusetts Insurers Insolvency Fund</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     “Commissioner”, the commissioner of insurance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     “Covered claim”, an unpaid claim, including one for unearned premiums, which arises out of and is within the coverage of an insurance policy to which this chapter applies issued by an insurer, if such insurer becomes an insolvent insurer and (a) the claimant or insured is a resident of the commonwealth; or (b) the property from which the claim arises is permanently located in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     “Fund”, the Massachusetts Insurers Insolvency Fund created under section three.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     “Insolvent Insurer”, an insurer authorized to transact insurance in this commonwealth either at the time the policy was issued or when the insured event occurred and determined to be insolvent by a court of competent jurisdiction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     “Insurer”, any person, except as provided in the ninth paragraph of section six of chapter three hundred and sixty-two of the acts of nineteen hundred and seventy-five, who (a) writes any kind of insurance to which this chapter applies, including the exchange of reciprocal or interinsurance contracts, and (b) is licensed to transact insurance in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     “Net direct written premiums”, direct gross premiums written in the commonwealth on insurance policies to which this chapter applies, less return premiums thereon and dividends paid or credited to policy holders on such direct business. Premiums written by any insurer on policies issued to self-insurers, whether or not designated reinsurance contracts, shall be deemed net direct written premiums. For workers’ compensation policies issued with deductibles under paragraph (4) of section 25A of chapter 152, net direct written premiums shall be deemed to be an amount equal to standard premium plus any applicable all risk adjustment program amounts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     “Plan”, the plan of operation established and approved under section six.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>