<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171" level="3">Credit Unions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter the following words shall, unless the context otherwise requires, have the following meanings:— 
“Central Credit Union Fund, Inc.”, the corporation established by chapter two hundred and sixteen of the acts of nineteen hundred and thirty-two. 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of banks. 
“Corporate credit union”, a federally chartered credit union primarily serving other credit unions. A corporate credit union is primarily serving other credit unions when the total dollar amount of the shares and deposits received from other credit unions plus loans to other credit unions exceeds fifty percent of the total dollar amount of all such shares, deposits and loans. For the purposes of this definition, the term “other credit unions” shall include state and federally chartered credit unions. 
“Credit union”, a corporation organized under this chapter or corresponding provisions of earlier laws. 
“Credit union employees retirement association” or “retirement association”, the association formed pursuant to sections eighty-two to eighty-four, inclusive. 
“Dividend”, payments on shares paid from the earnings which actually have been collected during the dividend period next preceding and which remain after the deduction of all expenses, interest on deposits and shares and the amounts required to be set apart to the loan reserve and investment reserve or such dividend may be declared in whole or in part from the undivided earnings of preceding years remaining after the aforesaid deductions for such years. 
“Federal credit union”, a credit union organized under the provisions of the Federal Credit Union Act. 
“Foreign credit union”, a credit union organized under the laws of another state in the United States. 
“Interest”, earnings paid on deposits. 
“Massachusetts Credit Union Share Insurance Corporation”, the corporation established by chapter two hundred and ninety-four of the acts of nineteen hundred and sixty-one. 
“Member”, a person who holds one or more shares in the credit union. 
“Minor”, a person under eighteen years of age. 
“National Credit Union Administration” or “Administration”, the agency established by the Federal Credit Union Act to charter and regulate federal credit unions and which operates the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund. 
“Organization member”, any fraternal organization, voluntary association, partnership or corporation, having a usual place of business within the commonwealth and composed principally of individual members or stockholders who are themselves eligible to membership in a credit union or the Central Credit Union Fund, Inc. 
“Share” or “share account”, a balance which constitutes the capital of the credit union and is held by the credit union in accordance with its by-laws. The sum of all shares and share accounts constitutes the equity capital of the credit union.
    </text>
</law>