<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176Q" order_by="176Q" level="3">Commonwealth Health Insurance Connector</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Requirements For Health Insurance Plans And Stand Alone Vision And Dental Plans Offered Through Connector</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Subsection (a) effective until June 19, 2012. For text effective June 19, 2012, see below.]  (a) Only health insurance plans that have been authorized by the commissioner and underwritten by a carrier may be offered through the connector.[ Subsection (a) as amended by 2012, 118, Sec. 46 effective June 19, 2012. For text effective until June 19, 2012, see above.]  (a) Only health insurance plans and stand-alone vision or stand-alone dental plans that have been authorized by the commissioner and underwritten by a carrier may be offered through the connector.[ Subsections (b) and (c) effective until June 19, 2012. For text effective June 19, 2012, see below.]  (b) Each health plan offered through the connector shall contain a detailed description of benefits offered, including maximums, limitations, exclusions and other benefit limits.  (c) No health plan shall be offered through the connector that excludes an individual from coverage because of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, marital status, health status, personal appearance, political affiliation, source of income, or age.[ Subsections (b) and (c) as amended by 2012, 118, Sec. 47 effective June 19, 2012. For text effective until June 19, 2012, see above.]  (b) Each health plan or stand-alone vision or stand-alone dental plans offered through the connector shall contain a detailed description of benefits offered, including maximums, limitations, exclusions and other benefit limits.  (c) No health plan or stand-alone vision or stand-alone dental plans shall be offered through the connector that excludes an individual from coverage because of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, marital status, health status, personal appearance, political affiliation, source of income, or age.[ Subsection (d) effective until June 19, 2012. For text effective June 19, 2012, see below.]  (d) Plans receiving the connector seal of approval shall meet all requirements of health benefit plans as defined in section 1 of chapter 176J; provided, however, in order to encourage lower cost, high quality health benefit plans, that plans shall not be required to meet health care delivery network design provisions in any other law or regulation, and shall be free to contract on a mutually agreed basis with, or determine not to contract with, any provider for covered services; provided, however, that the contracted network meets the requirements set forth by the board of the connector.[ Subsection (d) as amended by 2012, 118, Sec. 47A effective June 19, 2012. For text effective until June 19, 2012, see above.]  (d) Health plans receiving the connector seal of approval shall meet all requirements of health benefit plans as defined in section 1 of chapter 176J; provided, however, in order to encourage lower cost, high quality health benefit plans, that plans shall not be required to meet health care delivery network design provisions in any other law or regulation, and shall be free to contract on a mutually agreed basis with, or determine not to contract with, any provider for covered services; provided, however, that the contracted network meets the requirements set forth by the board of the connector.
    </text>
</law>