<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="161B" order_by="161B" level="3">Transportation Facilities, Highway Systems And Urban Development Plans</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Limitations, Conditions, Obligations And Duties Of Authority</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The authority shall have the duty to develop, finance and contract for the operation of mass transportation facilities and equipment in the public interest consistent with the purposes and provisions of this chapter, and to achieve maximum effectiveness in complementing other forms of transportation in order to promote the general economic and social well-being of the area and of the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No real estate shall be sold unless notice thereof shall have been given to the advisory board not less than thirty days prior to the date of sale and unless the sale shall have been advertised once a week for three successive weeks prior to the date of sale in a newspaper of general circulation in the city or town in which the real property to be sold is located, such real property shall be sold to the highest bidder.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Any concession in or lease of property for a term of more than one year shall be awarded to the highest bidder therefor unless the authority shall find, subject to the approval of the advisory board, that sound reasons in the public interest require otherwise.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     No change in fares shall be effective unless submitted to the advisory board and approved by it.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     No substantial change in mass transportation service in the region constituting the authority shall be made unless notice thereof shall have been given to the advisory board at least thirty days prior to the change, and approved by said board.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The authority shall in consultation with the department prepare and annually revise its program for public mass transportation which shall include a long-range program for the construction, reconstruction or alteration of facilities for mass transportation of persons within the area constituting the authority together with a schedule for the implementation of such program and comprehensive financial estimates of costs and revenues.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The authority shall on or before October first of each year render to the governor, the secretary of transportation and construction, the regional advisory board, the clerk of the senate and the clerk of the house of representatives, a report of its operations for the preceding fiscal year, including therein a description of organization of the authority, its recommendations for legislation, and its comprehensive program for mass transportation as most recently revised.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     All current expenses of the authority shall be in accordance with an annual budget prepared by the administrator and submitted to the advisory board no later than April first of each year for the ensuing fiscal year. On or before June first the advisory board shall approve said budget as submitted or subject it to such itemized reductions therein as the advisory board shall deem appropriate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Any agreement entered into by an authority with a contiguous municipality outside of the area of such authority for service to such municipality through an agreement with a private company, shall provide for reimbursement by such municipality to an authority only for the additional expense of such service as determined by the authority. Such agreements may be for such terms, not exceeding five years, as the parties may determine, except as provided in paragraph (f) of section six. They shall not be subject to the provisions of section four of chapter forty or section thirty-one of chapter forty-four. Municipalities may appropriate from taxes or from any available funds to meet their obligations under any such contracts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Any private company lawfully providing mass transportation service in the area constituting the authority at the commencement of operations by the authority may continue so to operate the same route or routes and levels of service as theretofore, and may conduct such further operations, without a contract, as the authority subject to the approval of the department of telecommunications and energy may permit.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     As a condition of any assistance to a private carrier operating under lease, contract, or other arrangement with the Authority, the rights, benefits, and other employee protective conditions and remedies of the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964, as amended (P.L. 88-365) as determined by the Secretary of Labor, shall apply for the protection of the employees affected by such assistance. Pursuant to said Urban Mass Transportation Act, the terms and conditions of a fair and equitable employee protective arrangement pursuant to this paragraph shall be a proper subject of collective bargaining and arbitration with the labor organizations that represent such employees. Such protective arrangement shall include, without limitation, provisions for the continuing employment or reemployment of those employees who are, or may be, displaced or otherwise affected by such assistance, paid training and re-training programs, preservation of all employment and retirement rights and interest, and any other protections which are necessary or appropriate to minimize the injury to such persons, provided, however, that any such protection shall not be detrimental to the employment or retirement rights and interests of any other persons affected by such assistance. The contract, lease, or other arrangement for the granting of any such assistance to a private carrier shall specify the terms and conditions of, the protective arrangements.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>