<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176T" order_by="176T" level="3">Risk Bearing Provider Organizations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Threat Of Financial Insolvency Due To Risk Bearing Provider Organization's Alternative Payment Contracts With Downside Risk;  Notice;  Suspension Or Cancellation Of Risk Certificate;  Hearing</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 216 effective November 4, 2012.]  (a) If upon examination or at any other time the commissioner determines that the risk-bearing provider organization's existing or proposed alternative payment contracts with downside risk are likely to threaten the financial solvency of the risk-bearing provider organization, the commissioner shall provide notice to the risk-bearing provider organization.  (b) The commissioner may suspend, cancel, non-renew or refuse to issue a risk-bearing provider organization's risk certificate upon a determination that the risk-bearing provider organization has not cured a threat to financial solvency, that the risk-bearing provider organization's application for a risk certificate is incomplete or contains or is based on fraudulent information, or that the risk-bearing provider organization has otherwise failed to comply with the requirements of this chapter. The commissioner shall notify the risk-bearing provider organization and advise, in writing, of the reason for any refusal to issue or non-renew a risk certificate under this chapter. A copy of the notice shall be forwarded to the commission and center. The applicant or certified risk-bearing provider organization may make written demand upon the commissioner within 30 days of receipt of such notification for a hearing before the commissioner to determine the reasonableness of the commissioner's action. The hearing shall be held pursuant to chapter 30A.  (c) The commissioner shall not suspend or cancel a risk certificate unless the commissioner has first afforded the risk-bearing provider organization an opportunity for a hearing pursuant to chapter 30A.  (d) Upon a ruling by the commissioner to suspend or cancel a risk-I bearing provider organization's certification, a written notice shall be forwarded to the commission and the center.
    </text>
</law>