<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="166" order_by="166" level="3">Telephone And Telegraph Companies, And Lines For The Transmission Of Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions; Required Equipment And Services For Disabled Subscribers; Advisory Committee On Disabled Persons’ Accessibility To Telephone Service</catch_line>
    <order_by>15E</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The department shall provide and maintain a SCPE distribution service, and shall make such services available to any residential subscriber who is: (i) certified by the Massachusetts commission on the deaf and hard of hearing as sufficiently deaf or hard of hearing to be in need of SCPE equipment; (ii) certified by the Massachusetts commission for the blind as sufficiently visually impaired to be in need of SCPE equipment; or (iii) certified by the Massachusetts rehabilitation commission as otherwise sufficiently disabled to be in need of SCPE equipment. Each commission may designate the department to administer the certification process required under this section. For the purposes of making this certification, the respective aforementioned commissions shall require a written verification of the claimed disability by a physician, certified audiologist or optometrist, or other medical professional qualified to verify the disability claimed, and licensed to do business in the commonwealth. The department, upon the request of a certified subscriber, shall provide SCPE equipment to the requesting subscriber. The SCPE distribution service shall include the reasonable distribution and replacement of SCPE equipment free of charge, to certified subscribers subject to this subsection and subsection (c). Such service shall be provided free of charge, or at reduced rates if the department of telecommunications and cable first certifies that the requesting subscriber is unable to afford SCPE equipment at its full cost. Any reduced rate shall be in accordance with a rate schedule established by the department of telecommunications and cable.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The department and the Massachusetts commission for the deaf and hard of hearing shall review the services specified in subsection (b) and make recommendations to the department of telecommunications and cable as to whether it conforms with the provisions herein. Prior to the implementation of services under subsection (b), the department and the Massachusetts commission on the deaf and hard of hearing shall issue a request for proposals subject to the department of telecommunications and cable’s review and approval seeking competitive bids from qualified vendors to provide such services. Communications services providers shall be permitted to submit a competitive bid to provide the aforementioned services. In any rate proceeding conducted under chapter 159 in which a common carrier seeks to reflect the costs for such services in rates, the carrier shall submit to the department of telecommunications and cable information about such requests for proposals such that the department of telecommunications and cable may determine whether the carrier’s proposal would provide such services at a cost to the carrier that reflects the least cost to its ratepayers with due regard for standards of reliability and quality, consistent with the public interest.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The department shall encourage prospective vendors of telecommunications relay service to provide such service from a center located within the commonwealth using residents of the commonwealth as employees of such center. Preference in employment at such center shall be given to people with disabilities as defined by this section. Specialty types of TRS shall not be required to be provided from a telecommunications service center located in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The department and the Massachusetts commission for the deaf and hard of hearing shall review the services specified in subsection (d) and make recommendations to the department of telecommunications and cable as to whether it conforms with the provisions herein. Prior to the implementation of such services, the department and the Massachusetts commission on the deaf and hard of hearing shall issue a request for proposals subject to the department of telecommunications and cable’s review and approval seeking competitive bids from qualified vendors to provide the aforementioned services. Communication services providers shall be permitted to submit a competitive bid to provide such services. In any rate proceeding conducted under chapter 159 in which a common carrier seeks to reflect the costs for such services in rates, such carrier shall submit to the department of telecommunications and cable information about such requests for proposals such that the department of telecommunications and cable may determine whether the carrier’s proposal would provide such services at a cost to the carrier that reflects the least cost to its ratepayers with due regard for standards of reliability and quality, consistent with the public interest.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The department of telecommunications and cable, in accordance with its certification by the FCC under 47 CFR 64.604 and 64.606 shall have general oversight over all aspects of the provision of the SCPE and TRS programs, unless such certification is not renewed or is revoked. Such oversight shall include, but shall not be limited to, authority over the rates, terms, and conditions, service quality, and enforcement of federal minimum standards for the provision of such services.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Any person, firm, corporation or other entity that provides public coin or coinless telephone service or semi-public coin or coinless telephone service, shall provide and maintain its public or semi-public telephones with a minimum of 25 per cent of its public or semi-public telephones with controls for sound amplification of incoming transmission consistent with Massachusetts Architectural Access Code, as provided in 521 CMR 1.0 to 47, inclusive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     There shall be an advisory committee on accessibility to communication services for disabled persons. The advisory committee shall consist of the secretary of health and human services or his designee; the commissioner of the Massachusetts commission for the deaf and hard of hearing or his designee; the commissioner of the Massachusetts rehabilitation commission or his designee; the commissioner of the Massachusetts commission for the blind or his designee; the director of the Massachusetts office on disability or his designee; and 12 persons to be appointed by the governor, 2 of whom shall be persons who are deaf, 2 of whom shall be persons who are hard of hearing, and 2 who are blind, 2 with other significant vision impairments, 2 with impaired speech, and 2 with impaired mobility or motor skills. Each such member of the advisory committee shall serve for a term of 3 years. The chairperson of the advisory council shall be appointed by the governor and shall serve in such capacity for a term of 1 year. The advisory council shall meet at least quarterly and shall make recommendations to the department and the department of telecommunications and cable on all matters of policy related to communication services and equipment for people with disabilities.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     The department, in consultation with the department of telecommunications and cable and the advisory committee on accessibility to telephone services for disabled persons, shall promulgate necessary regulations to implement this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>