<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>48</section_number>
    <catch_line>Stock Companies; Formation; Capital; Stock; Options; Promoter  Defined   </catch_line>
    <order_by>48</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Under the first and eighth, fourth, fifth, except as otherwise provided herein, eighth, ninth, tenth or twelfth clauses, not less than two hundred thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Under the second clause, and under the first and second clauses excepting ocean marine insurance, and clause eighth, not less than three hundred thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Under the first and second clauses, under the first and seventeenth clauses, under the first, second and eighth clauses, and under the first, second, eighth and seventeenth clauses, not less than four hundred thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Under the sixth clause, not less than four hundred thousand dollars of capital; and if, under the sixth clause, insurance to insure only against sickness and against the bodily injury or death by accident of the insured is transacted, not less than one hundred thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Under the seventh, thirteenth and nineteenth clauses, not less than one hundred thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Under the eleventh clause, not less than one hundred thousand dollars of capital; and if insurance against the insufficiency of mortgages as security or against any other loss in connection with mortgages, except insurance of titles is transacted, not less than two hundred thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Under the fourteenth or fifteenth clauses, not less than five hundred thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Under the sixteenth clause, not less than four hundred thousand dollars of capital, or under the sixth and sixteenth clauses, not less than eight hundred thousand dollars.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Under two or more of clauses fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh, eighth, ninth, tenth, twelfth and thirteenth, the capital shall be the largest amount for any one of these clauses, plus one-half of the total of all other clauses listed in this paragraph which it is authorized to transact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Under the fourth, fifth, seventh, ninth, tenth, eleventh, thirteenth, and nineteenth clauses, not less than two times the amount of capital as prescribed above.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Under the first, second, eighth, twelfth, sixteenth and seventeenth clauses, not less than four times the amount of capital as prescribed above.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Under the sixth, fourteenth and fifteenth clauses, not less than six times the amount of capital as prescribed above.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the nature and type of risks a company underwrites or reinsures;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the premium volume of risks a company underwrites or reinsures;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the composition, quality, duration or liquidity of a company’s investment portfolio;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     fluctuations in the market value of securities a company holds;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the adequacy of a company’s reserves; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     size of a company’s asset valuation reserves and interest maintenance reserves.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>