<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175K" order_by="175K" level="3">Interstate Insurance Compact</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Membership; Powers And Duties; Management Committee; Legislative Committee; Recordkeeping; Liability</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     each member shall be entitled to 1 vote and shall have an opportunity to participate in the governance of the commission in accordance with the by-laws. Notwithstanding any provision herein to the contrary, no action of the commission with respect to the promulgation of a uniform standard shall be effective unless 2/3 of the members vote in favor thereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     the commission, by a majority of the members, shall prescribe by-laws necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes, and exercise the powers, of the compact, including, but not limited to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     establishing the fiscal year of the commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     providing reasonable procedures for appointing and electing members, as well as holding meetings, of the management committee;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     providing reasonable standards and procedures: (i) for the establishment and meetings of other committees, and (ii) governing any general or specific delegation of authority or function of the commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     providing reasonable procedures for calling and conducting meetings of the commission that consists of a majority of commission members, ensuring reasonable advance notice of each meeting and providing for the right of citizens to attend each meeting with enumerated exceptions designed to protect the public’s interest, the privacy of individuals, and insurers’ proprietary information, including trade secrets; the commission may meet in camera only after a majority of the entire membership votes to close a meeting en toto or in part; as soon as practicable, the commission shall make public a copy of the vote to close the meeting revealing the vote of each member with no proxy votes allowed, and shall make public votes taken during the meeting;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     establishing the titles, duties and authority and reasonable procedures for the election of the officers of the commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     providing reasonable standards and procedures for the establishment of the personnel policies and programs of the commission and, notwithstanding any civil service or other similar laws of any compacting state, the by-laws shall exclusively govern the personnel policies and programs of the commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     promulgating a code of ethics to address permissible and prohibited activities of commission members and employees; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="viii">
    	     providing a mechanism for winding up the operations of the commission and the equitable disposition of surplus funds that may exist after the termination of the compact after the payment and/or reserving of all of its debts and obligations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The commission shall publish its by-laws in a convenient form and file a copy thereof and a copy of any amendment thereto, with the appropriate agency or officer in each of the compacting states.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     one member from each of the 6 compacting states with the largest premium volume for individual and group annuities, life, disability income and long-term care insurance products, determined from the records of the NAIC for the prior year;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     four members from those compacting states with at least 2 per cent of the market based on the premium volume described above, other than the 6 compacting states with the largest premium volume, selected on a rotating basis as provided in the by-laws; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     four members from those compacting states with less than 2 per cent of the market, based on the premium volume described above, with 1 selected from each of the 4 zone regions of the NAIC as provided in the by-laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     the management committee shall have the authority and duties set forth in the by-laws, including but not limited to:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     managing the affairs of the commission in a manner consistent with the by-laws and purposes of the commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     establishing and overseeing an organizational structure within, and appropriate procedures for, the commission to provide for the creation of uniform standards and other rules, receipt and review of product filings, administrative and technical support functions, review of decisions regarding the disapproval of a product filing, and the review of elections made by a compacting state to opt out of a uniform standard; but, a uniform standard shall not be submitted to the compacting states for adoption unless approved by 2/3 of the members of the management committee;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     overseeing the offices of the commission; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     planning, implementing, and coordinating communications and activities with other state, federal and local government organizations in order to advance the goals of the commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The commission shall elect annually officers from the management committee, with each having the authority and duties specified in the by-laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The management committee may, subject to the approval of the commission, appoint or retain an executive director for such period, upon such terms and conditions and for such compensation as the commission considers appropriate. The executive director shall serve as secretary to the commission, but shall not be a member of the commission. The executive director shall hire and supervise staff as authorized by the commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commission shall establish 2 advisory committees, 1 of which shall comprise consumer representatives independent of the insurance industry, and the other comprising insurance industry representatives.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The commission may establish additional advisory committees as its by-laws may provide for the carrying out of its functions.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The commission shall maintain its corporate books and records in accordance with the by-laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commission shall defend a member, officer, executive director, employee or representative of the commission in a civil action seeking to impose liability arising out of an actual or alleged act, error or omission that occurred within the scope of commission employment, duties or responsibilities, or that the person against whom the claim is made had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of commission employment, duties or responsibilities; provided, that nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit that person from retaining his or her own counsel; and provided further, that the actual or alleged act, error or omission did not result from that person’s intentional or willful and wanton misconduct.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The commission shall indemnify and hold harmless a member, officer, executive director, employee or representative of the commission for the amount of a settlement or judgment obtained against that person arising out of an actual or alleged act, error or omission that occurred within the scope of commission employment, duties or responsibilities, or that person had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of commission employment, duties or responsibilities, if, the actual or alleged act, error or omission did not result from the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of that person.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>