<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>108I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Disability Or Long Term Care Insurance Policies; Genetic Tests;   Discrimination Based On Genetic Information   </catch_line>
    <order_by>108I</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purposes of this section the following words shall have the following meanings:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No insurer, agent or broker authorized to issue policies against disability from injury or disease or policies providing for long term care in the commonwealth shall practice unfair discrimination against persons because of the results of a genetic test or the provisions of genetic information, as defined in this section. For purposes of this section, unfair discrimination means cancellation, refusing to issue or renew, charging any increased rate, restricting any length of coverage or in any way practicing discrimination against persons unless such action is taken pursuant to reliable information relating to the insured’s mortality or morbidity, based on sound actuarial principles or actual or reasonably anticipated claim experience.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In the provision of insurance against disability from injury or disease or policies providing for long term care in the commonwealth, a company, or officer or agent thereof, or an insurance broker may ask on an application for such coverage whether or not the applicant has taken a genetic as defined in this section. The applicant is not required to answer any questions concerning genetic testing. Any application requesting this information must contain or be accompanied by language informing the applicant that the applicant is not required to answer any questions in connection with genetic testing as defined in this section and language informing the applicant that the failure to do so may result in an increased rate or denial of coverage. If the applicant chooses to submit genetic information then the insurer is authorized to use that information to set the terms of a policy provided that such information is reliable information relating to the insured’s mortality or morbidity, based on sound actuarial principles, or actual or reasonably anticipated experience. If the commissioner of insurance has reason to believe that unfair discrimination as defined in this section has occurred, and that a proceeding by the commissioner would be in the interest of the public, the commissioner shall, in accordance with chapter 176D, issue and serve upon the insurer a statement of the charges and a notice of hearing thereon. Upon a determination that the practice or act of the insurer is in conflict with the provisions of this section, the commissioner shall issue an order requiring the insurer to cease and desist from engaging in the practice or act and may order payment of a penalty pursuant to the provisions of chapter 176D.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>