<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>140</section_number>
    <catch_line>Neighborhood Net Metering Facility; Election Of Net Metering; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>140</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     If the electricity generated by the neighborhood net metering facility during a billing period exceeds its kilowatt-hour usage during the billing period, the neighborhood net metering facility shall be billed for 0 kilowatt-hour usage and the excess neighborhood net metering credits shall be credited to those customers identified by the neighborhood net metering facility as being served by the same company to which the neighborhood net metering facility is interconnected, residing in the same neighborhood in which the neighborhood net metering facility is located and having an ownership interest in the neighborhood net metering facility. The amount of the excess neighborhood net metering credits to be attributed to each such customer shall be determined by the allocation provided by the neighborhood net metering facility. Credits may be carried forward by such customers from month to month. Written notice of the identity of the customers so designated and the allocation of the credits to be attributed to such customers shall be in such form as the distribution company shall reasonably require.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The department shall adopt rules and regulations necessary to carry out this section, including, but not limited to, further defining the term “neighborhood” and limiting the number of customers that may be designated by neighborhood net metering facilities to receive neighborhood net metering credits.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>