<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>111B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Combination Policies; Issuance By Mutual Companies; Notice Of  Reduced Or Eliminated Coverages   </catch_line>
    <order_by>111B</order_by>
    <text>
        Policies issued by mutual companies under section one hundred and eleven A and persons insured under such policies and dividends and assessments thereunder shall be subject to the provisions of the second, third, fourth and fifth paragraphs of section one hundred and two B and, except as otherwise provided in said paragraphs, sections seventy-six, eighty so far as applicable, eighty-one and ninety-eight, the last paragraph of section ninety-three and so much of section eighty-three as is not inconsistent with said last paragraph of section ninety-three, relative to policies issued by mutual fire companies, persons insured under such policies and dividends and assessments thereunder. Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting, except as provided herein, any provision of law relative to the rights, powers, duties and liabilities of mutual liability companies and persons insured thereby.
In the event a company or filing or rating organization eliminates or reduces certain coverages, conditions, or definitions in such policies issued under this section, the company must attach to each of such policy a printed notice setting forth what coverages, conditions or definitions have been eliminated or reduced. If explanations of such reduced or eliminated coverages are not contained in such a printed notice attached to such policy, then such coverages, conditions or definitions shall remain in full force and effect without such reductions and eliminations.
    </text>
</law>