<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="180" order_by="180" level="3">Corporations For Charitable And Certain Other Purposes</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>17H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Public Employees; Payroll Deductions For Periodic Pass For Public Transportation</catch_line>
    <order_by>17H</order_by>
    <text>
        Deductions on pay-roll schedules may be made from the salary of any state, county or municipal or other public employee of an amount which such employee may specify in writing to any state, county, municipal or other public officer, or the head of the state, county, municipal or public department, board, commission or agency by whom or which he is employed, for the payment of the cost of a periodic pass for public transportation for such time and for such amount as the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority or any regional transportation authorities may provide. Any such authorization may be withdrawn by the employee by giving at least sixty days’ notice in writing of such withdrawal to the state, county, municipal or public officer, or the head of the state, county, municipal or public department, board, commission or agency by whom or which he is then employed. 
The state treasurer, the common paymaster as defined in section one hundred and thirty-three of chapter one hundred and seventy-five, or the treasurer of the county, municipality or other public agency by which such employee is employed, shall deduct from the salary of such employee such amount for such periodic pass as may be certified to him on the pay-roll, and transmit the sum so deducted to the treasurer of said Authority. 
This section shall be effective in any county, city or town which has accepted it in the manner provided by section two of chapter seven hundred and forty of the acts of nineteen hundred and fifty, or which accepts it in the following manner:—In a county by vote of the county commissioners; in a city having a Plan D or Plan E charter by majority vote of its city council; in any other city by vote of its city council, approved by the mayor; and in a town by vote of the board of selectmen.
    </text>
</law>