<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="161A" order_by="161A" level="3">Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bonds Secured By Trust Agreement Between Authority And Corporate Trustee</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        In the discretion of the authority such bonds or refunding bonds shall be secured by a trust agreement by and between the authority and a corporate trustee, which may be any trust company or bank having the powers of a trust company within or without the commonwealth. Either the resolution providing for the issue of bonds or such trust agreement may contain such provisions for protecting and enforcing the rights and remedies of the bondholders as may be reasonable and proper and not in violation of law, including covenants setting forth the duties of the authority in relation to the acquisition, improvement, maintenance, operation, repair and insurance of property, and the custody, safeguarding and application of all monies and may pledge or assign the revenues to be received, but shall not convey or mortgage any property. 
It shall be lawful for any bank or trust company incorporated under the laws of the commonwealth to act as depository of the proceeds of bonds or of revenues and to furnish such indemnifying bonds or to pledge such securities as may be required by the authority. Such trust agreements or bond resolution may set forth the rights and remedies of the bondholders and of the trustee, and may restrict the individual right of action by bondholders. In addition to the foregoing, such trust agreement or bond resolution may contain such other provisions, including a provision for a sinking fund, as the authority may deem reasonable and proper for the security of the bondholders. All expenses incurred in carrying out the provisions of such trust agreement or bond resolution may be treated as current expenses of the authority.
    </text>
</law>