<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="161A" order_by="161A" level="3">Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Disapproval Of Certain Health Maintenance Contracts Based On High Deductibles</catch_line>
    <order_by>16A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until June 19, 2012. For text effective June 19, 2012, see below.]  The commissioner shall not disapprove a health maintenance contract on the basis that it includes a deductible that is consistent with the requirements for a high deductible plan as defined in section 223 of the Internal Revenue Code and implementing regulations or guidelines; provided, however, that the maximum deductible shall not be greater than the maximum annual contribution to a health savings account permitted under section 223 of the Internal Revenue Code. A deductible equal to the maximum annual contribution to a health savings account shall only be approved for products which include a health savings account permitted under said section 223 of the Internal Revenue Code.
Chapter 161A: Disapproval of certain health maintenance contracts based on high deductibles
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 118, Sec. 26 effective June 19, 2012. For text effective until June 19, 2012, see above.]  The commissioner shall not disapprove a health maintenance contract: (i) if it complies with the requirements of 42 U.S.C. Sec. 18022(e); or (ii) on the basis that it includes a deductible that is consistent with the requirements for a high deductible plan as defined in section 223 of the Internal Revenue Code and implementing regulations or guidelines; provided, however, that the maximum deductible shall not be greater than the maximum annual contribution to a health savings account permitted under said section 223 of the Internal Revenue Code; and, provided further, that a deductible equal to the maximum annual contribution to a health savings account shall only be approved for products which include a health savings account permitted under said section 223 of the Internal Revenue Code.
    </text>
</law>