<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>69M</section_number>
    <catch_line>Public Hearings On Petitions; National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System Permit; Notices; Procedures; Fact Sheets</catch_line>
    <order_by>69M</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Transmission of a fact sheet to any other states whose waters may be affected by the issuance of a national pollutant discharge elimination system permit at the time of the issuance of public notice pursuant to this section and, upon request, providing such affected state with a copy of the national pollutant discharge elimination system petition and a copy of the proposed permit. Each affected state shall be afforded an opportunity to submit written recommendations to the chairman of the board and to the regional administrator of the United States Environmental Protection Agency which the board may incorporate into the permit if issued. Should the board fail to incorporate any written recommendations thus received, the board shall provide to the affected state or states and to the regional administrator a written explanation of its reasons for failing to accept any of the written recommendations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A procedure for notifying any interstate agency having water quality control authority over waters which may be affected by the issuance of a certificate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Transmission of a fact sheet at the time of issuance of the public notice to the appropriate district engineer of the Army Corps of Engineers of the national pollutant discharge elimination system petitions for discharges, other than minor discharges, into navigable waters.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     a sketch or detailed description of the location of the discharge described in the national pollutant discharge elimination system petition;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     a quantitative description of the discharge described in the national pollutant discharge elimination system petition which includes at least the following:— (a) the rate or frequency of the proposed discharge; if the discharge is continuous, the average daily flow in gallons per day or million gallons per day; (b) for thermal discharge subject to limitation under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, the average summer and winter temperatures in degrees Fahrenheit; and (c) the average daily discharge in pounds per day of any pollutants which are present in significant quantities or which are subject to limitations or prohibition under sections 301, 302, 306, or 307 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as amended, 33 U.S.C. 1251, et seq., and regulations published thereunder;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the tentative determination required under this section;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     a brief citation, including a brief identification of the uses for which the receiving waters have been classified, of the water quality standards and effluent standards and limitations applied to the proposed discharge; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     a fuller description of the procedures for the formulation of final determinations than that given in the public notice including: the required thirty-day comment period; procedures for requesting a public hearing and the nature thereof; and any other procedures by which the public may participate in the formulation of the final determinations.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>