<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>34</section_number>
    <catch_line>Town’S Authority To Operate Gas Or Electric Plant Or Community Antenna Television System</catch_line>
    <order_by>34</order_by>
    <text>
        A town may, in accordance with this chapter, construct, purchase or lease, and maintain within its limits, one or more plants for the manufacture or distribution of gas or electricity or for the operation of a community antenna television system for municipal use or for the use of its inhabitants. Such plants may include suitable land, structures and machinery and other apparatus and appliances for operating a community antenna television system or for manufacturing, using and distributing gas or electricity for said purposes. A town, engaged in the business of operating a community antenna television system, or of distributing gas or electricity, may, as a part of such business if an appropriation is made therefor, rent, lease, or sell for cash or credit at prevailing retail prices, install and service, within the territory served by such business, merchandise, equipment, utensils and chattels of any description, incidental or auxiliary to the operation of a community antenna television system, or to the use of gas or electricity distributed to its consumers or necessary or expedient in the protection or management of its property used in such business. Wherever apt, the provisions of this chapter and chapter forty-four which apply to the operation and maintenance of a municipal light plant shall apply also to the operation and maintenance of a community antenna television system.
    </text>
</law>