<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175C" order_by="175C" level="3">Urban Area Insurance Placement</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Denial Of Association; Review</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        The denial by the association of a part or all of the coverage requested by an eligible applicant, and any other decision requiring improvements to be made or loss prevention measures to be taken as a condition of providing basic property insurance shall be subject to review by the commissioner if an eligible applicant files an appeal with the commissioner within ten days of any such denial or decision. On receipt of any such appeal the commissioner shall cause an investigation of the facts to be made, shall grant all interested parties an opportunity to be heard and shall enter such finding, order or decision as he deems will best meet the purposes of this chapter. 
Any person aggrieved by any such finding, order or decision and any person aggrieved by any other rule or regulation of the commissioner made pursuant to this chapter may, within ten days of the filing of any such finding, order, decision, rule or regulation in the office of the commissioner, appeal therefrom to the superior court, for the county in which the complainant resides. The court shall, after such notice to the parties as it deems reasonable, hold a summary hearing on such appeal and shall have jurisdiction in equity to review all questions of fact and law, and to affirm or reverse such finding or order and to make any appropriate decree. The decision of the court shall be final and binding on all parties and may include such order as to costs as the court deems equitable.
    </text>
</law>