<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171" level="3">Credit Unions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>65C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Reverse Mortgages; Disbursement Of Proceeds; Program Requirements;  Written Materials Provided To Borrower; Counseling Program; Priority Of Liens</catch_line>
    <order_by>65C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A credit union may make or acquire a reverse mortgage loan, pursuant to any program for reverse mortgage loans which has been submitted to and approved by the commissioner, to the owner of real estate improved with a dwelling designed to be occupied by not more than 4 families. Each owner shall be at least 60 years of age and shall occupy the mortgaged real estate, in whole or in part. A person shall be deemed to be the owner of real estate notwithstanding that legal title thereto is held in the name of a trust if such person is the beneficiary of such trust.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     For the purposes of sections 65 to 65E, inclusive, a reverse mortgage loan shall not be considered a residential mortgage transaction, as defined in section 1 of chapter 140D or any other transaction specified in subsection (e) of section 10 of said chapter 140D. The notices and rights contained herein shall be in addition to the disclosure and rights provided in said chapter 140D, including the right of rescission in said section 10 of said chapter 140D.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The proceeds from a reverse mortgage loan shall be disbursed to the borrower, pursuant to such program, and together with unpaid interest, if any, shall become due and payable:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     at the end of a fixed term, if any;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     upon the death of the borrower;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     upon the conveyance of title to the mortgaged real estate;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     upon such borrower ceasing to occupy such real estate as a principal dwelling; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     upon default by the borrower in the performance of his obligations under the loan agreement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The commissioner shall not approve any program for reverse mortgage loans which does not include the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the type of loan, whether open-end or closed and whether a recourse or non-recourse loan;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     an applicant for the loan shall not be bound for 7 days after his acceptance, in writing, of the lender’s written commitment to make the loan;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the credit union shall obtain a written statement signed by the borrower acknowledging receipt of disclosure of all contractual contingencies which could force a sale of the mortgaged real estate;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     a provision permitting prepayment of the loan without penalty at any time before the loan becomes due and payable;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the interest rate, which may be fixed or variable, and the method of calculation thereof, shall be established at loan origination quote and, at the option of the borrower, may be contingent on the value of the mortgaged real estate at closing or at maturity or on changes in said value during the period between closing and maturity;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     the method of disbursement of the proceeds of the loan to the borrower; but, at the request of the borrower, disbursement may be made to a third party pursuant to the terms of the loan agreement;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     a copy of the form of the note and mortgage deed that will be utilized for the loan;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     a detailed description of how the plan will function; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     such other information as the commissioner may require.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Before making the loan, a credit union shall provide a prospective borrower with written materials explaining in plain language, the type of mortgage being offered and its specific terms, including but not limited to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     a schedule, if applicable, and explanation of payments to the borrower pursuant to the terms of the mortgage agreement and whether or not property taxes and insurance premiums are to be deducted;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     a schedule of outstanding debt over time, if applicable;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     repayment date, if a fixed term loan, and other provisions which cause the loan to become due and payable;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     method of repayment and schedule, if any;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     all contractual contingencies, including lack of home maintenance and other default provisions which may result in a forced sale of the mortgaged property;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     interest rate and annual percentage rate, and for a reverse mortgage loan for a specified term, total interest payable thereon;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     loan fees and charges;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     description of prepayment and, if applicable, refinancing features; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     inclusion of a statement that any such mortgage has tax and estate planning consequences and may affect levels of, or eligibility for, certain government benefits, grants or pensions, and that applicants are advised to explore such matters with appropriate authorities.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A credit union shall not make a reverse mortgage loan as provided in this section until it has received a notice, in writing, that the prospective borrower has completed a reverse mortgage counseling program which has been approved by the executive office of elder affairs and which shall include instruction on reverse mortgage loans. The counseling program shall include, but not be limited to, the subject matters contained in clauses (1) to (9), inclusive, of subsection (d), relative to all reverse mortgage loan programs approved by the commissioner pursuant to this section. For the purpose of providing such counseling, the executive office of elder affairs shall establish and maintain a list of counseling programs approved by it and shall make such list available to all credit unions and to the public.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     A reverse mortgage loan shall constitute a lien against the property securing the loan to the extent of all advances made pursuant to the reverse mortgage and all interest accrued on such advances, and the lien shall have priority over any lien filed or recorded after recordation of a reverse mortgage loan. The commissioner may adopt regulations necessary to carry out this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Sections 96 to 114A, inclusive, of chapter 140 shall not apply to a reverse mortgage loan.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>