<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171" level="3">Credit Unions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>26</section_number>
    <catch_line>Annual Reports</catch_line>
    <order_by>26</order_by>
    <text>
        Within thirty days after the last business day of December in each year, every credit union shall make to the commissioner a report in such form as he may prescribe. 
Every credit union shall be required to make an annual report to the commissioner of any loan or extensions of credit in any manner to any officer or director of the credit union. Said credit union shall also be required to make an annual report to the commissioner of any loan or extension of credit, in any manner, to an organization member, the majority interest of which is owned or controlled by an officer or director of said credit union. 
Said report to the commissioner shall consist of, but not be limited to the following: (a) the name of the officer or director to whom any such loan or extension of credit has been made or the fraternal organization, voluntary association, partnership or corporation, the majority of interest of which is owned or controlled by an officer or director of said credit union to which such loan or extension of credit has been made, (b) the original amount of the loan, (c) the date of the loan, (d) the type of loan, (e) if the loan is secured in any manner, the type of secured asset and its valuation, (f) the terms of the payment, (g) the current balance, and (h) the amount of any principal or interest payments in default, if any, and the length of such default. This report shall be deemed a public record in accordance with the provisions of section ten of chapter sixty-six.
    </text>
</law>