<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>182</section_number>
    <catch_line>Special Inducements, Etc.; Rebates; Loans In Connection With Student Loan Insurance Programs</catch_line>
    <order_by>182</order_by>
    <text>
        No company, no officer or agent thereof and no insurance broker shall pay or allow, or offer to pay or allow, in connection with placing or negotiating any policy of insurance or any annuity or pure endowment contract or the continuance or renewal thereof, any valuable consideration or inducement not specified in the policy or contract, or any special favor or advantage in the dividends or other benefits to accrue thereon; or shall give, sell or purchase, or offer to give, sell or purchase, anything of value whatsoever not specified in the policy; or shall give, sell, negotiate, deliver, issue, or authorize to issue or offer to give, sell, negotiate, deliver, issue, or authorize to issue any policy of workers’ compensation insurance, or any motor vehicle liability bond or any motor vehicle liability policy, both as defined in section thirty-four A of chapter ninety, at a rate different from that fixed, established or approved by the commissioner. No such company, officer, agent or broker shall at any time pay or allow, or offer to pay or allow, any rebate of any premium paid or payable on any policy of insurance or any annuity or pure endowment contract. Nothing in this chapter shall prevent any life company from making supplemental agreements, not specified in the policy, which give the policy owner or insured the right to borrow money from the life company in connection with a student loan insurance program, pursuant to United States Public Law 89-329, or pursuant to any similar federal statute; provided, however, that such loans are to be made, issued, assumed or guaranteed by the United States of America or any instrumentality thereof, or by any state of the United States.
    </text>
</law>