<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="161A" order_by="161A" level="3">Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35</section_number>
    <catch_line>Plans For Group, General Or Blanket Hospital, Medical, Dental Or Other Health Insurance; Employee Share Of Monthly Premium; Retirees Under The Age Of 65</catch_line>
    <order_by>35</order_by>
    <text>
        Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the authority’s percentage share of premiums for group, general or blanket hospital, medical, dental or other health insurance, either by purchase of a policy or policies from one or more insurance companies, or nonprofit hospital, medical, dental or other service corporations, including health maintenance organizations, or by means of a self insurance plan or preferred provider arrangement plan, shall be determined by the authority or, where collective bargaining is authorized, through the process of collective bargaining. The percentage share of premiums for employees of the authority to whom a collective bargaining agreement is in force, shall be the percentage share which was paid during the month that such collective bargaining agreement first went into effect and shall continue until such time as that agreement expires. 
Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, a retiree under the age of 65, in a plan for group, general or blanket hospital, medical, dental or other health insurance, either by purchase of a policy from an insurance company, or nonprofit hospital, medical, dental or other service corporation, including a health maintenance organization, or by means of a self-insurance plan or preferred provider arrangement plan of the authority, shall contribute to the total monthly premium or rate applicable to that coverage an amount which shall be not less than the current retiree share of the monthly premium or rate established as a percentage for retirees from the service of the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>