<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161" level="3">Street Railways</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificate Of Incorporation</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        When it is shown to the satisfaction of the department that the requirements of this chapter preliminary to the incorporation of a company have been complied with, and that locations have been obtained for a railway between the termini and substantially over the route set forth in the agreement of association, the clerk of the department, upon its order, shall annex to the agreement of association a certificate stating such fact. The directors shall thereupon file the agreement of association, with all the certificates annexed thereto, including the plan, if any, required by the department, in the office of the state secretary, who, upon receipt of a fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven, said state secretary, shall receive and preserve the same in form convenient for reference and open to public inspection; and shall thereupon issue a certificate of incorporation substantially in the following form: 
COMMONWEALTH OF MASSACHUSETTS. 
Be it known that whereas (names of the subscribers to the agreement of association) have associated themselves with the intention of forming a corporation under the name of the (name of company), for the purpose of locating, constructing, maintaining and operating a street railway (description of the railway as in the agreement of association), and have complied with the statutes of this commonwealth in such cases made and provided: Now, therefore, I,         , secretary of the commonwealth of Massachusetts, do hereby certify that the persons aforesaid, their associates and successors, are legally established as a corporation under the name of the (name of the company), with all the powers and privileges, and subject to all the duties, liabilities and restrictions, set forth in all general laws which now are or hereafter may be in force relating to street railway companies. 
In witness whereof, I have hereunto subscribed my official signature, and affixed the great seal of said commonwealth, this        day of         , in the year      . 
The state secretary shall sign the certificate of incorporation, and cause the great seal of the commonwealth to be thereto affixed, and such certificate shall have the force and effect of a special charter. He shall also cause a record of the certificate of incorporation to be made, and such certificate, or such record, or a certified copy thereof, shall be conclusive evidence of the existence of such corporation.
    </text>
</law>