<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176O" order_by="176O" level="3">Health Insurance Consumer Protections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25</section_number>
    <catch_line>Use And Acceptance Of Specifically Designated Prior Authorization Forms</catch_line>
    <order_by>25</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 207A effective January 1, 2014. See 2012, 224, Sec. 294.]  (a) A payer or any entity acting for a payer under contract, when requiring prior authorization for a health care service or benefit, shall use and accept only the prior authorization forms designated for the specific types of services and benefits developed under subsection (c).  (b) If a payer or any entity acting for a payer under contract fails to use or accept the required prior authorization form, or fails to respond within 2 business days after receiving a completed prior authorization request from a provider, pursuant to the submission of the prior authorization form developed as described in subsection (c), the prior authorization request shall be deemed to have been granted.  (c) The division shall develop and implement uniform prior authorization forms for different health care services and benefits. The forms shall cover such health care services and benefits including, but not limited to, provider office visits, prescription drug benefits, imaging and other diagnostic testing, laboratory testing and any other health care services. The division shall develop forms for different kinds of services as it deems necessary or appropriate; provided that, all payers and any entities acting for a payer under contract shall use the uniform form designated by the division for the specific type of service. Six months after the full set of forms has been developed, every provider shall use the appropriate uniform prior authorization form to request prior authorization for coverage of the health care service or benefit and every payer or any entity acting for a payer under contract shall accept the form as sufficient to request prior authorization for the health care service or benefit.  Nothing in this section shall prohibit a payer or any entity acting for a payer under contract from using a prior authorization methodology that utilizes an internet webpage, internet webpage portal, or similar electronic, internet, and web-based system in lieu of a paper form, provided that it is consistent with the paper form, developed pursuant to subsection (c).  (d) The prior authorization forms developed under subsection (c) shall:  (1) not exceed 2 pages;  (2) be made electronically available; and  (3) be capable of being electronically accepted by the payer after being completed.  (e) The division, in developing the forms, shall:  (1) seek input from interested stakeholders and shall seek to use forms that have been mutually agreed upon by payers and providers;  (2) ensure that the forms are consistent with existing prior authorization forms established by the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; and  (3) consider other national standards pertaining to electronic prior authorization.  (f) Nothing in this section shall limit a health plan from requiring prior authorization for services.
    </text>
</law>