<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176F" order_by="176F" level="3">Optometric Service Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        In this chapter the following words shall have the following meanings: 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of insurance. 
“Covered dependent”, a dependent for whose optometric care provision is made in a subscription certificate issued by an optometric service corporation to a subscriber. 
“Dependent”, the spouse, child or foster child of a subscriber, or an adult relative dependent upon the subscriber for his support. 
“Optometric service”, the optometric services ordinarily provided by registered optometrists in accordance with accepted practices in the community where the services are rendered. 
“Optometric service corporation”, a corporation organized as provided by the provisions of this chapter for the purpose of establishing and operating a non-profit optometric service plan. 
“Non-profit optometric service plan”, a plan operated by an optometric service corporation under the provisions of this chapter, whereby the cost of optometric service furnished to subscribers and covered dependents is paid by the corporation to participating optometrists and to such other optometrists as are provided for herein. 
“Participating optometrist”, a registered optometrist who agrees in writing with an optometric service corporation to perform optometric service for subscribers and covered dependents and to abide by the by-laws, rules and regulations of such corporation. 
“Registered optometrist”, an optometrist registered to practice optometry in the commonwealth as provided in section sixty-eight of chapter one hundred and twelve. 
“Subscriber”, a person who has subscribed to a non-profit optometric service plan and to whom a subscription certificate has been issued in accordance with the provisions of section six.
    </text>
</law>