<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>94G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Proposed Performance Program; Unit Heat Rate Audit; Public Hearing;  Periodic Report; Deductions; Fuel Charge; Base Rates; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>94G</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     At least once a year, on dates set by the department, each electric company having a fuel charge approved by the department shall file with the department and simultaneously with the attorney general a proposed performance program relating to fuel procurement and use. Such program shall describe for the time period or periods designated reasonably attainable targets which shall include a thermal efficiency target for the performance of the company, consistent with reasonable regional power exchange requirements; provided, however, that such requirements do not impede an individual utility within the regional power exchange system from producing and distributing electric power at optimum efficiency and economy in a manner not detrimental to the public interest. Such program also shall provide for the efficient and cost-effective operation of individual generating units by an electric utility company in meeting the minimum needs of each unit of said company to maintain sufficient reserves of power for purposes of reliability and efficiency. Such program also shall describe the historic data, industry standards or reports, simulation models or other information and techniques upon which projections of the company’s performance are based and shall include, as goals for individual and system plant performance, availability, equivalent availability, capacity factor, forced outage rate, heat rate on a unit by unit basis and such other factors or operating characteristics required by the department. Any such program may specify a value or a range of values for the operating characteristic in question and shall reflect operating conditions when overall performance is optimized.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The department may approve an itemized fuel charge in rates filed by electric companies to reflect changes in prudently incurred reasonable costs of fuels and power purchased by such companies. Such fuel charge may be based on reasonable estimates of the total costs of fuel to be used in generating or supplying electricity to customers and power purchased for resale to customers, as appropriate in accordance with the company’s fuel charge rate schedule, during the quarter in which the charge shall apply. The burden of proof shall be upon the utility company to demonstrate the reasonableness of energy expenses sought to be recovered through the fuel charge. The fuel charge shall be billed to all customers of the company at uniform per kilowatt-hour rates and the total amount of such costs to a customer shall be itemized on the customer’s bill. Such rates may be time-differentiated but shall not otherwise differ among classes of customers or by the amount of a customer’s usage.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The department shall from time to time review the participation of an electric company in a regional power exchange and report its findings to the clerk of the senate and the clerk of the house, along with its recommendations. The department may petition the appropriate federal regulatory authority to implement its findings and recommendations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Upon request filed by an electric company, the department may allow interim adjustments to the base rates of such company to reflect extraordinary increases in operating, maintenance or capital costs for fuel procurement or the improvement of efficiency in operating generation facilities whenever the department finds by clear and convincing evidence after a public hearing that such increased expenditures were neither incurred as a result of company imprudence nor incurred in the ordinary course of business and would result in a net reduction in the cost of electric service by virtue of a reduction in fuel or purchased power costs in excess of the costs of such increased expenditures.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The department may promulgate such rules and regulations as it deems appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section and may, after public hearing, incorporate the use of any factors, in addition to and not inconsistent with factors set forth in this section, in its considerations under any subsection hereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     For the purpose of this section, the following terms shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The department is authorized to exempt any electric or generation company or supplier from any or all of the provisions of this section upon a determination by the department, after notice and a hearing, that an alternative process or incentive mechanism is in the public interest.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>