<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176" level="3">Fraternal Benefit Societies</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Amendment Of Articles Of Incorporation</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        A domestic society may amend its articles of incorporation, constitution or laws in accordance with the provisions thereof by action of its supreme legislative or governing body at any regular or special meeting thereof, or, if its articles of incorporation, constitution or laws so provide, by referendum. Such referendum may be held in accordance with the provisions of its articles of incorporation, constitution or by-laws by the vote of the voting members of the society, by the vote of delegates or representatives of voting members, or by the vote of local lodges or branches. No amendment submitted for adoption by referendum shall be adopted unless, within six months from the date of submission thereof, a majority of all of the voting members of the society shall have signified their consent to such amendment by one of the methods herein specified. 
No amendment to the articles of incorporation, constitution or by-laws of any domestic society shall take effect unless approved by the commissioner who shall approve such amendment if he finds that it has been duly adopted and is not inconsistent with any requirement of the laws of the commonwealth or with the character, objects and purposes of the society. Unless the commissioner shall disapprove any such amendment within sixty days after the filing of same, such amendment shall be considered approved. The approval or disapproval of the commissioner shall be in writing and mailed to the secretary or corresponding officer of the society at its principal office. In case he disapproves such amendment, the reasons therefor shall be stated in such written notice. 
Within ninety days from the approval thereof by the commissioner, or from the time such amendment is considered approved, as provided in this section, all such amendments, or a synopsis thereof, shall be furnished to all members of the society either by mail or by publication in full in the official organ of the society. The affidavit of any officer of the society or of any one authorized by it to mail any amendments or synopsis thereof, stating facts which show that same have been duly addressed and mailed, shall be prima facie evidence that such amendments or synopsis thereof have been furnished the addressee. 
Every foreign or alien society authorized to do business in the commonwealth shall file with the commissioner a duly certified copy of all amendments of, or additions to, its articles of incorporation, constitution or laws within ninety days after the enactment of same. 
Printed copies of the constitution or laws, as amended, certified by the secretary or corresponding officer of the society, shall be prima facie evidence of the legal adoption thereof.
    </text>
</law>