<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>94N</section_number>
    <catch_line>Conversion To Or Merger With Domestic Mutual Insurance Company;   Provisions Of Conversion Plan   </catch_line>
    <order_by>94N</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Such plan shall be filed with the commissioner and shall be approved by him as conforming to the requirements of this section and as fair, reasonable and not prejudicial to the subscribers of such exchange or to the insuring public, after a hearing thereon for which notice was given to the exchange and its attorney-in-fact, members of the advisory committee, employees and subscribers, all of whom shall have the right to appear and be heard at the hearing.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Such plan shall be approved by vote of not less than two-thirds of the votes of the exchange’s subscribers voting thereon in person, by proxy or by mail at a meeting of subscribers called for that purpose pursuant to such reasonable notice and procedure as may be approved by the commissioner. Upon such approval, the conversion shall be effective as of the date specified in the plan. On and after such date, all the rights, franchises and interests of the exchange in and to every species of property shall be vested in the converted insurer without any deed or transfer and the converted insurer shall succeed to all the obligations and liabilities of the exchange.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     In exchange for all membership interests in the exchange, such plan shall give each eligible subscriber appropriate consideration. Said consideration shall be determinable under a fair and reasonable formula approved by the commissioner, and shall be based upon the exchange’s entire surplus as shown by the exchange’s financial statement most recently filed with the commissioner pursuant to section ninety-four I, including all voluntary reserves but excluding contingently repayable funds and outstanding guaranty capital shares at the redemption value thereof, and without taking into account the value of nonadmitted assets or insurance business in force.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Such plan shall give each eligible subscriber a preemptive right to acquire his proportionate part of all of the proposed interests in the mutual insurer within a designated reasonable period; and to apply upon the purchase thereof the amount of his consideration, as determined under paragraph (3), except that the plan may provide that a subscriber may not purchase or receive interests pursuant to this section if he has an aggregate subscription price of two thousand dollars or less and that such preemptive right shall not apply to subscribers who reside in jurisdictions in which the issuance of mutual insurance company interests is impossible, would involve unreasonable delay or would require the exchange to incur unreasonable costs; provided, however, that any such subscriber shall receive his consideration in cash. Notwithstanding the above, the commissioner shall retain the full authority to disapprove such plan in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (1).
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The subscriber eligible to participate in the distribution of consideration and to purchase interests in the converted insurer shall be the person whose name appears, on the conversion date, on the exchange’s records as a member with a right to vote and who, on both the December thirty-first immediately preceding the conversion date and the date the exchange’s advisory committee first votes to convert to mutual form, owned a policy in full force for its full basic benefits with no unpaid premium or consideration at the expiration of any applicable grace period, or which is being continued under a nonforfeiture benefit and continues to be eligible for participation in the exchange’s annual distribution of divisible surplus.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Interests in the converted insurer are to be offered to subscribers at a price not greater than to be thereafter offered under the plan to others.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Such plan shall provide for payment to each subscriber of consideration which may consist of cash, securities, a certificate of contribution, additional insurance or annuity benefits, increased dividends or other consideration or any combination of such forms of consideration.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     Such plan, when completed, shall provide for the converted insurer’s surplus to be in an amount not less than the minimum combined capital and surplus required of a new domestic mutual insurer upon initial authorization to transact like kinds of insurance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     The commissioner shall find that the exchange’s management has not, through reduction in volume of new business written, or cancellation or through any other means sought to reduce, limit or affect the number or identity of the exchange’s subscribers to be entitled to participate in such plan or to otherwise secure for the individuals comprising management any unfair advantage through such plan.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>