<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>177E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Continuing Educational Requirements</catch_line>
    <order_by>177E</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     life insurance, annuity contracts, variable annuity contracts and variable life insurance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     sickness, accident and health insurance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     all lines of property and casualty insurance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Any person holding one or more such licenses shall during the first thirty-six month period following the date of original issue of the licenses satisfactorily complete courses or programs of instruction or attend seminars equivalent to a minimum of sixty hours of instruction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Any person holding one or more of such licenses, who has complied with subsection (1), shall for each thirty-six month period satisfactorily complete courses or programs of instruction or attend seminars equivalent to forty-five classroom hours of instruction.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Any part of the life underwriting training council life course curriculum, fifty hours, health course, twenty-five hours.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Any part of the American college chartered life underwriter “CLU” diploma curriculum, thirty hours.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Any part of the Insurance Institute of America’s program in general insurance, twenty-five hours.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Any part of the American Institute for property and liability underwriters charter property casualty underwriter “CPCU” professional designation program, thirty hours.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Any part of the certified insurance counselor “CIC” program, twenty-five hours.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Any insurance course approved by the commissioner taught by an accredited college or university per credit hour granted, fifteen hours.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Any course or program of instruction or seminar developed or sponsored by an authorized insurer, recognized agents association or insurance trade association or any independent program of instruction, shall, subject to the approval of the commissioner, qualify for the equivalency of the number of classroom hours assigned thereto by the commissioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     Any correspondence course approved by the commissioner shall qualify for the equivalency of the number of classroom hours assigned thereto by the commissioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     Any part of the accredited associate in insurance “AAII”, twenty-five hours.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Persons holding resident licenses for which an examination is not required.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Nonresident producers who hold an equivalent license or licenses in their home state and have satisfied their home state’s continuing education requirements, if the home state recognizes the satisfaction of its continuing education requirements imposed upon producers from the commonwealth on the same basis.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Any limited or restricted license, issued pursuant to those sections of this chapter enumerated in subsection A. hereof, which the commissioner may exempt.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>