<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="159" order_by="159" level="3">Common Carriers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notification Of Wish Not To Receive Calls From Automatic Telephone Dialing System</catch_line>
    <order_by>19C</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person who is a customer of a common carrier and who wishes not to receive telephone calls from an automatic telephone dialing system may notify such common carrier which provides telephone exchange service that he does not wish to receive such calls. 
The department shall prescribe regulations specifying the manner in which such notification shall be given, specifying the manner in which common carriers shall make available to persons using an automatic dialing system the names and telephone numbers of persons who do not wish to receive such calls, and specifying the time at which and manner in which a subscriber may give or revoke such notification. The regulations shall require that a customer be given the opportunity to give such notification whenever a telephone is installed, and not less frequently than annually thereafter. 
A common carrier shall not make any charge to a customer for the service of listing him as not wishing to receive such calls. The costs incurred by any common carrier to administer the provisions of this section shall be borne by those persons or institutions obtaining the names and telephone numbers of those subscribers who do not wish to receive calls under a schedule to be approved by the department. 
Nothing in this section or regulation promulgated thereunder shall be deemed to impose any liability on a common carrier providing local exchange service arising or resulting from the use of an automatic dialing system except in producing or using such a system.
    </text>
</law>