<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>113S</section_number>
    <catch_line>Inspection Of Vehicles Prior To Coverage   </catch_line>
    <order_by>113S</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For purposes of this section, “existing customer” shall mean an applicant for a motor vehicle liability policy who has been insured for three years or longer without interruption under a motor vehicle liability policy or policies issued by the insurer to which the applicant’s application is submitted.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A motor vehicle liability policy shall not provide fire and theft coverage or comprehensive coverage, so-called, or collision or limited collision coverage for a private passenger motor vehicle prior to an inspection of that motor vehicle by the insurer, unless:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the motor vehicle is new;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the applicant for such coverage is an existing customer of the insurer;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the motor vehicle is already insured for such coverages with the insurer by the applicant; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     as provided in paragraph (2) of subsection (c).
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The commissioner shall promulgate regulations which shall:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     provide that insurers shall offer inspection at locations and at times reasonably convenient to the insured. Where an inspection is required pursuant to this section, it shall be conducted by the insurer or its authorized representative and shall be recorded on a form prescribed by the commissioner. Such form shall be retained by the insurer with its policy records for the insured and a copy of such form shall be made available to the insured upon request.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     provide that the inspections required in this section shall be waived under circumstances specified in the regulation. Such circumstances may include, but are not limited to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     When requiring an inspection would cause a serious hardship to the insurer, the insured or an applicant for insurance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     When the insurer has no inspection facility or authorized representative either in the city or town in which the motor vehicle is principally garaged or within five miles of the said city or town.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     provide that such inspections shall include at least the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     taking a physical imprint of the vehicle identification number of the vehicle or otherwise record the vehicle identification number in a manner satisfactory to the commissioner;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     taking two color photographs of the car at angles which show the front, back and side of the vehicle;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     recording the presence of such accessories as the commissioner shall designate; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     recording the location of and a description of existing damage to the vehicle.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A motor vehicle liability policy shall not provide fire and theft coverage or comprehensive coverage, so-called, or collision or limited collision coverage for any motor vehicle for which a salvage certificate has been issued by the registrar of motor vehicles, unless a new certificate of title has been issued pursuant to section twenty D of chapter ninety D. Notwithstanding the foregoing, any insurer, authorized to issue motor vehicle liability policies may, but shall not be compelled to, issue a special policy or endorsement providing fire and theft coverage and/or comprehensive coverage, so-called, or collision or limited collision coverage for any motor vehicle having a salvage title, on such terms and conditions and subject to such inspections as the insurer shall require.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>