<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176" level="3">Fraternal Benefit Societies</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>44</section_number>
    <catch_line>Domestic Societies; Visitation And Examination; Report And Recommendations</catch_line>
    <order_by>44</order_by>
    <text>
        The commissioner, or any person he may appoint, shall have the power of visitation and examination into the affairs of any domestic society, and he shall make such examination at least once in every three years. He may employ assistants for the purpose of such examination, and he, or any person he may appoint, shall have free access to all books, papers and documents that relate to the business of the society. The minutes of the proceedings of the supreme legislative or governing body and of the board of directors or corresponding body of a society shall be in the English language. In making any such examination the commissioner may summon and qualify as witnesses under oath and examine its officers, agents and employees or other persons in relation to the affairs, transactions and condition of the society. A summary of the report of the commissioner and such recommendations or statements of the commissioner as may accompany such report, shall be read at the first meeting of the board of directors or corresponding body of the society following the receipt thereof, and if directed so to do by the commissioner, shall also be read at the first meeting of the supreme legislative or governing body of the society following the receipt thereof. A copy of the report, recommendations and statements of the commissioner shall be furnished by the society to each member of such board of directors or other governing body.
    </text>
</law>