<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>108G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Discrimination Against Abuse Victims In Terms Of Accident Or  Sickness Insurance Policy   </catch_line>
    <order_by>108G</order_by>
    <text>
        No company, and no officer or agent thereof, and no insurance broker, shall cancel, refuse to issue or renew, or in any way make or permit any distinction or discrimination in the amount or payment of premiums or rates charged, in the length of coverage, or in any other of the terms and conditions of an individual policy of accident or sickness insurance, authorized pursuant to section one hundred and eight, or group blanket policy of accident and sickness insurance, authorized pursuant to section one hundred and ten, or a policy providing coverage against disability from injury or disease, based on information that an individual has been a victim of abuse, as defined by section one of chapter two hundred and nine A. No company, and no officer or agent thereof, and no insurance broker shall seek information that such person has been a victim of abuse as defined by said section one of said chapter two hundred and nine A. The practices prohibited under this section shall include not only those overtly discriminatory but also practices and devices which are fair in form but discriminatory in practice. Nothing in this section shall be construed as creating a special class of insureds who have been victims of abuse as defined by said section one of said chapter two hundred and nine A. Any violation of this section shall constitute an unfair method of competition or an unfair or deceptive act or practice in violation of chapters ninety-three A and one hundred and seventy-six D.
    </text>
</law>