<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="156E" order_by="156E" level="3">Benefit Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16</section_number>
    <catch_line>Timing Of Annual Benefit Report Sent To Shareholders;  Posting On Website;  Copy To State Secretary</catch_line>
    <order_by>16</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 238, Sec. 52 effective December 1, 2012. See 2012, 238, Sec. 100.]  (a) The annual benefit report shall be sent to each shareholder at the same time that the benefit corporation delivers any other annual report to its shareholders, or within 120 days following the end of the fiscal year of the benefit corporation.  (b) A benefit corporation shall post its most recent annual benefit report on the public portion of its website, if any, but the compensation paid to directors and financial, confidential or proprietary information included in the benefit report may be omitted from the benefit report as posted.  (c) If a benefit corporation does not have a website, the benefit corporation shall provide a copy of its most recent benefit report, without charge, to any person that requests a copy, but the compensation paid to directors and financial or proprietary information included in the benefit report may be omitted from the copy of the benefit report provided.  (d) The benefit corporation shall deliver a copy of the benefit report to the state secretary with its annual report required by section 16.22 of chapter 156D, but the compensation paid to directors and financial, confidential or proprietary information included in the benefit report may be omitted from the benefit report as filed. The state secretary shall charge a fee of $75 for filing a benefit report in addition to the fee required for the annual report.
    </text>
</law>