<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="166A" order_by="166A" level="3">Community Antenna Television Systems</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>License Applications, Necessity, Form, Contents, Signatures, Disclosure Of Ownership; Additional Service Areas, Addition To License</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        No such license or renewal thereof shall be issued except upon written application to the appropriate issuing authority on an application form prescribed by the department. Such form shall contain such information as the division may prescribe as to the citizenship and character of the applicant, and the financial, technical and other qualifications of the applicant to operate the system; complete information as to its principals and ultimate beneficial owners, including, in the case of corporations, all stockholders, both nominal and beneficial, owning one per cent or more of the issued and outstanding stock, and, in the case of unincorporated associations, all members and ultimate beneficial owners, however designated; complete information on the extent and quality of service, number of channels, hours of operation, variety of programs, local coverage, safety measures, installation and subscription fees; and such other information as the division may deem appropriate or necessary. Such application shall be signed by the applicant or by a duly authorized representative, evidence of whose authority shall be submitted with the application. Each applicant shall make full disclosure of the true ownership of the applicant and of the equipment to be employed in rendering service and of the source of funds for the purchase, lease, rental and installation of such equipment. Each applicant shall set forth as completely as possible the equipment to be employed, the routes of the wires and cables, the area or areas to be served, the approximate starting and completion dates of construction of the system and the date service will actually be available to the areas named. Additional areas to be served may be added by amendment to the license from time to time pursuant to regulations promulgated by the division.
    </text>
</law>