<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176E" order_by="176E" level="3">Dental Service Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        In this chapter the following words shall have the following meanings: 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of insurance. 
“Covered dependent”, a dependent for whose dental care provision is made in a subscription certificate issued by a dental service corporation to a subscriber. 
“Dependent”, the spouse, child or foster child of a subscriber. 
“Dental service”, the dental services ordinarily provided by registered dentists in accordance with accepted practices in the community where the services are rendered. 
“Dental service corporation”, a corporation organized as provided by the provisions of this chapter for the purpose of establishing and operating a non-profit dental service plan. 
“Non-profit dental service plan”, a plan operated by a dental service corporation under the provisions of this chapter, whereby the cost of dental service furnished to subscribers and covered dependents is paid by the corporation to participating dentists and to such other dentists as are provided for herein. 
“Participating dentist”, a registered dentist who agrees in writing with a dental service corporation to perform dental service for subscribers and covered dependents and to abide by the by-laws, rules and regulations of such corporation. 
“Registered dentist”, a dentist registered to practice dentistry in the commonwealth as provided in sections 45 and 48 of chapter 112 or a dentist registered in any other jurisdiction within the United States and its territories. 
“Subscriber”, a person who has subscribed to a non-profit dental service plan and to whom a subscription certificate has been issued in accordance with the provisions of section six.
    </text>
</law>