<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175J" order_by="175J" level="3">Administrative Supervision And Hazardous Financial Conditions Of Insurities</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Authority Of Administrative Supervisor</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     During the period of supervision, the commissioner or the commissioner’s designee shall serve as the administrative supervisor. The administrative supervisor may impose operating restrictions or requirements on the insurer during the period of administrative supervision which are deemed necessary for the protection of policyholders or the general public. The administrative supervisor may order the insurer to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     reduce the total amount of present and potential liability for policy benefits by reinsurance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     reduce, suspend or limit the volume of business being accepted or renewed;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     reduce general insurance and commission expenses by specified methods;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     increase the insurer’s capital and surplus;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     suspend or limit the declaration and payment of dividends by an insurer to its stockholders or to its policyholders;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     file reports in a form acceptable to the commissioner concerning the market value of an insurer’s assets;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     limit or withdraw from certain investments or discontinue certain investment practices to the extent the commissioner deems necessary;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     document the adequacy of premium rates in relation to the risks insured;
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     file, in addition to regular annual statements, interim financial reports on the form adopted by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or on such format as promulgated by the commissioner; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     cease from engaging in certain business practices which are illegal or which the administrative supervisor deems harmful to policyholders or the general public.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     In addition to the provisions of subsection (A), the administrative supervisor may provide that the insurer may not do any of the following things during the period of supervision without the prior approval of the administrative supervisor:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     dispose of, convey or encumber any of its assets or its business in force;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     withdraw any funds from its bank accounts;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     lend any of its funds;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     invest any of its property;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     transfer any of its property;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     incur any debt, obligation or liability;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     merge or consolidate with any company;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     approve new premiums or renew any policies;
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     enter into any new reinsurance contract or treaty;
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     terminate, surrender, forfeit, convert, or lapse any insurance policy, certificate or contract, except for nonpayment of premiums due;
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     release, pay or refund premium deposits, accrued cash or loan values, unearned premiums, or other reserves on any insurance policy, certificate or contract;
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     make any material change in management; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     increase salaries and benefits of officers or directors or the preferential payment of bonuses, dividends or other payments deemed preferential.
        </section>
        <section prefix="C">
    	     If the insurer is a foreign insurer the administrative supervisor’s order may be limited to the extent provided by statute.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>