<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="159A" order_by="159A" level="3">Common Carriers Of Passengers By Motor Vehicle</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Permit Required; Interstate Carriers Excepted; Compliance With Department Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        No motor vehicle shall be operated under a license issued under the provisions of this chapter without a permit from the department, except that a motor vehicle of an interstate carrier being used simultaneously in both interstate operations and intrastate operations under the operating authority of a certified intrastate carrier may be operated without such permit, provided that such motor vehicle is equipped to comply with the rules and regulations promulgated by the department governing the operation of such vehicle. Such permit shall not be issued until an inspector of the department finds that such motor vehicle, in respect to type, construction, equipment and operating condition, conforms to the rules and regulations promulgated by the department under the provisions of this chapter. The department shall charge fees for the issuance of an original permit and for the renewal thereof, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven for the filing thereof. Such permit may be revoked or suspended by the department at any time when it appears to the department that the motor vehicle covered by such permit does not conform to said rules and regulations. No other permit, license or registration shall be required for any such motor vehicle, except as provided in chapter ninety. 
The intrastate carrier, under whose certificate the interstate carrier is operating, shall be responsible and shall annually certify to the department that every motor vehicle of the interstate carrier operated under this section complies in all respects to the rules and regulations promulgated by the department.
    </text>
</law>