<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>149</section_number>
    <catch_line>Participating And Nonparticipating Policies</catch_line>
    <order_by>149</order_by>
    <text>
        A domestic life company is authorized to issue both participating and nonparticipating policies of life, endowment and accident and sickness insurance, and annuity and pure endowment contracts, but no such company shall issue any such participating policies or contracts which do not by their terms give to the holders thereof full right to participate in the accumulations of said company attributable to such business as provided in section one hundred and forty. 
Every domestic mutual and stock life company issuing both participating and nonparticipating policies or contracts shall file with the commissioner each year together with its annual statement for the year a separate calculation of its annual analysis of operations by line of business. 
A domestic life company issuing policies or contracts on the nonparticipating plan may provide therein that, in addition to the rate of interest guaranteed by the company to be paid on deferred payments of the proceeds, excess interest may be paid thereon at such rate as the company may annually declare; and the inclusion in any nonparticipating policy or contract of such provision shall not be construed to make the policy or contract participating. 
The provisions of sections ninety-four, one hundred and ten, one hundred and thirty-two D and one hundred and thirty-seven relative to membership and voting rights shall not apply to nonparticipating policies and contracts issued by a domestic mutual life company under this section, unless the domestic mutual life company elects to provide membership and voting rights in the policy or contract. 
The provisions of this section shall not apply to policies of reinsurance.
    </text>
</law>