<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>135</section_number>
    <catch_line>Corporate Retail Load Aggregators</catch_line>
    <order_by>135</order_by>
    <text>
        Any for-profit corporation, non-profit corporation, or quasi-public authority, organized pursuant to the laws of the commonwealth, is hereby authorized to establish a corporate retail load aggregator for the purpose of purchasing bulk electricity to serve affiliated corporations or affiliated business units organized pursuant to the laws of the commonwealth which are not sited within the boundaries of a municipal light department within the commonwealth. A corporate retail load aggregator shall be authorized (i) to purchase electricity from any entity authorized to sell electricity; (ii) to sell electricity at retail to any corporate affiliate or business unit located outside of the boundaries of communities served by municipal light departments within the commonwealth; and (iii) to enter into such contracts and agreements as are necessary or appropriate to provide such service. A corporate retail load aggregator shall be prohibited from engaging in the generation of electric power and from owning or operating any facilities for the transmission or distribution of electric power, with the exception of meters. 
A corporation may establish a corporate retail load aggregator upon authorization by a majority vote of its board of directors. After a corporation has voted to establish a corporate retail load aggregator, the secretary of the corporation shall forthwith transmit to the department a certified copy thereof. A corporation that has established a corporate retail load aggregator shall appoint, by a majority vote of its board of directors or, as the case may be, a manager or a managing board of the corporate retail load aggregator. Such manager or managing board shall have full charge of the operation and management of the corporate retail load aggregator; the entry into contracts and agreements pursuant to which power will be purchased and sold; the employment of attorneys, agents, and servants; the collection of bills; and the keeping of accounts. At the discretion of the corporation, corporate officials may serve as such manager or on such managing board. The compensation and term of office of such manager or managing board shall be fixed by the corporation. 
Nothing in this section shall be construed as relieving any company which provides generation, transmission, or distribution of electricity or any combination thereof, from any obligation relative to the transmission and distribution of electricity to the corporation forming a corporate retail load aggregator. 
Corporate load aggregators shall be subject to any rules and regulations promulgated by the department through existing statute or amendments thereto, including licensure requirements.
    </text>
</law>