<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>162N</section_number>
    <catch_line>Nonresident Producer Licenses</catch_line>
    <order_by>162N</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Unless denied licensure pursuant to section 162R, a nonresident person shall receive a nonresident producer license if:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the person is currently licensed as a resident and in good standing in his home state;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the person has submitted the proper request for licensure and has paid the fees prescribed by section 14;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the person has submitted or transmitted to the commissioner the application for licensure that the person submitted to his home state, or in lieu of the same, a completed uniform application; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the person’s home state awards nonresident producer licenses to residents of the commonwealth on the same basis.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commissioner may verify the producer’s licensing status through the producer database maintained by the NAIC, its affiliates or subsidiaries.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A nonresident producer who moves from 1 state to another state or a resident producer who moves from the commonwealth to another state shall file a change of address and provide certification from the new resident state within 30 days of the change of legal residence. No fee or license application is required.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Notwithstanding any other provision of sections 162H to 162X, inclusive, a person licensed as a surplus lines producer in his home state shall receive a nonresident surplus lines producer license under subsection (a). Except as provided in said subsection (a), nothing in this section otherwise amends or supersedes any provision of section 168.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Notwithstanding any other provision of sections 162H to 162X, inclusive, a person licensed as a limited line credit insurance or other type of limited lines producer in his home state shall receive a nonresident limited lines producer license, under subsection (a), granting the same scope of authority as granted under the license issued by the producer’s home state. For the purposes of this subsection limited line insurance is any authority granted by the home state which restricts the authority of the license to less than the total authority prescribed in the associated major lines pursuant to clauses (1) to (5), inclusive, of subsection (a) of section 162M.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>