<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176E" order_by="176E" level="3">Dental Service Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>By Laws; Contracts With Hospital Service Or Medical Service Corporations, Governmental Agencies Or Persons</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        The by-laws of a dental service corporation may contain any lawful provisions approved by the commissioner and shall provide that a majority of the incorporators or members of the corporation and a majority of the directors shall at all times be persons who are not providers of health services licensed under the laws of the commonwealth and that a majority of the directors shall at all times be persons who are or agree to become subscribers to the nonprofit dental service plan. The by-laws of such a corporation may define the qualifications of those persons eligible to become subscribers as provided in section five. Any such corporation may adopt such rules and regulations as may be consistent with the provisions of this chapter. 
Any dental service corporation may contract with a corporation formed under chapter one hundred and seventy-six A or under chapter one hundred and seventy-six B, or both, for the joint or cooperative administration of their affairs and for the joint or cooperative writing and issuing of subscription certificates. Such a contract shall not require that a subscriber to the dental service corporation be a subscriber to a corporation formed under chapter one hundred and seventy-six A or under chapter one hundred and seventy-six B or both. 
Any dental service corporation may join with any other dental service corporation, non-profit hospital service corporation, or medical service corporation, or all of them, organized either under the laws of the commonwealth or of any other state for the purpose of establishing or maintaining an agency or corporation designed to facilitate the provisions of dental service for residents of the commonwealth employed by firms having employees located in more than one state and may also enter into contracts with such agency or corporation or with a corporation owned by such agency or corporation for the joint or cooperative administration of business or for the joint or cooperative writing and issuing of subscription certificates to residents of the commonwealth or of any other state. 
Any dental service corporation may contract with any agency of the United States of America, of the commonwealth or of any city or town within the commonwealth for the purpose of providing dental service. Any dental service corporation may join with or contract with any person for the purpose of providing or receiving administrative or other services relating to the providing of dental services or reimbursement therefor.
    </text>
</law>