<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176" level="3">Fraternal Benefit Societies</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Admission To Membership</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        A society may admit to benefit membership any person not less than fifteen years of age, nearest birthday, who has furnished evidence of insurability acceptable to the society. Any such member who shall apply for additional benefits more than six months after becoming a benefit member shall pass an additional medical examination, or make an additional declaration of insurability, as required by the society. 
Any person admitted prior to attaining the age of majority shall be bound by the terms of the application and certificate and by all the by-laws and rules of the society, and shall be entitled to all the rights and privileges of membership therein to the same extent as though said applicant had attained said full age at the time of application. 
No society authorized to issue certificates under this chapter may refuse to admit to benefit membership any person, otherwise qualified, for the sole reason of blindness. 
A society shall specify in its laws or rules eligibility standards for each and every class of membership, the process for admission to membership, the process for admission to membership for each membership class, and the rights and privileges of each membership class, but only the benefit members shall have the right to vote on the management of insurance affairs of the society. 
Membership rights of a society are personal to the member and are not assignable. 
A society may provide in its laws or rules for grievance or complaint procedures for members.
    </text>
</law>