<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176" level="3">Fraternal Benefit Societies</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        Any incorporated society, order or supreme lodge, without capital stock, conducted solely for the benefit of its members and their beneficiaries, and not for profit, operated on a lodge system with ritualistic form of work, having a representative form of government, and which makes provision for the payment of benefits in accordance with this chapter, is hereby declared to be a fraternal benefit society. 
As used in this chapter, the following words shall have the following meanings:— 
“Benefit contract”, the agreement for provision of benefits authorized by section 17. 
“Benefit member”, an adult member who is designated by the laws of the society to be a member under a benefit contract. 
“Certificate”, any document issued as written evidence of the benefit contract. 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of insurance. 
“Fraternal benefit society or society”, an incorporated society, order or supreme lodge, without capital stock, conducted solely for the benefit of its members and their beneficiaries, and not for profit, operated on a lodge system with a ritualistic form of work, having a representative form of government, and which makes provision for the payment of benefits in accordance with this chapter. Fraternal benefit societies shall be governed by the provisions of this chapter and shall not be subjected to any provisions of chapter 176P. 
“Laws”, the society’s articles of incorporation, constitution and by-laws however designated. 
“Limited society”, a domestic society or association that meets the requirements of section 45 or section 46 as in full force and effect immediately preceding August 15, 1958 and as codified in chapter 176P. Limited societies shall not include any society defined in this section. Limited societies shall be governed by said chapter 176P and shall not be subject to this chapter as modified, amended or added after August 15, 1958. 
“Premiums”, premiums, rates, dues or other required contributions by whatever name known, which are payable under the certificate. 
“Rules”, all rules, regulations or resolutions adopted by the supreme governing body or board of directors that are intended to have general application to the members of the society.
    </text>
</law>