<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="156B" order_by="156B" level="3">Certain Business Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>91</section_number>
    <catch_line>Parties To Suit To Determine Value; Service</catch_line>
    <order_by>91</order_by>
    <text>
        If the bill is filed by the corporation, it shall name as parties respondent all stockholders who have demanded payment for their shares and with whom the corporation has not reached agreement as to the value thereof. If the bill is filed by a stockholder, he shall bring the bill in his own behalf and in behalf of all other stockholders who have demanded payment for their shares and with whom the corporation has not reached agreement as to the value thereof, and service of the bill shall be made upon the corporation by subpoena with a copy of the bill annexed. The corporation shall file with its answer a duly verified list of all such other stockholders, and such stockholders shall thereupon be deemed to have been added as parties to the bill. The corporation shall give notice in such form and returnable on such date as the court shall order to each stockholder party to the bill by registered or certified mail, addressed to the last known address of such stockholder as shown in the records of the corporation, and the court may order such additional notice by publication or otherwise as it deems advisable. Each stockholder who makes demand as provided in section eighty-nine shall be deemed to have consented to the provisions of this section relating to notice, and the giving of notice by the corporation to any such stockholder in compliance with the order of the court shall be a sufficient service of process on him. Failure to give notice to any stockholder making demand shall not invalidate the proceedings as to other stockholders to whom notice was properly given, and the court may at any time before the entry of a final decree make supplementary orders of notice.
    </text>
</law>