<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>138</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>138</order_by>
    <text>
          As used in this section and sections 139 and 140, the following words shall, unless the context otherwise requires, have the following meanings:--  "Agricultural net metering facility'', a renewable energy generating facility operated as part of an agricultural business that generates electricity that does not have a generation capacity of more than 2 megawatts and is located on land owned or controlled by the agricultural business and is used to provide energy to metered accounts of the business.  "Agriculture'', the same meaning as provided in section 1A of chapter 128; provided, however, that when necessary, the commissioner of agricultural resources shall determine if a business is an agricultural business.[ Definition of "Anaerobic digestion net metering facility'' inserted following definition of "Agriculture'' by 2012, 209, Sec. 23 effective November 1, 2012.]  "Anaerobic digestion net metering facility'', a facility that (1) generates electricity from a biogas produced by the accelerated biodegradation of organic materials under controlled anaerobic conditions; and (2) has been determined by the department of energy resources, in coordination with the department of environmental protection, to qualify under the department of energy resources regulations as a Class I renewable energy generating source under section 11F of chapter 25A.[ Definition of "Class I net metering credit'' effective until November 1, 2012. For text effective November 1, 2012, see below.]  "Class I net metering credit'', a credit equal to the excess kilowatt-hours by time of use billing period, if applicable, multiplied by the sum of the distribution company's: (i) default service kilowatt-hour charge in the ISO-NE load zone where the customer is located; (ii) distribution kilowatt-hour charge; (iii) transmission kilowatt-hour charge; and (iv) transition kilowatt-hour charge; provided, however, that this shall not include the demand side management and renewable energy kilowatt-hour charges set forth in sections 19 and 20 of chapter 25; and provided further, that credit for a Class I net metering facility not using solar or wind as its energy source shall be the average monthly clearing price at the ISO-NE.[ Definition of "Class I net metering credit'' as amended by 2012, 209, Sec. 24 effective November 1, 2012. For text effective until November 1, 2012, see above.]  "Class I net metering credit'', a credit equal to the excess kilowatt-hours by time of use billing period, if applicable, multiplied by the sum of the distribution company's: (i) default service kilowatt-hour charge in the ISO-NE load zone where the customer is located; (ii) distribution kilowatt-hour charge; (iii) transmission kilowatt-hour charge; and (iv) transition kilowatt-hour charge; provided, however, that this shall not include the demand side management and renewable energy kilowatt-hour charges set forth in sections 19 and 20 of chapter 25; and provided further, that credit for a Class I net metering facility that is not an agricultural net metering facility or that is not using solar, anaerobic digestion or wind as its energy source shall be the average monthly clearing price at the ISO-NE.  "Class I net metering facility'', a plant or equipment that is used to produce, manufacture or otherwise generate electricity and that is not a transmission facility and that has a design capacity of 60 kilowatts or less.  "Class II net metering credit'', a credit equal to the excess kilowatt-hours by time of use billing period, if applicable, multiplied by the sum of the distribution company's: (i) default service kilowatt-hour charge in the ISO-NE load zone where the customer is located; (ii) distribution kilowatt-hour charge; (iii) transmission kilowatt-hour charge; and (iv) transition kilowatt-hour charge; provided, however, that this shall not include the demand side management and renewable energy kilowatt-hour charges set forth in sections 19 and 20 of chapter 25.[ Definition of "Class II net metering facility'' effective until November 1, 2012. For text effective November 1, 2012, see below.]  "Class II net metering facility'', an agricultural net metering facility, solar net metering facility, or wind net metering facility with a generating capacity of more than 60 kilowatts but less than or equal to 1 megawatt; provided, however, that a Class II net metering facility of a municipality or other governmental entity may have a generating capacity of more than 60 kilowatts but less than or equal to 1 megawatt per unit.[ Definition of "Class II net metering facility'' as amended by 2012, 209, Sec. 25 effective November 1, 2012. For text effective until November 1, 2012, see above.]  "Class II net metering facility'', an agricultural net metering facility, an anaerobic digestion net metering facility, solar net metering facility, or wind net metering facility with a generating capacity of more than 60 kilowatts but less than or equal to 1 megawatt; provided, however, that a Class II net metering facility of a municipality or other governmental entity may have a generating capacity of more than 60 kilowatts but less than or equal to 1 megawatt per unit.  "Class III net metering credit'', a credit equal to the excess kilowatt-hours by time of use billing period, if applicable, multiplied by the sum of the distribution company's: (i) default service kilowatt-hour charge in the ISO-NE load zone where the customer is located; (ii) transmission kilowatt-hour charge; and (iii) transition kilowatt-hour charge; provided, however, that for a Class III net metering facility of a municipality or other governmental entity, the credit shall be equal to the excess kilowatt-hours multiplied by the sum of (i), (ii) and (iii) and the distribution kilowatt-hour charge; and provided further, that this shall not include the demand side management and renewable energy kilowatt-hour charges set forth in sections 19 and 20 of chapter 25.[ Definition of "Class III net metering facility'' effective until November 1, 2012. For text effective November 1, 2012, see below.]  "Class III net metering facility'', an agricultural net metering facility, solar net metering facility, or wind-net-metering facility with a generating capacity of more than 1 megawatt but less than or equal to 2 megawatts; provided, however, that a Class III net metering facility of a municipality or other governmental entity may have a generating capacity of more than 1 megawatt but less than or equal to 2 megawatts per solar net metering or wind net metering unit.[ Definition of "Class III net metering facility'' as amended by 2012, 209, Secs. 25 and 26 effective November 1, 2012. For text effective until November 1, 2012, see above.]  "Class III net metering facility'', an agricultural net metering facility, an anaerobic digestion net metering facility, solar net metering facility, or wind-net-metering facility with a generating capacity of more than 1 megawatt but less than or equal to 2 megawatts; provided, however, that a Class III net metering facility of a municipality or other governmental entity may have a generating capacity of more than 1 megawatt but less than or equal to 2 megawatts per solar net metering, anaerobic digestion net metering or wind net metering unit.  "Customer'', a customer of a distribution company that is entitled to the net metering credits, including net metering facilities.  "Neighborhood'', a geographic area including and limited to a unique community of interests that is recognized as such by residents of such area and which, in addition to residential and undeveloped properties, may encompass commercial properties.  "Neighborhood net metering credit'', a credit equal to the excess kilowatt-hours by time of use billing period, if applicable, multiplied by the sum of the distribution company's: (i) default service kilowatt-hour charge in the ISO-NE load zone where the customer is located; (ii) transmission kilowatt-hour charge; and (iii) transition kilowatt-hour charge; provided, however, that this shall not include the demand side management and renewable energy kilowatt-hour charges set forth in sections 19 and 20 of chapter 25.  "Neighborhood net metering facility'', a Class I, II or III net metering facility that: (i) is owned by, or serves the energy needs of, a group of 10 or more residential customers that resides in a single neighborhood and is served by a single distribution company; and (ii) is located within the same neighborhood as the customers that own or are served by the facility.  "Net metering'', the process of measuring the difference between electricity delivered by a distribution company and electricity generated by a Class I, Class II, Class III or neighborhood net metering facility and fed back to the distribution company.  "Net metering facility of a municipality or other governmental entity'', a Class II or III net metering facility: (1) that is owned or operated by a municipality or other governmental entity; or (2) of which the municipality or other governmental entity is assigned 100 per cent of the output.  "Renewable energy'', energy generated from any source that qualifies as a Class I or Class II renewable energy generating source under section 11F of chapter 25A; provided, however, that after conducting administrative proceedings, the department of energy resources, in consultation with the department of agriculture, may add technologies or technology categories.  "Solar net metering facility'', a facility for the production of electrical energy that uses sunlight to generate electricity and is interconnected to a distribution company.  "Wind net metering facility'', a facility for the production of electrical energy that uses wind to generate electricity and is interconnected to a distribution company.
    </text>
</law>