<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="167" order_by="167" level="3">Supervision Of Banks</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>48</section_number>
    <catch_line>Financing Of Premises Containing Lead In Paint, Plaster Or Materials</catch_line>
    <order_by>48</order_by>
    <text>
        No bank, lending institution, credit union or mortgagee pursuant to applicable law, or mortgagee doing business in the commonwealth, which for the purposes of this section shall include any bank as defined in section one and shall include any national bank, national banking association, federal savings bank, federal savings and loan association, and federal credit union, or mortgage company defined in chapter two hundred and fifty-five E shall discriminate in any manner in the financing or refinancing of the purchase, improvement, repair or maintenance of a residential premises or dwelling unit solely because the residential premises do or may contain paint, plaster, or other structural materials containing dangerous levels of lead. Any such bank, lending institution, credit union, mortgage company or mortgagee may request and receive a copy of any lead inspection report, letter of interim control, poisoning prevention management plan, letter of full compliance or order to comply issued under the provisions of section one hundred and ninety-four or one hundred and ninety-seven of chapter one hundred and eleven or regulations promulgated thereunder which is in the possession of either the loan applicant or seller, as a condition of processing or granting the loan. Nothing contained in this section shall restrict the right of any such bank, lending institution, credit union, mortgage company or mortgagee to process or deny a mortgage or loan application in accordance with accepted underwriting practices or criteria.
    </text>
</law>