<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176B" order_by="176B" level="3">Medical Service Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>By Laws; Joint Service Contracts; Preferred Provider Arrangements</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        The by-laws of a medical service corporation may contain any lawful provisions approved by the commissioner, and shall provide that a majority of the incorporators or members of the corporation and a majority of the directors shall at all times be persons who are not providers of health services licensed under the laws of the commonwealth and that a majority of the directors shall at all times be persons who are or agree to become subscribers to the nonprofit medical service plan. The by-laws of such a corporation may define the qualifications of those persons eligible to become subscribers as provided in section five. Any such corporation may adopt such rules and regulations as may be consistent with the provisions of this chapter. Such rules and regulations and any changes or amendments thereto shall be filed with the commissioner thirty days before their effective dates and shall be subject to subsequent disapproval by the commissioner. 
Any medical service corporation may contract with a corporation formed under chapter one hundred and seventy-six A for the joint or co-operative administration of their affairs and for the joint or co-operative writing and issuing of subscription certificates, and shall contract with a corporation formed under chapter one hundred and seventy-six A for the joint or cooperative administration of their affairs when acting as a carrier under chapter one hundred and seventy-six G. 
Any medical service corporation may join with any other medical service corporation organized either under the laws of the commonwealth or of any other state for the purpose of establishing or maintaining an agency or corporation designed to facilitate the provision of medical service for residents of the commonwealth employed by firms having employees located in more than one state and may enter into contracts with such an agency or corporation or with a corporation owned by such an agency or corporation for the joint administration of their business and for the joint and cooperative writing and issuing of certificates, provided that any corporation or agency which is not a nonprofit medical service corporation with which there is joint and cooperative writing and issuing of certificates shall be qualified to do business in the commonwealth. 
Any medical service corporation may contract with any agency of the United States of America, of the commonwealth or of any city or town within the commonwealth or with any corporation organized under general or special laws for any of the purposes mentioned in chapter one hundred and eighty for the purpose of providing medical service or other health services or reimbursement for such medical service or other health services. 
Any medical service corporation which contracts with any agency of the United States of America to provide benefits under Title XVIII of the Social Security Act shall require that a practitioner who participates in said program shall post, in a conspicuous place, his policy regarding the acceptance of medicare assignment, and also require that said practitioner shall inform all eligible persons of his policy regarding medicare assignment prior to the delivery of care and services. 
Other provisions of this chapter and chapter one hundred and seventy-six G notwithstanding, any medical service corporation, either individually or by contract with a corporation formed under chapter one hundred and seventy-six A, one or more hospitals licensed under chapter one hundred and eleven, one or more health maintenance organizations under chapter one hundred and seventy-six G, physicians registered under chapter one hundred and twelve and other providers of health care licensed or registered pursuant to chapter one hundred and eleven and chapter one hundred and twelve or one or more insurance companies licensed under chapter one hundred and seventy-five, may establish, maintain, operate, own or offer plans, programs or arrangements which have been approved by the commissioner under said chapter one hundred and seventy-six I. 
A medical service corporation shall not condition its willingness to allow any physician or other provider of health services to participate in a preferred provider arrangement on such physician’s or provider’s agreeing to enter into other contracts or arrangements with the medical service corporation or any other persons that are not part of or related to such preferred provider arrangement. 
The terms and conditions offered by a medical service corporation that must be met or agreed to by physicians and other providers of health services desiring to enter into a preferred provider arrangement or plan shall be fair and reasonable. No physician or other provider of health services willing to meet the reasonable terms and conditions proposed or offered in connection with such preferred arrangements shall be denied the opportunity to offer to enter into an agreement with such medical service corporation. The terms and conditions offered by a medical service corporation that must be met or agreed to by physicians and other providers of health services desiring to enter into such agreements shall be subject to the disapproval of the commissioner.
    </text>
</law>