<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>51</section_number>
    <catch_line>Stock Companies; Kinds Of Business; Power To Combine   </catch_line>
    <order_by>51</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The first and second, if authorized to transact either, or the seventeenth, if authorized to transact any one or more of the first, second and eighth clauses, provided it has a paid-up capital of not less than four hundred thousand dollars, or the first and second excepting ocean marine insurance, if authorized to transact either, provided it has a paid-up capital of not less than three hundred thousand dollars, or subdivision (d) of the second clause, if authorized to transact the first.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Any one or more of the fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh, eighth, ninth, tenth, twelfth and thirteenth, if authorized to transact any one of said clauses, provided it conforms to the requirements of section forty-eight in respect to paid-up capital.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The eighth, if authorized to transact the first.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The sixth, if authorized to transact life insurance, provided, it has a paid-up capital of not less than eight hundred thousand dollars and net cash assets over all liabilities, computed on the basis fixed by sections nine to twelve, inclusive, of not less than eight hundred thousand dollars, exclusive of said capital.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The first, if authorized to transact fire insurance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The fifth, if incorporated by special act to insure against loss or damage caused by the explosion of steam boilers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Such other form or forms of insurance coverage not included in the provisions of section forty-seven and not contrary to law as the commissioner in his discretion may authorize and license and which shall be transacted only upon such terms and conditions as he may from time to time prescribe and upon payment of the fee prescribed by section fourteen.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Deleted.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>