<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="155" order_by="155" level="3">General Provisions Relative To Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Reservation Of Corporate Name</catch_line>
    <order_by>9A</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person intending to organize a corporation under the General Laws, or any corporation organized under the General Laws intending to change its name, or any foreign corporation, as defined in subsection (a) of section 1.40 of subdivision D of Part 1 of chapter 156D, intending to make application for a certificate of authority to transact business in the commonwealth, or any foreign corporation, as so defined, authorized to transact business in the commonwealth and intending to change its name, or any person intending to organize and incorporate a foreign corporation, as so defined, and intending to have the corporation make application for a certificate of authority to transact business in the commonwealth may reserve the exclusive right to the use of a corporate name. 
The reservation shall be made by filing with the secretary of the commonwealth an application to reserve a specific corporate name, signed by the applicant, accompanied by a fee to be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven. If the name is available for corporate use, in compliance with the provisions of sections nine and ten, the secretary of the commonwealth shall reserve the name for the exclusive use of the applicant for a period of thirty days, and shall so notify the applicant in writing. 
The secretary of the commonwealth may extend the reservation for an additional thirty days upon written request of the applicant accompanied by a fee to be determined also under the aforementioned chapter seven provision.
    </text>
</law>