<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="180" order_by="180" level="3">Corporations For Charitable And Certain Other Purposes</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>17G</section_number>
    <catch_line>State, County Or Municipal Employees;  Payroll Deductions For Payment Of Service Fees To Collective Bargaining Agencies</catch_line>
    <order_by>17G</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until October 30, 2012. For text effective October 30, 2012, see below.]  Deductions on payroll schedules shall be made from the salary of any state, county or municipal employee of any amount which such employee may specify in writing to any state, county or municipal officer, or the head of the state, county or municipal department, board or commission, by whom or which he is employed or which may be specified by a collective bargaining agreement with the PCA quality home care workforce council for the payment of agency service fees to the employee organization, which, in accordance with the provisions of chapter one hundred and fifty E is duly recognized by the employer or designated by the labor relations commission as the exclusive bargaining agent for the appropriate unit in which such employee is employed. The amount of such agency service fee shall be as provided in section twelve of chapter one hundred and fifty E. Any such authorization may be withdrawn by the employee by giving at least sixty days' notice in writing of such withdrawal to the state, county or municipal officer, or the head of the state, county or municipal department, board or commission, by whom or which he is then employed, and by filing a copy thereof with the treasurer of the employee organization.[ First paragraph as amended by 2012, 189, Sec. 4 effective October 30, 2012. For text effective until October 30, 2012, see above.]  Deductions on payroll schedules shall be made from the salary of any state, county or municipal employee of any amount which such employee may specify in writing to any state, county or municipal officer, or the head of the state, county or municipal department, board or commission, by whom or which he is employed or which may be specified by a collective bargaining agreement with the PCA quality home care workforce council or a collective bargaining agreement with the department of early education and care covering family child care providers for the payment of agency service fees to the employee organization, which, in accordance with the provisions of chapter one hundred and fifty E is duly recognized by the employer or designated by the labor relations commission as the exclusive bargaining agent for the appropriate unit in which such employee is employed. The amount of such agency service fee shall be as provided in section twelve of chapter one hundred and fifty E. Any such authorization may be withdrawn by the employee by giving at least sixty days' notice in writing of such withdrawal to the state, county or municipal officer, or the head of the state, county or municipal department, board or commission, by whom or which he is then employed, and by filing a copy thereof with the treasurer of the employee organization.  The state treasurer, the common paymaster as defined in section one hundred and thirty-three of chapter one hundred and seventy-five, or the treasurer of the county or municipality by which such employee is employed shall deduct from the salary of such employee such amount of agency service fees as may be certified to him on the payroll and transmit the sum so deducted to the treasurer of such employee organization; provided that the state treasurer or county or municipal treasurer, as the case may be, is satisfied by such evidence as he may require that the treasurer of such employee organization has given to said organization a bond, in a form approved by the commissioner of revenue for the faithful performance of his duties, in such sum and with such surety or sureties as are satisfactory to the state treasurer, or the county or municipal treasurer.  The provisions of this section shall not be applicable to the city of Boston.
    </text>
</law>