<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176B" order_by="176B" level="3">Medical Service Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Grounds For Enjoining Transaction Of Business; Receivers</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        If the commissioner is satisfied, as to any medical service corporation, that (1) it has failed to comply with the provisions of its charter, or (2) it is being operated for profit, or (3) it is fraudulently conducted, or (4) its condition is such as to render its further transaction of business hazardous to the public or to its subscribers, or (5) its officers and agents have refused to submit to an examination under section nine, or (6) it has exceeded its powers, or (7) it has violated any provision of law, or (8) it has compromised, or is attempting to compromise, with its creditors on the ground that it is financially unable to pay its claims in full, or (9) it is insolvent, he may apply to the supreme judicial court for an injunction restraining it from further proceeding with its business. 
If the right of any person or group of persons to become a participating physician, chiropractor, or nurse midwife, as defined in section one, is denied because of arbitrary or unfair discrimination, any such person or group of persons so aggrieved may apply to the supreme judicial court for an injunction restraining such corporation from further proceeding with its business. 
The court may, after application by the commissioner or any person or group of persons aggrieved as aforesaid, forthwith issue a temporary injunction restraining the transaction of any business, and it may, after a full hearing, make the injunction permanent, and appoint one or more receivers to take possession of the books, papers, moneys and other assets of the corporation, settle its affairs, and distribute its funds to those entitled thereto, subject to such rules and orders as the court may prescribe.
    </text>
</law>