<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="172" order_by="172" level="3">Trust Companies</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>36</section_number>
    <catch_line>Consolidation Or Merger; Purchase, Sale Or Exchange Of Assets; Conversion</catch_line>
    <order_by>36</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     any trust company, any banking company, or any national banking association engaged in the business of banking in the commonwealth may, upon compliance with the provisions of section seventy-eight of chapter one hundred and fifty-six B, which are hereby made applicable in all such cases, and subject, as to any such trust company or banking company, to the provisions of section eighty-five of chapter one hundred and fifty-six B as modified for the purposes of this section by the provisions hereof, consolidate or merge into any trust company. A request for approval by the commissioner of such a consolidation or merger shall be accompanied by an investigation fee, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     any trust company or banking company may, subject to the provisions of sections seventy-five and seventy-six of chapter one hundred and fifty-six B as modified for the purpose of this section by the provisions hereof, or any such national banking association may sell or exchange all or substantially all of its property and assets to or with any trust company, and any trust company may purchase all or substantially all of the assets of any trust company or any banking company of any such national banking association. A request for approval by the commissioner pursuant to this clause shall be accompanied by an investigation fee, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     by vote, at a meeting duly called for the purpose, of two-thirds of each class of its stock outstanding and entitled to vote and upon execution by a majority of its directors in form satisfactory to the commissioner of an agreement of association, an organization certificate and such other instruments as the commissioner shall prescribe, any such national banking association having an unimpaired capital stock sufficient in value or amount to satisfy the provisions of section five may, upon approval by the board of bank incorporation, be converted into a trust company and shall not, in connection with or upon such conversion, be subject to the requirements of this chapter with respect to the organization and commencement of business of trust companies; provided, however, that such conversion shall not be in contravention of the laws of the United States.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     any one or more such trust companies may, upon compliance with the provisions of section seventy-eight of chapter one hundred and fifty-six B, which are hereby made applicable in all such cases and subject as to any such trust company to the provisions of section eighty-five of chapter one hundred and fifty-six B as modified for the purposes of this section by the provisions hereof, consolidate or merge into any single state or federally-chartered stock corporation. A request for approval by the commissioner of such a consolidation or merger shall be accompanied by an investigation fee, the amount of which shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of section three B of chapter seven. A certificate under the hands of the presidents and clerks or other duly authorized officers of all merging or consolidating corporations setting forth that each corporation, respectively, has complied with the requirements of this section shall be submitted to the commissioner. No such transaction under this section shall be consummated until arrangements satisfactory to any excess deposit insurer of each such bank have been made and notice thereof has been received by the commissioner. The offices and depots of any such corporation merged or consolidated under this section may be maintained as branch offices or depots, respectively, of the continuing institution with the written permission of and under such conditions, if any, as may be approved by the commissioner.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>