<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171" level="3">Credit Unions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>80</section_number>
    <catch_line>Foreign Credit Unions; Consent For Incorporation</catch_line>
    <order_by>80</order_by>
    <text>
        Any credit union operating under a charter other than one issued by the commonwealth and having a usual place of business therein may, if authorized by a vote of at least a majority of its members present and voting at a meeting specially called for that purpose, make application to the commissioner for consent for incorporation under this chapter. Said commissioner may grant his consent to such incorporation when satisfied that the assets of such credit union qualify for investment by a credit union incorporated under this chapter. If any of the assets of the applicant credit union do not qualify as legal investments for a credit union incorporated under this chapter, such consent may nevertheless be given, subject to such terms with respect to the time in which the same shall be disposed of or converted into legal assets as the commissioner may impose. Upon the issuing by the state secretary of the certificate of incorporation, all of the assets of the applicant credit union shall be transferred to and vested in the credit union so incorporated, to the same extent as would result from a merger of the applicant credit union and the new credit union under section seventy-eight. The newly incorporated credit union shall thereupon issue its shares, in the same amount and to the same persons, in satisfaction of the shares of the applicant credit union, and assume the deposit and other liabilities thereof. Thereupon the charter of the applicant credit union shall be surrendered to the issuing authority for cancellation by it and the new credit union shall be operated under and governed by this chapter.
    </text>
</law>