<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="174B" order_by="174B" level="3">Regulation Of Automobile Clubs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        In this chapter, unless otherwise expressly provided or the context otherwise provides, the following words and phrases shall have the following meanings: 
“Automobile Club”, any person who in consideration of dues, assessments, or periodic payments of money, promises its members or subscribers to assist them in matters relating to travel and the operation, the use and maintenance of a motor vehicle and the supplying of services which, by way of illustration and not by way of limitation, may include such services as community traffic safety service, travel and touring service, theft or reward service, map service, towing service, emergency road service, bail bond service, legal fee reimbursement service in the defense of traffic offenses, and the participation in an accident and sickness or death insurance benefit program. 
“Person”, any person, firm, partnership, corporation or association which conducts an automobile club service business within the commonwealth. 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of insurance. 
“Club agent”, any person other than the automobile club itself, who acts or aids in any manner in the solicitation, delivery or negotiation of any service contract or of the renewal or continuance thereof; provided, however, that any person performing only work of a clerical nature in the office of the automobile club shall not be deemed to be a club agent. 
“Service contract”, any agreement whereby an automobile club, for a consideration, promises to render, furnish or procure specified services, procure or to reimburse club members therefor.
    </text>
</law>