<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>110E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Standards For Disclosure Of Contents And For Advertising Of  Policies; Rules And Regulations; Enforcement Procedures And Penalties   </catch_line>
    <order_by>110E</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     reasonable standardization and simplification of coverages to facilitate understanding and comparisons;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     elimination of provisions which may be misleading or unreasonably confusing, in connection either with the purchase of such insurance or with the settlement of claims;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     elimination of deceptive practices in connection with the sale of such insurance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     elimination of provisions which may be contrary to the health care needs of the public;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     elimination of coverages which are so limited in scope as to be of no substantial economic value to the holders thereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Words, phrases or illustrations shall not be used in a manner which misleads or has the capacity and tendency to deceive as to the extent of any policy benefit payable, loss covered or premium payable. An advertisement relating to any policy benefit payable, loss covered or premium payable shall be sufficiently complete and clear as to avoid deception or the capacity and tendency to deceive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     When an advertisement refers to any dollar amount, period of time for which any benefit is payable, cost of policy, or specific policy benefit or the loss for which such benefit is payable, it shall also disclose those exceptions, reductions and limitations affecting the basic provisions of the policy without which the advertisement would have the capacity and tendency to mislead or deceive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     An advertisement which refers to the right to renew, cancel or terminate a policy, or which refers to a policy benefit, or which states or illustrates time or age in connection with eligibility of applicants or the right to continue a policy, shall disclose the provisions relating to the right to renew, cancel and terminate and any modification of benefits, losses covered or premiums because of age or for other reasons, in such manner as not to minimize or render obscure the qualifying conditions.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     All information required to be disclosed shall be set out conspicuously and in close conjunction with the statements to which such information relates or under appropriate captions of such prominence that it shall not be minimized, rendered obscure or presented in an ambiguous fashion or intermingled with the context of the advertisements so as to be confusing or misleading.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Testimonials used in advertisements must be genuine, represent the current opinion of the author, be applicable to the policy advertised and be accurately reproduced. The insurer, in using a testimonial, makes as its own all of the statements contained therein.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     An advertisement relating to the dollar amounts of claims paid, the number of persons insured, or similar statistical information relating to any insurer or policy shall not be used unless it accurately reflects all of the relevant facts. Such an advertisement shall not imply that such statistics are derived from the policy advertised unless such is the fact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     When a choice of the amount of benefits is referred to, an advertisement shall disclose that the amount of benefits provided depends upon the plan selected and that the premium will vary with the amount of the benefits.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     When an advertisement refers to various benefits which may be contained in two or more policies, other than group master policies, the advertisement shall disclose that such benefits are provided only through a combination of such policies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     An advertisement shall not directly or indirectly make unfair or incomplete comparisons of policies or benefits or otherwise falsely disparage competitors, their policies, services or business methods.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     The identity of the insurer shall be made clear in all of its advertisements. An advertisement shall not use a trade name, service mark, slogan, symbol or other device which has the capacity and tendency to mislead or deceive as to the true identity of the insurer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     An advertisement of a particular policy shall not state or imply that prospective policyholders become group or quasi-group members and, as such, enjoy special rates or underwriting privileges, unless such is the fact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     An advertisement shall not state or imply that a particular policy or combination of policies is an introductory, initial or special offer and that the applicant will receive advantages by accepting the offer, unless such is the fact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     An advertisement shall not state or imply that an insurer or a policy has been approved or an insurer’s financial condition has been examined and found to be satisfactory by a governmental agency, whether or not such is the fact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="14">
    	     An advertisement shall not state or imply that an insurer or a policy has been approved or endorsed by an individual, group of individuals, society, association or other organization, unless such is the fact.
        </section>
        <section prefix="15">
    	     An advertisement shall not contain untrue statements with respect to the time within which claims are paid or statements which imply that claim settlements will be liberal or generous beyond the terms of the policy.
        </section>
        <section prefix="16">
    	     An advertisement shall not contain statements which are untrue in fact or by implication misleading with respect to the insurer’s assets, corporate structure, financial standing, age or relative position in the insurance business.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>