<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="169" order_by="169" level="3">Receipts Of Deposits For Transmittal To Foreign Countries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Books And Accounts; Inspections</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        A licensee shall keep such books, accounts and records as will enable the commissioner to determine whether such licensee is in compliance with the provisions of this chapter and rules and regulations made pursuant thereto and any other law, rule and regulation applicable to the conduct of such business. A licensee shall preserve such books, accounts and records for a period of at least three years. Preservation of such books, accounts and records by photographic reproduction thereof or record in photographic form shall constitute compliance with the requirements of this section. The books, accounts and records of every licensee shall be kept and audited in such manner and form as the commissioner may prescribe. 
A licensee shall, when directed by the commissioner, permit the commissioner or his duly authorized representative to inspect its records and evidence of compliance with this chapter or any rule or regulation issued thereunder and with any other law, rule and regulation applicable to the conduct of its business. For the purposes of such inspection, the commissioner or his representative shall have access to the offices and place of business, books, accounts, papers, records and files of licensee. The commissioner and any person designated by him may require the attendance and testimony of all persons as he may deem necessary relative to the inspection of such business. The total cost for any such inspection, which shall be paid by the licensee within thirty days after the receipt of invoice therefor, shall be determined by the commissioner of administration under the provisions of section three B of chapter seven.
    </text>
</law>