<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176Q" order_by="176Q" level="3">Commonwealth Health Insurance Connector</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Interagency Agreements With Department Of Revenue</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. For text effective July 1, 2011, see below.] 
The connector shall enter into interagency agreements with the department of revenue to verify income data for participants in the commonwealth care health insurance program. Such written agreements shall include provisions permitting the connector to provide a list of individuals participating in or applying for the commonwealth care health insurance program, including any applicable members of the households of such individuals, which would be counted in determining eligibility, and to furnish relevant information including, but not limited to, name, social security number, if available, and other data required to assure positive identification. Such written agreements shall include provisions permitting the department of revenue to examine the data available under the wage reporting system established under section 3 of chapter 62E. The department of revenue is hereby authorized to furnish the connector with information on the cases of persons so identified, including, but not limited to, name, social security number and other data to ensure positive identification, name and identification number of employer, and amount of wages received and gross income from all sources. 
Chapter 176Q: Interagency agreements with department of revenue [Text of section as amended by 2010, 288, Sec. 45 effective July 1, 2011. See 2010, 288, Sec. 72. For text effective until July 1, 2011, see above.] 
The connector shall enter into interagency agreements with the department of revenue to verify income data for participants in the commonwealth care health insurance program. Such written agreements shall include provisions permitting the connector to provide a list of individuals participating in or applying for the commonwealth care health insurance program, including any applicable members of the households of such individuals, which would be counted in determining eligibility, and to furnish relevant information including, but not limited to, name, social security number, if available, and other data required to assure positive identification. Such written agreements shall include provisions permitting the department of revenue to examine the data available under the wage reporting system established under section 3 of chapter 62E. The department of revenue is hereby authorized to furnish the connector with information on the cases of persons so identified, including, but not limited to, name, social security number and other data to ensure positive identification, name and identification number of employer, and amount of wages received and gross income from all sources. The connector shall not utilize any of the data received from the department of revenue for any solicitations or advertising.
    </text>
</law>