<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176Q" order_by="176Q" level="3">Commonwealth Health Insurance Connector</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>17</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employer Health Insurance Responsibility Disclosure And Employee Health Insurance Responsibility Disclosure</catch_line>
    <order_by>17</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 215 effective November 4, 2012.]  (a) The connector shall prepare a form, to be called the employer health insurance responsibility disclosure, on which an employer shall report whether it is in compliance with chapter 151F and any other information required by the connector relative to section 18 and paragraph (4) of subsection (a) of section 69 of chapter 118E. The form shall be completed, signed and returned to the connector by every employer with 11 or more full-time equivalent employees.  (b) The connector shall prepare a form, to be called the employee health insurance responsibility disclosure, on which an employee of employers with 11 or more full-time equivalent employees who declines an employer-sponsored health plan shall report whether the employee has an alternative source of health insurance coverage. The form shall be completed and signed by the employee and shall be retained by the employer for 3 years. The connector may request a copy of the signed employee form.  (c) Information that indentifies individual employees by name or health insurance status shall not be a public record, but the information shall be exchanged with the department of revenue, the commonwealth health insurance connector authority and the health care access bureau in the division of insurance under an interagency services agreement to enforce this section, sections 3 to 7A, inclusive, and sections 3, 6B and 18B of chapter 118H. An employer who knowingly falsifies or fails to file with the connector any information required by this section or by any regulation promulgated by the connector shall be punished by a fine of not less than $1,000 and not more than $5,000.
    </text>
</law>