<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>69E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Cadet Engineers; Civil Service Laws; Retirement Benefits;  Workmen’S Compensation</catch_line>
    <order_by>69E</order_by>
    <text>
        The employment of the cadet engineer in “on the job training” shall not be subject to civil service laws and rules, but the appointment shall be reported to the division of personnel administration in such form as the personnel administrator may require. 
A cadet engineer in “on the job training” shall not be subject to or entitled to the benefits of pension and retirement laws nor shall any deductions be taken from his pay for these purposes. 
The employment of a cadet engineer in graduate on the job training shall not be subject to civil service law and rules but such cadet engineer shall be subject to and entitled to the benefit of retirement laws and pensions, and deductions shall be made from his salary and paid into the contributory retirement system of the city or town in accordance with the provisions of the contributory retirement laws. The on the job training period of any cadet engineer who continues in the employ of the contracting city or town as a permanent full-time employee shall be considered as creditable service for purposes of retirement laws, pension laws and other laws pertaining to municipal employees; provided, however, that such cadet engineer shall pay into the retirement fund such sums as may be required by the retirement board to acquire such creditable service; and, provided, further, that time in attendance at a community college, college, university or other educational institution shall not be considered as creditable service under this section. 
Cadet engineers when actually employed in “on the job training” shall be considered as employees of the contracting city or town for purposes of chapter 152.
    </text>
</law>