<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="180" order_by="180" level="3">Corporations For Charitable And Certain Other Purposes</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>17F</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Employees; Payroll Deductions For Contributions To Massachusetts Independent Health Agencies</catch_line>
    <order_by>17F</order_by>
    <text>
        Deductions on payroll schedules may be made from the salary of any state employee of any amount which such employee may specify in writing to the officer, or the head of the department, board or commission, by whom or which he is employed, for the payment of a contribution to the Massachusetts Independent Health Agencies, provided, however, that a state employee shall have the right to select one or more affiliating agencies of said Massachusetts Independent Health Agencies to which he wishes to have his contribution credited. Any such authorization may be withdrawn by the employee by giving sixty days notice in writing of such withdrawal to the officer, or the head of the department, board or commission, by whom or which he is then employed. The state treasurer shall deduct from the salary of such employee such amount of contribution as may be certified to him on the payroll and transmit the sum so deducted to the treasurer of the Massachusetts Independent Health Agencies Committee; provided that the state treasurer is satisfied by such evidence as he may require that the treasurer of such Massachusetts Independent Health Agencies Committee has given to said committee a bond, in a form approved by the commissioner, for the faithful performance of his duties, in a sum and with such surety or sureties as are satisfactory to the state treasurer.
    </text>
</law>