<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176O" order_by="176O" level="3">Health Insurance Consumer Protections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Policies And Procedures To Enforce Sec. 5 A</catch_line>
    <order_by>5B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  To ensure uniformity and consistency in the submission and processing of claims for health care services pursuant to section 5A, the bureau of managed care within the division of insurance, after consultation with a statewide advisory committee including, but not limited to, representatives of the Massachusetts Hospital Association, the Massachusetts Medical Society, the Massachusetts Association of Health Plans, the Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Massachusetts, the Massachusetts Health Information Management Association, the Massachusetts Health Data Consortium, a representative of America's Health Insurance Plans, a representative of a MassHealth contracted managed care organization, the executive office of health and human services, the division of health care finance and policy, the health care quality and cost council, the house of representatives and the senate, shall adopt policies and procedures to enforce said section 5A. The policies and procedures shall include a system for reporting inconsistencies related to a carrier's compliance with said section 5A. The bureau shall work jointly with the executive office of health and human services to resolve reports of noncompliance with the requirements of section 61 of chapter 118E. The bureau shall convene the advisory committee annually to review and discuss issues reported by health care providers pursuant to this section and to discuss further recommendations to improve the uniformity and consistency of the reporting of patient diagnostic information and patient care service and procedure information as it relates to the submission and processing of health care claims.
Chapter 176O: Policies and procedures to enforce Sec. 5A
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 190 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  To ensure uniformity and consistency in the submission and processing of claims for health care services pursuant to section 5A, the bureau of managed care within the division of insurance, after consultation with a statewide advisory committee including, but not limited to, representatives of the Massachusetts Hospital Association, the Massachusetts Medical Society, the Massachusetts Association of Health Plans, the Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Massachusetts, the Massachusetts Health Information Management Association, the Massachusetts Health Data Consortium, a representative of America's Health Insurance Plans, a representative of a MassHealth contracted managed care organization, the executive office of health and human services, the center for health information and analysis, the house of representatives and the senate, shall adopt policies and procedures to enforce said section 5A. The policies and procedures shall include a system for reporting inconsistencies related to a carrier's compliance with said section 5A. The bureau shall work jointly with the executive office of health and human services to resolve reports of noncompliance with the requirements of section 61 of chapter 118E. The bureau shall convene the advisory committee annually to review and discuss issues reported by health care providers pursuant to this section and to discuss further recommendations to improve the uniformity and consistency of the reporting of patient diagnostic information and patient care service and procedure information as it relates to the submission and processing of health care claims.
    </text>
</law>