<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176G" order_by="176G" level="3">Health Maintenance Organizations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Prenatal, Childbirth And Postpartum Care Benefits; Minimum Coverage For In Patient Care</catch_line>
    <order_by>4I</order_by>
    <text>
        Any health maintenance contract shall provide coverage for prenatal care, childbirth and postpartum care in accordance with section four of chapter one hundred and seventy-six G. In addition to such benefits, such health maintenance contract shall provide coverage of a minimum of forty-eight hours of in-patient care following a vaginal delivery and a minimum of ninety-six hours of in-patient care following a caesarean section for a mother and her newly born child. Any decision to shorten these minimum coverages shall be made by the attending physician in consultation with the mother. Any such decision shall be made in accordance with rules and regulations promulgated by the department of public health. Said regulations shall be relative to early discharge, defined as less than forty-eight hours for a vaginal delivery and ninety-six hours for a caesarean delivery, and post-delivery care and shall include, but not be limited to, home visits, parent education, assistance and training in breast or bottle feeding and the performance of any necessary and appropriate clinical tests; provided, however, that the first home visit shall be conducted by a registered nurse, physician, or certified nurse midwife; and provided, further, that any subsequent home visit determined to be clinically necessary shall be provided by a licensed health care provider. 
For the purposes of this section, attending physician shall include the attending obstetrician, pediatrician, or certified nurse midwife attending the mother and newly born child. 
Any subscriber or member who is aggrieved by a denial of benefits to be provided under this section may appeal said denial in accordance with regulations of the department of public health.
    </text>
</law>