<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176Q" order_by="176Q" level="3">Commonwealth Health Insurance Connector</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Surcharge To Health Benefit Or Stand Alone Vision Or Dental Plans;  Reports;  Withdrawal Of Health Plan From Connector</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Subsection (a) effective until June 19, 2012. For text effective June 19, 2012, see below.]  (a) The connector shall be authorized to apply a surcharge to all health benefit plans which shall be used only to pay for administrative and operational expenses of the connector; provided, however, that such a surcharge shall be applied uniformly to all health benefit plans offered through the connector and sub-connectors; provided further that a sub-connector may charge an additional fee to be used only to pay for additional administrative and operational expenses of the sub-connector. These surcharges shall not be used to pay any premium assistance payments under the commonwealth care health insurance program, as described in chapter 118H.[ Subsection (a) as amended by 2012, 118, Sec. 49 effective June 19, 2012. For text effective until June 19, 2012, see above.]  (a) The connector may apply a surcharge to all health benefit plans or stand-alone vision or stand-alone dental plans which shall be used only to pay for administrative and operational expenses of the connector; provided, however, that any such surcharge shall be applied uniformly to all health benefit plans or uniformly to all stand-alone vision or stand-alone dental plans offered through the connector and subconnectors; and provided further, that a subconnector may charge an additional fee to be used only to pay for additional administrative and operational expenses of the subconnector. The surcharges shall not be used to pay any premium assistance payments under the commonwealth care health insurance program under chapter 118H.  (b) Each carrier participating in the connector shall be required to furnish such reasonable reports as the board determines necessary to enable the executive director to carry out his duties under this chapter.  (c) The board may withdraw a health plan from the connector only after notice to the carrier.
    </text>
</law>