<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="156C" order_by="156C" level="3">Limited Liability Company Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>26</section_number>
    <catch_line>Relative Rights, Duties And Powers Of Classes Or Groups Of Managers</catch_line>
    <order_by>26</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     An operating agreement may provide for classes or groups of managers having such relative rights, powers and duties as the operating agreement may provide, and may make provision for the future creation in the manner provided in the operating agreement of additional classes or groups of managers having such relative rights, powers and duties as may from time to time be established, including rights, powers and duties senior to existing classes and groups of managers. An operating agreement may provide for the taking of an action, including the amendment of the operating agreement, without the vote or approval of any manager or class or group of managers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The operating agreement may grant to all or certain identified managers or a specified class or group of the managers the right to vote, separately or with all or any class or group of managers or members, on any matter. Voting by managers may be on a per capita, number, financial interest, class, group or any other basis.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     An operating agreement which grants managers a right to vote may set forth provisions relating to notice of the time, place or purpose of any meeting at which any matter is to be voted on by any manager or class or group of managers, waiver of any such notice, action by consent without a meeting, the establishment of a record date, quorum requirements, voting in person or by proxy, or any other matter with respect to the exercise of any such right to vote.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     If an operating agreement does not provide for the voting rights of managers, the decision of a majority in number of the managers shall be controlling.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>