<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>174B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Revoked Licenses; Surrender; Renewal Certificates; Penalty</catch_line>
    <order_by>174B</order_by>
    <text>
        A person licensed under section 162M, 162N, one hundred and sixty-eight or one hundred and seventy-two shall, upon the revocation of his license and upon written demand therefor, and a partnership licensed under section one hundred and seventy-three or a corporation licensed under section one hundred and seventy-four shall, upon the revocation of its license as to all the members of the firm or as to the corporation and upon such demand, forthwith surrender his or its license or the renewal certificate thereof to the commissioner. Such partnership or corporation shall, upon the revocation of its license as to less than all of its members or officers and upon such demand, forthwith surrender its license or renewal certificate to the commissioner, and he shall thereupon cancel it, and issue an amended license or renewal certificate covering the remaining partners or other officers of the corporation and running for the unexpired term of the surrendered license or renewal certificate. Demands hereunder may be served as provided in section one hundred and seventy-four A. If the license or renewal certificate has been lost, stolen or destroyed, an affidavit to that effect shall be filed with the commissioner in such form as he may require. Whoever neglects or refuses to comply with this section or knowingly and wilfully makes a false affidavit hereunder shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred nor more than five hundred dollars.
    </text>
</law>