<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164" level="3">Manufacture And Sale Of Gas And Electricity</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>69I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Long Range Forecasts Of Electric And Gas Companies; Filing;  Hearings; Approval</catch_line>
    <order_by>69I</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     A description of all then existing agreements with other electric or gas companies for joint planning or joint forecasting of electric power or gas needs and the purchase or sale of electric power or gas or reserve capacity.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A forecast of the electric power needs or gas requirements for its market area, taking into account wholesale bulk power or gas sales or purchases, or other co-operative arrangements with other utilities and energy policies as adopted by the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A description of actions planned to be taken by the company which will affect capacity to meet such needs or requirements, including, but not limited to: expansion, reduction or removal of existing facilities; construction or acquisition of additional facilities; a description of alternatives to planned action such as other methods of generating, manufacturing or storing, other site locations, other sources of electrical power or gas, including facilities which operate on solar or geothermal energy and wind or facilities which operate on the principle of cogeneration or hydrogeneration, and no additional electrical power or gas; a reduction of requirements through load management; a description of the environmental impact of each proposed facility; provided, however, that the above provisions shall not apply to facilities which have been approved as part of a previous long-range forecast or supplement thereto. The department shall after public notice and a period for comment be empowered to issue and revise its own list of guidelines. A minimum of data shall be required by these guidelines from the applicant for review concerning land use impact, water resource impact, air quality impact, solid waste impact, radiation impact and noise impact.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>