<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="176A" order_by="176A" level="3">Non Profit Hospital Service Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>17</section_number>
    <catch_line>Submission Of Disputes And Controversies</catch_line>
    <order_by>17</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. For text effective November 4, 2012, see below.]  Any dispute arising between a corporation subject to this chapter, and any hospital with which such corporation has a contract for hospital service as authorized by this chapter, may with the consent of both parties be submitted to the division of health care finance and policy for its decision with respect thereto. Any dispute or controversy arising between a non-profit hospital service corporation and any subscriber, or any person whose subscription certificate has been cancelled, may with the consent of both parties be submitted to the commissioner of insurance for his decision with respect thereto. All decisions and findings of the division of health care finance and policy and the commissioner of insurance made under this section shall be final as to the facts.
Chapter 176A: Submission of disputes and controversies
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 164 effective November 4, 2012. For text effective until November 4, 2012, see above.]  Any dispute arising between a corporation subject to this chapter, and any hospital with which such corporation has a contract for hospital service as authorized by this chapter, may with the consent of both parties be submitted to the center for health information and analysis for its decision with respect thereto. Any dispute or controversy arising between a non-profit hospital service corporation and any subscriber, or any person whose subscription certificate has been cancelled, may with the consent of both parties be submitted to the commissioner of insurance for his decision with respect thereto. All decisions and findings of the center for health information and analysis and the commissioner of insurance made under this section shall be final as to the facts.
    </text>
</law>