<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>144</section_number>
    <catch_line>Cash Surrender Value; Terms Defined; Paid Up Annuities After Three Years</catch_line>
    <order_by>144</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     This paragraph shall not apply to ordinary policies issued on or after the operative date of subdivision 6A as defined therein. In the case of policies or ordinary insurance issued on or after January first, nineteen hundred and sixty-six, all adjusted premiums and present values referred to in this section shall be computed on the basis of the “Commissioners 1958 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table”, and the rate of interest specified in the policy for the computation or the cash surrender values and other nonforfeiture benefits provided that such rate of interest shall not exceed three and one-half per cent per annum for policies issued prior to March sixth, nineteen hundred and seventy-four, shall not exceed four per cent per annum but policies issued on or after March sixth, nineteen hundred and seventy-four and prior to December first, nineteen hundred and seventy-nine and shall not exceed five and one-half per cent per annum for policies issued on or after December first, nineteen hundred and seventy-nine, provided that for any category of ordinary insurance issued on female risks, adjusted premiums and present values may be calculated according to an age not more than six years younger than the actual age of the insured; and provided, further, that in computing the present value of any extended term insurance with accompanying pure endowment, if any, the rates of mortality assumed may not be more than those shown in the “Commissioners 1958 Extended Term Insurance Tables”; and provided, further, that in the case of any policy issued on a substandard basis any such adjusted premiums and present values may be computed on such other table of mortality as the company may specify with the approval of the commissioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     All values referred to in this section may be computed on the assumption that any death benefit is payable at the end of the policy year in which death occurs.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The nonforfeiture net level premium shall be equal to the present value, at the date of issue of the policy, of the guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy divided by the present value, at the date of issue of the policy, of an annuity of one per annum payable on the date of issue of the policy and on each anniversary of such policy on which a premium falls due.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In the case of policies which cause on a basis guaranteed in the policy unscheduled changes in benefits or premiums, or which provide an option for changes in benefits or premiums other than a change to a new policy, the adjusted premiums and present values shall initially be calculated on the assumption that future benefits and premiums do not change from those stipulated at the date of issue of the policy. At the time of any such change in the benefits or premiums the future adjusted premiums, nonforfeiture net level premiums and present values shall be recalculated on the assumption that future benefits and premiums do not change from those stipulated by the policy immediately after the change.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (g) the recalculated future adjusted premiums for any such policy shall be such uniform percentage of the respective future premiums specified in the policy for each policy year, excluding amounts payable as extra premiums to cover impairments and special hazards, and also excluding any uniform annual contract charge or policy fee specified in the policy in a statement of the method to be used in calculating the cash surrender values and paid-up nonforfeiture benefits, that the present value, at the time of change to the newly defined benefits or premiums, of all such future adjusted premiums shall be equal to the excess of (A) the sum of (i) the then present value of the then future guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy and (ii) the additional expense allowance, if any, over (B) the then cash surrender value, if any, or present value of any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit under the policy.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The additional expense allowance, at the time of the change to the newly defined benefits or premiums, shall be the sum of (i) one per cent of the excess, if positive, of the average amount of insurance at the end of each of the first ten policy years subsequent to the change at the beginning of each of the first ten policy years subsequent to the time of the most recent previous change, or, if there has been no previous change, the date of issue of the policy; and (ii) one hundred and twenty-five per cent of the increase, if positive, in the nonforfeiture net level premium.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The recalculated nonforfeiture net level premium shall be equal to the result obtained by dividing (A) by (B) where (A) equals the sum of (i) the nonforfeiture net level premium applicable prior to the change times the present value of an annuity of one per annum payable on each anniversary of the policy on or subsequent to the date of the change on which a premium would have fallen due had the change not occurred, and (ii) the present value of the increase in future guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy; and (B) equals the present value of an annuity of one per annum payable on each anniversary of the policy on or subsequent to the date of change on which a premium falls due.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subdivision to the contrary, in the case of a policy issued on a substandard basis which provides reduced graded amounts of insurance so that, in each policy year, such policy has the same tabular mortality cost as an otherwise similar policy issued on the standard basis which provides higher uniform amounts of insurance, adjusted premiums and present values for such substandard policy may be calculated as if it were issued to provide such higher uniform amounts of insurance on the standard basis.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     All adjusted premiums and present values referred to in this section shall for all policies of ordinary insurance be calculated on the basis of (i) the Commissioner 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table of (ii) at the election of the company for any one or more specified plans of life insurance, the Commissioners 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table with Ten-Year Select Mortality Factors and shall for all policies issued in a particular calendar year be calculated on the basis of a rate of interest not exceeding the nonforfeiture interest rate as defined in this subdivision for policies issued in that calendar year; provided, however, that:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     At the option of the company, calculations for all policies issued in a particular calendar year may be made on the basis of a rate of interest not exceeding the nonforfeiture interest rate, as defined in this subdivision, for policies issued in the immediately preceding calendar year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Under any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, including any paid-up dividend additions, any cash surrender value available, whether or not required by subdivision 1, shall be calculated on the basis of the mortality table and rate of interest used in determining the amount of such paid-up nonforfeiture benefit and paid-up dividend additions, if any.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A company may calculate the amount of any guaranteed paid-up nonforfeiture benefit including any paid-up additions under the policy on the basis of an interest rate no lower than that specified in the policy for calculating cash surrender values.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     In calculating the present value of any paid-up term insurance with accompanying pure endowment, if any, offered as a nonforfeiture benefit, the rates of mortality assumed may be not more than those shown in the Commissioners 1980 Extended Term Insurance Table for policies of ordinary insurance.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     For insurance issued on a substandard basis, the calculation of any such adjusted premiums and present values may be based on appropriate modifications of the aforementioned tables.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Any ordinary mortality tables, adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, that are approved by regulation promulgated by the commissioner for use in determining the minimum nonforfeiture standard may be substituted for the Commissioners 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table with or without Ten-Year Select Mortality Factors or for the Commissioners 1980 Extended Term Insurance Table.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     The nonforfeiture interest rate per annum for any policy issued in a particular calendar year shall be equal to one hundred and twenty-five per cent of the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for such policy as defined in the standard Valuation Law, rounded to the nearer one quarter of one per cent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Notwithstanding any other provision in this code to the contrary, any refiling of nonforfeiture values or their methods of computation for any previously approved policy form which involves only a change in the interest rate or mortality table used to compute nonforfeiture values shall not require refiling of any other provisions of that policy form.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     After the effective date of this subdivision, any company may file with the commissioner a written notice of its election to comply, with respect to any plan of insurance, with the provisions of this subdivision after a specified date before January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine, which shall be the operative date of this subdivision for that plan of insurance for such company. If a company makes no such election, the operative date of this subdivision for that plan of insurance for such company shall be January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     the commissioner must be satisfied that the benefits provided under the plan are substantially as favorable to policyholders and insureds as the minimum benefits otherwise required by subdivisions 1 to 6A, inclusive;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     the commissioner must be satisfied that the benefits and the pattern of premiums of that plan are not such as to mislead prospective policyholders or insureds;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     the cash surrender values and paid-up nonforfeiture benefits provided by such plan must not be less than the minimum values and benefits required for the plan computed by a method consistent with the principles of this Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Life Insurance, as determined by regulations promulgated by the commissioner.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     must be the same percentage for each policy year between the second policy anniversary and the later of (i) the fifth policy anniversary and (ii) the first policy anniversary at which there is available under the policy a cash surrender value in an amount, before including any paid-up additions and before deducting any indebtedness, of at least two-tenths of one per cent of either the amount of insurance, if the insurance be uniform in amount, or the average amount of insurance at the beginning of each of the first ten policy years; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     must be such that no percentage after the later of the two policy anniversaries specified in the preceding item (a) may apply to fewer than five consecutive policy years.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     contracts of reinsurance,
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     policies of group life insurance; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     annuity or pure endowment contracts of any kind with or without return of premiums or premiums and interest, whether simple or compound, or to survivorship annuity contracts;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     any term policy of uniform amount, which provides no guaranteed nonforfeiture or endowment benefits, or renewal thereof, of twenty years or less expiring before age seventy-one, for which uniform premiums are payable during its entire term,
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     term policy providing for a decreasing amount of insurance, which provides no guaranteed nonforfeiture or endowment benefits, on which each adjusted premium computed as in this section, is less than the adjusted premium, so computed, on a term policy of uniform amount, or renewal thereof, which provides no guaranteed nonforfeiture or endowment benefits, issued at the same age and for the same initial amount of insurance and for a term of twenty years or less expiring before age seventy-one, for which uniform premiums are payable during the entire term of the policy.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     policy, which provides no guaranteed nonforfeiture or endowment benefits, for which no cash surrender value, if any, or present value of any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, at the beginning of any policy year, calculated as specified in subdivisions 2 to 6A, inclusive, exceeds two and one-half per cent of the amount of insurance at the beginning of the same policy year.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>