<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="167D" order_by="167D" level="3">Deposits And Accounts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advertisement And Payment Of Interest; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>15</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     “Nonfederally-insured bank”, any bank, except a credit union as defined in section one of chapter one hundred and seventy-one, which is subject to supervision by the commissioner, which is not a “member” of a Federal Home Loan Bank as defined in 1422), and the deposits of which are not insured in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (12 U.S.C. 1811-1831);
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     “Insured nonmember bank”, the same meaning that such term has in the Federal Deposit Insurance Act;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     “Member”, the same meaning that such term has in the Federal Home Loan Bank Act;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     “Insured institution”, the same meaning that such term has in section 401(a) of the National Housing Act (12 U.S.C. 1724(a));
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     “Deposits”, all deposits authorized under section two; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     “Affiliate”, the same meaning that such term has in section 2(b) of the Banking Act of 1933 (12 U.S.C. 221a), except that the term “member bank”, as used in said section 2(b), shall be deemed to refer to a nonfederally-insured bank.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     In addition to any other penalty provided by this or any other law, any bank, subject to this section, which violates a rule promulgated pursuant to this section shall be subject to such civil penalties, which shall not exceed one hundred dollars for each violation, as may be prescribed by the commissioner by regulation, and such regulation may provide, with respect to any or all such violations, that each day on which the violation continues shall constitute a separate violation. The commissioner may recover any such civil penalty for his own use, through action or otherwise, including recovery thereof in any other action or proceeding under this section. The commissioner may, at any time before collection of any such penalty, whether before or after the bringing of an action or other legal proceeding, the obtaining of any judgment or other recovery or the issuance or levy of any execution or other legal process therefor, and with or without consideration, compromise, remit or mitigate in whole or in part any such penalty of any such recovery.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>