<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>113V</section_number>
    <catch_line>Overutilization Of Practice Or Fraud Involving Automobile Insurance  Claims; Medical Licensing Boards; Investigations   </catch_line>
    <order_by>113V</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meaning:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     At least annually, the medical licensing boards that receive funding pursuant to paragraph (3) of subsection (d) shall review the data made available to them by the Automobile Insurers Bureau of Massachusetts for indication of overutilization of practice or fraud involving automobile insurance claims by individual practitioners or by provider groups. Where overutilization of practice or fraud involving automobile insurance claims by 1 or more licensees is suspected, the board shall conduct an investigation. If the investigation results in evidence that a pattern of fraud, overutilization of practice, or professional misconduct exists, the medical licensing boards shall initiate professional disciplinary proceedings to determine whether that practitioner’s or provider group’s license should be suspended, revoked, or be subjected to some other appropriate penalty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     If a licensee subject to the jurisdiction of the medical licensing boards has been convicted of insurance fraud, the medical licensing boards shall immediately initiate professional disciplinary proceedings to determine whether the applicable license should be suspended, revoked, or subjected to some other appropriate remedy.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     On or before March 1 of each year, the commissioner shall consult with an advisory group consisting of the attorney general or his designee, a district attorney or his designee to be appointed by the attorney general, a representative of the insurance fraud bureau, and 2 members of the public to be appointed by the governor on how the funds paid under subsection (1) should be distributed. Within 60 days of the receipt of said moneys, the commissioner shall allocate and distribute moneys to the medical licensing boards on an analysis of the likelihood of overutilization of practice or fraud relating to automobile related injuries by practitioners under each medical licensing board’s jurisdiction and the needs of each applicable board for the use of the funds after disbursement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The funds collected pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be used solely by the health care fraud unit of the division of professional licensure, the disciplinary unit of the board of registration in medicine and other medical licensing boards for the investigation of overutilization of practice or fraud involving automobile insurance claims. Any funds not expended by the various medical licensing boards within 12 months of their receipt shall be returned to the commissioner who shall keep the funds in a separate account. These funds shall be made available to the medical licensing boards during the next calendar year in accordance with this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Any data made available to or received by the medical licensing boards from the Automobile Insurers Bureau of Massachusetts pursuant to this act shall not be considered a “public record” as defined in clause Twenty-sixth of section 7 of chapter 4.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     In the absence of fraud or bad faith, an insurer or employee or agent thereof, member of said insurance fraud bureau or an employee or an agent thereof, member of said medical licensing boards or an employee or agent thereof, member of said Automobile Insurers Bureau of Massachusetts or an employee or agent thereof, or other person subject to this section, shall not be subject to criminal or civil liability, and no civil cause of action of any nature shall arise against such person for any information relating to suspected over-treatment or fraudulent insurance transactions furnished to medical provider licensing boards or the insurance fraud bureau, their agents and employees pursuant to this section. Nothing herein is intended to abrogate or modify in any way common law privilege of immunity heretofore enjoyed by any person.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>