<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175" level="3">Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>47W</section_number>
    <catch_line>Outpatient Services; Hormone Replacement Therapy For Peri And Post  Menopausal Women; Contraceptive Services; Approved Prescription  Contraceptive Drugs Or Devises; Exception   </catch_line>
    <order_by>47W</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Any individual policy of accident and sickness insurance issued pursuant to section 108 and any group blanket policy of accident and sickness insurance issued pursuant to section 110 that is delivered, issued or renewed within or without the commonwealth and that provides benefits for outpatient services shall provide hormone replacement therapy services for peri and post menopausal women and outpatient contraceptive services under the same terms and conditions as for such other outpatient services. Outpatient contraceptive services shall mean consultations, examinations, procedures and medical services provided on an outpatient basis and related to the use of all contraceptive methods to prevent pregnancy that have been approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Any individual policy of accident and sickness insurance issued pursuant to section 108 and any group blanket policy of accident and sickness insurance issued pursuant to section 110 that is delivered, issued or renewed within or without the commonwealth and that provides benefits for outpatient prescription drugs and devices shall provide benefits for hormone replacement therapy for peri and post menopausal women and for outpatient prescription contraceptive drugs or devices which have been approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration under the same terms and conditions as for such other prescription drugs or devices, provided that in covering all FDA approved prescription contraceptive methods, nothing in this section precludes the use of closed or restricted formulary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     This section shall not apply to an individual policy of accident and sickness insurance delivered, issued or renewed pursuant to section 108 or any group blanket policy of accident and sickness insurance delivered, issued or renewed pursuant to section 110 if that policy is purchased by an employer that is a church or qualified church-controlled organization, as those terms are defined in 26 U.S.C. section 3121(w)(3)(A) and (B).
        </section>
    </text>
</law>