<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="156D" order_by="156D" level="3">Business Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9.34</section_number>
    <catch_line>Effect Of Nonprofit Conversion</catch_line>
    <order_by>9.34</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     When a conversion of a domestic business corporation to a domestic nonprofit corporation becomes effective:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the title to all real and personal property, both tangible and intangible, of the corporation remains in the corporation without reversion or impairment;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the liabilities of the corporation remain the liabilities of the corporation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     an action or proceeding pending against the corporation continues against the corporation as if the conversion had not occurred;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the articles of nonprofit conversion, or the articles of organization attached to the articles of nonprofit conversion, constitute the articles of organization of the corporation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the shares of the corporation are reclassified into memberships, securities, obligations, rights to acquire memberships or securities of the corporation or into cash or other property in accordance with the plan of conversion, and the shareholders are entitled only to the rights provided in the plan of nonprofit conversion or to any rights they may have under PART 13; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     the corporation is considered to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     be a domestic nonprofit corporation for all purposes;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     be the same corporation without interruption as the corporation that existed before the conversion; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     have been incorporated on the date that it was originally incorporated as a domestic business corporation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     When a conversion of a domestic business corporation to a foreign nonprofit corporation becomes effective, the foreign nonprofit corporation is considered to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     appoint the secretary of state as its agent for service of process in a proceeding to enforce the rights of shareholders who exercise appraisal rights in connection with the conversion; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     agree that it will promptly pay the amount, if any, to which such shareholders are entitled under PART 13.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The owner liability of a shareholder in a domestic business corporation that converts to a domestic nonprofit corporation shall be as follows:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The conversion does not discharge any owner liability of the shareholder with respect to the business corporation to the extent any such owner liability arose before the effective date of the articles of nonprofit conversion.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The shareholder shall not have owner liability for any debt, obligation or liability of the nonprofit corporation that arises after the effective date of the articles of nonprofit conversion.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The laws of the commonwealth shall continue to apply to the collection or discharge of any owner liability preserved by paragraph (1), as if the conversion had not occurred and the nonprofit corporation were still a business corporation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The shareholder shall have whatever rights of contribution from other shareholders are provided by the laws of the commonwealth with respect to any owner liability preserved by paragraph (1), as if the conversion had not occurred and the nonprofit corporation were still a business corporation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A shareholder who becomes subject to owner liability for some or all of the debts, obligations or liabilities of the nonprofit corporation shall be personally liable only for those debts, obligations or liabilities of the nonprofit corporation that arise after the effective time of the articles of nonprofit conversion.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>