<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="2">Corporations</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="167F" order_by="167F" level="3">Investments And Other Powers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Investments; Classes Of Stocks</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Kind of Business — In the calendar year immediately preceding the date of investment not less than one-fourth of the net premiums written by such company and its subsidiaries shall have been in respect to risks involving loss of or damage to property belonging to or in the custody of the insured, which risks shall be deemed to be fire and allied risks. As used herein, the term “fire and allied risks” shall be deemed to include homeowners, commercial and industrial multiple period risks, boiler and machinery, glass, burglary and theft and fidelity risk. Net premiums written in the same period in respect to casualty risks shall have been not less than one-fourth of the net premiums written by the company and its subsidiaries. The term “casualty risks” shall be deemed to include risks involving liability of the insured for injury or damage to the person or property of others, workers’ compensation, accident and health, hospital and medical, surety and credit risks. Not more than one-half of the net premiums written in the same period shall have been in respect to liability of owners or operators of motor vehicles for personal injury or property damage. If more than one-fifth of the net premiums written by the company and its subsidiaries in the same period shall have been life insurance premiums, the company or the subsidiary or subsidiaries writing such life insurance shall be licensed to conduct such business in this commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     Subsidiary Defined — For the purposes of this section, “subsidiary” shall be construed to mean any insurance company fifty per cent or more of the capital stock of which is owned by such insurance company or by any other subsidiary thereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     Large Company Requirement — At the end of the calendar year immediately preceding the date of investment the total admitted assets of such company shall be not less than one hundred million dollars, and it shall be one of the companies which meet the provisions of clause (i) and of which a majority of stock is not owned by five or less stockholders.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     Operating Profit Ratio — Of the companies referred to in clause (iii), such company shall be one of the fifteen having the highest average operating profit ratio for the five years immediately preceding the date of investment. The annual operating profit ratio of each of the five years preceding the date of investment shall be calculated by subtracting from one hundred per cent the ratio of loss and loss adjustment expense to net premiums earned and thereafter subtracting from the remainder the ratio of other operating expenses, excluding all income taxes, to net premiums written. The ratios of the five years immediately preceding the date of investment shall be averaged to obtain the measurement. The losses, expenses, premiums written and profits earned referred to above shall be the totals of such items for such company and all its fire and casualty insurance subsidiaries except that, if less than ninety per cent of the capital stock of a subsidiary is owned by such company, the totals of said items for such subsidiary shall be included in the calculation only in proportion of the percentage of stock so owned.
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     Ratio of Assets to Liabilities — At the end of the calendar year immediately preceding the date of investment, the total admitted assets of the company shall be equal to or in excess of one hundred and twenty-five per cent of all liabilities of the company excluding capital, surplus and voluntary reserves.
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     Dividends — Such company shall have paid a dividend in cash in each of the ten years preceding the date of investment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     Other Limitations — The following additional limitation also shall apply to stocks of insurance companies:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Preferred Stock, etc. — Such company shall have no preferred stock or other senior securities outstanding at the date of investment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Aggregate Investment Limit — No insurance stock shall be purchased (a) if the cost thereof added to the cost of insurance stocks and bank stocks already owned shall exceed sixty-six and two-thirds per cent of the total of the capital stock and surplus account for a stock corporation or the surplus account for a thrift institution or (b) if the cost thereof added to the amount already invested in stocks and in shares of beneficial interest of the Savings Bank Investment Fund shall exceed the total of such capital stock and surplus accounts for a stock corporation or such surplus account for a thrift institution.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Investment Limit in One Company — No investment shall be made in the stock of any one insurance company if the cost thereof added to the amount already invested in its stock shall exceed one-fifteenth of the total of said surplus accounts of such corporation, as so appearing.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>