<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="62C" order_by="62C" level="3">Administrative Provisions Relative To State Taxation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16</section_number>
    <catch_line>Filing Of Returns By Taxpayers Subject To Chapters 64 A And 64 C, 64 E To 64 J, 64 L To 64 M And 138</catch_line>
    <order_by>16</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Every distributor and unclassified exporter, as defined in paragraphs (c) and (j) of section one of chapter sixty-four A, shall, on or before the twentieth day of each month file with the commissioner a return stating the number of gallons and the selling price of fuel sold by him in the commonwealth or exported or caused to be exported from the commonwealth during the preceding calendar month and such other information as the commissioner may deem necessary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Every licensee under section two of chapter sixty-four C, other than an unclassified acquirer or a retailer, shall, on or before the twentieth day of each calendar month file with the commissioner a return for each place of business maintained, stating the quantity of tobacco products sold by such licensee in the commonwealth during the preceding calendar month and such return shall contain or be accompanied by such further information as the commissioner shall require; provided, that if a licensee ceases to sell tobacco products within the commonwealth he shall forthwith file with the commissioner such a return for the period ending with such cessation. Each unclassified acquirer shall, upon importation or acquisition of tobacco products into or within the commonwealth, file with the commissioner a return stating the quantity of tobacco products imported or acquired and such other information as the commissioner may deem necessary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     All stampers, as defined in section one of chapter sixty-four C, shall file with the commissioner, monthly reports on or before the twentieth day of each calendar month showing the number of stamps on hand at the beginning of the month, the number purchased during the month, the number on hand at the end of the month, the number affixed or otherwise disposed of during the month, and such other information as the commissioner may deem necessary.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Every person licensed under chapter sixty-four E, other than a user, shall, on or before the twentieth day of each month file with the commissioner a return stating the number of gallons of special fuels sold or used by him in the commonwealth during the preceding calendar month, and such further information as the commissioner may deem necessary, including information relative to the cost and gross receipts from the purchase and sale of such fuel by type.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Every person licensed under chapter sixty-four F shall, on or before the thirtieth day of April, July, October and January of each year, file with the commissioner a return stating the number of gallons of fuel and special fuels used by him in the commonwealth during the preceding calendar quarter, and such further information as the commissioner may deem necessary. The commissioner may by regulation require returns under this subsection to be filed annually or on such other basis as he may determine and to have different filing periods for different groups of licensees. Every such return shall be filed on or before the last day of the month after the expiration of the period covered thereby.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Every operator, as defined in section one of chapter sixty-four G, subject to taxation under chapter sixty-four G, shall file a return with the commissioner for each calendar month. The commissioner may by regulation require returns under this section to be filed on a quarterly rather than a monthly basis or on such other basis as he may determine and to have different filing periods for different groups of operators. Every such return shall be filed within twenty days after the expiration of the period covered thereby.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Each vendor who has made any sale taxable under the provisions of chapter 64H, 64I or 64L shall file a return with the commissioner for each calendar month. The commissioner may by regulation require returns under this section to be filed on a quarterly rather than a monthly basis or on such other basis as it may determine and to have different filing periods for different groups of vendors. Every such return shall be filed within twenty days after the expiration of the period covered thereby. A materialman shall file a return with the commissioner each month. Each return shall be filed within 50 days after the expiration of the period covered by the return. The department may require each materialman electing to remit sales and use tax under this section to file an application with the department stating his intention to remit sales and use tax pursuant to this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Every purchaser who is required to pay a tax under chapter sixty-four I shall file a return with the commissioner for each calendar month. The commissioner may by regulation require returns under this section to be filed on a quarterly rather than a monthly basis or on such other basis as he may determine, and to have different filing periods for different groups of purchasers. Such returns shall show the total sales prices of all services or tangible personal property purchased at retail sale upon which the tax imposed has not been paid by purchasers to vendors, the amount of tax for which the purchaser is liable, and such other information as the commissioner deems necessary for the computation and collection of the tax. Every such return shall be filed within twenty days after the expiration of the period covered thereby unless the commissioner by regulation prescribes otherwise. The return filed by a purchaser shall include the sales prices of all services or tangible personal property purchased at taxable retail sale during the calendar month or other period for which the return is filed and upon which the tax imposed has not been reimbursed by the purchaser to a vendor.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Every person licensed under chapter sixty-four J shall, on or before the twentieth day of each month file with the commissioner a return stating the number of gallons of aircraft fuel sold or used by him in the commonwealth during the preceding calendar month, and such further information as the commissioner may deem necessary, including information relative to the cost and gross receipts from the purchase and sale of such fuel.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     Every person subject to taxation under section twenty-one of chapter one hundred and thirty-eight shall file a return with the commissioner for each calendar month covering his sales of all alcoholic beverages or alcohol and all malt beverages imported into the commonwealth by him. Every such return shall be filed within twenty days after the expiration of the period covered thereby.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     Every direct broadcast satellite service provider subject to taxation under section 2 of chapter 64M shall, on or before the twentieth day of each calendar month, file a return with the commissioner stating the gross revenues derived by the direct broadcast satellite service provider during such month from the provision of direct broadcast satellite service and such other information as the commissioner may deem necessary.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>