<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="62C" order_by="62C" level="3">Administrative Provisions Relative To State Taxation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>55A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Exempt Property</catch_line>
    <order_by>55A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be exempt from levy the following property:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Such items of wearing apparel and such school books as are necessary for the taxpayer or for the members of his family.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     If the taxpayer is the head of a family, so much of the fuel, provisions, furniture and personal effects in his household, and of the arms for personal use, livestock, and poultry of the taxpayer, as does not exceed fifteen hundred dollars in value.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     So many of the books and tools necessary for the trade, business or profession of the taxpayer as do not exceed in the aggregate one thousand dollars in value.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Any amount payable to an individual with respect to his unemployment, including any portion thereof payable with respect to dependents, under an unemployment compensation law of the United States, or of any state.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Mail, addressed to any person, which has not been delivered to the addressee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Annuity or pension payments under the Railroad Retirement Act, benefits under the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act, special pension payments received by a person whose name has been entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll 38 USC 562, and annuities based on retired or retainer pay under chapter seventy-three of title ten of the United States Code.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Any amount payable to an individual as workers’ compensation, including any portion thereof payable with respect to dependents, under a workers’ compensation law of the United States, or of any state.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     If the taxpayer is required by judgment of a court of competent jurisdiction, entered prior to the date of levy, to contribute to the support of his minor children, so much of his salary, wages, or other income as is necessary to comply with such judgment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     Any amount payable to or received by an individual as wages or salary for personal services, or as income derived from other sources, during any period, to the extent that the total of such amounts payable to or received by him during such period does not exceed the applicable exempt amount determined under subsection (d).
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The officer seizing property of the type described in subsection (a) shall appraise and set aside to the owner the amount of such property declared to be exempt. If the taxpayer objects at the time of the seizure to the valuation fixed by the officer making the seizure, the commissioner shall summon three disinterested individuals who shall make the valuation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Notwithstanding any other law, no property or rights to property shall be exempt from levy other than the property specifically made exempt by subsection (a).
        </section>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     Seventy-five dollars, plus
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     Twenty-five dollars for each individual who is specified in a written statement which is submitted to the person on whom notice of levy is served and which is verified in such manner as the commissioner shall prescribe by regulations and:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     over half of whose support for the payroll period was received from the taxpayer,
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     who is the spouse of the taxpayer, or who bears a relationship to the taxpayer specified in paragraphs (1) to (9), inclusive, of section 152(a) of the Code, relating to definition of dependents, and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     who is not a minor child of the taxpayer with respect to whom amounts are exempt from levy under paragraph (8) of subsection (a) for the payroll period.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     In the case of any individual not described in paragraph (1), the amount of the wages, salary, and other income payable to or received by him during any applicable pay period or other fiscal period, as determined under regulations prescribed by the commissioner, which is exempt from levy under paragraph (9) of subsection (a) shall be an amount, determined under such regulations, which as nearly as possible will result in the same total exemption from levy for such individual over a period of time as he would have under paragraph (1) of said subsection (a) if, during such period of time, he were paid or received such wages, salary, and other income on a regular weekly basis.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>