<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="61B" order_by="61B" level="3">Classification And Taxation Of Recreational Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certificate Of Amount Of Conveyance Or Roll Back Tax</catch_line>
    <order_by>15</order_by>
    <text>
        In connection with any proposed or completed sale or other transfer of any land which has been valued, assessed and taxed under the provisions of this chapter, the owner of record of the land may apply to the board of assessors for a certificate of the amount of conveyance tax and roll-back tax, if any, payable by reason of such sale or other transfer, or that no such tax is payable and stating the amount of any conveyance or roll-back taxes that are payable with respect to such land. Such certificate shall be provided to the applicant within twenty days after application therefor. Such certificate may be recorded with the registry of deeds, and upon such recording of such a certificate become payable, or a certificate by the collector of taxes that the amount of tax stated in such certificate of the board of assessors has been paid, all liens on such land for taxes under this chapter shall terminate, except that any liens for any roll-back taxes assessed by reason of land ceasing to qualify for valuation, assessment and taxation under this chapter after the date of such sale or other transfer, shall continue. In connection with the issuance of such a certificate, the board of assessors may rely upon their own records, affidavits and such other information as they may deem appropriate. The board of assessors shall charge six dollars for each certificate so issued, and the money so received shall be paid into the town treasury.
    </text>
</law>