<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="63" order_by="63" level="3">Taxation Of Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>38FF</section_number>
    <catch_line>Wellness Program Tax Credit</catch_line>
    <order_by>38FF</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 56 effective January 1, 2013 until December 31, 2017. Repealed by 2012, 224, Sec. 56A. See 2012, 224, Secs. 297 and 298.]  (a) The purpose of this section shall be to provide incentives for business to recognize the benefits of wellness programs. Wellness programs implemented by business have resulted in both savings to their premiums as well as overall savings to the cost of health care. The goal of this tax credit is to provide smaller businesses with an expanded opportunity to implement these programs.  (b) There is hereby established a Massachusetts wellness program tax credit. The total of all tax credits available to a taxpayer pursuant to this section or section 6N of chapter 62 shall not exceed $10,000 in any 1 tax year. A business that implements a wellness program shall be allowed a credit, to be computed as hereinafter provided, against taxes owed to the commonwealth under chapter 62 or chapter 63 or other applicable law. For the purposes of this section, "businesses'' shall include professions, sole proprietorships, trades, businesses or partnerships.  (c) The credit allowed under this chapter shall be equal to 25 per cent of the costs associated with implementing the program, with a maximum credit of $10,000 per business in any 1 fiscal year. The department of public health shall determine the criteria for eligibility for the credit, such criteria to be set forth in regulations promulgated under this section. The regulations shall require proof of using a wellness program qualified under section 206A of chapter 111. The department shall issue a certification to the taxpayer after the taxpayer submits documentation as required by the department. The certification shall be acceptable as proof that the expenditures related to the implementation of a wellness program for the purposes of the credit allowed under this section.  (d) The credit allowed in this chapter for any taxable year shall not reduce the excise to less than the amount due under subsection (b) of section 39, section 67 or any other applicable section.  (e) Wellness program tax credits allowed to a business under this section shall be allowed for the taxable year in which the program is implemented. A taxpayer allowed a credit under this section for a taxable year may carry over and apply against the taxpayer's tax liability in any of the succeeding 5 taxable years, the portion, as reduced from year to year, of those credits which exceed the tax for the taxable year.
    </text>
</law>