<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="64C" order_by="64C" level="3">Cigarette Excise</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certification To Be Submitted By Manufacturer; Fee; Cigarette Fire Safety And Firefighter Protection Act Enforcement Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>2C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Each manufacturer shall submit to the secretary a written certification attesting that:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     each cigarette listed in the certification has been tested in accordance with section 2B;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     each cigarette listed in the certification meets the performance standard set forth under section 2B;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     each cigarette listed in the certification shall be described with the following information:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     brand, the trade name on the package;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     style, light or ultra light;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     length in millimeters;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     circumference in millimeters;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     flavor, menthol or chocolate, if applicable;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     filter or non-filter;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     package description, soft pack or box; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="viii">
    	     the marking approved in accordance with section 2C.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Such certifications shall be made available to the attorney general and the department of revenue for the purposes of ensuring compliance with this section. Each cigarette certified under section 2C shall be re-certified every 3 years.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     For each cigarette listed in a certification a manufacturer shall pay to the secretary a $250 fee. The secretary may, by regulation, adjust this fee to an amount sufficient only to provide for processing, testing, enforcement and oversight activities related to sections 2B to 2F, inclusive.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     There shall be a separate fund on the books of the commonwealth to be known as the Cigarette Fire Safety and Firefighter Protection Act Enforcement Fund. Such fund shall consist of all certification fees submitted by manufacturers and shall, in addition to any other monies made available for such purpose, be expended by the secretary, without further appropriation, and shall be used solely to support state processing, testing, enforcement and oversight activities related to implementation of sections 2B to 2F, inclusive. All payments from the Cigarette Fire Safety and Firefighter Protection Act Enforcement Fund shall be made on the audit and warrant of the state treasurer on vouchers certified and submitted by the secretary. The secretary may incur expenses for, and the comptroller may certify for payment, amounts from the fund not to exceed the most recent revenue estimate in the state accounting system for the fiscal year; provided, however, that no expenditure shall cause the fund to be out of balance at the end of any fiscal year.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>