<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="62C" order_by="62C" level="3">Administrative Provisions Relative To State Taxation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>47B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Driver’S License, Permit, Right To Operate Or Certificate Of Motor Vehicle Registration; Revocation, Suspension Or Nonrenewal For Failure To File Return Or Pay Tax; Appeal And Hearing</catch_line>
    <order_by>47B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     If the commissioner determines that any person who holds a driver’s license, learner’s permit, right to operate a motor vehicle or certificate of motor vehicle registration has neglected or refused to file any returns or to pay any tax required under this chapter and that the person has not filed in good faith a pending application for abatement of such tax or a pending petition before the appellate tax board contesting such tax or entered a payment agreement with which the taxpayer is fully compliant, the commissioner shall notify the person in writing and the registry of motor vehicles of that determination. Upon receipt of notice from the commissioner, the registrar shall promptly suspend or revoke, or prohibit issuance or renewal, of the license, learner’s permit, right to operate a motor vehicle or certificate of motor vehicle registration of the taxpayer. A license, learner’s permit, right to operate a motor vehicle or certificate of motor vehicle registration suspended or revoked under this section shall not be issued, reissued or renewed until the registry receives a certificate from the commissioner stating that the taxpayer is in good standing with respect to all returns due and taxes payable to the commissioner as of the date of issuance of the certificate, including all taxes and returns referenced in the initial notice.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Where a revocation, suspension or nonrenewal of a license, permit, right to operate or certificate of motor vehicle registration is based upon nonpayment of an assessed tax administered under this chapter, the sole right of appeal and to a hearing shall be pursuant to and within the time limitations of this chapter and not pursuant to chapter 30A. The commissioner shall give the taxpayer not less than 30 days notice of any such proposed action, during which time the taxpayer may enter into a payment agreement with the commissioner or file a good faith abatement application within the time periods determined under section 37. Filing of an abatement application shall stay the proposed revocation, suspension or nonrenewal of a license, permit, right to operate or certificate of motor vehicle registration until the amount of disputed tax due is finally determined. The taxpayer subject to a proposed revocation, suspension or nonrenewal of a license, permit, right to operate or certificate of motor vehicle registration, who is beyond the time limitations in said section 37 but who disputes that he is liable for the assessment and is unable to resolve that issue with the commissioner during the 30-day period, may appeal the proposed revocation, suspension or nonrenewal by filing a civil action as provided in section 14 of chapter 30A. The scope of the appeal shall be limited to assertions of mistake or verification of payments made and shall not include determination or redetermination of the proper amount of tax assessed or any other issues appropriately raised through a timely-filed abatement under said section 37. Any stay of the proposed revocation, suspension or nonrenewal pending resolution of an appeal shall be within the discretion of the court.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>