<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="63" order_by="63" level="3">Taxation Of Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31M</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions;  Life Sciences Tax Credit</catch_line>
    <order_by>31M</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until December 31, 2018. Repealed by 2008, 130, Sec. 22. See 2008, 130, Secs. 53 and 54 as amended by 2011, 9, Sec. 25. See also 2011, 9, Sec. 56.]  (a) As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context otherwise requires, have the following meanings:--  "Life sciences'', advanced and applied sciences that expand the understanding of human physiology and have the potential to lead to medical advances or therapeutic applications including, but not limited to, agricultural biotechnology, biogenerics, bioinformatics, biomedical engineering, biopharmaceuticals, biotechnology, chemical synthesis, chemistry technology, diagnostics, genomics, image analysis, marine biology, marine technology, medical devices, nanotechnology, natural product pharmaceuticals, proteomics, regenerative medicine, RNA interference, stem cell research and veterinary science.  "Person'', a natural person, corporation, association, partnership or other legal entity.  "Primarily'', more than 50 per cent.  "Research and development costs'', in-house research expenses within the meaning of section 41(b)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code.  "Taxpayer'', a certified life sciences company or person subject to the taxes imposed by chapters 62, 63, 64H or 64I.  "User fees'', the monetary amount actually paid by a taxpayer to the U.S.F.D.A. that constitutes the fee due upon the submission of a human drug application or supplement pursuant to 21 U.S.C. section 379h(a)(1) for a human drug, the research and development costs of which, were primarily incurred in the commonwealth.  "U.S.F.D.A.'', the United States Food and Drug Administration.  (b) Except as otherwise limited by subsection (e), a taxpayer may, to the extent authorized pursuant to the life sciences tax incentive program established by said section 5 of chapter 23I, be allowed a refundable credit against the tax liability imposed under this chapter in an amount equal to 100 per cent of the cost of user fees paid by such company.  (c) A taxpayer shall claim the credit in the taxable year in which its application for the licensure of an establishment to manufacture the human drug in the commonwealth is approved by the U.S.F.D.A.  (d) The credit allowed may reduce the excise due under subsection (b) of section 32, or subsection (b) of section 39. The credit allowed to a taxpayer shall not be subject to the provisions of section 32C. Where such credit allowed to a taxpayer exceeds the excise otherwise due under said subsection (b) of section 32 or subsection (b) of said section 39, 90 per cent of the balance of that credit may, at the option of the taxpayer and to the extent authorized pursuant to the life sciences tax incentive program established by said section 5 of said chapter 23I, be refundable to the taxpayer for the taxable year in which the credit is claimed.  If a taxpayer files as a member of a combined group and applies its excess credit against the excise of another group member, then the credit as applied to corporations other than such taxpayer is not subject to section 32C and may reduce to zero the excise due under subsection (b) of section 32, or subsection (b) of section 39 and under any act in addition thereto. Where such credit allowed to a taxpayer that is applied against the excise liability of such other corporations exceeds the excise otherwise due to such corporations under this chapter, 90 per cent of the balance of that credit may, at the option of the taxpayer and to the extent authorized pursuant to the life sciences tax incentive program, be refundable to the taxpayer for the taxable year in which the credit is claimed.  (e) For the purposes of section 30, the deduction from gross income that may be taken with respect to any expenditures qualifying for the credit under this section is disallowed to the extent of the credit.[ Subsection (f) applicable to user fees paid on or after January 1, 2009. See 2008, 130, Sec. 51.]  (f) Only user fees paid by a taxpayer to the U.S.F.D.A. on or after the effective date of this section shall be eligible for the credit.
    </text>
</law>