<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="64G" order_by="64G" level="3">Room Occupancy Excise</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Local Excise Tax; Information Concerning Amount Collected Available</catch_line>
    <order_by>3A</order_by>
    <text>
        Any city or town which accepts the provisions of this section shall be authorized to impose a local excise tax upon the transfer of occupancy of any room or rooms in a bed and breakfast establishment, hotel, lodging house or motel located within such city or town by any operator at a rate up to, but not exceeding, 6 per cent of the total amount of rent for each such occupancy; provided, however, that the city of Boston is hereby authorized to impose such local excise upon the transfer of occupancy of any room in a bed and breakfast establishment, hotel, lodging house or motel located within said city by any operator at the rate of up to but not exceeding 6.5 per cent of the total amount of rent of each such occupancy. No excise shall be imposed if the total amount of rent is less than fifteen dollars per day or its equivalent or if the accommodation is exempt under the provisions of section two of this chapter. The operator shall pay the local excise tax imposed under the provisions of this section to the commissioner at the same time and in the same manner as the excise tax due the commonwealth. All sums received by the commissioner under this section as excise, penalties or forfeitures, interest, costs of suit and fines shall at least quarterly be distributed, credited and paid by the state treasurer upon certification of the commissioner to each city or town that has adopted the provisions of this section in proportion to the amount of such sums received from the transfer of occupancy in each such city or town. This section shall only take effect in a city or town accepting the provisions of this section by a majority vote of the city council with the approval of the mayor, in the case of a city with a Plan A, Plan B, or Plan F charter; by a majority vote of the city council, in the case of a city with a Plan C, Plan D, or Plan E charter; by a majority vote of the annual town meeting or a special meeting called for the purpose, in the case of a municipality with a town meeting form of government; or by a majority vote of the town council, in the case of a municipality with a town council form of government. The provisions of this section shall take effect on the first day of the calendar quarter following thirty days after such acceptance, or on the first day of such later calendar quarter as the city or town may designate. The city or town, in accepting the provisions of this section, may not revoke or otherwise amend the applicable local tax rate more often than once in any twelve month period. 
The commissioner of the department of revenue shall make available to any city or town requesting such information the total amount of room occupancy tax collected in the preceding fiscal year in the city or town requesting the information.
    </text>
</law>