<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="2">Taxation</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="62C" order_by="62C" level="3">Administrative Provisions Relative To State Taxation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>67D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Biotechnology Or Medical Device Manufacturing Companies; Jobs Incentive Payment</catch_line>
    <order_by>67D</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     When used in this section, the following words shall have the following meaning:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A biotechnology or medical device manufacturing or marine science technology company that creates 10 or more eligible jobs in the commonwealth during a single calendar year shall be entitled to a jobs incentive payment if its weighted average employment for such year reflects a net increase of at least 10 jobs over the company’s weighted average employment for the prior calendar year. The jobs incentive payment shall be equal to 50 per cent of the amount paid by the company as salary attributable to eligible jobs created by the company in such year to the extent that the salary was subject to Massachusetts withholding pursuant to chapter 62B for such year, multiplied by the applicable Massachusetts income tax rate for such salary. For the purposes of this provision, an eligible job shall be deemed created in the commonwealth on the first day for which Massachusetts withholding is required in connection with the compensation paid to the employee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The jobs incentive payment shall be paid to a biotechnology or medical device manufacturing or marine science technology company in 3 equal installments in each of the 3 calendar years commencing with the calendar year subsequent to the application year. If, for the first or second payment year, the company’s weighted average employment falls below its weighted average for the application year, the company shall be disqualified from receiving its second installment payment, it may still receive its third installment payment if its weighted average employment for its second payment year is above its weighted average employment for the application year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A biotechnology or medical device manufacturing or marine science technology company that seeks a jobs incentive payment shall apply to the commissioner to receive such payment on a form to be prescribed by the commissioner. This form shall reference the necessary information concerning the eligible jobs created by the company in the Commonwealth during the application year and also the company’s weighted average employment for such year and the prior calendar year. The commissioner shall advise the company of his determination in writing.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Not later than March 1 of each calendar year for which a biotechnology or medical device manufacturing or marine science technology company has been approved to receive a jobs incentive payment, the company shall submit to the commissioner, in a form prescribed by the commissioner, the information necessary to evaluate the company’s prior year weighted employment average.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A biotechnology or medical device manufacturing or marine science technology company that has previously been approved to receive a jobs incentive payment is entitled to re-apply for an additional payment for a second or third application year. In such cases, the company may be entitled to receive a jobs incentive payment that relates to different application years in the same calendar year. When a company has previously been granted a jobs incentive payment for 3 application years, it shall not request an additional jobs incentive payment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The commissioner shall issue payments, as authorized in subsection (b), without further appropriation. The commissioner may issue rules and regulations as necessary or helpful to implement this section, including rules and regulations to ensure compliance with this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>