<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221" order_by="221" level="3">Clerks, Attorneys And Other Officers Of Judicial Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>94</section_number>
    <catch_line>Manner Of Payment; Salaries Of Clerks And Assistant Clerks</catch_line>
    <order_by>94</order_by>
    <text>
        Except as provided in section ninety-three and except as otherwise provided, the salaries of the clerks of the courts and their assistants and the clerk of the supreme judicial court for Suffolk county and his assistants, the clerk of the superior court department for criminal business in Suffolk county and his assistants, the clerk of the superior court department for civil business in Suffolk county and his assistants shall be paid by the commonwealth, and shall be as follows: 
SUPREME JUDICIAL COURT FOR SUFFOLK COUNTY 
The salary of the clerk of the supreme judicial court for Suffolk county shall be 81.57 per cent of the salary of the chief justice of the supreme judicial court and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salary of the first assistant clerk of the supreme judicial court for Suffolk county shall be 89.25 per cent of the salary of said clerk and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salary of the assistant clerks of the supreme judicial court for Suffolk county shall be 82.50 per cent of the salary of said clerk and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. 
The salaries of the clerks in the superior court shall be 81.57 per cent of the salary of the chief justice of said department and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salaries of the first assistant clerks of the superior court division shall be eighty-three and one-half percent of the salaries of said clerks and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salaries of the assistant clerks in said department shall be seventy-seven percent of the salary of said clerks and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>