<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211B" order_by="211B" level="3">Trial Court Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Administrator For Trial Court</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. For text effective July 1, 2011, see below.]  There may be an administrator for the trial court of the commonwealth appointed by the chief justice for administration and management to serve at the pleasure of said chief justice. Said court administrator shall receive a salary to be fixed by the chief justice for administration and management and subject to appropriation. The court administrator shall perform such duties and responsibilities as the chief justice for administration and management may from time to time designate. The court administrator shall be quartered in the office of the chief justice for administration and management.  The chief justice may appoint such other personnel as are necessary for the administration of the trial court. Said personnel shall receive salaries to be fixed by the chief justice for administration and management and subject to appropriation.
Chapter 211B: Office of court management; court administrator
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 56 effective July 1, 2011 until the appointment of a court administrator. See 2011, 93, Secs. 132 and 138. See also 2011, 93, 136. For text effective until the appointment of a court administrator, see above. For text effective upon the appointment of a court administrator, see below.]  There may be an office of court management within the trial court, under the executive control of a court administrator, to support judicial functions, performance and management of the trial court. Said court administrator shall be appointed by a majority vote of the justices of the supreme judicial court; provided, however, that said court administrator shall have significant leadership experience in the fields of management and finance and shall not be a justice of the trial court. Said court administrator shall be paid a salary equal to that of the chief justice of the trial court. The court administrator shall hold said office for a term of 5 years, shall be eligible to be reappointed for additional 5-year terms, and shall devote his full time to the duties of his office. The court administrator shall perform such duties and responsibilities as may be prescribed by law and as the chief justice of the supreme judicial court may from time to time designate. The court administrator may be removed by a majority vote of the justices of the supreme judicial court.  If after due discussion and collaboration disputes between the chief justice of the trial court and the court administrator remain unresolved, such disputes shall be resolved by the chief justice of the supreme judicial court. The decision of the chief justice of the supreme judicial court shall be final and binding.
Chapter 211B: Office of court management; court administrator
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 57 effective upon the appointment of a court administrator. See 2011, 93, Sec. 132. For text effective until the appointment of a court administrator, see above.]  There shall be an office of court management within the trial court, under the executive control of a court administrator, to support judicial functions, performance and management of the trial court. Said court administrator shall be appointed by a majority vote of the justices of the supreme judicial court; provided, however, that said court administrator shall have significant leadership experience in the fields of management and finance and shall not be a justice of the trial court. Said court administrator shall be paid a salary equal to that of the chief justice of the trial court. The court administrator shall hold said office for a term of 5 years, shall be eligible to be reappointed for additional 5-year terms, and shall devote his full time to the duties of his office. The court administrator shall perform such duties and responsibilities as may be prescribed by law and as the chief justice of the supreme judicial court may from time to time designate. The court administrator may be removed by a majority vote of the justices of the supreme judicial court.  If after due discussion and collaboration disputes between the chief justice of the trial court and the court administrator remain unresolved, such disputes shall be resolved by the chief justice of the supreme judicial court. The decision of the chief justice of the supreme judicial court shall be final and binding.
    </text>
</law>