<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221" order_by="221" level="3">Clerks, Attorneys And Other Officers Of Judicial Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>88</section_number>
    <catch_line>Furnishing Transcripts Of Notes;  Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>88</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. For text effective July 1, 2011, see below.]  Upon request of the presiding justice or any party, the stenographer shall furnish a transcript of his notes, or any part thereof, taken at a trial or hearing, for which he shall be paid by the party requesting it at the rate of three dollars per page for the original and one dollar per page for each additional copy ordered at the same time. In the event that daily copy is ordered by the presiding justice or any party, the rate shall be four dollars and fifty cents per page for the original copy and one dollar and fifty cents per page for each additional copy. If transcript is ordered by the presiding justice or, in a criminal case, by the district attorney, payment therefor at the same rate shall be made by the administrative office of the trial court upon a voucher approved by the presiding justice and, in a criminal case, the charges of transcripts furnished to said justice and to the district attorney shall be taxed like other expenses. If the presiding justice orders that a statement given to the police be transcribed, all parties shall receive a copy, and payment therefor shall be at the same rate and made by the administrative office of the trial court upon a voucher approved by the presiding justice.
Chapter 221: Furnishing transcripts of notes; fees
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 68, Sec. 119 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221. For text effective until July 1, 2011, see above.]  Upon request of the presiding justice or any party, the stenographer shall furnish a transcript of his notes, or any part thereof, taken at a trial or hearing, for which he shall be paid by the party requesting it at the rate of $3 per page for the original and $1 per page for each additional copy ordered at the same time. If requested by a party, the stenographer shall furnish an electronic reproduction at an amount not to exceed $5 for each electronic reproduction requested. All electronic reproductions shall be in an open source format as specified by the office of transcription services. Additional paper copies, if so requested by an indigent person or counsel for an indigent person, shall be paid at $.10 per page. In the event that daily copy is ordered by the presiding justice or any party, the rate shall be $4.50 per page for the original copy and $1.50 per page for each additional copy; provided that, if requested by a party, the stenographer shall furnish an electronic reproduction at an amount not to exceed $5 for each electronic reproduction; and provided further, that additional paper copies, if so requested by an indigent person or counsel for an indigent person, shall be paid at $.10 per page. If a transcript is ordered by the presiding justice or, in a criminal case, by the district attorney, payment therefor shall be made at the same rate by the administrative office of the trial court upon a voucher approved by the presiding justice and, in a criminal case, the charges for transcripts furnished to a justice and to the district attorney shall be taxed like other expenses. If the presiding justice orders that a statement given to the police be transcribed, all parties shall receive a copy and payment therefor shall be made at the same rate by the administrative office of the trial court upon a voucher approved by the presiding justice.
    </text>
</law>