<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211D" order_by="211D" level="3">Committee For Public Counsel Services</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Private Counsel Compensation;  Audit And Oversight Department;  Invoices</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. For text effective July 1, 2011, see below.]  The committee shall establish policies and procedures to provide fair compensation to private counsel, which shall include a remedy for an attorney aggrieved by the amount of payment. The committee shall also establish an audit and oversight department to monitor billing and private attorney compensation. All invoices shall be processed for payment within 30 days of receipt by the chief counsel. Bills shall be submitted to the committee within 60 days of the conclusion of a case or, if the case is pending at the end of the fiscal year, within 30 days after the end of such fiscal year. The amount of payment for invoices received by the chief counsel more than 60 days but less than 90 days after the final disposition of the case or more than 30 days but less than 90 days after the end of the fiscal year shall be reduced by 10 per cent. Bills submitted after such date need not be processed for payment within 30 days. For all bills not submitted to the committee within 90 days after the conclusion of a case or, if the case is pending at the end of the fiscal year, within 90 days after the end of the fiscal year, those bills so submitted after such date shall not be processed for payment; provided, however, that the chief counsel may authorize the payment of such bills either in whole or in part upon a determination that the delay was due to extraordinary circumstances beyond the control of the attorney. The committee may further prescribe such policies and procedures for payment as it deems appropriate; provided, however, that the committee may impose interest and penalties, where appropriate, upon overpayment of the private attorney bills recovered from private attorneys.
Chapter 211D: Private counsel compensation; audit and oversight department; submission of invoices for payment
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 68, Sec. 116 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221. For text effective until July 1, 2011, see above.]  (a) The committee shall establish policies and procedures to provide fair compensation to private counsel and vendors, which shall include a remedy for an attorney aggrieved by the amount of payment. The committee shall also establish an audit and oversight department to monitor billing and private attorney and vendor compensation. All private attorney invoices shall be processed for payment within 30 days of receipt by the chief counsel, excluding any bills held for review or audit. Bills shall be submitted to the committee within 60 days of the conclusion of a case or, if the case is pending at the end of the fiscal year, within 30 days after the end of such fiscal year. The amount of payment for invoices received by the chief counsel more than 60 days but less than 90 days after the final disposition of the case or more than 30 days but less than 60 days after the end of the fiscal year shall be reduced by 10 per cent. Bills submitted after such date need not be processed for payment within 30 days. For all bills not submitted to the committee within 90 days after the conclusion of a case or, if the case is pending at the end of the fiscal year, within 60 days after the end of the fiscal year, those bills so submitted after such date shall not be processed for payment; provided, however, that the chief counsel may authorize the payment of such bills, either in whole or in part, upon a determination that the delay was due to extraordinary circumstances beyond the control of the attorney.  (b) Bills shall be submitted to the committee for services provided under sections 27A to 27G, inclusive, of chapter 261 within 60 days of the last date of service or, if the case is pending at the end of the fiscal year, within 30 days after the end of such fiscal year. The amount of payment for invoices received by the chief counsel more than 60 days but less than 90 days after the last date of service or more than 30 days but less than 60 days after the end of the fiscal year shall be reduced by 10 per cent. For all bills not submitted to the committee within 90 days after the last date of service or, if the case is pending at the end of the fiscal year, within 60 days after the end of the fiscal year, those bills so submitted after such date shall not be processed for payment; provided, however, that the chief counsel may authorize the payment of such bills either in whole or in part upon a determination that the delay was due to extraordinary circumstances beyond the control of the vendor.  (c) The committee may further prescribe such policies and procedures for payment as it deems appropriate; provided, however, that the committee may impose interest and penalties, where appropriate, upon overpayment of the private attorney bills recovered from private attorneys and upon overpayment of vendor bills recovered from vendors.
    </text>
</law>