<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211B" order_by="211B" level="3">Trial Court Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Limitation Of Powers, Duties Or Responsibilities Of Clerks Or Registers Of Probate</catch_line>
    <order_by>10C</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The general superintendence and administrative authority of the chief justice for administration and management, the chief justices of the respective departments of the trial court and the first justices of particular courts shall not include the authority or power to exercise, supersede, limit, prevent the exercise of or otherwise affect any of the powers, duties and responsibilities of the clerks or registers of probate in any general or special law, including laws authorizing or governing the selection and appointment of personnel, except where expressly authorized.
Chapter 211B: Limitation of powers, duties or responsibilities of clerks or registers of probate
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 54 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The general superintendence and administrative authority of the chief justice of the trial court, court administrator, and the chief justices of the respective departments of the trial court and the first justices of particular courts shall not include the authority or power to exercise, supersede, limit, prevent the exercise of or otherwise affect any of the powers, duties and responsibilities of the clerks or registers of probate in any general or special law, including laws authorizing or governing the selection and appointment of personnel, except where expressly authorized.
    </text>
</law>