<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211B" order_by="211B" level="3">Trial Court Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>6A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  There shall be an advisory board to assist the justices of the supreme judicial court and the chief justice for administration and management of the judicial department. The board shall consist of the attorney general, or his designee, the executive director of the Massachusetts office of victim assistance and the following additional members appointed by the supreme judicial court: 2 persons who have significant experience in public administration, 2 persons who have significant experience in business administration, 1 lawyer with significant experience in the practice of criminal law, 1 lawyer with significant experience in the practice of civil law, 1 lawyer with significant experience in the practice of probate and family law, 1 lawyer with significant experience in the representation of juveniles in the courts, 1 lawyer with significant judicial experience but not a current justice of the commonwealth or a retired justice serving the commonwealth pursuant to judicial recall, and 1 person who has significant experience in information technology. The board shall choose its chair. The appointed members of said board shall serve for a term of 3 years. The maximum amount of time that said members may serve on said board shall be 2 such terms. The chief justice for administration and management shall be the executive secretary of the board.  The board shall advise the justices of the supreme judicial court and the chief justice for administration and management on all matters of judicial reform including, but not limited to, a proposal for the allocation of resources based on the demonstrated workload of each court.
Chapter 211B: Advisory board
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 52 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  There shall be an advisory board to assist the justices of the supreme judicial court, the chief justice of the trial court, and the court administrator. The board shall consist of the attorney general, or his designee, the executive director of the Massachusetts office of victim assistance and the following 10 additional members appointed by the supreme judicial court: 2 persons who have significant experience in public administration, 2 persons who have significant experience in business administration, 1 lawyer with significant experience in the practice of criminal law, 1 lawyer with significant experience in the practice of civil law, 1 lawyer with significant experience in the practice of probate and family law, 1 lawyer with significant experience in the representation of juveniles in the courts, 1 lawyer with significant judicial experience but not a current justice of the commonwealth or a retired justice serving the commonwealth pursuant to judicial recall, and 1 person who has significant experience in information technology. The board shall choose its chair. The appointed members of said board shall serve for a term of 3 years. The maximum amount of time that said members may serve on said board shall be 2 such terms. The chief justice of the trial court shall be the executive secretary of the board.  The board shall advise the justices of the supreme judicial court, the chief justice of the trial court, and the court administrator on all matters of judicial reform including, but not limited to, a proposal for the allocation of resources based on the demonstrated workload of each court.
    </text>
</law>