<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211B" order_by="211B" level="3">Trial Court Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Organization</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  There shall be a trial court of the commonwealth which shall consist of the following departments: the superior court department, the housing court department, the land court department, the probate and family court department, the Boston municipal court department, the juvenile court department and district court department. The trial court, as an administrative unit, shall consist of no more than 378 justices and special justices. There shall be selected as herein after provided, a chief justice for administration and management and a chief justice for each of the departments of the trial court.
Chapter 211B: Organization
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 49 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  There shall be a trial court of the commonwealth which shall consist of the following departments: the superior court department, the housing court department, the land court department, the probate and family court department, the Boston municipal court department, the juvenile court department and district court department. The trial court, as an administrative unit, shall consist of no more than 378 justices and special justices. There shall be selected as herein provided, a chief justice of the trial court, a court administrator, a chief justice for each of the departments of the trial court and a deputy court administrator for each of the departments of the trial court.
    </text>
</law>