<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221B" order_by="221B" level="3">Child Support Hearing Officers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Committee On Child Support Hearing Officers;  Membership;  Terms;  Chairman</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The committee on child support hearing officers shall be comprised of the chief administrative justice of the trial court, the administrative justices of the probate and family court department, the district court department, and the Boston municipal court department, or their designees. The committee shall also include the following appointees of the chief administrative justice: a representative of the agency designated under Title IV, Part D of the Social Security Act, a representative of the department of transitional assistance if it is not the designated IV-D agency, as set forth in chapter one hundred and nineteen A, a representative of a bar association, a district attorney, a representative of an agency funded by chapter two hundred and twenty-one A, a custodial parent who is not a member of the bar and a noncustodial parent who is not a member of the bar. The terms of such appointees shall be three years; provided, however, that the first representative of a bar association, the first district attorney and the first representative of an agency funded pursuant to chapter two hundred and twenty-one A who are appointed shall serve for one year and the first custodial parent and the first noncustodial parent who are appointed shall serve for two years. Thereafter, all appointees shall serve for a term of three years, so that terms shall be staggered. The chief administrative justice shall be chairman of the committee on child support hearing officers.
Chapter 221B: Committee on child support hearing officers; membership; terms; chairman
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Secs. 106 and 107 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The committee on child support hearing officers shall be comprised of the chief justice of the trial court, the administrative justices of the probate and family court department, the district court department, and the Boston municipal court department, or their designees. The committee shall also include the following appointees of the chief justice of the trial court: a representative of the agency designated under Title IV, Part D of the Social Security Act, a representative of the department of transitional assistance if it is not the designated IV-D agency, as set forth in chapter one hundred and nineteen A, a representative of a bar association, a district attorney, a representative of an agency funded by chapter two hundred and twenty-one A, a custodial parent who is not a member of the bar and a noncustodial parent who is not a member of the bar. The terms of such appointees shall be three years; provided, however, that the first representative of a bar association, the first district attorney and the first representative of an agency funded pursuant to chapter two hundred and twenty-one A who are appointed shall serve for one year and the first custodial parent and the first noncustodial parent who are appointed shall serve for two years. Thereafter, all appointees shall serve for a term of three years, so that terms shall be staggered. The chief justice of the trial court shall be chairman of the committee on child support hearing officers.
    </text>
</law>