<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211D" order_by="211D" level="3">Committee For Public Counsel Services</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2.5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Affidavit Of Indigency;  Waiver Authorizing Access To Verifying Information;  Quarterly Reports On Implemented Procedures</catch_line>
    <order_by>2.5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2011. Repealed by 2011, 68, Sec. 112. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221.]  (a) Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, a person claiming indigency under the provisions of section 2 must execute a waiver authorizing the court's chief probation officer or his designee, to obtain the person's wage and tax information from the department of revenue and any other information from the registry of motor vehicles that the court may find useful in verifying the person's claim of indigency. The waiver shall authorize the chief probation officer, or his designee, to conduct any further re-assessment required by this section.  (b) It shall be the responsibility of the chief probation officer assigned to each court to ensure that a person claiming to be indigent meets the definition of indigency under section 2. A person seeking the appointment of counsel shall be interviewed by the chief probation officer or his designee before the appointment of counsel. The person conducting the interview shall explain to the person seeking appointment of counsel (1) the definition of indigency, (2) the process used to verify his information with other state agencies, and (3) the consequences of misrepresenting his financial information in applying for the appointment of counsel. The person conducting the interview shall prepare a written indigency intake report that shall record the results of the interview and his recommendation on whether or not the person seeking appointment of counsel is indigent. The person seeking appointment of counsel and the person conducting the interview shall sign the indigency intake report. In signing the report, the person seeking appointment of counsel shall certify under the pains and penalties of perjury that the information contained therein is true and that he has not concealed any information relevant to his financial status. All statements contained in the report shall be deemed material statements. The completed report shall be presented to a judge who may adopt or reject the recommendations in the report, either in whole or in part.  (c) Any appointment of counsel by the court is at all times subject to verification of indigency by the chief probation officer assigned to each court. Not later than 60 days after the appointment of counsel, the chief probation officer or his designee shall complete a re-assessment of the financial circumstances of the person for whom counsel was appointed to ensure that such person continues to meet the definition of indigency. In preparing his re-assessment, the chief probation officer or his designee may access wage and tax information in the possession of the department of revenue and such other information relevant to the verification of indigency in the possession of the registry of motor vehicles. Said departments shall provide such information to the chief probation officer or his designee upon request. Upon completion of his re-assessment, the chief probation officer shall prepare a written report of his findings. The chief probation officer shall sign the report, certifying that the person for whom counsel was appointed either continues to meet or does not continue to meet the definition of indigency. The report shall be filed with the case papers and shall be presented to the judge presiding at the person's next court appearance. If, upon receipt of the report, a judge finds that the person for whom counsel was appointed no longer meets the definition of indigency, he shall revoke the appointment of counsel and allow such person a reasonable continuance to obtain new counsel. Not later than 6 months after the appointment of counsel, and every 6 months thereafter, the chief probation officer or his designee shall conduct a further re-assessment of the financial circumstances of the person for whom counsel was appointed to ensure that he continues to meet the definition of indigency and shall prepare, sign and file a written report certifying that the person either continues to meet, or does not continue to meet, the definition of indigency.  (d) If a criminal defendant is charged with a second or further offense while continuing to be represented by court-appointed counsel for a previously charged offense, the court in its discretion shall determine whether any further determination of indigency, other than the 60-day and bi-annual re-assessments required by the defendant's representation for the first offense, need be undertaken. Upon completion of a re-assessment, the chief probation officer shall prepare a written report of his findings. The chief probation officer shall sign the report, certifying that the defendant either continues to meet or does not continue to meet the definition of indigency. The report shall be filed with the case papers and shall be presented to the judge presiding at the defendant's next court appearance. If, upon receipt of the report, a judge finds that the defendant no longer meets the definition of indigency, he shall revoke the appointment of counsel and allow the defendant a reasonable continuance to obtain new counsel.  (e) If the court finds that a person has materially misrepresented or omitted information concerning his property or assets for purposes of determining indigency, and that such person does not meet the definition of indigency, the court shall immediately terminate any assignment or appointment of counsel made under chapter 211D and shall assess costs of not less than $500 against such person.  (f) A person provided counsel under this chapter shall be assessed a counsel fee of $150, which the court may waive only upon determining that the person is unable to pay such $150 within 180 days. If, upon reviewing the chief probation officer's report on the 60-day re-assessment of the person's indigency, the court concludes that the person is able to pay the $150 counsel fee of which he obtained a waiver, the court shall invalidate the waiver and re-impose the $150 counsel fee.  (g) The court may authorize a person for whom counsel was appointed to perform community service in lieu of payment of the counsel fee. A person seeking to work off his counsel fee in community service shall perform 10 hours of community service for each $100 he owes in legal counsel fees. Notwithstanding any general or special law, rule or regulation to the contrary, a court proceeding shall not be terminated and the person shall not be discharged if he owes any portion of the legal counsel fee imposed by this section. The clerk shall not release any bail posted on such court proceeding until the legal counsel fee is satisfied in accordance with this chapter.  (h) The clerk of the court shall, within 60 days of appointment after counsel, report to the department of revenue and the registry of motor vehicles the amount of any legal counsel fee owed by the person for whom counsel was appointed under this chapter. The department of revenue shall intercept the fee from tax refunds due to persons who have not paid it. The registrar of motor vehicles shall place a lien in the amount of any portion of the legal counsel fee owed by the person for whom counsel was appointed upon the title of any motor vehicle owned in whole or in part by him. If the person for whom counsel was appointed does not own a motor vehicle the registry of motor vehicles shall not issue or renew such persons' driver's license or motor vehicle registration for any vehicle subsequently purchased by such person. The registry of motor vehicles shall not release the lien or issue or renew the license or motor vehicle registration until it receives notification from the clerk of the court that the fee has been collected or worked off in community service.  (i) The office of the commissioner of probation shall submit quarterly reports to the house and senate committees on ways and means detailing the effectiveness of any procedures implemented pursuant to this section to verify an individual's claim of indigency. The report shall include, but not limited to, the number of individuals determined to be indigent, number of individuals determined not to be indigent, number of individuals found to have concealed or otherwise misrepresented information relevant to his financial status, number of individuals found to no longer qualify for appointment of counsel upon any re-assessment of indigency required by this section, revenue generated through collection of indigent client fees, the average indigent client fee that each court division collects per case, recommendations to improve the procedures for verifying eligibility for counsel and other pertinent information to ascertain the effectiveness of verification procedures. The information within such report shall be delineated by court division.
    </text>
</law>