<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221A" order_by="221A" level="3">The Massachusetts Legal Assistance Corporation Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Participation In Litigation; Influencing Legislation; Political Activity; Attorney Compensation</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        The corporation shall not itself participate in litigation unless the corporation or a recipient of the corporation is a party, or a recipient is representing an eligible client in litigation in which the interpretation of this chapter or a regulation promulgated under this chapter is an issue, and shall not participate on behalf of any client other than itself; nor shall the corporation undertake to influence the passage or defeat of any legislation by the general court or by the Congress of the United States except that personnel of the corporation may testify or make other appropriate communication when formally requested to do so by a legislative body, a committee, or a member thereof, or in connection with legislation or appropriations directly affecting the activities of the corporation. 
Neither the corporation nor any recipient shall contribute or make available corporate funds or program personnel or equipment to any political party or association, or so contribute to the campaign of any candidate for public or party office. 
No class action suit, class action appeal, or amicus curiae class action may be undertaken, directly or through others, by a staff attorney employed by a recipient except with the express approval of a project director of a recipient in accordance with policies established by the governing body of such recipient. 
Attorneys employed by a recipient shall be appointed to provide legal assistance without reasonable compensation only when such appointment is made pursuant to a statute, rule, or practice applied generally to attorneys practicing in the court where the appointment is made. 
Employees of the corporation or of recipients shall not at any time intentionally identify the corporation or the recipient with any partisan or nonpartisan political activity associated with a political party or association, or the campaign or any candidate for public or party office.
    </text>
</law>