<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211B" order_by="211B" level="3">Trial Court Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Chief Justices;  Appointment;  Term;  Removal</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The office of the chief justice of a department of the trial court, as provided in section one, shall not be deemed a judicial office as comprehended under the provisions of Article I of Chapter III of Part the Second of the Constitution. Said office of chief justice shall be filled by appointment, from among the justices appointed to the particular department, by the chief justice for administration and management. A chief justice shall hold said office for a term of five years, and shall be eligible to be reappointed for additional five-year terms. A chief justice, so appointed, may be removed from that office prior to the expiration of his term upon a determination by the chief justice for administration and management that such removal is in the best interests of the administration of justice.
Chapter 211B: Chief justices; appointment; term; removal
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 52 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The office of the chief justice of a department of the trial court, as provided in section 1, shall not be deemed a judicial office as comprehended under the provisions of Article I of Chapter III of Part the Second of the Constitution. Said office of chief justice shall be filled by appointment, from among the justices appointed to the particular department, by the chief justice of the trial court. A chief justice shall hold said office for a term of 5 years, and shall be eligible to be reappointed for additional 5-year terms. A chief justice, so appointed, may be removed from that office prior to the expiration of his term by the chief justice of the trial court; provided, however, that any such removal is not for arbitrary or capricious reasons and, if the employee so requests, is approved by the Committee.
    </text>
</law>