<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218" level="3">District Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19</section_number>
    <catch_line>General Provisions</catch_line>
    <order_by>19</order_by>
    <text>
        Except as otherwise provided by law, the district court and Boston municipal court departments shall have original jurisdiction of civil actions for money damages. The actions may proceed in the courts only if there is no reasonable likelihood that recovery by the plaintiff will exceed $25,000, or an amount ordered from time to time by the supreme judicial court. Where multiple damages are allowed by law, the amount of single damages claimed shall control. Notwithstanding the limitation of $25,000, or other amount ordered by the supreme judicial court, the district courts may proceed with actions for money damages in any amount in summary process actions. The Boston municipal and district court departments shall have original jurisdiction concurrent with the probate and family court department of actions relative to paternity and support under chapter two hundred and nine C. The district courts shall also have jurisdiction of actions in summary process under chapter two hundred and thirty-nine and in the hearing and disposition of such actions shall have the same equitable powers and jurisdiction as is provided for the divisions of the housing court department pursuant to section three of chapter one hundred and eighty-five C. The Boston municipal and district court departments shall have original jurisdiction concurrent with the probate and family court department of proceedings under chapter two hundred and nine D. They shall have jurisdiction of proceedings transferred to them under the provisions of section four A of chapter two hundred and eleven.
    </text>
</law>