<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211F" order_by="211F" level="3">Office Of Community Corrections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Sentence To Community Corrections Program; Duration; Conditions;  Eligibility</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Any court exercising jurisdiction is authorized to sentence any eligible offender to a community corrections program; provided, however, that the court designate the duration of the sentence of imprisonment that otherwise would have been imposed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The court may dictate the duration and conditions of the sentence in a community corrections program for any period of time consistent with existing law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A sentence to a community corrections program shall be imposed as a condition of probation consistent with chapters two hundred and seventy-six and two hundred and seventy-six A. The court may modify the sentence of an offender serving a sentence in a community corrections program in the same manner as if the offender had been placed on probation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The commissioner shall develop interim standards for the eligibility of offenders for community corrections, taking into consideration the following factors:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the nature and circumstances of the offense;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the offender’s mental state at the time of the offense;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the relationship, if any, between the offender and victim;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the nature and degree of the harm caused by the offense;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the community view of the gravity of the offense;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     the public concern generated by the offense;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     the age of the offender;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     the deterrent effect a particular sentence may have on the commission of the offense by others;
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     the current incidence of the offense in the community and in the commonwealth as a whole;
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     the role of the offender in cases involving multiple offenders;
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     the mental and emotional condition of the offender;
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     the offender’s physical condition;
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     the offender’s family ties and responsibilities;
        </section>
        <section prefix="14">
    	     the offender’s community ties;
        </section>
        <section prefix="15">
    	     the offender’s degree of dependence upon criminal activity for a livelihood;
        </section>
        <section prefix="16">
    	     the offender’s character and personal history;
        </section>
        <section prefix="17">
    	     the offender’s amenability to correction, treatment, or supervision;
        </section>
        <section prefix="18">
    	     the offender’s past criminal history, including convictions, acquittals, guilty pleas, pleas of nolo contendere, dismissals and matters continued without a finding;
        </section>
        <section prefix="19">
    	     the offender’s arrest record;
        </section>
        <section prefix="20">
    	     the offender’s past history of violence.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>