<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211" level="3">The Supreme Judicial Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>25</section_number>
    <catch_line>Disability Benefits Project</catch_line>
    <order_by>25</order_by>
    <text>
        There is hereby created under the superintendence of the supreme judicial court, hereinafter called the court, a disability benefits project, hereinafter called the project, for the exclusive purpose of providing increased legal assistance for mentally or physically disabled persons to secure federal disability benefits provided through the Social Security Disability Insurance program under Title II of the Social Security Act, through the Supplemental Security Income program under Title XVI of the Social Security Act, and through such other programs subsequently established by Congress to accomplish similar purposes for persons with disabilities. The purpose and intent of said project shall be to make funds available, subject to appropriation for such purposes, to organizations, including qualified legal services programs as defined in section one of chapter two hundred and twenty-one A, and other groups, corporations or associations to fund a program of statewide legal assistance, such funds to be distributed pursuant to contracts which set general goals for case-handling, or include other appropriate measures of service, for each organization receiving financial assistance and which require, where appropriate, that a portion of said financial assistance be made available to private attorneys to further effectuate the intent of the project. The court may administer or contract with any organization for the purpose of administering the project. The court may further appoint a disability advisory committee, consisting of members of the legal community including those with experience in advocacy for persons with disabilities, and members of the disabled community, for the purpose of assisting the court in matters pertaining to the project. The composition of the committee, the terms of its members, and the scope of its responsibilities shall be determined by the court.
    </text>
</law>