<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211F" order_by="211F" level="3">Office Of Community Corrections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>County Community Corrections Advisory Boards</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) There is hereby established within each county a county community corrections advisory board consisting of at least eight but not more than twelve members including the following:  (1) the first justice of the superior court, or his designee;[ Clause (2) of subsection (a) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (2) a district court judge appointed by the chief justice for administration and management of the trial court;[ Clause (2) of subsection (a) as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 65C effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (2) a district court judge appointed by the chief justice of the trial court;  (3) a probation officer appointed by the commissioner;  (4) a representative of the parole board appointed by the secretary of public safety;  (5) the district attorney, or his designee;  (6) a public defender appointed by the committee for public counsel services;[ Clause (7) of subsection (a) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (7) a mental health professional or substance abuse counselor appointed by the chief justice for administration and management of the trial court;[ Clause (7) of subsection (a) as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 65C effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (7) a mental health professional or substance abuse counselor appointed by the chief justice of the trial court;  (8) the sheriff, or his designee;  (9) not more than four other members appointed by the commissioner.  (b) The county community corrections advisory board shall assist in the review and monitoring of community corrections programs located in that county. Its responsibilities shall include holding public hearings on community corrections plans submitted to the executive director, reporting any allegations of provider noncompliance, and submitting written comments to the executive director and to the commission, which shall include evaluations of each provider located in that county, analysis of the results of community corrections programs located in that county, recommendations for change and any other information, statistics or data requested by the executive director or the commission, no later than May fifteenth and November fifteenth of each year.
    </text>
</law>