<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221" order_by="221" level="3">Clerks, Attorneys And Other Officers Of Judicial Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>69A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Court Officer Appointments And Removals;  Security Of John Adams Courthouse</catch_line>
    <order_by>69A</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) The chief justice of the supreme judicial court shall appoint, and may remove for cause, the chief court officer, the assistant chief court officer and the court officers of the supreme judicial court, who shall be responsible for security in all areas of the John Adams courthouse occupied by the supreme judicial court and in all areas of any other building occupied permanently by the supreme judicial court. The chief justice shall provide for the discipline, assignment and supervision of those court officers and define their duties.  (b) The chief justice of the appeals court shall appoint, and may remove for cause, the chief court officer, the assistant chief court officer and the court officers of the appeals court, who shall be responsible for security in all areas of the John Adams courthouse occupied by the appeals court and in all areas of any other building occupied permanently by the appeals court. The chief justice shall provide for the discipline, assignment and supervision of those court officers and define their duties.[ Subsection (c) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (c) The chief justice for administration and management shall assign such associate court officers to the John Adams courthouse as are sufficient to meet the security needs of the John Adams courthouse, including those spaces not occupied permanently by the supreme judicial court or the appeals court.[ Subsection (c) as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 97 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (c) The court administrator shall assign such associate court officers to the John Adams courthouse as are sufficient to meet the security needs of the John Adams courthouse, including those spaces not occupied permanently by the supreme judicial court or the appeals court.  (d) The chief court officer of the supreme judicial court shall be the senior person in charge of security for the John Adams courthouse. The chief court officer of the supreme judicial court shall coordinate the security of the John Adams courthouse with the chief court officer of the appeals court and the director of security of the administrative office of the trial court or other representative as the chief justice for administration and management may designate.
    </text>
</law>