<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211B" order_by="211B" level="3">Trial Court Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Vacancies In Office</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  In the case of a vacancy in the office of chief justice of a department of the trial court due to the absence of said chief justice or due to his inability to perform his duties, the office of chief justice in such event shall be filled as provided in section five. The temporary chief justice so appointed may hold said office until the incumbent shall resume his duties and subject to the chief justice for administration and management, but in no event longer than six months. A temporary chief justice shall be eligible to serve a consecutive full term as chief justice.  In the case of a vacancy in the office of chief justice for administration and management due to the absence of said chief justice for administration and management or due to his inability to perform his duties, said office shall be filled by the justices of the supreme judicial court until said chief justice for administration and management shall resume his duties and subject to the justices of said court or until a new chief justice for administration and management is qualified as hereinbefore provided, but in no event shall such office be so filled for a period in excess of six months. The justice appointed as chief justice for administration and management under the provisions of this section shall be eligible to serve a consecutive full term as chief justice for administration and management of the trial court. A chief justice for administration and management may be removed for cause in such manner as shall be provided by the justices of the supreme judicial court, and after a public hearing if it is so requested by the chief justice for administration and management. A vote for removal shall be by a majority of the justices of the supreme judicial court.
Chapter 211B: Vacancies in office
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 52 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  In the case of a vacancy in the office of chief justice of a department of the trial court due to the absence of said chief justice or due to his inability to perform his duties, the office of chief justice in such event shall be filled as provided in section 5. The temporary chief justice so appointed may hold said office until the incumbent shall resume his duties and subject to the chief justice of the trial court, but in no event longer than 6 months. A temporary chief justice shall be eligible to serve a consecutive full term as chief justice.  In the case of a vacancy in the office of deputy court administrator of a department of the trial court due to the absence of said deputy court administrator or due to his inability to perform his duties, the office of deputy court administrator in such event shall be filled as provided in section 5A. The temporary deputy court administrator so appointed may hold said office until the incumbent shall resume his duties, but in no event longer than 6 months. A temporary deputy court administrator shall be eligible to serve a consecutive full term as deputy court administrator.  In the case of a vacancy in the office of chief justice of the trial court due to the absence of said chief justice of the trial court or due to his inability to perform his duties, said office shall be filled by the justices of the supreme judicial court until said chief justice of the trial court shall resume his duties and subject to the justices of said court or until a new chief justice of the trial court is qualified as hereinbefore provided, but in no event shall such office be so filled for a period in excess of 6 months. The justice appointed as chief justice of the trial court under the provisions of this section shall be eligible to serve a consecutive full term as chief justice of the trial court. A chief justice of the trial court may be removed by a majority vote of the justices of the supreme judicial court.  In the case of a vacancy in the office of court administrator due to the absence of said court administrator or due to his inability to perform his duties, said office shall be filled by the justices of the supreme judicial court until said court administrator shall resume his duties and subject to the justices of said court or until a new court administrator is qualified as hereinbefore provided, but in no event shall such office be so filled for a period in excess of 6 months. The court administrator appointed under the provisions of this section shall be eligible to serve a consecutive full term as court administrator of the trial court. A court administrator may be removed by a majority vote of the justices of the supreme judicial court.
    </text>
</law>