<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211F" order_by="211F" level="3">Office Of Community Corrections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
          The following terms as used in this chapter shall have the following meanings:[ Definition of "Chief justice'' effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  "Chief justice'', the chief justice for administration and management of the trial court.[ Definition of "Chief justice'' amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 65A effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  "Chief justice'', the chief justice of the trial court.  "Commission'', the Massachusetts sentencing commission.  "Commissioner'', the commissioner of probation.  "Community corrections program'', any program that is operated by a state, local or private service agency, that has been deemed an appropriate intermediate sanctions program by the office of community corrections.  "Intermediate sanctions program'', any program that has been determined to impose an appropriate sanction upon an offender for whom imprisonment may not be necessary or appropriate, including but not limited to standard probation, intensive supervision probation, community service, home confinement, weekend jail sentences, day reporting, residential programming, substance abuse treatment, restitution, means-based fines, continuing education, including but not limited to the "Changing Lives Through Literature'' program administered by the trial court and the University of Massachusetts at Dartmouth, vocational training, special education, and psychological counseling.  "Community corrections plan'', a written proposal submitted to the executive director of the office of community corrections for approval and funding as a community corrections program.[ Definition of "Court administrator'' inserted following definition of "Community corrections plan'' by 2011, 93, Sec. 65B effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137.]  "Court administrator'', the court administrator of the trial court.  "Executive director'', the executive director of the office of community corrections.
    </text>
</law>