<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218" level="3">District Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Clerks;  Appointment;  Number;  Retirement;  Vacation And Sick Leave</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
          Each district court shall have a clerk and the central division of the Boston municipal court department shall have one clerk as provided in section 52A. All such clerks shall be appointed by the governor, with the advice and consent of the council. Said clerks shall hold office during good behavior, but subject, however, to retirement under the provisions of any applicable general or special law relative to retirement systems. Said clerk shall have responsibility for the internal administration of his office, including personnel, staff services and record keeping.[ Second paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  Each clerk appointed prior to January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-seven under the authority of this section and serving continuously thereafter shall be entitled to thirty days vacation and thirty days sick leave in each calendar year. Any such clerk may accumulate vacation and sick leave not used in any such year; provided, however, that the total amount of vacation days so accumulated shall not exceed sixty and the total amount of sick leave so accumulated shall not exceed one hundred and eighty days; and, provided further, that no additional such days shall be accumulated on or after said January first except in accordance with the policies and procedures established by the chief justice for administration and management pursuant to section eight of chapter two hundred and eleven B. All other clerks appointed under the authority of this section shall be entitled to vacation leave and sick leave in accordance with the policies and procedures established by the chief justice for administration and management pursuant to said section eight.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 79 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  Each clerk appointed prior to January first, nineteen hundred and eighty-seven under the authority of this section and serving continuously thereafter shall be entitled to thirty days vacation and thirty days sick leave in each calendar year. Any such clerk may accumulate vacation and sick leave not used in any such year; provided, however, that the total amount of vacation days so accumulated shall not exceed sixty and the total amount of sick leave so accumulated shall not exceed one hundred and eighty days; and, provided further, that no additional such days shall be accumulated on or after said January first except in accordance with the policies and procedures established by the court administrator pursuant to section eight of chapter two hundred and eleven B. All other clerks appointed under the authority of this section shall be entitled to vacation leave and sick leave in accordance with the policies and procedures established by the court administrator pursuant to said section eight.
    </text>
</law>