<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221A" order_by="221A" level="3">The Massachusetts Legal Assistance Corporation Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter, the following words and terms shall have the following meanings:— 
“Board”, the board of directors of the Massachusetts Legal Assistance Corporation. 
“Corporation”, the Massachusetts Legal Assistance Corporation. 
“Eligible client”, any indigent person who is a resident of the commonwealth. 
“Fee generating case”, any matter which, if undertaken on behalf of an eligible client by an attorney in private practice, may reasonably be expected to result in payment of the fee of such attorney from an award to the client or by the opposing party. 
“Fiscal year”, the twelve-month period beginning on July first and ending on June thirtieth. 
“Fund”, the Legal Assistance Fund. 
“Indigent person”, a person who receives public assistance under the Massachusetts Aid to Families with Dependent Children, general relief or veterans’ benefits programs or receives assistance under Title XVI of the Social Security Act, or the Medicaid Program, 42 USC 1396 to 1396(n), inclusive, or a person whose income, after taxes, is one hundred and twenty-five per cent or less of the current poverty threshold annually established by the United States Office of Management and Budget, or a person who is otherwise considered indigent due to hardship circumstances under standards established by the board. 
“Local program”, a qualified legal services program serving clients in an area limited to certain counties, cities, or towns of the commonwealth. 
“Qualified legal services program”, a nonprofit program which provides legal services in civil cases without charge to indigent persons and has a board of directors composed of both attorneys and consumers of legal services. Legal services programs which have been or are funded in whole or in part by the Legal Services Corporation established pursuant to 42 USC 2996 to 2996(l), inclusive, shall be presumed to be qualified legal services programs. 
“Recipient”, a qualified legal services program receiving financial assistance under this chapter. 
“Statewide program”, a qualified legal services program serving eligible clients, or providing support services to local programs throughout the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>