<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221" order_by="221" level="3">Clerks, Attorneys And Other Officers Of Judicial Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assistant Clerks; Appointment</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Introductory paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  In addition to the assistant clerks provided for in section four, the clerks of the courts for the following counties may, subject to the approval of the chief justice for administration and management as to compliance with personnel standards promulgated pursuant to section 8 of chapter 211B, appoint assistant clerks with the same powers and duties. Said appointments shall be as follows:[ Introductory paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 94 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  In addition to the assistant clerks provided for in section four, the clerks of the courts for the following counties may, subject to the approval of the court administrator as to compliance with personnel standards promulgated pursuant to section 8 of chapter 211B, appoint assistant clerks with the same powers and duties. Said appointments shall be as follows:  Barnstable, 2 assistant clerks  Bristol, 9 assistant clerks  Essex, 11 assistant clerks  Hampden, 12 assistant clerks  Nantucket, 1 assistant clerk  Norfolk, 11 assistant clerks  Middlesex, 26 assistant clerks  Plymouth, 6 assistant clerks  Worcester, 11 assistant clerksSuffolk, (a) superior court department, by the clerk of the superior court department for criminal business, 22 assistants; (b) superior court department, by the clerk of the superior court department for civil business, 26 assistants; (c) supreme judicial court, by the clerk of the supreme judicial court for said county, a second assistant clerk, designated from his office force and a third assistant clerk, designated from his office force.
    </text>
</law>