<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221" order_by="221" level="3">Clerks, Attorneys And Other Officers Of Judicial Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>70</section_number>
    <catch_line>Appointment;  Security Of John Adams Courthouse</catch_line>
    <order_by>70</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  Subject to appropriation, the chief justice for administration and management may appoint for attendance upon the several sessions of the trial court such officers as he deems necessary for the efficient operation of said court.  If a trial court department shall locate to the John Adams courthouse, the chief justice for administration and management shall assign such security personnel, who may be court officers or associate court officers, as are sufficient to meet the security needs in the areas of the John Adams courthouse occupied by any such trial court department.
Chapter 221: Appointment; security of John Adams courthouse
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 98 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  Subject to appropriation, the court administrator may appoint for attendance upon the several sessions of the trial court such officers as he deems necessary for the efficient operation of said court.  If a trial court department shall locate to the John Adams courthouse, the court administrator shall assign such security personnel, who may be court officers or associate court officers, as are sufficient to meet the security needs in the areas of the John Adams courthouse occupied by any such trial court department.
    </text>
</law>