<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211" level="3">The Supreme Judicial Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Transfer Of Causes Between Supreme Judicial Court And Lower Courts</catch_line>
    <order_by>4A</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Motions for relief from judgment rendered by the supreme judicial court.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Civil actions under section five of chapter two hundred and forty-nine against the supreme judicial court or the appeals court or a judicial officer thereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Dismissal under section thirteen of chapter fifty-eight A of appeals from the appellate tax board or stays of execution of sentence after exceptions or appeal under section forty-nine A of chapter two hundred and seventy-nine.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Any matter incidental to the exclusive appellate jurisdiction of the full court for which provision may hereafter be made; and further provided, that no transfer shall be made to any court other than the appeals court of the following:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Civil actions under section five of chapter two hundred and forty-nine against any court other than the supreme judicial court or the appeals court or a judicial officer thereof;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Stays of execution of sentence after the filing or allowance of exceptions or the entry of an appeal under section four of chapter two hundred and seventy-nine; reductions of bail under section fifty-eight of chapter two hundred and seventy-six; summary review of questions of law pertaining to issuance or denial of preliminary injunctions in labor dispute cases under subsection (6) of section six of chapter two hundred and fourteen; summary review of workers’ compensation orders pending appeal under section sixty A of chapter one hundred and fifty-two; suspension, modification or annulment of orders or judgments under section one hundred and seventeen of chapter two hundred and thirty-one pending an appeal; and stays of orders or decrees in equity and other certain matters in the probate court under sections twenty-three and twenty-four of chapter two hundred and fifteen.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>