<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211" level="3">The Supreme Judicial Court</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>26</section_number>
    <catch_line>Program For Evaluation Of Judicial Performance</catch_line>
    <order_by>26</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  A majority of the supreme judicial court, in consultation with the chief justice for administration and management shall design and implement a program for performance evaluation of judges. The sole purpose of said program shall be the improvement of the performance of individual judges and of the judiciary as a whole and, notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, all information compiled by said program shall be confidential. Said court may consult with individuals and organizations and may contract for technical assistance for the purpose of said program to the extent it deems necessary.
Chapter 211: Program for evaluation of judicial performance
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 47 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  A majority of the supreme judicial court, in consultation with the chief justice of the trial court shall design and implement a program for performance evaluation of judges. The sole purpose of said program shall be the improvement of the performance of individual judges and of the judiciary as a whole and, notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, all information compiled by said program shall be confidential. Said court may consult with individuals and organizations and may contract for technical assistance for the purpose of said program to the extent it deems necessary.
    </text>
</law>