<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217" level="3">Judges And Registers Of Probate And Insolvency</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Administrative Deputy Assistants</catch_line>
    <order_by>23B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Introductory paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The registers of probate of the respective courts of the probate and family court department for the following counties may, subject to the approval of the chief justice for administration and management as to compliance with personnel standards promulgated pursuant to section 8 of chapter 211B, appoint 1 or more administrative deputy assistants; provided, however, that administrative deputy assistants may be removed at the pleasure of the registers of probate. The administrative deputy assistants shall meet the definition of both confidential and managerial employees as those terms appear in chapter 150E and shall perform no official judicial duties. The appointments shall be as follows:[ Introductory paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 77 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The registers of probate of the respective courts of the probate and family court department for the following counties may, subject to the approval of the court administrator as to compliance with personnel standards promulgated pursuant to section 8 of chapter 211B, appoint 1 or more administrative deputy assistants; provided, however, that administrative deputy assistants may be removed at the pleasure of the registers of probate. The administrative deputy assistants shall meet the definition of both confidential and managerial employees as those terms appear in chapter 150E and shall perform no official judicial duties. The appointments shall be as follows:  Barnstable, 1 administrative deputy assistant  Essex, 1 administrative deputy assistant  Middlesex, 4 administrative deputy assistants  Norfolk, 1 administrative deputy assistant  Plymouth, 1 administrative deputy assistant  Suffolk, 2 administrative deputy assistants  Worcester, 2 administrative deputy assistants.
    </text>
</law>