<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="221" order_by="221" level="3">Clerks, Attorneys And Other Officers Of Judicial Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>71</section_number>
    <catch_line>Chief Deputy Sheriff For Suffolk, Middlesex And Hampden;  Chief Court Officer For Hampden, Norfolk And Worcester Counties</catch_line>
    <order_by>71</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The chief justice for administration and management shall designate a court officer to act as chief deputy sheriff for attendance on each superior court in Suffolk, Middlesex, and Hampden counties. In Hampden, Norfolk and Worcester counties the chief justice for administration and management may designate one court officer as chief court officer for attendance on the superior court. Such officers, under the orders of the chief justice for administration and management, in addition to their regular duties as court officers, shall supervise, direct and assign the officers of their respective courts.
Chapter 221: Chief deputy sheriff for Suffolk, Middlesex and Hampden; chief court officer for Hampden, Norfolk and Worcester counties
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 100 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The chief justice of the trial court shall designate a court officer to act as chief deputy sheriff for attendance on each superior court in Suffolk, Middlesex, and Hampden counties. In Hampden, Norfolk and Worcester counties the chief justice of the trial court may designate one court officer as chief court officer for attendance on the superior court. Such officers, under the orders of the chief justice of the trial court, in addition to their regular duties as court officers, shall supervise, direct and assign the officers of their respective courts.
    </text>
</law>