<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="211B" order_by="211B" level="3">Trial Court Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Estimates Of Expenses, Costs And Revenue</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The first justice of each division or court within the superior, probate and family, land, housing, juvenile, Boston municipal and district court departments of the trial court of the commonwealth, or if there is no first justice the chief justice, shall periodically prepare and submit to the chief justice of the department an estimate, in detail, for the ordinary maintenance of the division or place for holding court, and all revenues therefrom as provided in clause (5) of the first paragraph of section three of chapter twenty-nine. Said estimate shall include judicial salaries and the salaries of all officers and employees within the division or place for holding court and shall include estimates of all sums which the commonwealth is obligated to pay under the provisions of chapter twenty-nine A, together with any other information which the chief justice may require. The clerk of courts for each county, the clerk for criminal business for Suffolk county, the clerk for civil business for Suffolk county and the registers of probate in each county shall periodically prepare and submit to the chief administrative justice an estimate, in detail, for the ordinary maintenance of the office, and all revenue therefrom as provided in clause (5) of the first paragraph of section three of chapter twenty-nine. Said estimate shall include salaries of all officers and employees within the office and shall include estimates of all sums which the commonwealth is obligated to pay under the provisions of chapter twenty-nine A, together with any other information which the chief administrative justice may require.[ First paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 58 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The first justice of each division or court within the superior, probate and family, land, housing, juvenile, Boston municipal and district court departments of the trial court of the commonwealth, or if there is no first justice the chief justice, shall periodically prepare and submit to the chief justice of the department an estimate, in detail, for the ordinary maintenance of the division or place for holding court, and all revenues therefrom as provided in clause (5) of the first paragraph of section three of chapter twenty-nine. Said estimate shall include judicial salaries and the salaries of all officers and employees within the division or place for holding court and shall include estimates of all sums which the commonwealth is obligated to pay under the provisions of chapter twenty-nine A, together with any other information which the chief justice may require. The clerk of courts for each county, the clerk for criminal business for Suffolk county, the clerk for civil business for Suffolk county and the registers of probate in each county shall periodically prepare and submit to the court administrator an estimate, in detail, for the ordinary maintenance of the office, and all revenue therefrom as provided in clause (5) of the first paragraph of section three of chapter twenty-nine. Said estimate shall include salaries of all officers and employees within the office and shall include estimates of all sums which the commonwealth is obligated to pay under the provisions of chapter twenty-nine A, together with any other information which the court administrator may require.  In the case of the district, juvenile, housing, and Boston municipal court departments the first justice of a division thereof shall consult with the clerk of his division in the preparation of his budget estimate.[ Third paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The chief justice of each department shall review such estimates of the divisions or courts within his department and shall periodically submit to the chief administrative justice for review and approval an estimate of the amount required for all expenses and costs of his entire department, except as otherwise provided in this section.[ Third paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 58 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The chief justice of each department shall review such estimates of the divisions or courts within his department and shall periodically submit to the court administrator for review and approval an estimate of the amount required for all expenses and costs of his entire department, except as otherwise provided in this section.
    </text>
</law>