<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="3" order_by="3" level="1">Courts, Judicial Officers And Proceedings In Civil Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Courts And Judicial Officers</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218" level="3">District Courts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>42A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Administrative Head Of District Court Department</catch_line>
    <order_by>42A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The justice, as provided under section one of chapter two hundred and eleven B, as the chief justice for the district court department, in addition to his judicial powers and duties, shall, subject to the superintendence authority of the supreme judicial court as provided in section three of chapter two hundred and eleven and the administrative authority of the chief justice for administration and management be the administrative head of the district court department.  In addition to the powers conferred in section ten of said chapter two hundred and eleven B, said chief justice shall have the powers and duties prescribed in sections forty-three to forty-three D, inclusive, of this chapter and in such other provision of statute. A chief justice shall hold said office for a term of five years, and shall be eligible to be reappointed for additional five-year terms. A chief justice, so appointed, may be removed from that office prior to the expiration of his term upon a determination by the chief justice for administration and management that such removal is in the best interests of the administration of justice.
Chapter 218: Chief justice; powers and duties
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 83 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The justice, as provided under section 1 of chapter 211B, as the chief justice for the district court department, in addition to his judicial powers and duties, shall, subject to the superintendence authority of the supreme judicial court as provided in section 3 of chapter 211, have the power, authority and responsibility of a chief justice as set forth in section 10 of chapter 211B.  In addition to the powers conferred in section 10 of said chapter 211B, said chief justice shall have the powers and duties prescribed in sections 43 to 43B, inclusive, and in such other provision of statute.
    </text>
</law>