<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="54" order_by="54" level="3">Elections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>143</section_number>
    <catch_line>County Treasurers; Registers Of Deeds</catch_line>
    <order_by>143</order_by>
    <text>
        Upon failure to choose a county treasurer or a register of deeds for a county or district, except Suffolk and Nantucket counties, the county commissioners shall forthwith issue precepts to the aldermen of each city and the selectmen of each town in such county or district, directing them to call an election for the election of such officer on a day appointed therein. 
Upon a vacancy by removal or otherwise in the office of county treasurer or of register of deeds in a county or district, except in Suffolk and Nantucket counties, the county commissioners shall in like manner issue precepts for an election to fill such vacancy at the next biennial state election for which precepts can be seasonably issued, unless the term of the office expires on the first Wednesday of January following such state election, and may appoint some person to fill such office until a person is elected thereto and qualified. The person so appointed shall give bond as provided in section three of chapter thirty-five or section three of chapter thirty-six, as the case may be. 
Upon failure to choose a register of deeds in Suffolk county, or upon a vacancy in that office, the city council of Boston shall call meetings to elect a register of deeds or to fill such vacancy, as is above provided for an election in other counties; and, upon a vacancy in that office in said Suffolk county, the superior court shall appoint some person to the office until a person is elected thereto and qualified. 
Upon failure to choose a register of deeds in Nantucket county, or upon a vacancy in that office, the selectmen of the town of Nantucket shall call a meeting to elect a register of deeds as is above provided for an election in other counties, and may appoint some person to the office until a person is elected thereto and qualified.
    </text>
</law>