<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="55C" order_by="55C" level="3">Limited Public Financing Of Campaignsfor Statewide Elective Office</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Qualifying Candidates</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        On or before the ninth Tuesday before the primary election in any year in which elections are held for statewide elective office the state secretary shall determine and certify to the director and the state treasurer the names and addresses of all candidates for statewide elective office who qualify for the primary ballot and are opposed, by one or more candidates who have qualified for the same ballot in the primary election. For purposes of this chapter any candidate for statewide elective office for whom certificates of nomination and nomination papers have been filed in apparent conformity with law shall be considered qualified for the ballot notwithstanding any objections thereto that may be filed and notwithstanding any vacancy that may occur following the filing of such certificates of nominations and nomination papers other than a vacancy caused by withdrawal of a candidate within the time allowed by law. On or before the fifth Tuesday before the state election in any such year the state secretary shall determine and certify to the director and to the state treasurer the names and addresses of all candidates for statewide elective office who qualify for the state election ballot and are opposed by one or more candidates who have qualified for the state election ballot. For purposes of this chapter any candidate for statewide elective office for whom certificates of nomination and nomination papers have been filed in apparent conformity with law shall be considered qualified for the ballot, as provided with respect to candidates for the primary election, and any, such candidates nominated at the primary election shall be considered qualified for the ballot notwithstanding any objections thereto that may be filed and notwithstanding any vacancy that may occur other than a vacancy caused by withdrawal of a candidate within the time allowed by law. The state secretary shall promptly determine and certify to the director and state treasurer the name and address of any candidate that no longer qualifies for the primary or state election ballot or no longer has opposition because of death or withdrawal or ineligibility for office or because objections to certificates of nomination and nomination papers have been sustained or because of a recount or for any other like reason.
    </text>
</law>