<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="55" order_by="55" level="3">Disclosure And Regulation Of Campaign Expenditures And Contributions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Electioneering Communication Expenditures</catch_line>
    <order_by>18F</order_by>
    <text>
        Every individual, group or association not defined as a political committee who makes an electioneering communication expenditure, in an aggregate amount exceeding $250 during a calendar year, shall electronically file with the director, within 7 days after making such an expenditure, a report stating the name and address of the individual, group or association making the electioneering communication, the name of any candidate clearly identified in the communication, the total amount or value of the communication, the name and address of the vendor to whom the payments were made and the purpose and date of any such expenditure. In addition, any individual, group or association not defined as a political committee who makes an electioneering communication expenditure, in an aggregate amount exceeding $250 during a calendar year, who receives funds for the purpose of making such electioneering communications shall include in the electronic filing the date the funds were received and the name and address of the provider of any such funds in excess of $250, if any. Reports required by this section shall be filed with the director as provided in section 18C if communications were made to promote the election or defeat of any candidate who files with the director. Reports required by this section shall be filed with the city or town clerk if the communications were made to promote the election or defeat of any candidate seeking public office at a city or town election who does not otherwise file with the director. 
Any person, group or association that makes or contracts to make electioneering communications aggregating $1,000 or more within 7 days before the date of an election shall file a report containing the information required by this section within 48 hours after making such expenditure. 
A violation of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than $5,000 or by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 1 year.
    </text>
</law>