<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="54" order_by="54" level="3">Elections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>76B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Failure To Present Voter Identification; Right To Challenge Vote</catch_line>
    <order_by>76B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Except as provided in subsection (b), a person desiring to vote, who fails to present suitable written identification when so requested by an election officer, shall be permitted to vote, but that person’s right to vote may be challenged under section 85.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     the person registered to vote in the city or town by mail after January 1, 2003; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     the person has not previously voted in an election for federal office in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     in the case of a person who votes in person:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     presents to the appropriate election officer a current and valid photo identification; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     presents to the appropriate election officer a copy of a current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck, or other government document that shows the name and address of the voter; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     in the case of a person who votes by absentee ballot, submits with the ballot:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     a copy of a current and valid photo identification; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     a copy of a current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck, or other government document that shows the name and address of the voter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     A person who desires to vote by absentee ballot but who does not meet the requirements of subclause (ii) of said clause (a) of said subparagraph (A) may return the absentee ballot by mail, and the ballot shall be treated as a provisional ballot under section 76C.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a person:
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     who registers to vote by mail and submits as part of that registration either:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     a copy of a current and valid photo identification; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     a copy of a current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck, or government document that shows the name and address of the voter;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     who registers to vote by mail and submits with that registration either:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     a driver’s license number;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     at least the last 4 digits of the individual’s social security number; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     with respect to whom the city or town clerk matches the information submitted under clause (i) with an existing state identification record bearing the same number, name and date of birth as provided in that registration; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     who:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     is entitled to vote by absentee ballot under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 42 U.S.C. sections 1973ff-1 et seq.;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     is provided the right to vote otherwise than in person under section 3(b)(2)(B)(ii) of the Voting Accessibility for the Elderly and Handicapped Act, 42 U.S.C. section 1973ee-1(b)(2); or
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     is otherwise entitled by federal law to vote otherwise than in person.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>