<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="55" order_by="55" level="3">Disclosure And Regulation Of Campaign Expenditures And Contributions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Campaign Contributions To Candidates From Individuals;  Limitation;  Contributions From Legislative And Executive Agents;  Contributions From Gaming Licensee</catch_line>
    <order_by>7A</order_by>
    <text>
          (a)(1) An individual may make campaign contributions to candidates or candidate's committees; provided, however, that the aggregate of all such contributions for the benefit of any one candidate and that candidate's committee shall not exceed the sum of five hundred dollars in any calendar year.  (2) An individual may in addition make campaign contributions for the benefit of elected political committees or non-elected political committees organized on behalf of a political party; provided, however, that the aggregate of such campaign contributions for the benefit of the political committees of any one political party shall not exceed in any one calendar year the sum of five thousand dollars.  (3) An individual may in addition make campaign contributions to any political committee not specified in paragraph (1), (2) or (4); provided, however, that the aggregate of such campaign contributions to any one such political committee shall not exceed in any one calendar year the sum of five hundred dollars.  (4) An individual may in addition make contributions without limitation to ballot question committees.  (5) Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the aggregate of all contributions from any one individual to all candidates and candidate's committees shall not exceed the sum of twelve thousand five hundred dollars in any one calendar year.  (b) Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the aggregate of all contributions by a legislative or executive agent for the benefit of any one candidate and such candidate's committee shall not exceed the sum of two hundred dollars in any one calendar year. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the aggregate of all contributions by a legislative or executive agent to any other political committee, other than a ballot question committee, shall not exceed the sum of two hundred dollars in any one calendar year.[ Subsection (c) added by 2011, 194, Sec. 24 effective November 22, 2011.]  (c) The aggregate of all contributions by a person who holds a license issued by the Massachusetts gaming commission, who was required to apply for that license under section 14 of chapter 23K, for the benefit of any 1 candidate and such candidate's committee shall not exceed $200 in a calendar year. The aggregate of all contributions by a person who holds a license issued by the Massachusetts gaming commission, who was required to apply for that license under said section 14 of said chapter 23K, for the benefit of any other political committee, other than a ballot question committee, shall not exceed $200 in a calendar year.
    </text>
</law>