<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="55C" order_by="55C" level="3">Limited Public Financing Of Campaignsfor Statewide Elective Office</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bond For Faithful Compliance</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        No candidate shall be eligible to receive public financing under this chapter unless and until the candidate deposits with the director a bond for the faithful compliance by such candidate and any political committee organized on his behalf with the provisions of this chapter. Such bond shall be in a form approved by the director, shall be signed by such candidate and the chairman and treasurer of any such committee, shall run to the commonwealth, shall be in force during the year in which elections for statewide elective office are held and for the following calendar year. The bond deposited for the purpose of receiving public financing for the primary election campaign must be for the amount which the comptroller has credited to the account established on behalf of that candidate for the primary election campaign. The bond deposited for the purpose of receiving public financing for the state election campaign must be for the amount which the comptroller has credited to the account established on behalf of that candidate for the state election campaign, but in the case of a candidate for governor, the bond on behalf of said candidate shall be in the amount which the comptroller has credited to the account established on behalf of that governor and lieutenant governor team. 
On determination by the director that a candidate has failed to make the payments to the state treasurer required by section 9 the director may request the attorney general to bring an action in the name of the state treasurer upon the bond of such candidate and his political committee and may recover for the benefit of the state election campaign fund, up to the sum of such bond, any such payments so required. Any such action shall be in addition to remedies otherwise available by law and no action on any such bond shall preclude the director from bringing such other civil or criminal proceedings as may otherwise be provided by law.
    </text>
</law>