<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="53" order_by="53" level="3">Nominations, Questions To Be Submitted To The Voters, Primaries And Caucuses</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>56</section_number>
    <catch_line>Primaries For Nomination; Submission Of Question; Notice Of Result To State Secretary</catch_line>
    <order_by>56</order_by>
    <text>
        In any city or town which has adopted the provisions of law for nominating by primaries, the following question shall be put on the official ballot at any city election or annual town meeting on petition of five per cent of the voters registered at the time of the preceding city election or annual town meeting, filed with the city or town clerk on or before the last day for filing nomination papers: “Shall primaries for the nomination of candidates to be voted for at city (or town) elections continue to be held in this city (or town)?” In any city or town not nominating by primaries, where such nominations are permitted by law, the following question may, by similar petition, be put on the ballot at the next city election or annual town meeting: “Shall primaries for the nomination of candidates to be voted for at city (or town) elections be held in this city (or town)?” In accordance with the result of such vote, such primaries shall or shall not thereafter be held. 
Clerks of cities or towns which vote to hold primaries or to rescind such action shall forthwith notify the state secretary of such vote. 
The provisions of law relative to the signing of nomination papers of candidates for state office, and to the identification and certification of names thereon and submission to the registrars therefor, shall apply, so far as apt, to the signing of petitions under this section and to the identification and certification of names thereon.
    </text>
</law>