<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="55C" order_by="55C" level="3">Limited Public Financing Of Campaignsfor Statewide Elective Office</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Minimum Financing Available; State Election</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        Any candidate for statewide elective office certified by the state secretary under section two as qualifying for the ballot and having opposition in the state election shall be eligible to receive limited public financing of his state election campaign, to the extent provided by section 7, on determination and certification by the director that the candidate (a) has filed a request for public financing with the director together with the bond required by section 8; (b) has filed with the director a statement under subsection (a) of section 1A agreeing to abide by the expenditure limits provided thereby; and (c) has received qualifying contributions as defined by section 1 in at least the following minimum amounts for the following statewide elective offices: 
Governor and Lieutenant Governor  $125,000 
Attorney General  62,500 
Secretary  25,000 
Treasurer and Receiver General  25,000 
Auditor  25,000 
Only amounts appearing in statements of qualifying contributions filed with the director, in such form as he shall prescribe, shall be considered in determining whether any such minimum amount has been met. Determination and certification of the eligibility of candidates shall be made by the director on the fourth Tuesday before the state election and shall be based solely upon information contained in such statements as have been filed by candidates. Candidates for governor and lieutenant governor seeking public financing shall file the statement on or before the Friday that is 11 days preceding said fourth Tuesday and other candidates seeking public financing shall file said statements on or before the Friday next preceding said fourth Tuesday. 
The fact that a qualifying contribution has previously been considered in determining eligibility for, or the extent of, public financing of a candidate’s primary election campaign shall not prevent consideration of the same contribution in determining eligibility for public financing of such candidate’s state election campaign.
    </text>
</law>