<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="2">Elections</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="54" order_by="54" level="3">Elections</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>32</section_number>
    <catch_line>Examination And Approval Of Voting Equipment</catch_line>
    <order_by>32</order_by>
    <text>
        The state secretary shall examine all types of voting equipment including ballot boxes, counting apparatus, and voting machines and determine whether such equipment complies with the minimum requirements for such equipment imposed by law and whether the use of such equipment would further the efficient administration of elections. 
Any person owning or interested in such equipment may submit it to the state secretary for examination. For the purpose of assistance in examining such new equipment, the secretary, subject to appropriation, may employ not more than three individuals who are experts in one or more of the fields of data processing, mechanical engineering and public administration. 
Within thirty days after completing the examination and approval of any such equipment the state secretary shall make and file in his office his report on the equipment together with a written or printed description and drawings and photographs clearly identifying the equipment. As soon as practicable after such filing, the state secretary upon request shall send a copy of the report to any governing body within the state. 
Any voting equipment that receives the approval of the state secretary may be used for conducting elections. Any voting equipment that does not receive such approval shall not be adopted for or used at any election. After such equipment has been approved by the state secretary, any change or improvement in the equipment that does not impair its accuracy, efficiency or capacity shall not render necessary a reexamination or reapproval of the equipment. 
All voting equipment being used upon the effective date of this act shall within twelve months of said effective date be submitted to the state secretary for his approval. Within twenty-four months of the effective date of this act the secretary shall approve or disapprove of such equipment and promulgate uniform regulations for such equipment in accordance with section thirty-seven.
    </text>
</law>