<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="185" order_by="185" level="3">The Land Court And Registration Of Title To Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>101</section_number>
    <catch_line>Grounds For Recovery From Fund; Exhausting Other Remedies;  Continuance Of Action To Await Result Of Tort Action</catch_line>
    <order_by>101</order_by>
    <text>
        A person who, without negligence on his part, sustains loss or damage by reason of any error, omission, mistake or misdescription in any certificate of title or in any entry or memorandum in a registration book, or a person who, without negligence on his part, is deprived of land or of any estate or interest therein, by the registration of another person as owner of such land or of any estate or interest therein, through fraud or in consequence of any error, omission, mistake or misdescription in any certificate of title or in any entry or memorandum in a registration book may institute an action in contract in the superior court for compensation from the assurance fund for such loss, damage or deprivation; but a person so deprived of land or of any estate or interest therein, having a right of action or other remedy for the recovery of such land, estate or interest, shall exhaust such remedy before resorting to the action of contract herein provided. This section shall not deprive the plaintiff of any action of tort which he may have against any person for such loss or damage or deprivation of land or of any estate or interest therein. If the plaintiff elects to pursue his remedy in tort, and also brings an action of contract under this chapter, the action of contract shall be continued to await the result of the action of tort.
    </text>
</law>