<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183" level="3">Alienation Of Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>54</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions; Method Of Discharge</catch_line>
    <order_by>54</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purposes of sections 54 to 55, inclusive, the following words, unless the context otherwise requires, shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A mortgage may be discharged by 1 of 2 or more joint holders of a mortgage or the mortgagee, mortgage servicer or note holder, or an heir, executor, administrator, successor or assignee thereof, but, the discharge shall comply with the requirements of subsection (b) of section 55. The discharge shall have the same effect as a deed of release, and may be recorded when duly executed and acknowledged or on proof of its execution in accordance with sections 34 to 41, inclusive, or on such other proof of its due execution by credible evidence in the form of corroborating documents or affidavits establishing the authenticity of the discharge and the execution thereof and, in that case, the discharge and the corroborating documents or affidavits may be recorded along with or as exhibits to an affidavit under section 5B that refers to the documents or affidavits. The recordation of a duly executed and acknowledged or proven discharge as provided herein shall be conclusive evidence that the mortgage has been discharged, notwithstanding the fact that the party signing the instrument may have assigned the note or other evidence of debt to another party, unless the assignment had been duly recorded before the instrument discharging the mortgage. If a discharge is executed by a person who is not the holder of record at the time the discharge is recorded, the recorded discharge shall become conclusive when an assignment of mortgage from the then record holder or holders to that person is thereafter recorded. A discharge shall contain the street address of the mortgaged property, the book number and page number or the land court document number and recording date of the mortgage, and the name of the original mortgagor; but, the failure to include the information shall not affect the validity of the instrument. This section shall apply notwithstanding section 3-116 of chapter 106.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>