<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="185C" order_by="185C" level="3">Housing Court Department</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Sittings Of Court</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The western division of the housing court department shall hold its sittings in the city of Springfield in Hampden county and at least one sitting each week in courthouse facilities in Berkshire, Franklin and Hampshire counties. The court, with the consent of the chief administrative justice and management shall also sit in such other courthouse facilities as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.[ First paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 30 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The western division of the housing court department shall hold its sittings in the city of Springfield in Hampden county and at least one sitting each week in courthouse facilities in Berkshire, Franklin and Hampshire counties. The court, with the consent of the chief justice of the trial court shall also sit in such other courthouse facilities as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.[ Second through fifth paragraphs effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The division of the housing court department for the city of Boston shall hold its sittings in the Suffolk county courthouse and, with the consent of the chief justice for administration and management, in such other courthouse facilities within the city of Boston as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.  The division of the housing court department for Worcester county shall hold its sittings in the facilities of the Worcester county courthouse in the city of Worcester and at regular and frequent intervals in a district courthouse in the northern and southern areas of said county, but in no event less frequently than once per week in each of said northern and southern areas. The court, with the consent of the chief justice for administration and management shall also sit in such other courthouse facilities within said county as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.  The northeastern division of the housing court department shall hold its sittings in the courthouse facilities located in the city of Lawrence and at regular and frequent intervals at the courthouse facilities in the city of Salem, including at least one sitting each week in Salem, including one sitting each week in the city of Lowell, and also at least one sitting each week in the courthouse facilities in either the city of Lynn or the city of Peabody or the city of Haverhill. The court, with consent of the chief justice for administration and management shall also sit in such other courthouse facilities as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.  The southeastern division of the housing court department shall hold its sittings in the courthouse facilities located in the city of Taunton and at regular and frequent intervals at the courthouse facilities in the cities of Brockton, Fall River and New Bedford; provided, however, that said southeastern division shall hold at least two sittings each week in Plymouth county and two sittings each week in Bristol county. The court, with the consent of the chief justice for administration and management shall also sit in such other courthouse facilities as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.[ Second through fifth paragraphs as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 31 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The division of the housing court department for the city of Boston shall hold its sittings in the Suffolk county courthouse and, with the consent of the chief justice of the trial court, in such other courthouse facilities within the city of Boston as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.  The division of the housing court department for Worcester county shall hold its sittings in the facilities of the Worcester county courthouse in the city of Worcester and at regular and frequent intervals in a district courthouse in the northern and southern areas of said county, but in no event less frequently than once per week in each of said northern and southern areas. The court, with the consent of the chief justice of the trial court shall also sit in such other courthouse facilities within said county as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.  The northeastern division of the housing court department shall hold its sittings in the courthouse facilities located in the city of Lawrence and at regular and frequent intervals at the courthouse facilities in the city of Salem, including at least one sitting each week in Salem, including one sitting each week in the city of Lowell, and also at least one sitting each week in the courthouse facilities in either the city of Lynn or the city of Peabody or the city of Haverhill. The court, with consent of the chief justice of the trial court shall also sit in such other courthouse facilities as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.  The southeastern division of the housing court department shall hold its sittings in the courthouse facilities located in the city of Taunton and at regular and frequent intervals at the courthouse facilities in the cities of Brockton, Fall River and New Bedford; provided, however, that said southeastern division shall hold at least two sittings each week in Plymouth county and two sittings each week in Bristol county. The court, with the consent of the chief justice of the trial court shall also sit in such other courthouse facilities as the chief justice of the housing court department may deem to be expedient or convenient.
    </text>
</law>