<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="185" order_by="185" level="3">The Land Court And Registration Of Title To Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Salaries And Expenses;  Practice Of Law;  Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The salary of the recorder of the land court department shall be 81.57 per cent of the salary of the chief justice of said department and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salaries of the deputy recorder and the chief title examiner of said department shall be eighty-three and one-half percent of said recorder's salary and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salaries of the assistant clerks of said department shall be seventy-seven percent of said recorder's salary and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salaries of the title examiners of said department shall be paid by the commonwealth in accordance with the job classification and pay plan established, subject to appropriation, by the chief justice for administration and management.[ First paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 29 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The salary of the recorder of the land court department shall be 81.57 per cent of the salary of the chief justice of said department and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salaries of the deputy recorder and the chief title examiner of said department shall be eighty-three and one-half percent of said recorder's salary and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salaries of the assistant clerks of said department shall be seventy-seven percent of said recorder's salary and shall be paid, subject to appropriation, by the commonwealth. The salaries of the title examiners of said department shall be paid by the commonwealth in accordance with the job classification and pay plan established, subject to appropriation, by the court administrator.  The recorder, deputy recorder, chief title examiner, title examiners, and assistant clerks shall devote their entire time during business hours to their respective duties and shall not, directly or indirectly, engage in the practice of law.  All salaries and expenses of the court shall be paid by the commonwealth, except the salaries of the assistant recorders and the expenses incurred by them under this chapter and the compensation and expenses of their technical assistants appointed under section ten A, which shall be paid by the respective counties. All fees collected by the assistant recorders, except those received upon the filing of petitions, which shall be transmitted with the petitions to the recorder, shall be paid to their respective counties.
    </text>
</law>