<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="183B" order_by="183B" level="3">Real Estate Time Shares</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Instruments For Creation Of More Than Twelve Time Shares In Single Property; Recording; Contents</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Except as provided in subsection (b), more than twelve time-shares may be created in a single time-share property only by a time-share instrument recorded in the registry of deeds or land registration office for the district in which the time-share unit is situated. Said instrument shall contain or provide for the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     a legally sufficient description of the time-share property and the name or other identification of the project, if any, within which it is situated;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the name of the registry district or land registration office in which the time-share property is situated;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     identification of time periods by letter, name, number, or combination thereof;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     the time-share expense liability and any voting rights assigned to each time-share;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     if additional units may become part of the time-share property, the method of doing so and the formula for allocation and reallocation of the time-share expense liabilities and any votes;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     the method of designating the insurance trustee required under section twenty-six;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     allocation of time for maintenance of the time-share units;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     provisions for management by a managing entity or by the time-share owners;
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     if all of the time-shares are time-share licenses, the rights of a licensee, if his license is terminated, with respect to any of the property his license affects, or a statement that he has no rights; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     any requirements for amendments to the time-share instrument.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     If a time-share license applies to units in more than one time-share property, the time-share instrument creating the license need not comply with the provisions of clauses (1) to (7), inclusive, of subsection (a).
        </section>
    </text>
</law>