<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="183B" order_by="183B" level="3">Real Estate Time Shares</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>45</section_number>
    <catch_line>Express Warranties</catch_line>
    <order_by>45</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Express warranties made by any seller to a purchaser of a time-share shall be created as follows:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     any affirmation of fact or promise which relates to the time-share, the time-share unit, rights appurtenant to either, area improvements that would directly benefit the time-share, or the right to use or have the benefit of facilities not located on the time-share unit, creates an express warranty that the time-share, the time-share unit, and related rights and uses shall conform to the affirmation or promise;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     any model or description of the physical characteristics of the time-share property, including plans and specifications of or for improvements, creates an express warranty that the property shall conform to the model or description, provided, however, that this paragraph shall not preclude the substitution of items of substantially the same kind, function and quality as those in the model or description;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     any description of the quantity or extent of the real estate constituting the time-share property, including plats or surveys, creates an express warranty that the property shall conform to the description, subject to customary tolerances; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     a provision that a purchaser may put a time-share unit only to a specified use is an express warranty that the specified use is lawful.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Neither formal words, such as “warranty” or “guarantee”, nor a specific intention to make a warranty, shall be necessary to create an express warranty of quality, but a statement purporting to be merely an opinion or commendation of the time-share, the time-share unit, or the value of either shall not create a warranty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Any transfer of a time-share transfers to the purchaser all express warranties of quality made by previous sellers.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>