<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="183A" order_by="183A" level="3">Condominiums</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Master Deed; Recording; Contents</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The statement required by section two.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A description of the land on which the building or buildings and improvements are located.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A description of each building stating the number of stories, the number of units if there is more than one and the principal materials of which it is constructed.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The unit designation of each unit, and a statement of its location, approximate area, number of rooms, and immediate common area to which it has access, and any other data necessary for its proper identification.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A description of the common areas and facilities and the proportionate interest of each unit therein.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A set of the floor plans of the building or buildings, showing the layout, location, unit numbers and dimensions of the units, stating the name of the building or that it has not a name, and bearing the verified statement of a registered architect, registered professional engineer, or registered land surveyor, certifying that the plans fully and accurately depict the layout, location, unit number and dimensions of the units as built.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     A statement of the purposes for which the building and each of the units are intended and the restrictions, if any, as to their use.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     The method by which the master deed may be amended.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     The name and mailing address of the corporation, trust or association which has been formed and through which the unit owners will manage and regulate the condominium, together with a statement that such corporation, trust or association has enacted by-laws pursuant to this chapter. If a trust or unincorporated association is named, the master deed shall also set forth the names of the trustees or managing board. Changes in the trustees or members of the managing board, as the case may be, or changes in the mailing address of the organization of unit owners subsequent to the recording of the master deed, shall be stated in a certificate signed and acknowledged by at least one trustee or member of the managing board then appearing of record, or by a vote of the unit owners, and signed and acknowledged by one of them, and such certificate or vote shall be recorded in the registry of deeds or land registration office where the real estate is located. Persons may rely in good faith upon the master deed, declaration of trust, or the most recently recorded certificate or vote as to the names of the trustees or members of the managing board and the address of the organization of unit owners. Notices under this chapter sent in writing to the address listed in the master deed, declaration of trust, or the most recently recorded certificate or vote, if relied upon in good faith, shall be deemed sufficiently given; provided, however, that the person or entity sending the notice has complied with other requirements, if any, of this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     The name of the lessor of each lease which is submitted to the provisions of this chapter and the recording data for each such lease or notice thereof.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>