<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="185" order_by="185" level="3">The Land Court And Registration Of Title To Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Jurisdiction; Place Of Sittings; Rules And Forms Of Procedure</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Complaints for the confirmation and registration and complaints for the confirmation without registration of title to land and easements or rights in land held and possessed in fee simple within the commonwealth, with power to hear and determine all questions arising upon such complaints, and such other questions as may come before it under this chapter, subject to all rights to jury trial and of appeal provided by law. The proceedings upon such complaints shall be proceedings in rem against the land, and the judgments shall operate directly on the land and vest and establish title thereto. A certified copy of the judgment of confirmation and registration shall be filed and registered in the registry district or districts where the land or any portion thereof lies, as provided in section forty-eight, and a certificate of title in the form prescribed by law shall be issued pursuant thereto. Immediately upon the entry of a judgment of confirmation without registration, the recorder shall cause a certified copy of the same to be recorded in the registry of deeds for the district or districts where the land or any portion thereof lies, and thereafter, the land therein described shall be dealt with as unregistered land.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Proceedings for foreclosure of and for redemption from tax titles under chapter sixty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Actions to recover freehold estates under chapter two hundred and thirty-seven. In such an action brought in accordance with section forty-seven of chapter two hundred and thirty-six, where the tenant is entitled under clause (2) of section nine of chapter one hundred and nine A to retain the real estate as security for repayment of the consideration paid therefor by him, said court may determine the amount of such consideration and may order a judgment for possession upon being satisfied that such amount, with lawful interest, has been paid or tendered by the plaintiff to the defendant.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Petitions to require actions to try title to real estate, under sections one to five, inclusive, of chapter two hundred and forty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Complaints to determine the validity of encumbrances, under sections eleven to fourteen, inclusive, of chapter two hundred and forty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Complaints to discharge mortgages, under section fifteen of chapter two hundred and forty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Complaints under section twenty-seven of chapter two hundred and forty to establish power or authority to transfer an interest in real estate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Complaints to determine the boundaries of flats, under section nineteen of chapter two hundred and forty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Complaints under sections sixteen to eighteen, inclusive, of chapter two hundred and forty to determine whether or not equitable restrictions are enforceable.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Complaints under section twelve of chapter forty-two to determine county, city, town or district boundaries.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     All cases and matters cognizable under the general principles of equity jurisprudence where any right, title or interest in land is involved, including actions for specific performance of contracts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     Actions under clauses (4) and (10) of section 3 of chapter 214, where any right, title or interest in real estate is involved.
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     Actions under clause (8) of said section 3 of said chapter 214 or under section 9 of chapter 109A, where the property claimed to have been fraudulently conveyed or encumbered consists of rights, titles or interest in real estate only.
        </section>
        <section prefix="n">
    	     Proceedings transferred to it under the provisions of section 4A of chapter 211.
        </section>
        <section prefix="o">
    	     Civil actions of trespass to real estate involving title to real estate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="p">
    	     Actions brought pursuant to the provisions of sections 7 and 17 of chapter 40A.
        </section>
        <section prefix="q">
    	     Actions brought pursuant to sections 81B, 81V, 81Y, and 81BB of chapter 41.
        </section>
        <section prefix="r">
    	     Actions brought pursuant to section 4 or 5 of chapter 249 where any right, title or interest in land is involved, or which arise under or involve the subdivision control law, the zoning act, or municipal zoning, subdivision, or land-use ordinances, by-laws or regulations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="s">
    	     Actions brought pursuant to section 1 of chapter 245.
        </section>
        <section prefix="t">
    	     Petitions for partition under chapter 241.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>