<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="185" order_by="185" level="3">The Land Court And Registration Of Title To Land</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>46</section_number>
    <catch_line>Encumbrances Affecting Certificates Of Title</catch_line>
    <order_by>46</order_by>
    <text>
        Every plaintiff receiving a certificate of title in pursuance of a judgment of registration, and every subsequent purchaser of registered land taking a certificate of title for value and in good faith, shall hold the same free from all encumbrances except those noted on the certificate, and any of the following encumbrances which may be existing: 
First, Liens, claims or rights arising or existing under the laws or constitution of the United States or the statutes of this commonwealth which are not by law required to appear of record in the registry of deeds in order to be valid against subsequent purchasers or encumbrances of record. 
Second, Taxes, within three years after they have been committed to the collector. 
Third, Any highway, town way, or any private way laid out under section twenty-one of chapter eighty-two, if the certificate of title does not state that the boundary of such way has been determined. 
Fourth, Any lease for a term not exceeding seven years. 
Fifth, Any liability to assessment for betterments or other statutory liability, except for taxes payable to the commonwealth, which attaches to land in the commonwealth as a lien; but if there are easements or other rights appurtenant to a parcel of registered land which for any reason have failed to be registered, such easements or rights shall remain so appurtenant notwithstanding such failure, and shall be held to pass with the land until cut off or extinguished by the registration of the servient estate, or in any other manner. 
Sixth, Liens in favor of the United States for unpaid taxes arising or existing under the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 as amended from time to time and any other federal lien which may be filed in the commonwealth. 
Seventh, Liens in favor of the commonwealth for unpaid taxes arising or existing under the laws of the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>