<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="183A" order_by="183A" level="3">Condominiums</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Profits And Expenses; Lien</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     (i) Except as provided in paragraph (ii), all common expenses shall be assessed against all units either in accordance with their respective percentages of undivided interest in the common areas and facilities or, if stated in the master deed or an amendment thereto duly recorded in the approximate relation that the area of the unit bears to the aggregate area of all the units, which may take into account unit location, amenities in the unit, and limited common areas and facilities benefiting the unit; provided, however, that such an amendment shall require the consent of all unit owners whose common expense assessment is materially affected. The organization of unit owners shall have a lien on a unit for any common expense assessment levied against that unit from the time the assessment becomes due. Common expense assessments must be made at least annually, based on a budget adopted at least annually in accordance with the master deed, trust, or by-laws.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     If any expense is incurred by the organization of unit owners as a result of the unit owner’s failure to abide by the requirements of this chapter or the requirements of the master deed, trust, by-laws, restrictions, rules or regulations, or by the misconduct of any unit owner, or his family members, tenants, or invitees, the organization of unit owners may assess that expense exclusively against the unit owner and such assessment shall constitute a lien against that unit from the time the assessment is due, and such assessment shall be enforceable as a common expense assessment under this chapter. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (i), the organization of unit owners may assess the cost of maintaining, repairing or replacing a limited common area and facility, solely to the owner of the unit to which a limited common area and facility is appurtenant, allocated, or designated, and such assessment shall be enforceable as a common expense assessment under this chapter; in the alternative, the organization of unit owners may require the owner of the unit to which a limited common area and facility is appurtenant, allocated, or designated to maintain, repair, or replace such limited common area and facility without the intervention of the organization of unit owners. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (i), the organization of unit owners may assess to each unit owner the direct cost of any energy conservation device installed in a unit, not already separately metered for water and utilities, including but not limited to the installation of separate water meters, low-flow toilets and showerheads, faucet aerators, windows and storm windows; provided, however, that a unit owner required to install such energy conservation device hereunder may appeal to the board of trustees of the organization of unit owners or if there is no board of trustees, the entity performing its duties. Said board or entity of said organization, in its sole and reasonable discretion, may grant to such unit owner a waiver of such required installation upon such terms and conditions as the organization of unit owners shall deem fit. The cost thereof shall be collected in the same manner as common expense assessments under this chapter. The organization of unit owners may assess to each unit owner his proportionate share of the costs for water and other utilities, as measured by the meter attached to the unit; provided however, that the board of trustees of the organization of unit owners receives the approval of the majority of unit owners in attendance at a meeting, for which notice was duly given and which was held for the purposes of issuing such an assessment. A unit owner assessed costs hereunder may appeal the assessment to said board or entity of said organization of unit owners. Such appeal shall be in writing and shall set forth a clear and concise statement of reasons for an exemption from the assessment for the unit owners. Said board or entity of said organization, in its sole and reasonable discretion, may grant to said unit owner a waiver of the assessment provided herein upon such terms and conditions as the organization of unit owners shall deem fit. In the event of a conflict between this subsection and the master deed, trust, or bylaws, and any amendment thereto, of any condominium submitted to the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of this subsection shall control. Notwithstanding the aforesaid, nothing contained herein shall be construed to be in conflict with the provisions of the state sanitary code. The organization of unit owners may also assess any fees, attorneys’ fees, charges, late charges, fines, costs of collection and enforcement, court costs, and interest charged pursuant to this chapter against the unit owner and such assessment shall constitute a lien against the unit from the time the assessment is due, and shall be enforceable as common expense assessments under this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     Common profits shall be distributed among unit owners in the same manner as common expenses are charged to the unit owners.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The unit owner shall be personally liable for all sums assessed for his share of the common expenses including late charges, fines, penalties, and interest assessed by the organization of unit owners and all costs of collection including attorneys’ fees, costs, and charges.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     When any portion of the unit owner’s share of the common expenses has been delinquent for at least sixty days subsequent to April 1, 1993, the organization of unit owners shall send a notice stating the amount of the delinquency to the unit owner by certified and first class mail. The organization of unit owners shall also send a notice stating the amount of the delinquency to the first mortgagee by certified and first class mail, provided, that the first mortgagee has informed the organization of unit owners of its name and mailing address. Furthermore, thirty days prior to the filing of an action by the organization of unit owners to enforce its lien for delinquent common expenses, the organization of unit owners shall send a notice stating its intention to file said action to the first mortgagee by certified and first class mail, provided that the first mortgagee has informed the organization of unit owners of its name and mailing address. In the event of the appointment of a receiver for the condominium pursuant to the provisions of chapter one hundred and eleven, the lien for charges imposed for the payment of expenses incurred by the receiver shall have priority over all other liens and mortgages, except municipal liens.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A statement from the organization of unit owners setting forth the amount of unpaid common expenses and any other sums which have been assessed against a unit owner, including a statement of the amount which the organization of unit owners claims is entitled to priority with respect to any mortgage under subsection (c), shall operate to discharge the unit from any lien for other sums then unpaid when recorded in the appropriate registry of deeds; provided, however, that any statement or document issuing from an unincorporated organization of unit owners may be recorded in a registry of deeds and if so recorded shall indicate and specify therein the book and page, or document number if registered land, within such registry of the instrument from which the signatory or signatories of the statement obtained authority to sign on behalf of the unincorporated organization. The statement shall be furnished within ten business days after receipt of a written request, upon payment of a reasonable fee, and shall be binding on the organization of unit owners, the governing body of the organization of unit owners, and every unit owner; provided, however, that no fee shall be required of any mortgagee, in connection with a foreclosure of a mortgage, who has given the organization notice of its intention to foreclose a mortgage upon the unit.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>