<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Title To Real Property</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="188" order_by="188" level="3">Homesteads</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Set Off Of Homestead Estate To Insolvent Debtor; Appraisal Of Property</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section applicable as provided by 2010, 395, Sec. 3.] 
If the property of a debtor is assigned under the laws relative to insolvent debtors and debtor claims and it appears to the court wherein the insolvency proceedings are pending that the debtor is entitled to hold a part thereof as a homestead and that the property in which estate of homestead exists is of greater value than either the automatic homestead exemption or the declared homestead exemption, as applicable, the court shall cause the property to be appraised by 3 disinterested appraisers, 1 of whom shall be appointed by the insolvent debtor, 1 of whom shall be appointed by the assignee and 1 of whom shall be appointed by the court; provided, however, that if either the assignee or insolvent debtor fails to make such appointment, the court shall appoint an appraiser for the assignee or the insolvent debtor. The appraisers shall be sworn faithfully and impartially to appraise the property and shall appraise and set off an estate of homestead therein to the insolvent debtor in the manner prescribed in section 18 of chapter 236 for a judgment debtor and the residue shall vest in and be disposed of by the assignee in the same manner as property which is not exempt by law from levy on execution. The appraisers shall be entitled to the same fees, to be paid out of the estate in insolvency, as are allowed to appraisers of land seized upon execution.
    </text>
</law>