<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="103" order_by="103" level="3">Pilots</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Accounts Of Pilots; Payment Of Pilotage Fees To Commissioners;  Compensation Of Commissioners</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        [Text of section effective until the effective date of the initial pilotage rates established by the board pursuant to section 31A of chapter 103 of the General Laws. For text effective on the effective date of the initial pilotage rates established by the board pursuant to section 31A of chapter 103 of the General Laws, see below.] 
Once in every three months each pilot shall render to the commissioners for his district an accurate account of all vessels piloted by him and of all money received for pilotage by him or by any person for him, and shall pay to the said commissioners four per cent of the amount thereof, except in district one, wherein each pilot or any person for him, shall pay to said commissioners two per cent of the amount thereof, and if he makes a false return of money received he shall pay to them not more than fifty dollars. The trustees of the Boston Marine Society shall fix the compensation of the commissioners and their allowance for office rent, clerk hire and incidental expenses, which shall be paid out of the amounts so paid to the commissioners, and the surplus, if any, shall be paid to said society. 
Chapter 103: Accounts of pilots; payment of pilotage fees to commissioners; compensation of commissioners; reimbursement for travel and other reasonable expenses [Text of section as amended by 2010, 433, Sec. 3 effective on the effective date of the initial pilotage rates established by the board pursuant to section 31A of chapter 103 of the General Laws. See 2010, 433, Sec. 9. For text effective until the effective date of the initial pilotage rates established by the board pursuant to section 31A of chapter 103 of the General Laws, see above.] 
Once in every three months each pilot shall render to the commissioners for his district an accurate account of all vessels piloted by him and of all money received for pilotage by him or by any person for him, and shall pay to the said commissioners four per cent of the amount thereof, except in district one, wherein each pilot or any person for him, shall pay to said commissioners two per cent of the amount thereof, and if he makes a false return of money received he shall pay to them not more than fifty dollars. The trustees of the Boston Marine Society shall fix the compensation of the commissioners and their allowance for office rent, clerk hire and incidental expenses, which shall be paid out of the amounts so paid to the commissioners, and the surplus, if any, shall be paid to said society. The Boston Marine Society shall reimburse the members of the state pilotage rate board established in section 31A for travel and other reasonable expenses associated with the duties of the members of the board.
    </text>
</law>