<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Powers Of Department Of Public Health; Enforcement Of Rules And Regulations; Examinations And Investigations</catch_line>
    <order_by>10I</order_by>
    <text>
        The department of public health shall enforce the provisions of sections ten H and ten K, inclusive, and shall from time to time make, amend or rescind rules and regulations for the enforcement thereof. Said rules and regulations shall include standards and tolerances of enrichment, and shall specify the quantities of the enriching ingredients necessary for compliance with the definitions of “enriched bread” and “enriched flour”, respectively, as set forth in section one, consistent with law and conforming to the standards and tolerances, if any, adopted under the provisions of the federal food, drug and cosmetic act for the enforcement of federal law. Said rules and regulations with respect to labeling requirements as set forth in section ten J shall conform to the labeling requirements, if any, adopted for the enforcement of federal law. 
The department of public health and the inspectors appointed under the provisions of chapter one hundred and eleven, section nine, may conduct examinations and investigations and may take samples of flour, white bread or rolls for analysis to determine compliance with the provisions of sections ten H to ten J, inclusive. Said inspectors may enter at any reasonable time any factory, mill, warehouse, shop or establishment where flour, white bread or rolls are manufactured, processed, packed, sold or held, or any vehicle being used for the transportation thereof for the purpose of inspection and investigation for the enforcement of these sections; provided, that nothing in this paragraph shall be deemed to authorize any interference with interstate commerce.
    </text>
</law>