<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>99A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Standard Box For Farm Produce; Standard Half Box; Lug;  Specifications; Markings</catch_line>
    <order_by>99A</order_by>
    <text>
        The Massachusetts standard box for farm produce sold at wholesale, except as otherwise provided, shall contain two thousand one hundred fifty and forty-two one-hundredths cubic inches and shall be of the following dimensions by inside measurements: seventeen and one half inches in length by seventeen and one-half inches in width and seven and one sixteenth inches in depth. The Massachusetts standard half box for farm produce sold at wholesale shall contain one thousand seventy-five and twenty-one one hundredths cubic inches and shall be of the following dimensions by inside measurements: twelve and three eighths inches in length by twelve and three eighths inches in width and seven and one sixteenth inches in depth. When the above specified boxes are made of wood the ends shall be not less than five eighths inches in thickness and the sides and bottom not less than three eighths inches in thickness. All such boxes and half boxes of the dimensions specified herein shall be marked on at least one outer side in bold, uncondensed capital letters, not less than one inch in height:— Standard Box Farm Produce, — and, — Standard Half Box Farm Produce, — respectively. The Massachusetts lug for tomatoes sold at wholesale or retail shall contain one thousand seventy-eight and forty-three one hundredths cubic inches and shall be of the following dimensions by inside measurements: seventeen and one half inches in length by eight and one half inches in width by seven and one quarter inches in depth. Whoever marks or otherwise represents any box or half box to be a standard box or half box for the sale of farm produce at wholesale shall, unless such box or half box complies with every specification and requirement of this section, be punished by a fine of not more than fifty dollars. The deputy director of standards in the office of consumer affairs and business regulation, his inspectors and the sealers and deputy sealers of weights and measures in cities and towns shall enforce the provisions of this section.
    </text>
</law>