<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="101" order_by="101" level="3">Transient Vendors, Hawkers And Pedlers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>34</section_number>
    <catch_line>Door To Door Sales For Future Delivery; Employment Of Minors; Duties Of Sales Organization; Registration</catch_line>
    <order_by>34</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section the following terms shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No sales organization shall recruit, hire, or employ a person to engage in the sale of goods or periodicals door-to-door for future delivery unless and until such person furnishes the sales organization with information sufficient to inform such sales organization of such person’s age and identification.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     prior to the employment of a person under eighteen years of age, furnish to a parent or guardian of such person a listing of cities or towns in which the sales group will be working in the two weeks immediately following such employment, the dates when the sales group shall be in each such city or town, the address of the sales group in each such city or town during the time the sales group is in such city or town, and the business address at which such parent or guardian may be informed of such person’s work address.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     keep accurate accounts of sales made, lawful expenses incurred, and all amounts earned by each sales agent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     provide to each sales agent for each pay period, but not less than once each seven days, an itemized written statement of the account of such sales agent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     pay, on the same day each pay period to each sales agent, all money earned from all sales made a week or more prior thereto by such sales agent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     threats or acts of reprisals, intimidation, or physical violence against any sales agent, or any person acting on behalf of any sales agent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     refusal to disburse commissions, salary, compensation, or other remuneration owing to a sales agent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     All sales agents and sales supervisors covered by the provisions of this section shall register with a chief of police or with another official to be designated by the city council of a city or the board of selectmen of a town of initial registration. Each applicant for registration shall provide positive identification, give a permanent street address, provide an exemplar of his signature, the name of his employer or the party responsible for complying with the provisions of subsection (b), the business address of such employer, the identity and registration of any motor vehicle to be used to transport goods or persons engaged in said business, and a brief description of the goods to be sold and proposed method of operation. Said chief of police or designated official shall photograph each applicant for the purpose of identification and shall retain a copy of each such photograph for a minimum of two years.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A person or sales organization that knowingly violates any provision of this section shall be subject to a fine of five hundred dollars or imprisonment for not more than six months.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The provisions of this section shall not apply to any person who goes door-to-door to sell goods or periodicals on behalf of any group organized for any political purpose or for any purpose described in section four of chapter one hundred and eighty, nor shall this section apply to a person engaged in any sale governed by section sixty-nine of chapter one hundred and forty-nine.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>