<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>289</section_number>
    <catch_line>Turpentine; Manufacture; Sale; Marking; Adulteration</catch_line>
    <order_by>289</order_by>
    <text>
        No person shall manufacture, mix for sale, dispose of, offer or expose for sale, have in possession with intent to sell or dispose of, or sell under the name of turpentine, or spirits of turpentine, or under any name or phrase of which the word turpentine forms a part, or under any name or device illustrating or suggesting turpentine or spirits of turpentine, any article which is not wholly distilled from rosin, turpentine gum, or scrapings from pine trees, unmixed and unadulterated with any other substance, unless the package containing the same shall be stencilled or marked, with letters not less than two inches in height and one inch in width, “Adulterated Spirits of Turpentine”, except that these letters upon packages of one gallon capacity, or less, may be reduced to one fourth of the said size. No person shall sell or deliver such adulterated spirits of turpentine without informing the purchaser at the time of sale that the article is not pure spirits of turpentine. Nothing herein contained shall be construed as prohibiting the manufacture or sale of such compound or imitation, if the container is plainly marked and the purchaser notified as aforesaid. 
Whoever violates any provision of this section shall be punished for the first offence by a fine of one hundred dollars, for the second offence by a fine of two hundred dollars, and for a subsequent offence by a fine of five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not more than one month, or both.
    </text>
</law>