<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>40A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Dishonored Checks; Demand For Payment</catch_line>
    <order_by>40A</order_by>
    <text>
        Whoever makes, draws, utters or delivers any check, draft or order for the payment of money upon any bank or other depository which refuses to honor the same because the maker has no account with such bank or other depository or because the maker has insufficient funds on deposit therein and who fails to pay the amount of such check, draft or order within thirty days following a written demand therefor by the payee in accordance with this section and delivered to such person by regular mail and also by certified mail return receipt requested shall, in addition to any criminal penalties which may be imposed in accordance with law, be liable to the payee for the face amount of such check, draft or order, and for additional damages, as determined by the court, but in no event shall the amount of such damages be less than one hundred nor more than five hundred dollars. 
The written demand for payment required by this section shall be in the following form and shall be printed in at least ten point type in both the English and Spanish languages: 
DEMAND FOR PAYMENT OF DISHONORED CHECK
DATE:_________________________________ 
TO:___________________________________ 
   NAME OF MAKER
WARNING: YOU MAY BE SUED 30 DAYS AF-
         TER THE DATE OF THIS NOTICE IF YOU DO
         NOT MAKE PAYMENT
_______________________________________ 
_______________________________________ 
_______________________________________ 
LAST KNOWN RESIDENCE ADDRESS OR PLACE OF BUSINESS 
YOUR CHECK/DRAFT/ORDER IN THE AMOUNT OF $___________ 
DATED _________ PAYABLE TO THE ORDER OF ________________ 
HAS BEEN DISHONORED BY THE BANK OR OTHER DEPOSITORY UPON WHICH IT HAS BEEN DRAWN BECAUSE: 
— THE MAKER HAD NO ACCOUNT WITH SUCH BANK OR DEPOSITORY 
— THE MAKER HAD INSUFFICIENT FUNDS ON DEPOSIT WITH SUCH BANK OR DEPOSITORY 
IF YOU DO NOT MAKE PAYMENT WITHIN THIRTY DAYS OF THE ABOVE DATE, YOU MAY BE SUED TO RECOVER PAYMENT. IF A JUDGMENT IS RENDERED AGAINST YOU IN COURT, IT WILL INCLUDE NOT ONLY THE ORIGINAL FACE AMOUNT OF THE CHECK/DRAFT/ORDER, BUT ALSO ADDITIONAL LIQUIDATED DAMAGES OF NOT LESS THAN ONE HUNDRED DOLLARS ($100.00) NOR MORE THAN FIVE HUNDRED DOLLARS ($500.00). 
PLEASE MAKE PAYMENT IN THE AMOUNT OF $_____________ TO: 
_______________________________________ 
NAME OF PAYEE 
_______________________________________ 
_______________________________________ 
_______________________________________ 
ADDRESS TO WHICH PAYMENT SHOULD BE DELIVERED
    </text>
</law>