<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>68A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>68A</order_by>
    <text>
        For the purposes of sections sixty-eight B to sixty-eight D, inclusive, the following words, unless the context requires otherwise, shall have the following meanings:— 
“Buyer”, any individual who is solicited to purchase or who purchases the services of a credit services organization. 
“Credit services organization”, any person who, with respect to the extension of credit by others, sells, provides, performs, or who represents to sell, provide or perform for the payment of money or other valuable consideration any of the following services: (i) improving a buyer’s credit record, history or rating; (ii) obtaining an extension of credit for a buyer; or (iii) providing advice or assistance to a buyer with respect to either clause (i) or (ii); provided, however, that such term shall not include (a) any person authorized to make loans or extensions of credit under the laws of the commonwealth or the United States, (b) a lender approved by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development of the United States for participation in any mortgage insurance program under 12 USC 1701 et seq. (National Housing Act), (c) any bank whose deposits or accounts are eligible for insurance by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, or any subsidiary of such bank, (d) any credit union authorized to do business in the commonwealth under state or federal law, (e) any nonprofit organization exempt from taxation under (Fair Credit Reporting Act). 
“Extension of credit”, credit extended to a buyer primarily for personal, family or household purposes including the right to defer payment of debt or to incur debt and defer its payment.
    </text>
</law>