<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94C" order_by="94C" level="3">Controlled Substances Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>21B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advertisement And Sale Of Prescription Lock Boxes By Pharmacies</catch_line>
    <order_by>21B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 244, Sec. 6 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 244, Sec. 29.]  (a) For the purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meanings unless the context clearly requires otherwise:  "Lock box'', a box with a locking mechanism that cannot be tampered with or opened without extreme force.  "Pharmacy'', a facility under the direction or supervision of a registered pharmacist which is authorized to dispense controlled substances; provided, however, that "pharmacy'' shall not include an institutional pharmacy or a pharmacy department except as otherwise provided in 247 CMR.  "Prescription drug'', a drug which, under federal law, is required, prior to being dispensed or delivered, to be labeled with the statement "Caution, federal law prohibits dispensing without prescription'' or a drug which is required by applicable federal or state law or regulation to be dispensed pursuant only to a prescription drug order.  (b) A pharmacy registered in the commonwealth to dispense schedule II, III, IV or V prescription drugs shall make available prescription lock boxes for sale at each store location. Pharmacies shall make customers aware of the availability of the lock boxes by displaying a sign on or near the pharmacy counter that: (i) is at least 4 inches by 5 inches; and (ii) includes the following statement in legibly printed font: "Lock boxes for securing your prescription medications are available at this pharmacy''.
    </text>
</law>