<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10D1/2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Laboratory Testing Of Water Contained In Bottled Product</catch_line>
    <order_by>10D1/2</order_by>
    <text>
        All persons permitted to manufacture, bottle or sell water intended for human consumption under section ten A or ten B shall, at least annually, cause to be tested by a laboratory certified as provided herein, the water contained in their finished bottled water product. If the water source or sources from which such water product is derived is located within the commonwealth, the laboratory performing such tests shall be certified by the department of environmental protection to perform such tests for water quality purposes. If the water source or sources from which such water product is derived is located without the commonwealth, the laboratory performing such tests shall be certified to perform such tests for water quality testing purposes by the appropriate agency within that state or jurisdiction wherein such laboratory is located. The testing for finished bottled water product shall include those physical, chemical, microbiological and radiological test parameters required by the department of environmental protection for the testing of public water supplies. The department of public health in consultation with the department of environmental protection, may, from time to time, require by rule and regulation such additional tests as it deems necessary for the protection of the public health. 
The department of public health shall require any person manufacturing, bottling or selling such water to test for physical, chemical and microbiological parameters at least annually. Said department shall require that radiological testing of the finished product be performed at least once every four years. Test results shall be submitted to said department on or before November the first of the year when such tests are required. Said department shall make available to the public, upon request, any test results so submitted upon payment of a reasonable fee to be determined by the department.
    </text>
</law>