<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>76</section_number>
    <catch_line>Sale Of Life Leases And Long Term Leases In Nursing Homes, Retirement Homes And Homes For Aged</catch_line>
    <order_by>76</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The following terms, as used in this section, shall have the following meanings:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     At the time of or prior to the execution of a contract to provide continuing care, or at the time of or prior to the transfer of any money or other property to a provider by or on behalf of a prospective resident, whichever shall first occur, the provider shall deliver a disclosure statement to the person with whom the contract is to be entered into, the text of which shall contain, to the extent not clearly and completely set forth in the contract for continuing care attached as an exhibit thereto, at least the following information:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The name and business address of the provider and a statement of whether the provider is a partnership, corporation, or other type of legal entity.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The names of the officers, directors, trustees, or managing or general partners of the provider and a description of each such person’s occupation with the provider.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A description of the business experience of the provider in the operation or management of similar facilities and of the manager of the facility if the facility will be managed on a day-to-day basis by an organization other than the provider.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     A statement as to whether or not the provider is, or is affiliated with, a religious, charitable or other nonprofit organization; the extent of the affiliation, if any, the extent to which the affiliate organization will be responsible for the financial and contract obligations of the provider, and the provision of the federal Internal Revenue Code, if any, under which the provider or affiliate is exempt from the payment of income tax.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The location and description of the physical property or properties of the facility, existing or proposed; and to the extent proposed, the estimated completion date or dates, whether or not construction has begun and the contingencies subject to which construction may be deferred.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Certified financial statements of the provider, including (a) a balance sheet as of the end of the most recent fiscal year and (b) income statements for the three most recent fiscal years of the provider or such shorter period of time as the provider shall have been in existence. If the provider’s fiscal year ended more than ninety days prior to the date the application is filed, interim financial statements as of a date not more than ninety days prior to such filing shall be included, but need not be certified.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     If the operation of the facility has not yet commenced, a statement of the anticipated source and application of the funds used or to be used in the purchase or construction of the facility, including: (i) an estimate of the cost of purchasing or constructing and equipping the facility including such related costs as financing expense, legal expense, land costs, occupancy development costs, and all other similar costs which the provider expects to incur or become obligated for prior to the commencement of operations, (ii) a description of any mortgage loan or other long-term financing intended to be used for the financing of the facility, including the anticipated terms and costs of such financing, (iii) an estimate of the total entrance fees to be received from residents at or prior to commencement of operation of the facility, (iv) an estimate of the funds, if any, which are anticipated to be necessary to fund start-up losses and provide reserve funds to assure full performance of the obligations of the provider under contracts for the provision of continuing care, (v) a projection of estimated income from fees and charges other than entrance fees, showing individual rates presently anticipated to be charged and including a description of the assumptions used for calculating the estimated occupancy rate of the facility and the effect on the income of the facility of government subsidies for health care services, if any, to be provided pursuant to the contracts for continuing care, and (vi) such other material information concerning the facility or the provider as the provider wishes to include.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     All contracts for continuing care used by a provider shall provide that:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The party contracting with the provider may rescind the contract at any time prior to occupying a living unit in the facility, in which event the party shall, within a reasonable period, receive a refund of all money or property transferred to the provider, less (a) those costs specifically incurred by the provider or facility at the request of the party and described in the contract or an addendum thereto signed by the party; and (b) a reasonable service charge, if set out in the contract, not to exceed one per cent of the entrance fee. If the unit is available for occupancy on the occupancy date agreed upon in the contract, and the party has failed to occupy said unit, the party shall be deemed to have rescinded the contract, unless the party and the provider agree in writing to extend the occupancy date.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     If the unit is not available for occupancy on the date agreed upon in the contract, and the party has not rescinded the contract, the contract shall be automatically canceled, unless the party and the provider agree in writing to extend the occupancy date. If the contract is automatically canceled the party shall, within a reasonable period, receive a refund of all money or property transferred to the provider plus a reasonable inconvenience fee, if set out in the contract, not to exceed one per cent of the amount of the entrance fee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     If a resident dies before occupying a living unit in the facility, the contract is automatically canceled and the legal representative of the resident shall receive a refund of all money or property transferred to the provider, less (a) those costs specifically incurred by the provider or facility at the request of the resident and described in the contract or an addendum thereto signed by the resident; and (b) a reasonable service charge, if set out in the contract, not to exceed one per cent of the entrance fee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The entrance fee minus no more than one per cent for each month of occupancy shall be refunded to the resident when the resident leaves the facility or dies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The services provided or proposed to be provided under contracts for continuing care at the facility, including the extent to which medical care is furnished, and specifying those services which are included in the basic contract and those made available at or by the facility at extra charge.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     A description of all fees required of residents, including the entrance fee and periodic charges, if any. The description shall include: (i) a statement of the fees that will be charged if the resident marries while at the facility, and a statement of the terms concerning the entry of a spouse to the facility and the consequences if the spouse does not meet the requirement for entry, (ii) the circumstances under which the resident will be permitted to remain in the facility in the event of possible financial difficulties of a resident, (iii) the conditions under which a living unit occupied by a resident may be made available by the facility to a different or new resident other than on the death of the original resident and (iv) the manner by which the provider may adjust periodic charges or other recurring fees and the limitations on such adjustments, if any. If the facility is already in operation, or if the provider or manager operates one or more similar facilities within the commonwealth, there shall be included tables showing the frequency and average dollar amount of each increase in periodic rates at each such facility for the previous five years or such shorter period as the facility may have been operated by the provider or manager.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     The health and financial conditions required for an individual to be accepted as a resident and to continue as a resident once accepted, including the effect of any change in the health or financial condition of a person between the date of entering a contract for continuing care and the date of initial occupancy of a living unit by that person.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     The provisions that have been made or will be made, if any, to provide reserve funding or security to enable the provider to fully perform its obligations under contracts to provide continuing care at the facility, including the establishment of escrow accounts, trusts or reserve funds, together with the manner in which such funds will be invested and the names and experience of persons who will make the investment decisions.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     For the purpose of this subsection, “marketing” shall include but not be limited to establishment of a waiting list, acceptance of money, property or other consideration or distribution of marketing brochures by the provider. Any provider intending to market or develop continuing care pursuant to a contract which would require prepayment for some or all of the covered long-term care services or intending to market or develop additional units of such continuing care shall forward a copy of the following information to the executive office of elder affairs within thirty days following the implementation of marketing of the continuing care facility:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the disclosure statement required under subsection (b) to be delivered to the persons with whom the contract for continuing care is to be entered;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the contracts for continuing care to be entered into by the provider under subsection (c) with a person who will occupy a living unit in a continuing care facility; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     any available advertising or promotional material to be used in conjunction with such marketing effort.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A provider providing continuing care on the effective date of this statute under a contract which would require prepayment for some or all of the covered long-term care services shall, within thirty days after such effective date, forward a copy of the following information to the executive office of elder affairs:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the disclosure statement required under subsection (b) to be delivered to the persons with whom the contract for continuing care shall be entered;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the contract for continuing care to be entered into by the provider under subsection (c) with a person who will occupy a living unit in any such continuing care facility;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     any available advertising or promotional material to be used in conjunction with such marketing effort; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     a copy of the building permit for such continuing care facility.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>