<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>97</section_number>
    <catch_line>Disclosure Of Plaintiff Personal Injury Listing</catch_line>
    <order_by>97</order_by>
    <text>
        Every listing service shall disclose in writing to all persons named in a plaintiff personal injury listing the fact of such listing and the information contained therein. Disclosure shall also include the identity of all subscribers to whom the person’s listing has been furnished and the following statement: 
Your name appears in a listing of persons who have taken action against a doctor, clinic, hospital or other health care provider. You have the right to review the information on the list for accuracy and completeness. If you believe any information contained in this listing is either incorrect or incomplete, you may submit a written statement to the listing service explaining in what way the information is incomplete or inaccurate and correcting the information. You cannot be refused the services of any provider of health care services on the basis of your name appearing on this list. 
If the person believes the information disclosed to him by the listing service to be either inaccurate or incomplete, such person may submit a written statement to the listing service which explains in what way the information is incomplete or inaccurate and corrects the information. The listing service shall, within twenty days of receiving the statement, correct or complete the listing service’s information and shall promptly notify all subscribers of the correct or complete information; provided, however, that if the listing service believes the statement to be incorrect, it shall investigate and state in writing to the person who submitted the statement its reasons for declining to correct or complete the listing in whole or in part. The listing service shall report in all future listings that the person has submitted such a statement, and shall include as part of the listing a copy of such statement and any response of the listing service.
    </text>
</law>