<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>249H1/2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Classification As Eligible Petroleum Distillate Substitute Fuel; Minimum Content Requirements; Application Of Percentage Requirements On Statewide Average Basis; Inspection Of Samples; Quality Assurance;  Accreditation</catch_line>
    <order_by>249H1/2</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:-
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Manufacturers and wholesale distributors of petroleum distillate substitute fuel who seek to have their fuel classified as eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel shall provide documentation satisfactory to the department that such fuel yields at least a 50 per cent reduction in lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions per unit of delivered energy, in comparison to the petroleum distillate fuel displaced.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Except as provided in paragraph (4), the following shall apply to all number 2 petroleum distillate fuel and all other liquid fuel sold as a substitute for number 2 distillate fuel, offered for sale to end-users, retail sellers or to any other entity that will be providing such fuel directly to end-users in the commonwealth for use in residential, commercial or industrial heating applications. Such fuel must contain at least 2 per cent eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel, measured by available energy content or as otherwise provided by the department, no later than July 1, 2010. Except as provided in subsection (4), all such fuel must contain at least 3 per cent eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel no later than July 1, 2011, 4 per cent eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel no later than July 1, 2012, and 5 per cent eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel no later than July 1, 2013.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The department, in consultation with the department of environmental protection and the executive office of energy and environmental affairs, shall study the feasibility, benefits and costs, including benefits and costs to consumers, producers and the state government, of making the percentage mandates in subsection (3) apply on a statewide average basis rather than for every gallon of petroleum distillate fuel sold for heating purposes. If the department determines that such a system is feasible and that its benefits substantially exceed its costs, the department shall have the authority to implement such a system. The department shall determine on which entities the percentage requirements shall be applied. If the department implements such a system, the department shall promulgate regulations allowing and tracking sales of certificates or other documentation from the department that show use of eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel in the commonwealth. Entities may meet their percentage requirements for use of eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel by purchasing certificates or other documentation, and such certificates may be re-sold.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Manufacturers and wholesale distributors of eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel, and of fuel blended from petroleum distillate and eligible petroleum distillate substitute, doing business in the commonwealth shall furnish samples of such products to the department, shall permit the entry and inspection by the department or the department of environmental protection of the premises of such manufacturers or distributors, and the inspection and sampling of fuel stored thereon.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Manufacturers of eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel that is sold in the commonwealth shall meet quality assurance criteria or accreditation requirements determined by the department, in consultation with the department of environmental protection. Manufacturers shall submit documentation of quality assurance or accreditation to the department by November 1, 2009, or at least 3 months prior to the date on which the department certifies their fuel as eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel, and shall submit documentation to the department showing that their accreditation remains current every 2 years thereafter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     The department shall evaluate the feasibility and desirability of requiring BQ-9000 or other comparable accreditation requirement for producers and wholesale distributors of petroleum distillate substitute fuel and petroleum distillate fuel blended with petroleum distillate substitute fuel operating in the commonwealth. If the department concludes that such accreditation is feasible and desirable in order to protect consumers and the environment, the department shall promulgate regulations to implement an accreditation requirement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     The department shall promulgate regulations to implement the provisions of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     No person shall sell or offer to sell petroleum distillate heating fuel in the commonwealth, including eligible petroleum distillate substitute fuel that does not conform to the provisions of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     Notwithstanding section 249H, failure to comply with subsection (9) of this section shall constitute an unfair or deceptive act under chapter 93A, and may be enforced as provided therein.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>