<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="100A" order_by="100A" level="3">Motor Vehicle Damage Repair Shops</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Violations; Penalties</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        Any person violating any of the provisions of this chapter may be punished by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or both. Such fine may be imposed by the deputy director, after hearing, or in a civil or criminal action brought by the attorney general. Violation of any of the provisions of this chapter shall constitute a violation of chapter ninety-three A. 
In addition to any other penalties provided herein, whenever the deputy director determines that a person who is required to be registered hereunder has failed to so register, the deputy director may serve a stop work order on said person, requiring the cessation of all business operations. Such order shall take effect five days after the date of service upon such person. Any person who is aggrieved by the imposition of a stop work order shall have five days from the date of service to appeal such order, and shall thereafter be granted a hearing by the deputy director within five days of receipt of appeal. If the deputy director finds at the hearing that the person was required to be registered, and failed to register, the stop work order shall be effective immediately on the conclusion of the hearing, and shall remain in effect until the person becomes properly registered. Any law enforcement agency in the commonwealth shall, at the request of the deputy director, render any assistance necessary to carry out the provisions of this paragraph, including but not limited to preventing any employee or other person from remaining at the place of business after a stop work order has taken effect.
    </text>
</law>