<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>28A</section_number>
    <catch_line>License To Receive Raw Milk At Dairy Farms; Issuance To Persons Certified Under Sec. 27 A; Temporary Or Emergency License; Revocation Or Suspension; Reinstatement; Fees</catch_line>
    <order_by>28A</order_by>
    <text>
        Said chief of the bureau of milk marketing or his agent shall, upon application on a form provided by him, issue a license to receive raw milk at dairy farms to any person holding a certificate of competency obtained as provided in section twenty-seven A and dated within thirty days of the date of application. He may also, without prior evidence of competency and upon application by telephone or otherwise, issue such a license on a temporary basis not to exceed thirty days; provided, however, that he deems such action to be required because of emergency conditions to assure the uninterrupted collection of raw milk from dairy farms. No temporary license shall be renewed or extended except upon submission by the licensee of a certificate of competency obtained as hereinabove provided. The license fee in either case shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provision of said section three B of said chapter seven payable to the chief of the bureau of milk marketing. Said chief may at any time revoke or suspend a license issued under this section for violation of any of the provisions of sections twenty-five to thirty, inclusive, or of the rules and regulations made thereunder, and may reinstate such license upon his determination that the cause for revocation or suspension has been removed. An additional fee to be determined also under the provisions of said section three B of said chapter seven shall be paid to the chief of milk marketing for reinstatement of a license which has been revoked. Names of licensees and notice of any suspension, revocation or reinstatement shall be furnished to the director.
    </text>
</law>