<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="93" order_by="93" level="3">Regulation Of Trade And Certain Enterprises</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>107</section_number>
    <catch_line>Customized Wheelchairs; Nonconformity With Warrant; Rights And Remedies</catch_line>
    <order_by>107</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     As used in this section the following words shall have the following meanings unless the context clearly indicates otherwise:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     a nonconformity within the warranty is subject to repair at least four times by the manufacturer, customized wheelchair lessor, or any of the manufacturer’s authorized dealers and the nonconformity continues, or
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the customized wheelchair is out of service for an aggregate of at least thirty days because of a warranty nonconformity.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     A manufacturer who sells a customized wheelchair to a consumer, either directly or through a customized wheelchair dealer, shall furnish the consumer with an express warranty for the customized wheelchair. The duration of the express warranty shall be not less than one year after first delivery of the customized wheelchair to the consumer. In the absence of an express warranty from the manufacturer, the manufacturer shall be deemed to have expressly warranted to the consumer that, for a period of one year from the date of first delivery to such consumer, the customized wheelchair shall be free from any condition or defect which substantially impairs the use value or safety of the customized wheelchair.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     At the direction of a consumer other than one who leases a customized wheelchair, the manufacturer shall:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     accept return of the customized wheelchair and replace it with a comparable new customized wheelchair and refund any collateral costs; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     accept return of the customized wheelchair and refund to the consumer and to any holder of a perfected security interest, as their interest may appear, the full purchase price and any finance charge amount paid by the consumer at the point of sale and any collateral costs, less a reasonable allowance for use. A reasonable allowance for use shall not exceed the amount obtained by multiplying the full purchase price of the customized wheelchair by a fraction, the denominator of which shall be one thousand eight hundred and twenty-five and the numerator of which shall be the number of days that the customized wheelchair was in the consumer’s possession before the consumer first reported the nonconformity to the customized wheelchair dealer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     At the direction of a consumer who leases a customized wheelchair, the manufacturer shall accept return of the customized wheelchair, refund to the customized wheelchair lessor and to any holder of a perfected security interest, as their interest may appear, the current value of the written lease and refund to the consumer the amount such consumer paid under the written lease and any collateral costs, less a reasonable allowance for use. A reasonable allowance for use shall not exceed the amount obtained by multiplying the total amount for which the written lease obligates the consumer by a fraction, the denominator of which shall be one thousand eight hundred and twenty-five and the numerator of which shall be the number of days that the consumer possessed the customized wheelchair before first reporting the nonconformity to the manufacturer, customized wheelchair lessor or customized wheelchair dealer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     In order to receive a comparable new customized wheelchair or a refund due under paragraph (b) of subsection (2), a consumer described thereunder shall offer to the manufacturer of the customized wheelchair having the nonconformity to transfer possession of that customized wheelchair to that manufacturer. No later than thirty days after such offer, the manufacturer shall provide the consumer with the comparable new customized wheelchair or refund. When the manufacturer provides the new customized wheelchair or refund, the consumer shall return the customized wheelchair having the nonconformity to the manufacturer, along with any endorsements necessary to transfer legal possession to the manufacturer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     To receive a refund due under paragraph (c) of subsection (2), a customized wheelchair lessor shall offer to transfer possession of the customized wheelchair having the nonconformity to its manufacturer. No later than thirty days after such offer, the manufacturer shall provide the refund to the customized wheelchair lessor. When the manufacturer provides the refund, the customized wheelchair lessor shall provide to the manufacturer any endorsements necessary to transfer legal possession to the manufacturer.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     No person may enforce the lease against the consumer after he receives a refund due under paragraph (c) of subsection (2).
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     No customized wheelchair returned by a consumer or customized wheelchair lessor in the commonwealth or by a consumer or customized wheelchair lessor in another state under a similar law of that state, may be resold or leased in the commonwealth unless full disclosure of the reasons for such return has been made to a prospective buyer or lessee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="D">
    	     Each consumer shall have the option of submitting any dispute arising under this section, upon the payment of a prescribed filing fee, to an alternate arbitration mechanism established pursuant to regulations promulgated hereunder by the secretary of the executive office of consumer affairs and business regulation. Upon application of the consumer and payment of the appropriate filing fee, all manufacturers shall submit to such alternative arbitration. Such alternate arbitration shall be conducted by a professional arbitrator or arbitration firm appointed by and under regulations established by the attorney general. Such mechanism shall ensure the personal objectivity of its arbitrators and the right of each party to present its case, to be in attendance during any presentation made by the other party and to rebut or refute such presentation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="E">
    	     Nothing contained in this section shall be deemed to limit any rights or remedies available to a consumer under any other law. Any waiver by a consumer of rights under this section shall be void.
        </section>
        <section prefix="F">
    	     In addition to pursuing any other remedy, a consumer may bring an action to recover for damages caused by a violation of this section. The court shall award a consumer who prevails in such an action twice the amount of any pecuniary loss, together with costs, disbursements and reasonable attorney fees, and any equitable relief that the court deems is appropriate.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>