<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94F" order_by="94F" level="3">Complementary Provisions Concerning Tobacco Product Manufacturers</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Information Which May Be Required By Commissioner And Attorney General</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Not later than 20 days after the end of each calendar quarter, and more frequently if so directed by the commissioner, each stamper shall submit such information as the commissioner requires to facilitate compliance with this chapter. The stamper shall maintain and make available to the commissioner and the attorney general all invoices and documentation of sales of all nonparticipating manufacturer of cigarettes and any other information relied upon in reporting to the commissioner for a period of 5 years.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The commissioner may disclose to the attorney general any information received under this chapter and requested by the attorney general for purposes of determining compliance with and enforcing the provisions of this chapter and chapter 94E. The commissioner and the attorney general may share information received under this chapter and chapter 94E with each other and with other federal, state and local agencies for purposes of enforcement of this chapter, chapter 94E and the corresponding laws of other states.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The attorney general may require from the nonparticipating manufacturer or from the financial institution at which the nonparticipating manufacturer has established a qualified escrow fund for the purpose of compliance with chapter 94E, information and documents relating to such fund, including proof of the amount of money in the fund, exclusive of interest, and the dates and amounts of deposits and withdrawals.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     In addition to such other information as may be required, the commissioner and the attorney general may require a stamper or tobacco product manufacturer to submit information including, but not limited to, samples of the packaging and labeling of each brand family, as may be necessary to enable the commissioner and the attorney general to determine whether a stamper or a tobacco product manufacturer is in compliance with this chapter and chapter 94E.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     To promote compliance with this chapter and chapter 94E, the commissioner may promulgate regulations requiring a tobacco product manufacturer subject to the requirements of subsection (c) of section 2 to make the required escrow deposit in quarterly installments. The commissioner and the attorney general may require production of information sufficient to enable the commissioner and the attorney general to determine the adequacy of the amount of the installment deposit.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>