<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>295G1/2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Classification As Eligible Diesel Substitute Fuel; Minimum Content Requirements; Application Of Percentage Requirements On Statewide Average Basis; Inspection Of Samples; Quality Assurance; Accreditation</catch_line>
    <order_by>295G1/2</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall have the following meanings:-
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Manufacturers and wholesale distributors of diesel substitute fuel doing business in the commonwealth who wish to have their fuel classified as eligible diesel substitute fuel shall provide documentation satisfactory to the department that such fuel yields at least a 50 per cent reduction in lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions per unit of delivered energy, in comparison to the petroleum-based diesel fuel displaced.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Except as provided in subsection (4), the following shall apply to all diesel motor vehicle fuel and all other liquid fuel used in motor vehicle diesel engines, offered for sale to end-users, retail sellers or to any other entity that will be providing such fuel directly to end-users in the commonwealth for use in transportation. All such fuel must contain at least 2 per cent eligible diesel substitute fuel, measured by available energy content or in such other manner as determined by the department no later than July 1, 2010. Except as provided in subsection (4), all such fuel must contain at least 3 per cent eligible diesel substitute fuel no later than July 1, 2011, 4 per cent eligible diesel substitute fuel no later than July 1, 2012, and 5 per cent eligible diesel substitute fuel no later than July 1, 2013.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The department, in consultation with the department of environmental protection and the executive office of energy and environmental affairs, shall study the feasibility, benefits and costs, including benefits and costs to consumers, producers and the commonwealth, of making the percentage mandates in subsection (3) apply on a statewide average basis rather than for every gallon of diesel motor fuel sold. If the department implements such a system, the department shall promulgate regulations allowing and tracking sales of certificates or other documentation from the department that show use of eligible diesel substitute fuel in the commonwealth. Entities may meet their percentage requirements for use of eligible diesel substitute fuel by purchasing certificates or other documentation, and such certificates may be re-sold.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Manufacturers and wholesale distributors of eligible diesel substitute fuel, and of fuel blended from petroleum diesel and eligible diesel substitute, doing business in the commonwealth shall furnish samples of such products to the department, shall permit the entry and inspection by the division and department of the premises of such manufacturers or distributors and the inspection and sampling of fuel stored thereon.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Manufacturers of eligible diesel substitute fuel that is sold in the commonwealth shall meet quality assurance criteria or accreditation requirements determined by the department, in consultation with the department of environmental protection. Manufacturers shall submit documentation of quality assurance or accreditation to the department on or before November 1, 2009, or at least 3 months prior to the date on which the department certifies their fuel as eligible diesel substitute fuel, and must submit documentation to the department showing that their accreditation remains current every 2 years thereafter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     The department shall evaluate the feasibility and desirability of requiring BQ-9000 or other comparable accreditation requirement for producers and wholesale distributors of diesel substitute fuel and petroleum-based motor fuel blended with diesel substitute fuel operating in the commonwealth. If the department concludes that such accreditation is feasible and desirable in order to protect consumers and the environment, the department shall promulgate regulations to implement an accreditation requirement.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     The department shall promulgate regulations to implement the provisions of this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     No person shall sell or offer to sell heating fuel, including eligible diesel substitute fuel, that does not conform to this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     Notwithstanding section 249H, failure to comply with subsection (9) shall constitute an unfair or deceptive act under the provisions of chapter 93A, and may be enforced as provided therein.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>