<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="110A" order_by="110A" level="3">Uniform Securities Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>202</section_number>
    <catch_line>Registration Procedure</catch_line>
    <order_by>202</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A broker-dealer, agent, investment adviser or investment adviser representative may obtain an initial or renewal registration by filing with the secretary or his designee an application together with a consent to service of process pursuant to paragraph (g) of section 414, and paying any reasonable costs charged for processing such filings. The application shall contain whatever information the secretary by rule requires concerning such matters as:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the applicant’s form and place of organization;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the applicant’s proposed method of doing business;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the qualifications and business history of the applicant; in the case of a broker-dealer or investment adviser, the qualifications and business history of any partner, officer, or director, any person occupying a similar status or performing similar functions, or any person directly or indirectly controlling the broker-dealer or the investment adviser;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     any injunction or administrative order or conviction of a misdemeanor involving a security or any aspect of the securities business and any conviction of a felony;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     the applicant’s financial condition and history; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     any information to be furnished or disseminated to any client or prospective client, if the applicant is an investment adviser.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     It is unlawful for a person to transact business in the commonwealth as a federal covered adviser unless the person has made a notice filing with the secretary or his designee consisting of (1) a copy of those documents that have been filed by the federal covered adviser with the Securities and Exchange Commission, (2) a consent to service of process, and (3) a filing fee, as the secretary prescribes by rule or order, not to exceed $300.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     (1) Broker-dealers and broker-dealer agents.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Investment advisers and investment adviser representatives.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Federal covered advisers.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A registered broker-dealer, an investment adviser, or a federal covered adviser may file an application for registration of a successor, or file a notice filing for a successor, as applicable, whether or not the successor is then in existence, for the unexpired portion of the year. There shall be no filing fee.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The secretary may, by rule or order, establish minimum financial requirements, including minimum capital and bonding requirements, for registered broker-dealers, subject to the limitations of section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934; and for investment advisers, subject to the limitations of section 222 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940, which may include different requirements for those registered investment advisers who maintain custody of clients’ funds or securities, who have discretionary authority over same or who require payment of more than $500 in fees and more than 6 months in advance and those registered investment advisers who do not.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The secretary may by rule provide that an applicant may submit 1 application for registration as both a broker-dealer agent and an investment adviser representative. Each applicant shall pay a registration fee, as the secretary prescribes by rule or order, not to exceed $50.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Any fee that is required to be paid pursuant to this section or the accompanying regulations may be transmitted through a designee.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>