<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>88D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Inspection Of Fish Offered For Sale</catch_line>
    <order_by>88D</order_by>
    <text>
        The commissioner, his agents or inspectors may inspect all fish offered or exposed for sale or kept with intent to sell, and for such purpose may enter any place where fish is stored, kept, offered or exposed for sale, may examine the conditions of such place and the equipment thereof and may require that such place and equipment be kept in a sanitary condition. If on inspection it is found that such fish is tainted, diseased, corrupted, decayed, unwholesome or unfit for food from any cause, the inspector shall seize and cause the same to be destroyed forthwith or disposed of otherwise than for food. All money received for fish disposed of as aforesaid, after deducting the expense of said seizure and disposal, shall be paid to the owner of such fish. Whoever, by himself or by his agent or employee, sells, or offers or exposes for sale, or keeps with intent to sell or offer or expose for sale, for food purpose fish which is tainted, diseased, corrupted, decayed, unwholesome or unfit for food from any cause, or whoever violates any provisions of sections seventy-seven A to eighty-eight D, inclusive, or any rule or regulation made thereunder, or hinders, obstructs, or interferes with any inspection authorized hereunder, or secretes or removes fish for the purpose of preventing such inspection shall be punished by a fine of not more than five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for six months, or both.
    </text>
</law>