<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="2">Regulation Of Trade</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94" level="3">Inspection And Sale Of Food, Drugs And Various Articles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>60</section_number>
    <catch_line>Complaints For Violations Of Sections Relative To Oleomargarine, Butter And Cheese</catch_line>
    <order_by>60</order_by>
    <text>
        Each inspector of milk shall institute complaints for the violation of any provision of sections forty-nine to fifty-eight, inclusive, sixty-two or sixty-five G to sixty-five S, inclusive, except subsections (c) to (e), inclusive, of section sixty-five P, on the information of any person who lays before him satisfactory evidence to sustain such complaint, if he has reasonable cause to believe that said provision has been violated. He may enter each place where butter, cheese or imitations thereof, or frozen desserts or frozen dessert mix as defined in section sixty-five G, are stored or kept for sale, and shall take samples of suspected butter, cheese or imitations thereof, or frozen desserts or frozen dessert mix, and cause them to be analyzed or otherwise satisfactorily tested, and shall record and preserve as evidence the result of such analysis or test. Before commencing the analysis of any sample in any proceeding for violation of any provision of sections forty-nine to fifty-one, inclusive, and sixty-five G to sixty-five S, inclusive, the analyst shall reserve and seal a portion of the sample, and, upon complaint made against the person from whom such sample was taken, such reserved portion of the sample alleged to be adulterated shall, upon application, be delivered to such person or to his attorney. The expense of such analysis or test, not exceeding twenty dollars in any one case, may be included in the expense of such prosecution.
    </text>
</law>