<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32B" order_by="32B" level="3">Contributory Group General Or Blanket Insurance For Persons In The Service Of Counties, Cities, Towns And Districts, And Their Dependents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Optional Medicare Extension</catch_line>
    <order_by>11C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Each person or his dependent to which this section applies shall furnish the treasurer of the governmental unit or the appropriate retirement authority in such form as he or they may prescribe, such information as is necessary to be insured for optional medicare extension, and shall authorize the withholding of the appropriate premium from salary, wages, other compensation, pension, annuity or retirement allowance. Each person may also authorize the withholding of any premium which may be required by the federal health insurance for the aged act, to be paid by any enrollee thereof, or to make direct payment to the treasurer as he may determine, and he shall transmit all such amounts to the appropriate federal agency on behalf of such enrollee in a manner prescribed by said agency.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     With respect to any period of insurance authorized by this section which is in effect for an active employee or a retired employee and his dependent, payment for such insurance shall be made as provided in section seven.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Upon the death of an active or retired employee insured under this section, the surviving spouse may continue the insurance under this section, or the group hospital, surgical, medical, dental and other health insurance benefits provided under section three, whichever may be applicable, and the duration of such insurance, the determination and the amount of premium to be paid will be in accordance with section nine B.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     If it is determined by the appropriate public authority to be in the best interests of the governmental unit and its active and retired employees and dependents eligible for optional medicare extension under this section that the optional medicare extension program administered by the commission under section ten C of chapter thirty-two A would be less costly to the governmental unit and the employees as well as being administratively advantageous to the governmental unit, the appropriate public authority may make application to the commission in accordance with the procedure the commission may establish and upon approval by the commission the employees of the governmental unit shall become so insured.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The medicare extension coverage permitted by this section shall be mandatory, rather than optional, for any governmental unit that accepts section eighteen.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>