<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32A" order_by="32A" level="3">Contributory Group General Or Blanket Insurance For Persons In The Service Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>27</section_number>
    <catch_line>Toll Free Telephone Number And Website Providing Customers With Estimated Or Maximum Allowed Amount Or Charge For Proposed Admission, Procedure Or Service</catch_line>
    <order_by>27</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 36 effective October 1, 2013 until October 1, 2014. See 2012, 224, Sec. 295. For text effective October 1, 2014, see below.]  The commission shall require any carriers or third party administrators with whom it contracts to provide a toll-free telephone number and website that enables consumers to request and obtain from the carrier or third party administrator, within 2 working days, the estimated or maximum allowed amount or charge for a proposed admission, procedure or service and the estimated amount the insured will be responsible to pay for a proposed admission, procedure or service that is a medically necessary covered benefit, based on the information available to the carrier or third party administrator at the time the request is made, including any facility fee, copayment, deductible, coinsurance or other out of pocket amount for any covered health care benefits; provided, that the insured shall not be required to pay more than the disclosed amounts for the covered health care benefits that were actually provided; provided, however, that nothing in this section shall prevent carriers from imposing cost sharing requirements disclosed in the insured's evidence of coverage for unforeseen services that arise out of the proposed admission, procedure or service; and provided further, that the carrier shall alert the insured that these are estimated costs, and that the actual amount the insured will be responsible to pay may vary due to unforeseen services that arise out of the proposed admission, procedure or service.
Chapter 32A: Toll-free telephone number and website providing customers with estimated or maximum allowed amount or charge for proposed admission, procedure or service
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 224, Sec. 37 effective October 1, 2014. See 2012, 224, Sec. 296. For text effective until October 1, 2014, see above.]  The commission shall require any carriers or third party administrators with whom it contracts to provide a toll-free telephone number and website that enables consumers to request and obtain from the carrier or third party administrator, in real time, the estimated or maximum allowed amount or charge for a proposed admission, procedure or service and the estimated amount the insured will be responsible to pay for a proposed admission, procedure or service that is a medically necessary covered benefit, based on the information available to the carrier or third party administrator at the time the request is made, including any facility fee, copayment, deductible, coinsurance or other out of pocket amount for any covered health care benefits; provided, that the insured shall not be required to pay more than the disclosed amounts for the covered health care benefits that were actually provided; provided, however, that nothing in this section shall prevent carriers from imposing cost sharing requirements disclosed in the insured's evidence of coverage for unforeseen services that arise out of the proposed admission, procedure or service; and provided further, that the carrier shall alert the insured that these are estimated costs, and that the actual amount the insured will be responsible to pay may vary due to unforeseen services that arise out of the proposed admission, procedure or service.
    </text>
</law>