<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="31" order_by="31" level="3">Civil Service</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>73</section_number>
    <catch_line>Violations; Notice; Writs Of Mandamus</catch_line>
    <order_by>73</order_by>
    <text>
        If, in the opinion of the administrator, a person is appointed or employed in a civil service position in violation of the civil service law and rules, the commission or the administrator shall mail a written notice of such violation to such person and to the appointing authority. The commission or the administrator shall then file a written notice of such violation with the treasurer, auditor or other officer whose duty it is to pay the salary or compensation of such person or to authorize the drawing, signing or issuing of any warrant for such payment. 
The payment of any salary or compensation to such person shall cease at the expiration of one week after the filing of such written notice with such treasurer, auditor or other officer. No such treasurer, auditor or other officer shall pay any salary or compensation to such person, or draw, sign or issue, or authorize the drawing, signing or issuing of any warrant for such payment, until the legality of the appointment or employment is duly established. 
Any person found by the administrator to be illegally appointed or employed may file a petition for a writ of mandamus in the supreme judicial court to compel the administrator to authorize such appointment or employment and the payment of compensation or salary. 
At any time after the filing of such petition, the court may order that the compensation accruing to such person for services actually rendered shall be paid to him until further order of the court, if the court is of the opinion that there is a reasonable doubt whether the appointment or employment of such person is in violation of the civil service law and rules.
    </text>
</law>