<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32A" order_by="32A" level="3">Contributory Group General Or Blanket Insurance For Persons In The Service Of The Commonwealth</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Retired Teachers; Life And Health Insurance; Agreements;  Contributions; Withholding Of Premiums; Reimbursement Of Premiums And Expenses; Dividends; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Each retired teacher or insured surviving spouse to whom this section applies shall furnish the commission, in such form as it shall prescribe, such information as is necessary to insure himself or himself and his dependents under the applicable insurance coverages described herein, and shall authorize the withholding of the appropriate premium from his pension, annuity or retirement allowance by the teachers’ retirement board established by chapter fifteen. Such authorization may include the withholding of any premium which may be required by the federal health insurance for the aged act to be paid by any enrollee thereof, or make direct payment to the commission as it may determine, and the commission shall transmit all such amounts to the appropriate federal agency on behalf of such enrollee in a manner prescribed by said agency.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     With respect to any period of insurance which is in effect for a retired teacher or surviving spouse, and dependents, notwithstanding the provisions of section nineteen of chapter thirty-two or any other general or special law to the contrary, there shall be withheld from each monthly payment of pension, annuity or retirement allowance by the teachers’ retirement board the appropriate premium to be paid by said teacher or surviving spouse for such insurance and the commonwealth shall make primary payment of the remaining premium together with the subsidiary or additional rate if any, subject to reimbursement as outlined in paragraph (d).
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The teachers’ retirement board shall transmit the premiums withheld as provided in paragraph (b) to the commission in accordance with the rules and regulations of the commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The commission shall determine at least annually, or sooner, the amount of premiums and subsidiary or additional rates which shall be reimbursed to the commonwealth by counties, cities, towns and districts having retired teachers, surviving spouses and dependents insured under this section. The commission shall also determine, at least annually, the portion of the commission’s expense of administering these life and health insurance coverages for retired teachers and their dependents applicable to the political subdivision from which they retired. After such determinations, the commission shall certify the amounts determined, as aforesaid, to the state treasurer for assessment. The state treasurer shall issue his warrant in the manner provided by section twenty of chapter fifty-nine requiring the cities, towns and districts concerned to pay into the treasury of the commonwealth the amounts of such premium, subsidiary or additional rate and administrative expenses attributable to such cities, towns and districts. In the case of counties, the commission on or before December the fifteenth in each year shall notify the county commissioners of each county of the amount of premium, subsidiary or additional rate and the administrative expenses attributable to such county, and said amounts shall be included in the estimate of county receipts and expenses of said county; and reimbursement for said amounts shall be made to the state treasurer as prescribed by the commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Any dividend or refund accepted by the commission from the carrier or carriers as a result of the agreements or contracts negotiated under this section shall be deposited by the commission with the state treasurer as provided in section nine. The commission shall determine the amount of dividend or refund apportionable to the various counties, cities, towns and districts having retired teachers insured hereunder and, in the case of a city, town or district, shall notify the state treasurer to reduce the premium, subsidiary rate and administrative expenses attributable to each such city, town or district by the amount of dividend or refund attributable thereto. In the case of counties, the commission shall notify the county commissioners of each county of the amount of dividend or refund attributable thereto and the estimate of receipts and expenditures for the ensuing year in each such county shall be reduced by the amount of such dividend or refund. If no premium is to be payable by a county, city, town or district for the succeeding year, the commission shall certify the same to the state treasurer who shall pay over the amount of such dividend or refund to the political subdivision entitled thereto.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Upon the death of a retired teacher insured under this section, the surviving spouse may continue the health insurance coverage upon the payment of the appropriate premium and in a manner prescribed by the commission.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The rules and regulations of the commission which govern the administration of this section shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter thirty A.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>