<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="31" order_by="31" level="3">Civil Service</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Rules</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Establishment of civil service series and titles, provided that for employment in the service of the commonwealth such series and titles shall be consistent with those established pursuant to section forty-five of chapter thirty.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Placement of civil service positions in the official or labor service.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Open competitive and other examinations to test the practical fitness of applicants.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Selection of persons for positions and employment in accordance with the results of examinations, or in the order of application, or otherwise.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Promotional appointments, on the basis of merit as determined by examination, performance evaluation, seniority of service or any combination of factors which fairly test the applicant’s ability to perform the duties of the position as determined by the administrator.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Preferences to veterans in original and promotional appointments.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Subject to prior preference to disabled veterans, preference to blind persons in the employment by any state department, board or commission of typists to take dictation solely from dictating machines.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Transfers within and between departmental units.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     In the development of examination procedures shall consult with representatives of labor and professionals in the field to increase emphasis upon aptitudes relevant to performing the position to be tested.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     The establishment and direction of a career management service program.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     The development of recruitment programs, and
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     The oversight responsibility for development of training programs in the various state agencies of the commonwealth.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>