<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="2">Civil Service, Retirements And Pensions</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="32" order_by="32" level="3">Retirement Systems And Pensions</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>65D.5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Election Of Appointed Justice To Membership In Service Of A Retirement System</catch_line>
    <order_by>65D.5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until February 16, 2012. For text effective February 16, 2012, see below.]  Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter to the contrary, any member inactive of a retirement system appointed by the governor to a position as a chief justice, justice, associate justice, judge, associate judge or special justice may elect within thirty days of such appointment to become a member in service of the system pertaining to the position to which he is appointed, subject to the provisions of sections sixty-five A to sixty-five D, inclusive; provided, however, that any such member inactive who is receiving or had received a retirement allowance shall repay into the system from which he is receiving or had received such allowance the total amount of any such allowance received from the date of his retirement to the date of his again becoming a member in service.
Chapter 32: Election of appointed justice to membership in service of a retirement system
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 176, Sec. 46 effective February 16, 2012 applicable as provided by 2011, 176, Sec. 63. For text effective until February 16, 2012, see above.]  Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter to the contrary, any member inactive of a retirement system appointed by the governor to a position as a chief justice, justice, associate justice, judge, associate judge or special justice may elect within thirty days of such appointment to become a member in service of the system pertaining to the position to which he is appointed, subject to the provisions of sections sixty-five A to sixty-five D, inclusive; provided, however, that any such member inactive who is receiving or had received a retirement allowance shall repay into the system from which he is receiving or had received such allowance the total amount of any such allowance received from the date of his retirement to the date of his again becoming a member in service, together with buyback interest.
    </text>
</law>