<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>49C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employment Of Prisoners Of County Correctional Institutions On Municipal Properties Within County</catch_line>
    <order_by>49C</order_by>
    <text>
        Prisoners in county correctional institutions may, in the custody of an officer, be eligible to provide services for municipalities within the county, including the care of public lands or buildings and grounds. No prisoner may participate in a program under this section unless he has been screened both by the committee for the correctional institution wherein he is confined that determines an inmate’s fitness to participate in outside programs, and by a member of the professional staff of the institution or agency at which he is to provide such care or service. Said member shall be designated by the head of said institution or agency or the person in charge of such public lands or buildings. Any prisoner who escapes from the premises at which he is providing care or service under this section shall be deemed to have escaped from the institution of which he is an inmate. No prisoner, except as provided in section forty-nine, shall be employed outside the precincts of the place of his imprisonment doing work of any kind for private persons. 
No person who is serving a sentence for violation of or for an attempt to commit any crime referred to in section two, three, four, five, six, seven, twelve, thirteen, fourteen, fifteen, sixteen, seventeen, eighteen, twenty-four, twenty-six, twenty-eight, twenty-eight A, twenty-eight B, twenty-nine, thirty, thirty A, thirty-one, thirty-two, thirty-four, thirty-five, or thirty-five A of chapter two hundred and seventy-two or section thirteen B, 13B1/2, 13B3/4, twenty-two, twenty-two A, 22B, 22C, twenty-three, 23A, 23B, twenty-four, twenty-four B of chapter two hundred and sixty-five or who is under commitment under the provisions of chapter one hundred and twenty-three A may participate in a program under the provisions of this section.
    </text>
</law>