<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>151B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>151B</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in sections 151A to 151N, inclusive, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires a different meaning have the following meanings:— 
“Adult”, individuals legally classified as adults and juveniles treated as adults by court order, statute, or operation of law. 
“By-laws”, by-laws established by the interstate commission for its governance, or for directing or controlling the interstate commission’s actions or conduct. 
“Compact administrator”, the individual in each compacting state appointed pursuant to the terms of this compact responsible for the administration and management of the state’s supervision and transfer of offenders subject to the terms of this compact, the rules adopted by the interstate commission and policies adopted by the state council under this compact. 
“Compacting state”, any state which has enacted the enabling legislation for this compact. 
“Commissioner”, the voting representative of each compacting state appointed pursuant to section 151D. 
“Interstate commission”, the interstate commission for adult offender supervision established by this compact. 
“Member”, the commissioner of a compacting state or his designee, who shall be a person officially connected with the commissioner. 
“Non compacting state”, any state which has not enacted the enabling legislation for this compact. 
“Offender”, an adult placed under or subject to supervision as the result of the commission of a criminal offense and released to the community under the jurisdiction of courts, paroling authorities, corrections or other criminal justice agencies. 
“Person”, any individual, corporation, business enterprise, or other legal entity, either public or private. 
“Rules”, acts of the interstate commission, duly promulgated pursuant to section 151H, substantially affecting interested parties in addition to the interstate commission, which shall have the force and effect of law in the compacting states. 
“State”, a state of the United States, the District of Columbia and any other territorial possessions of the United States. 
“State council”, the resident members of the state council for interstate adult offender supervision created by each state under section 151D.
    </text>
</law>