<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>151H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Rulemaking; Authority And Procedure</catch_line>
    <order_by>151H</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The interstate commission shall promulgate rules in order to effectively and efficiently achieve the purposes of the compact including transition rules governing administration of the compact during the period in which it is being considered and enacted by the states.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Rulemaking shall occur pursuant to the criteria set forth in this section and the by-laws and rules adopted pursuant thereto. Such rulemaking shall substantially conform to the principles of the federal Administrative Procedure Act, 5 U.S.C.S. section 551 et seq., and the Federal Advisory Committee Act, 5 U.S.C.S. app. 2, section 1 et seq., as may be amended.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     All rules and amendments shall become binding as of the date specified in each rule or amendment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     If a majority of the legislatures of the compacting states rejects a rule, by enactment of a statute or resolution in the same manner used to adopt the compact, then such rule shall have no further force and effect in any compacting state.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     When promulgating a rule, the interstate commission shall:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     publish the proposed rule stating with particularity the text of the rule which is proposed and the reason for the proposed rule;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     allow persons to submit written data, facts, opinions and arguments, which information shall be publicly available;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     provide an opportunity for an informal hearing; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     promulgate a final rule and its effective date, if appropriate, based on the rulemaking record.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     Subjects to be addressed within 12 months after the first meeting shall, at a minimum, include:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     notice to victims and opportunity to be heard;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     offender registration and compliance;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     violations or returns;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     transfer procedures and forms;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     eligibility for transfer;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     collection of restitution and fees from offenders;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     data collection and reporting;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     the level of supervision to be provided by the receiving state;
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     transition rules governing the operation of the compact and the interstate commission during all or part of the period between the effective date of the compact and the date on which the last eligible state adopts the compact; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     mediation, arbitration and dispute resolution.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The existing rules governing the operation of the previous compact superceded by this chapter shall be null and void 12 months after the first meeting of the interstate commission created hereunder.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     Upon determination by the interstate commission that an emergency exists, it may promulgate an emergency rule which shall become effective immediately upon adoption, provided that the usual rulemaking procedures provided hereunder shall be retroactively applied to said rule as soon as reasonably possible, but in no event later than 90 days after the effective date of the rule.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>