<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>38B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assaults Upon Guards;  Bodily Substances;  Penalty</catch_line>
    <order_by>38B</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) For the purposes of this section, "bodily substance'' shall mean any human secretion, discharge or emission including, but not limited to, blood, saliva, mucous, semen, urine or feces.[ Subsections (b) and (c) effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (b) Any person in the custody of a correctional facility, including any jail, house of correction or state prison, who commits an assault or an assault and battery upon an officer or other employee, any volunteer or employee of a contractor in any such facility or any duly authorized officer or other employee of any such facility engaged in the transportation of a prisoner for any lawful purpose shall be punished by imprisonment for not more than 2 and one-half years in a jail or house of correction or for not more than 10 years in a state prison. Such sentence shall begin from and after all sentences currently outstanding and unserved at the time of said assault or assault and battery.  (c) Any person in the custody of a correctional facility, including any jail, house of correction or state prison, who commits an assault or an assault and battery by means of a bodily substance upon an officer or other employee, any volunteer or employee of a contractor in any such facility or any duly authorized officer or other employee of any such facility engaged in the transportation of a prisoner for any lawful purpose shall be punished by imprisonment for not more than 2 and one-half years in a jail or house of correction or for not more than 10 years in a state prison. Such sentence shall begin from and after all sentences currently outstanding and unserved at the time of said assault or assault and battery.[ Subsections (b) and (c) as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 121 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (b) Any person in the custody of a correctional facility, including any jail, house of correction, trial court detention facility or state prison, who commits an assault or an assault and battery upon an officer or other employee, any volunteer or employee of a contractor in any such facility or any duly authorized officer or other employee of any such facility engaged in the transportation of a prisoner for any lawful purpose shall be punished by imprisonment for not more than 2 and one-half years in a jail or house of correction or for not more than 10 years in a state prison. Such sentence shall begin from and after all sentences currently outstanding and unserved at the time of said assault or assault and battery.  (c) Any person in the custody of a correctional facility, including any jail, house of correction, trial court detention facility or state prison, who commits an assault or an assault and battery by means of a bodily substance upon an officer or other employee, any volunteer or employee of a contractor in any such facility or any duly authorized officer or other employee of any such facility engaged in the transportation of a prisoner for any lawful purpose shall be punished by imprisonment for not more than 2 and one-half years in a jail or house of correction or for not more than 10 years in a state prison. Such sentence shall begin from and after all sentences currently outstanding and unserved at the time of said assault or assault and battery.
    </text>
</law>