<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="2">Prisons, Imprisonment, Paroles And Pardons</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="127" order_by="127" level="3">Officers And Inmates Of Penal And Reformatory Institutions. Paroles And Pardons</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>135</section_number>
    <catch_line>Furnishing Information To Parole Board; Filing Information;  Statement; Contents; Availability; Duty Of Clerk Of Court And Probation Officer</catch_line>
    <order_by>135</order_by>
    <text>
        The commissioner or the jailer, superintendent or keeper of a jail or house of correction shall furnish to the parole board all information in his possession relating to any prisoner whose case is under consideration. As each prisoner is received in the correctional institutions of the commonwealth or in the jails or houses of correction, it shall be the duty of the commissioner of correction or of the jailer, superintendent or keeper, while the case is still recent, to cause to be obtained and filed information as complete as may be obtainable at that time with regard to such prisoner. Such information shall include a complete statement of the crime for which he is then sentenced, the circumstances of such crime, the nature of his sentence, the court in which he was sentenced, the name of the judge and district attorney, and copies of such probation reports as may have been made, as well as reports as to the prisoner’s social, physical, mental and psychiatric condition and history. It shall be the duty of the clerk of the court and of all probation officers and other appropriate officials to send such information as may be in their possession or under their control to the commissioner or the jailer, superintendent or keeper of a jail or house of correction, upon request. The commissioner or the jailer, superintendent or keeper of a jail or house of correction shall also at that time obtain and file a copy of the complete criminal record of such prisoner, so far as reasonably available, including any juvenile court record that may exist. When all such existing available records have been assembled, they shall be made available to the parole board so as to be readily accessible when the parole or pardon of such prisoner is being considered.
    </text>
</law>