<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="199A" order_by="199A" level="3">General Provisions Regarding Certain Foreign Fiduciaries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Payment Or Delivery Of Property To Foreign Fiduciaries</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 20. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  At any time after the expiration of sixty days from the death of a nonresident decedent, any person indebted to the estate of the nonresident decedent or having possession or control of personal property, or of an instrument evidencing a debt, obligation, stock or chose in action belonging to the estate of the nonresident decedent, or holding personal property subject to a general power of appointment exercised by the will of a nonresident decedent duly admitted to probate in a foreign jurisdiction, may pay the debt, deliver the personal property, or the instrument evidencing the debt, obligation, stock or chose in action, to the domiciliary foreign personal representative of the nonresident decedent upon being presented with proof of his status and an affidavit made by or on behalf of the representative stating:  (1) the date of death of the nonresident decedent,  (2) that no local administration, or application or petition therefor, is pending in the commonwealth, and  (3) that the foreign personal representative is entitled to payment or delivery.  Payment or delivery may be made to a foreign personal representative of a nonresident decedent appointed in a jurisdiction which was not the domicile of the decedent upon similar proof of appointment and affidavit, if such affidavit also states that there is no domiciliary foreign personal representative and no proceedings are pending for appointment of a personal representative in any court in the jurisdiction of the decedent's domicile and that the foreign personal representative is the personal representative appointed in the appointment proceeding first commenced.  If such nonresident decedent owned tangible personal property located in the commonwealth at the time of his death, or at any time during the twelve months preceding his death had a permanent or temporary place of abode in the commonwealth, a foreign personal representative of the decedent shall not accept payment or delivery pursuant to this section earlier than one month after filing proof of his authority in accordance with section five with a copy to the commissioner of revenue.  Any person indebted to a nonresident protected person who has not been domiciled in the commonwealth at any time within the preceding year, or having possession or control of personal property, or of an instrument evidencing a debt, obligation, stock or chose in action belonging to such nonresident protected person may pay the debt, deliver the personal property, or the instrument to the domiciliary foreign guardian or conservator upon being presented with proof of his appointment and an affidavit made by or on behalf of the guardian or conservator stating:  (1) that the protected person is not and has not been domiciled in the commonwealth at any time within the preceding year,  (2) that no local guardian or conservator has been appointed for the protected person and no application or petition therefor is pending in the commonwealth, and  (3) that the foreign guardian or conservator has duly qualified, is currently acting and is entitled to payment or delivery.  Payment or delivery may be made to a foreign guardian or conservator of a nonresident protected person appointed in a jurisdiction which is not the current domicile of the protected person upon similar proof of appointment and affidavit, if such affidavit also states:  (1) that there is no domiciliary foreign guardian or conservator and no proceedings are pending for appointment of a guardian or conservator in any court of the jurisdiction of the protected person's domicile, and  (2) that either the protected person was domiciled in the jurisdiction in which the foreign guardian or conservator was appointed at the time of his appointment, or that the foreign guardian or conservator is the guardian or conservator appointed in the appointment proceeding first commenced.
    </text>
</law>