<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="192" order_by="192" level="3">Probate Of Wills And Appointment Of Executors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Proof Of Will In Uncontested Proceedings;  Waiver Of Proof</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 12. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  If it appears to the probate court, by the consent in writing of the heirs, or by other satisfactory evidence, that no person interested in the estate of deceased person intends to object to the probate of an instrument purporting to be the will of such deceased, the court may grant probate thereof; (i) upon the testimony of one of the subscribing witnesses; and the affidavit of such witness taken before the register or an assistant register of probate may be received as evidence; (ii) without testimony if it is self-proved by affidavits of the testator and of the witnesses, each made before an officer authorized to administer oaths under the laws of the state where executed, under official seal, in form and content substantially as follows: State of _____, County of _____, before me, the undersigned authority on this day personally appeared the testator and the witnesses whose names are signed to the attached or foregoing instrument, and, all of these persons being by me duly sworn; the testator declared to me and to the witnesses in my presence that the instrument is his last will and that he had willingly signed or directed another to sign for him, and that he executed it as his free and voluntary act for the purposes therein expressed; and each of the witnesses stated to me, in the presence of the testator, that he signed the will as witness and that to the best of his knowledge the testator was eighteen years of age or over, of sound mind and under no constraint or undue influence. _____ (Testator), _____ (Witness), _____ (Witness). Subscribed and sworn to before me by the said testator and the said witnesses, this _____ day of _____ A.D. (signed) _____ (SEAL) official capacity of officer; (iii) without testimony if it is executed, attested and made self-proved by affidavits of the testator and the witnesses, each affidavit being made before an officer authorized to administer oaths under the laws of the state where executed, and under official seal. The same signature shall be sufficient for the execution, or attestation and the affidavit. The form and content shall be substantially as follows:  I, the undersigned testator, do hereby declare that I sign (or direct another to sign for me) and execute this instrument as my last will, that I sign it willingly (or willingly direct another to sign for me) in the presence of each of said witnesses, and that I execute it as my free and voluntary act for the purposes herein expressed. ______________________________ Testator  We, the undersigned witnesses, each do hereby declare in the presence of the aforesaid testator that the testator signed (or directed another to sign for him and said person signed for him) and executed this instrument as his last will in the presence of each of us, that he signed it willingly (or willingly directed another to sign it for him), that each of us hereby signs this will as witness in the presence of the testator, and that to the best of our knowledge the testator is eighteen (18) years of age or over, of sound mind, and under no constraint or undue influence. ______________________________ (Witness) ______________________________ (Witness)STATE OF ________COUNTY OF ________Subscribed, sworn to and acknowledged before me by the said testator and witnesses this _____ day of _____ A.D. (Signed) ____________________ (Seal) ____________________ Official Capacity; or (iv) without testimony if the probate of such instrument is assented to in writing by the widow or husband of the deceased, if any, and by all the heirs at law and next of kin.
    </text>
</law>