<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="192" order_by="192" level="3">Probate Of Wills And Appointment Of Executors</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Powers And Duties Of Temporary Executors Or Administrators With Will Annexed</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 12. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  A temporary executor or a temporary administrator with the will annexed shall collect all the personal property of the deceased and preserve the same for the executor, administrator or administrator with the will annexed when appointed, and for that purpose may commence, maintain and defend suits. Unless otherwise directed in the will, the court may, in the decree appointing him or otherwise, without the necessity of notice, authorize the temporary executor or temporary administrator with the will annexed:--  (1) to take charge of the real property of the deceased or any part thereof, and collect rents, make necessary repairs and do all other things which the court may consider necessary for the preservation of such real property and as a charge thereon;  (2) to sell any personal property of the estate and to make such investments as would be proper investments for an executor;  (3) to pay from the personal property in his hands the reasonable expenses of the last sickness, funeral and taxes of the deceased; and  (4) to continue the business of the deceased for the benefit of his estate.  The probate court may, upon such notice, if any, as it considers reasonable, authorize or require a temporary executor or temporary administrator with the will annexed to do such other acts relative to any property or estate in his charge as it may deem necessary, but except as to continuing the business of the deceased this section shall not give to the temporary executor or temporary administrator with the will annexed other or greater powers than those granted to the named executor by the will. The temporary executor or temporary administrator with the will annexed shall not distribute any of the property in his hands except such amounts as may be allowed by the court to the widow or minor children for necessities.
    </text>
</law>