<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="191A" order_by="191A" level="3">Disclaimer Of Certain Property Interest Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Filing;  Acknowledgment;  Recording;  Service</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 11. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  The original of the disclaimer or an attested copy thereof, if filing is required to be made with more than one probate court, shall be filed with the probate court, or probate courts, if any, wherein a duly appointed fiduciary, if any, having custody or control of the property, an interest in which is being disclaimed, is required to file periodic accounts.  If the property, an interest in which is being disclaimed, is real property, the disclaimer shall be acknowledged in the manner provided for deeds of real property. The disclaimer shall not be valid as against any person, except the beneficiary, the heirs and devisees of the beneficiary, and any person, estate, trust, corporation or other legal entity having actual notice of the disclaimer, unless the original thereof or an attested copy thereof if the original is required to be filed with a probate court, is recorded in the registry of deeds for the county or district in which the real property is situated or, in the case of registered real property, is filed and registered in the office of the assistant recorder for the registry district in which the real property is located.  A copy of the disclaimer shall be served by delivering in hand or by mailing by certified mail to the last known address of the person or persons or other legal entity or entities having custody or possession of the property, an interest in which is being disclaimed. Failure to comply with these requirements of service shall not affect the validity of the disclaimer.
    </text>
</law>