<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="190" order_by="190" level="3">Descent And Distribution Of Real And Personal Property</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Intermarriage Of Parents Of Persons Born Out Of Wedlock</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 7. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  A person born out of wedlock whose parents have intermarried and whose father has acknowledged him as his child or has been adjudged his father under chapter two hundred and seventy-three, chapter two hundred and nine C or under similar law of another jurisdiction shall be deemed legitimate and shall be entitled to take the name of his parents to the same extent as if born in lawful wedlock. If a decedent has acknowledged paternity of a person born out of wedlock or if during his lifetime or after his death a decedent has been adjudged to be the father of a person born out of wedlock that person is heir of his father and of any person from whom his father might have inherited, if living, and the descendents of a person born out of wedlock shall represent that person and take by descent any estate which such person would have taken, if living. A person may establish paternity if, within the period provided under section nine of chapter one hundred and ninety-seven for bringing actions against executors and administrators, such person either (a) delivers to the executor or administrator an authenticated copy of a judgment rendered by a court of competent jurisdiction during a decedent's lifetime adjudging the decedent to be the father of a person born out of wedlock, or (b) commences, in a court of competent jurisdiction, an action in which the executor or administrator is a named party and in which such paternity is ultimately proved.
    </text>
</law>