<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197" level="3">Payment Of Debts, Legacies And Distributive Shares</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24</section_number>
    <catch_line>Distributive Shares, Enforcement Of Payment</catch_line>
    <order_by>24</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 16. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  When the amount due a person who is next of kin or a distributee of an intestate estate on account of his share of the personal property has been ascertained by a decree of the probate court for distribution or partial distribution, or whenever any real or personal estate comprised in a trust or in the estate of a deceased person is ordered by the probate court to be sold and distributed under section nineteen of chapter two hundred and two, section twenty-five of chapter two hundred and three or section twenty-one of chapter two hundred and six, or any legacy or any surplus proceeds of sale are ordered by said court to be distributed or disposed of pursuant to the preceding section or section nine of chapter two hundred and four, or whenever said court in pursuance of any authority conferred on it orders the distribution or disposal of any fund or moneys, payment of the same, by the executor, administrator, trustee or other person so ordered to pay or distribute, to the person entitled may, if the executor, administrator, trustee or other person neglects upon demand to pay such amount, be enforced summarily by the probate court upon motion of the person entitled, in the same manner as a like payment under a decree in equity may be enforced, and execution may also be issued therefor against the executor, administrator, trustee or other person personally as upon a judgment at law.
    </text>
</law>