<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="199A" order_by="199A" level="3">General Provisions Regarding Certain Foreign Fiduciaries</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Proceedings To Determine Property Rights;  Representation By Foreign Fiduciaries</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 20. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  In any proceeding in the commonwealth to determine rights in real or personal property in the commonwealth or administered by a fiduciary in the commonwealth or under a will admitted to probate in the commonwealth:  (a) The interest of a nonresident decedent whose estate is not under local administration may be represented by any foreign personal representative of a decedent named a party to the proceeding and served in the manner provided in section eleven or by other lawful means;  (b) The interest of a nonresident protected person named a party to the proceeding for whom there is no local guardian or conservator may be represented by a foreign guardian or conservator served in the manner provided in section eleven or by other lawful means. The authority of a foreign personal representative or of a foreign guardian or conservator under this section shall include authority to be a party to an agreement of compromise in respect of the rights of the decedent or the protected person in such property. The procedures authorized in this section are in addition to and not in limitation of all other applicable procedures.
    </text>
</law>