<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="204" order_by="204" level="3">General Provisions Relative To Sales, Mortgages, Releases, Compromises, Etc., By Executors, Etc.</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Power Of Massachusetts Fiduciary To Transfer Personal Property To Foreign Fiduciaries;  Petition;  Proceedings;  Decree;  Exoneration Of Massachusetts Fiduciary</catch_line>
    <order_by>3A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 28. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  An executor, administrator, guardian, conservator or trustee who has in his hands personal property to which an executor, administrator, guardian, conservator or trustee duly appointed in another state or in a foreign country and duly qualified and acting is entitled may pay over and transfer the whole or any part of such personal property to such foreign fiduciary upon such terms and in such manner as the probate court by which such Massachusetts fiduciary was appointed, or, if not appointed by the probate court, as the probate court for any county where there is property to which such foreign fiduciary is entitled, may decree upon petition filed therefor. Proceedings upon such petition shall be governed by the provisions of section three. No such petition for a decree ordering distribution to a foreign executor or administrator shall be filed until the expiration of three months after the death of his testator or intestate. Payment or transfer by a Massachusetts fiduciary in accordance with a decree under this section or section three shall forever exonerate such fiduciary unless the decree is impeached for fraud or manifest error.
    </text>
</law>