<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="203" order_by="203" level="3">Trusts</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Testamentary Additions To Trusts</catch_line>
    <order_by>3B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 25. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  A devise or bequest, the validity of which is determinable by the laws of the commonwealth, may be made to the trustee or trustees of a trust established or to be established by the testator or by the testator and some other person or persons or by some other person or persons, including a funded or unfunded life insurance trust, although the trustor has reserved any or all rights of ownership of the insurance contracts, if the trust is identified in the will and the terms of the trust are set forth in a written instrument executed before or concurrently with the execution of the testator's will or set forth in the valid will of a person who has predeceased the testator, regardless of the existence, size or character of the corpus of the trust. The devise or bequest shall not be invalid because the trust is amendable or revocable, or both, or because the trust was amended after the execution of the will or after the death of the testator. Unless the will provides otherwise, the property so devised or bequeathed (a) shall not be deemed to be held under a testamentary trust of the testator, but shall become a part of the trust to which it is given and (b) shall be administered and disposed of in accordance with the provisions of the instrument or will setting forth the terms of the trust, including any amendments thereto made before or after the death of the testator. A revocation or termination of the trust before the death of the testator shall cause the devise or bequest to lapse.
    </text>
</law>