<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="191A" order_by="191A" level="3">Disclaimer Of Certain Property Interest Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Interests Which May Be Disclaimed</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 31, 2012. Repealed by 2008, 521, Sec. 11. See 2008, 521, Sec. 44 as amended by 2010, 409, Sec. 23 and 2011, 224.]  Unless barred by the provisions of section eight, a beneficiary may disclaim any interest in property which, except for the execution and filing of a disclaimer in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, pass to the beneficiary:--  1. By intestate succession, devise, legacy, bequest, exercise or nonexercise of a power of appointment exercisable by will, or testamentary exercise or nonexercise of a power of appointment exercisable by either deed of trust or will; as beneficiary of a testamentary trust, beneficiary of a testamentary gift to a nontestamentary trust, or donee of a power of appointment created by will; by succession in any manner described in this clause to a disclaimed interest; or in any other manner not specified above under a testamentary instrument or by operation of any statute or rule of law governing devolution or disposition of property upon or after a person's death.  2. As donee, grantee, beneficiary of an inter-vivos trust, beneficiary of an insurance or annuity contract, donee of a power of appointment created by a nontestamentary instrument, or as surviving joint tenant or tenant by the entirety, except that a surviving joint tenant or tenant by the entirety may not disclaim that portion of an interest in joint property or property held by the entirety which is allocable to amounts contributed by him or her to the interest in such property; through exercise or nonexercise of a power of appointment exercisable by deed, or nontestamentary exercise or nonexercise of a power of appointment exercisable by deed of trust or will; under any deed, assignment, or other nontestamentary instrument of conveyance or transfer; by succession in any manner described in this clause to a disclaimed interest; or in any other manner not specified above under a nontestamentary instrument or by operation of any statute or rule of law.  Disclaimer may be made for a beneficiary under a legal disability by the duly appointed guardian or conservator of such beneficiary, and for a deceased beneficiary by the legal representative of such beneficiary's estate; provided, in any case, however, that the probate court having jurisdiction of the estate of such beneficiary shall have decreed, upon complaint filed by such guardian, conservator, or legal representative, that such disclaimer is in the best interests of those interested in the estate of such beneficiary and not detrimental to the best interests of the beneficiary or the estate of such beneficiary, and that such guardian, conservator, or legal representative is authorized to execute and file such disclaimer on behalf of such beneficiary in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.
    </text>
</law>