<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="1">Real And Personal Property And Domestic Relations</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Descent And Distribution, Wills, Estates Of Deceased Persons And Absentees, Guardianship, Conservatorship And Trusts</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="203A" order_by="203A" level="3">Uniform Common Trust Fund Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Court Accountings</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 8, 2012. For text effective July 8, 2012, see below.]  An account of the administration of each common trust fund and a copy of the annual financial report of the fund shall be filed annually in the registry of probate in which the declaration of trust has been filed. A fiduciary may file an application for allowance of any such account, but shall not be required to file such application unless ordered by said probate court on motion of any interested party to such account or on motion of the court. Application for allowance of any such account shall be made in accordance with section twenty-four of chapter two hundred and six. The allowance of any such account shall be conclusive as to all matters shown therein upon all persons then or thereafter interested in the funds invested in said common trust fund.
Chapter 203A: Court accountings
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 140, Sec. 55 effective July 8, 2012 applicable as provided by 2012, 140, Sec. 66. For text effective until July 8, 2012, see above.]  An account of the administration of each common trust fund and a copy of the annual financial report of the fund shall be filed annually in the registry of probate in which the declaration of trust has been filed. A fiduciary may file an application for allowance of any such account, but shall not be required to file such application unless ordered by said probate court on motion of any interested party to such account or on motion of the court. A proceeding for the allowance of an account brought pursuant to this chapter in the probate and family court department of the trial court may be initiated by filing a petition and giving notice as provided under sections 1-401 and 1-403 of chapter 190B and section 1-404 of said chapter 190B shall apply to such proceeding. The allowance of any such account shall be conclusive as to all matters shown therein upon all persons then or thereafter interested in the funds invested in said common trust fund.
    </text>
</law>