<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="265" order_by="265" level="3">Crimes Against The Person</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>49</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions For Secs. 49 To 57</catch_line>
    <order_by>49</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 178, Sec. 23 effective February 19, 2012.]  As used in sections 50 to 51, inclusive, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:  "Commercial sexual activity'', any sexual act on account of which anything of value is given, promised to or received by any person.  "Financial harm'', a detrimental position in relation to wealth, property or other monetary benefits that occurs as a result of another person's illegal act including, but not limited to, extortion under by section 25, a violation of section 49 of chapter 271 or illegal employment contracts.  "Forced services'', services performed or provided by a person that are obtained or maintained by another person who: (i) causes or threatens to cause serious harm to any person; (ii) physically restrains or threatens to physically restrain another person; (iii) abuses or threatens to abuse the law or legal process; (iv) knowingly destroys, conceals, removes, confiscates or possesses any actual or purported passport or other immigration document, or any other actual or purported government identification document, of another person; (v) engages in extortion under section 25; or (vi) causes or threatens to cause financial harm to any person.  "Services'', acts performed by a person under the supervision of or for the benefit of another including, but not limited to, commercial sexual activity and sexually-explicit performances.  "Sexually-explicit performance'', an unlawful live or public act or show intended to arouse or satisfy the sexual desires or appeal to the prurient interests of patrons.
    </text>
</law>