<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="268A" order_by="268A" level="3">Conduct Of Public Officials And Employees</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Other Compensation; Offer, Gift, Receipt Or Request; Acting As Agent Or Attorney For Other Than State; Legislators; Special State Employees</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     No state employee shall otherwise than as provided by law for the proper discharge of official duties, directly or indirectly receive or request compensation from anyone other than the commonwealth or a state agency, in relation to any particular matter in which the commonwealth or a state agency is a party or has a direct and substantial interest.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No person shall knowingly, otherwise than as provided by law for the proper discharge of official duties, directly or indirectly give, promise or offer such compensation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     No state employee shall, otherwise than in the proper discharge of his official duties, act as agent or attorney for anyone other than the commonwealth or a state agency for prosecuting any claim against the commonwealth or a state agency, or as agent or attorney for anyone in connection with any particular matter in which the commonwealth or a state agency is a party or has a direct and substantial interest.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the particular matter before the state agency is ministerial in nature; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the appearance is before a court of the commonwealth; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     the appearance is in a quasi-judicial proceeding.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the action of the state agency is adjudicatory in nature; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the action of the state agency in appealable to the courts; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     both sides are entitled to representation by counsel and such counsel is neither the attorney general nor the counsel for the state agency conducting the proceeding.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>