<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="271" order_by="271" level="3">Crimes Against Public Policy</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Gambling Devices;  Forfeiture;  Antique Slot Machines</catch_line>
    <order_by>5A</order_by>
    <text>
          Whoever manufactures, transports, sells, offers for sale, stores, displays, repairs, reconditions, possesses or uses any gambling device or parts for use therein shall be punished by a fine of not more than five thousand dollars; provided, however, that fifty percent of the said fine shall be remitted to the city or town in which the violation occurred. The remaining fifty percent shall be remitted to the general fund of the commonwealth. As used in this section, the term "gambling device'' means any so called "slot machine'' or any other machine or mechanical device an essential part of which is a drum or reel with insignia thereon, and which, when operated, may deal, as a result of the application of an element of chance, any money or property; or by the operation of which a person may become entitled to receive, as the result of the application of an element of chance, any money or property; or any sub-assembly or essential part intended to be used in connection with any such machine or mechanical device. Any gambling device or parts for use therein manufactured, transported, sold, offered for sale, stored, displayed, repaired, reconditioned, possessed or used in violation of this section shall be seized and be forfeited to the commonwealth and disposed of in the manner provided under the provisions of chapter two hundred and seventy-six. In respect to their constitutionality, the provisions of this section are hereby declared to be separable.  It shall be a defense to any prosecution under this section to show that the slot machine is an antique slot machine and was not operated for gambling purposes while in the defendant's possession. For the purposes of this section, a slot machine shall be presumed to be an antique slot machine, if it was manufactured at least thirty years prior to either the arrest of the defendant, or seizure of the machine.[ Paragraph added by 2011, 194, Sec. 55 effective November 22, 2011.]  This section shall not apply to persons who manufacture, transport, sell, offer for sale, store, display, repair, recondition, possess or use any gambling device or parts for use in such a device for licensed gaming conducted under chapter 23K.
    </text>
</law>