<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="269" order_by="269" level="3">Crimes Against Public Peace</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Willful And Malicious Communication Of False Information To Public Safety Answering Points; Penalty</catch_line>
    <order_by>14B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Whoever willfully and maliciously communicates with a PSAP, or causes a communication to be made to a PSAP, which communication transmits information which the person knows or has reason to know is false and which results in the dispatch of emergency services to a nonexistent emergency or to the wrong location of an actual emergency; or (b) whoever willfully and maliciously, makes or causes to be made 3 or more silent calls to any PSAP and thereby causes emergency services to be dispatched 3 or more times shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 21/2 years or by a fine of not more than $1,000. Whoever commits a second or subsequent violation of this section shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 21/2 years or by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than 10 years or by a fine of not more than 5,000 dollars, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Upon any conviction of this section, the court shall conduct a hearing to ascertain the extent of costs incurred, and damages and financial loss sustained by any emergency response services provider as a result of the violation and shall order the defendant to make restitution to the emergency response services provider or providers for any such costs, damages or loss. Restitution shall not be waived and shall be imposed in addition to any imprisonment or fine, and not in lieu thereof, except that the court shall consider the defendant’s present and future ability to pay restitution in its determinations relative to the imposition of a fine. In determining the amount, time and method of payment of restitution, the court shall consider the financial resources of the defendant and the burden restitution will impose upon the defendant.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>