<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="271" order_by="271" level="3">Crimes Against Public Policy</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Gaming Relative To Cattle Shows, Military Muster Or Public Gathering;  Arrest Without Warrant</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 22, 2011. For text effective November 22, 2011, see below.]  Whoever, during or within twelve hours of the time of holding a cattle show, military muster or public gathering, within one mile of the place thereof, practices or engages in any gambling or unlawful game, shall forfeit not more than twenty dollars. If discovered in the act, he may be arrested without a warrant by any sheriff, deputy sheriff, constable or any officer qualified to serve criminal process, and held in custody, in jail or otherwise, for not more than twenty-four hours, Sunday and legal holidays excepted, until a complaint may be made against him for such offence.
Chapter 271: Gaming relative to cattle shows, military muster or public gathering; arrest without warrant
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 194, Sec. 56 effective November 22, 2011. For text effective until November 22, 2011, see above.]  Whoever, during or within twelve hours of the time of holding a cattle show, military muster or public gathering, within one mile of the place thereof, practices or engages in illegal gaming, shall forfeit not more than twenty dollars. If discovered in the act, he may be arrested without a warrant by any sheriff, deputy sheriff, constable or any officer qualified to serve criminal process, and held in custody, in jail or otherwise, for not more than twenty-four hours, Sunday and legal holidays excepted, until a complaint may be made against him for such offence.
    </text>
</law>