<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="271" order_by="271" level="3">Crimes Against Public Policy</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Gaming, Lottery, Pool Or Betting Houses;  Tables Or Apparatus For Gaming</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 22, 2011. For text effective November 22, 2011, see below.]  Whoever keeps or assists in keeping a common gaming house, or building or place occupied, used or kept for the purposes described in section twenty-three, or is found playing or present as provided in said section, or commonly keeps or suffers to be kept, in a building or place actually used and occupied by him, tables or other apparatus for the purpose of playing at an unlawful game or sport for money or any other valuable thing, shall be punished by a fine of not more than fifty dollars or by imprisonment for not more than three months.
Chapter 271: Gaming, lottery, pool or betting houses; tables or apparatus for gaming
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 194, Sec. 54 effective November 22, 2011. For text effective until November 22, 2011, see above.]  Whoever, except as permitted under chapter 23K, keeps or assists in keeping a common gaming house, or building or place occupied, used or kept for the purposes described in section twenty-three, or is found playing or present as provided in said section, or commonly keeps or suffers to be kept, in a building or place actually used and occupied by him, tables or other apparatus for the purpose of playing at an unlawful game or sport for money or any other valuable thing, shall be punished by a fine of not more than fifty dollars or by imprisonment for not more than three months.
    </text>
</law>