<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="272" order_by="272" level="3">Crimes Against Chastity, Morality, Decency And Good Order</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>105</section_number>
    <catch_line>Photographing, Videotaping Or Electronically Surveilling Partially Nude Or Nude Person; Exceptions; Punishment</catch_line>
    <order_by>105</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall have the following meanings unless the context clearly requires otherwise:
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Whoever willfully photographs, videotapes or electronically surveils another person who is nude or partially nude, with the intent to secretly conduct or hide such activity, when the other person in such place and circumstance would have a reasonable expectation of privacy in not being so photographed, videotaped or electronically surveilled, and without that person’s knowledge and consent, shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 21/2 years or by a fine of not more than $5,000, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Whoever willfully disseminates the visual image of another person who is nude or partially nude, with knowledge that such visual image was unlawfully obtained in violation of subsection (b) and without consent of the person so depicted, shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 21/2 years or in the state prison for not more than 5 years or by a fine of not more than $10,000, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     This section shall not apply to a merchant that electronically surveils a customer changing room, provided that signage warning customers of the merchant’s surveillance activity is conspicuously posted at all entrances and in the interior of any changing room electronically surveilled.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     This section shall not apply to a law enforcement officer acting within the scope of the officer’s authority under applicable law, or by an order or warrant issued by a court.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     A sheriff, deputy sheriff or police officer may arrest without a warrant, a person whom he has probable cause to believe has violated this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     A photograph, videotape or other recorded visual image, depicting a person who is nude or partially nude that is part of any court record arising from a prosecution under this section, shall not be open to public inspection and shall only be made available by court personnel to a law enforcement officer, prosecuting attorney, defendant’s attorney, defendant, or victim connected to such prosecution for inspection, unless otherwise ordered by the court.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     In a prosecution under this section, a justice of the superior court or district court may issue appropriate orders to restrain or prevent the unlawful dissemination of a person’s visual image in violation of this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>