<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="271" order_by="271" level="3">Crimes Against Public Policy</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Organizing Or Promoting Gambling Facilities Or Services</catch_line>
    <order_by>16A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 22, 2011. For text effective November 22, 2011, see below.]  Whoever knowingly organizes, supervises, manages or finances at least four persons so that such persons may provide facilities or services or assist in the provision of facilities or services for the conduct of illegal lotteries, or for the illegal registration of bets or the illegal buying or selling of pools upon the result of a trial or contest of skill, speed or endurance of man, beast, bird or machine, or upon the happening of any event, or upon the result of a game, competition, political nomination, appointment or election, or whoever knowingly receives from at least four such persons compensation or payment in any form as a return from such lotteries, such registration or such buying or selling shall be punished by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than fifteen years or by a fine of not more than ten thousand dollars, or by both such fine and imprisonment. As used in this section the word "persons'' shall not include bettors or wagerers who merely avail themselves of such facilities or services for the purpose of making a bet or wager and do not otherwise provide or assist in the provision of such facilities or services. This section shall not apply to such bettors or wagerers.
Chapter 271: Organizing or promoting gambling facilities or services
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 194, Sec. 60 effective November 22, 2011. For text effective until November 22, 2011, see above.]  Whoever knowingly organizes, supervises, manages or finances at least four persons so that such persons may provide facilities or services or assist in the provision of facilities or services for the conduct of illegal lotteries, or for the illegal registration of bets or the illegal buying or selling of pools upon the result of a trial or contest of skill, speed or endurance of man, beast, bird or machine, or upon the happening of any event, or upon the result of a game, competition, political nomination, appointment or election, or whoever knowingly receives from at least four such persons compensation or payment in any form as a return from such lotteries, such registration or such buying or selling shall be punished by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than fifteen years or by a fine of not more than ten thousand dollars, or by both such fine and imprisonment. As used in this section the word "persons'' shall not include bettors or wagerers or persons who organize, supervise, manage or finance persons for the purpose of gaming conducted under chapter 23K who merely avail themselves of such facilities or services for the purpose of making a bet or wager and do not otherwise provide or assist in the provision of such facilities or services. This section shall not apply to such bettors or wagerers.
    </text>
</law>