<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="270" order_by="270" level="3">Crimes Against Public Health</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22</section_number>
    <catch_line>Smoking In Public Places</catch_line>
    <order_by>22</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall have the following meanings, unless the context requires otherwise:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     a society, organization or association of a fraternal nature that operates under the lodge system, and having 1 or more affiliated chapters or branches incorporated in any state; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     a corporation organized under chapter 180 ; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     an established religious place of worship or instruction in the commonwealth whose real or personal property is exempt from taxation; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     a veterans’ organization incorporated or chartered by the Congress of the United States, or otherwise, having 1 or more affiliated chapters or branches incorporated in any state.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Smoking shall be prohibited in workplaces, work spaces, common work areas, classrooms, conference and meeting rooms, offices, elevators, hallways, medical facilities, cafeterias, employee lounges, staircases, restrooms, restaurants, cafes, coffee shops, food courts or concessions, supermarkets or retail food outlets, bars, taverns, or in a place where food or drink is sold to the public and consumed on the premise as part of a business required to collect state meals tax on the purchase; or in a train, airplane, theatre, concert hall, exhibition hall, convention center, auditorium, arena, or stadium open to the public; or in a school, college, university, museum, library, health care facility as defined in section 9C of chapter 112, group child care center, school age child care center, family child care center, school age day or overnight camp building, or on premises where activities are licensed under section 38 of chapter 10 or in or upon any public transportation conveyance or in any airport, train station, bus station, transportation passenger terminal, or enclosed outdoor platform.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A person shall not smoke in the state house or in a public building or in a vehicle or vessel, owned, leased, or otherwise operated by the commonwealth or a political subdivision thereof, or in a space occupied by a state agency or department of the commonwealth which is located in another building, including a private office in a building or space mentioned in this sentence, or at an open meeting of a governmental body as defined in section 11A of chapter 30A, section 23A of chapter 39 and section 9F of chapter 34, or in a courtroom or courthouse. This subsection shall not apply to a resident or patient of a state hospital, the Soldiers’ Home in Massachusetts located in the city of Chelsea or the Soldiers’ Home in Holyoke.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Notwithstanding subsection (b), smoking may be permitted in the following places and circumstances:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Private residences; except during such time when the residence is utilized as part of a business as a group childcare center, school age child care center, school age day or overnight camp, or a facility licensed by the department of early education and care or as a health care related office or facility;
        </section>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     open to the public; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     occupied by a non-member who is not an invited guest of a member or an employee of the association; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="C">
    	     rented from the association for a fee or other agreement that compensates the association for the use of such space.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     Smoking may be permitted in an enclosed indoor space of a membership association at all times, if the space is restricted by the association to admittance only of its members, the invited guest of a member, and the employees of the membership association. A person who is a contract employee, temporary employee, or independent contractor shall not be considered an employee of a membership association under this subsection. A person who is a member of an affiliated chapter or branch of a membership association that is fraternal in nature operating under the lodge system, and is visiting the affiliated association, shall be an invited guest for the purposes of this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A guest room in a hotel, motel, inn, bed and breakfast or lodging home that is designed and normally used for sleeping and living purposes, that is rented to a guest and designated as a smoking room pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (g).
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     A retail tobacco store, if the store maintains a valid permit for the sale of tobacco products issued by the appropriate authority in the city or town in which the retail tobacco store is located. All required permits shall be displayed in a conspicuous manner, visible at all times to patrons of the establishment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     A smoking bar, if the smoking bar maintains a valid permit pursuant to this section. All required permits shall be displayed in a conspicuous manner, visible at all times to patrons of the establishment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     By a theatrical performer upon a stage or in the course of a professional film production, if the smoking is part of a theatrical production, and if permission has been obtained from the appropriate local authority;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     By a person, organization or other entity that conducts medical or scientific research on tobacco products, if the research is conducted in an enclosed space not open to the public, in a laboratory facility at an accredited college or university, or in a professional testing laboratory as defined by regulation of the department of public health;
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     Religious ceremonies where smoking is part of the ritual; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     A tobacco farmer, leaf dealer, manufacturer, importer, exporter, or wholesale distributor of tobacco products, may permit smoking in the workplace for the sole purpose of testing said tobacco for quality assurance purposes; if the smoking is necessary to conduct the test.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     If the outdoor space has a structure capable of being enclosed by walls or covers, regardless of the materials or the removable nature of the walls or covers, the space will be considered enclosed, when the walls or covers are in place. All outdoor spaces shall be physically separated from an enclosed work space. If doors, windows, sliding or folding windows or doors or other fenestrations form any part of the border to the outdoor space, the openings shall be closed to prevent the migration of smoke into the enclosed work space. If the windows, sliding or folding windows or doors or other fenestrations are opened or otherwise do not prevent the migration of smoke into the work space, the outdoor space shall be considered an extension of the enclosed work space and subject to this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     All applications shall designate the residential area of the facility. The residential area shall not contain an employee workspace, such as offices, restrooms or other areas used primarily by employees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The entire facility may not be designated as a residence.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The designated residential area must be for the sole use of permanent residents of the facility. No temporary or short-term resident may reside in the residential portion of the facility.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     All areas in the designated residential area in which smoking is allowed shall be conspicuously designated as smoking areas and be adequately ventilated to prevent the migration of smoke to nonsmoking areas.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     The facility shall provide suitable documentation, acceptable to the local board of health, that the facility is the permanent domicile of the residents residing in that portion of the facility, that information on the hazards of smoking and second hand smoke have been provided to all residences and that smoking cessation aids are available to all residents who use tobacco products.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     The designated residential area shall be in conformance with the smoking restriction requirements of section 72X of chapter 111 and 105 CMR 150.015 (D)(11)(b). All residential areas shall be clearly designated as such and shall not be altered or otherwise changed without the express approval of the local board of health.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     All areas of a nursing home not designated as a residence shall comply with this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     The nursing home shall make reasonable accommodations for an employee, resident or visitor who does not wish to be exposed to tobacco smoke.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     Upon compliance with this section, submission of the required documentation and satisfactory inspection, the local board of health shall certify the designated portion of the facility as a residence. The certification shall be valid for 1 year from the date of issuance. No fewer than 30 days before the expiration of the certification, the facility may apply for re-certification. If the local board of health does not renew the certification before its expiration or provide notice that it has found sufficient cause to not recertify the residence portion of the nursing home as such, the certification shall be considered to continue until the time as the local board of health notifies the nursing home of its certification status.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A retail tobacco store that permits smoking on the premises shall, pursuant to paragraph (4), post in a clear and conspicuous manner, a sign at each entrance warning persons entering the establishment that smoking may be present on the premises; of the health risks associated from second hand smoke; and, that persons under the age of 18 years of age may not enter the premises.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     A smoking bar shall, pursuant to paragraph (4), post in a clear and conspicuous manner signs at all entrances which warn persons entering the establishment that smoking may be present on the premises; and, of the health risks associated from second hand smoke; and, that persons under the age of 18 years of age may not enter the premises.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Every area in which smoking is prohibited by law shall have “no smoking” signs conspicuously posted so that the signs are clearly visible to all employees, customers, or visitors while in the workplace.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Additional signs may be posted in public areas such as, the following areas: lobbies; hallways; cafeterias; kitchens; locker rooms; customer service areas; offices where the public is invited; conference rooms; lounges; waiting areas; and elevators.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Approved signs and templates for signage design may be obtained from the department of public health or the local boards of health.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     It shall be the responsibility of the establishment to ensure that the appropriate signage is displayed and that an individual or group renting the space enforces the prohibition against smoking.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A non-refundable fee may be required with each permit and renewal application. Each permit issued by the department shall be non-transferable, for a specific location and business; and, only 1 permit may be issued to a business for a specific location during any permit period.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The department shall not issue or renew a smoking bar permit to any business that has not filed all tax returns and paid all taxes due the commonwealth; or is delinquent in filing all declaration statements in connection with the smoking bar permit as required by the department.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The department shall notify the local board of health or municipal health department in the city or town where the establishment is located of any permits issued, renewed, suspended, revoked or reinstated to a business.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A smoking bar shall demonstrate on a quarterly basis that revenue generated from the sale of tobacco products are equal to or greater than 51 per cent of the total combined revenue generated by the sale of tobacco products, food and beverages. The department shall require each business that has been issued a smoking bar permit to submit a quarterly declaration for each 3 month period that the business is in operation; notwithstanding, the first declaration may include a period of not to exceed 4 months. A declaration submitted to the department in connection with a smoking bar permit shall be signed by the owner or business agent under the pains and penalties of perjury. A declaration received by the department shall be confidential and the financial information contained therein shall not be disclosed to the public or any other state governmental agency or department except the attorney general. In the event a business has not filed a required declaration statement, the department shall give written notice to the business that the statement is delinquent and, shall suspend the permit of a business that does not submit the required report after 21 days of the date of notice; but the department shall reinstate the suspended permit within 5 days after receiving the delinquent report.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The department of revenue shall promulgate regulations to implement this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Companies which sell ownership rights to owners of time share properties shall distinguish between smoking and non-smoking time share properties. Companies shall disclose to potential buyers whether the unit they are purchasing is a smoking or non-smoking property and post signs accordingly.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Nothing in this section shall permit smoking in an area in which smoking is or may hereafter be prohibited by law including, without limitation: any other law or ordinance or by-law or any fire, health or safety regulation. Nothing in this section shall preempt further limitation of smoking by the commonwealth or any department, agency or political subdivision of the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     An individual, person, entity or organization subject to the smoking prohibitions of this section shall not discriminate or retaliate in any manner against a person for making a complaint of a violation of this section or furnishing information concerning a violation, to a person, entity or organization or to an enforcement authority. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a person making a complaint or furnishing information during any period of work or time of employment, shall do so only at a time that will not pose an increased threat of harm to the safety of other persons in or about such place of work or to the public.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     An individual or person who violates this section by smoking in a place where smoking is prohibited shall be subject to a civil penalty of $100 for each violation. As an alternative to criminal prosecution, a violation of subsection (l) may also be considered a civil violation. Each enforcing agency under paragraph (1) shall dispose of a civil violation of this section by the non-criminal method of disposition procedures contained in section 21D of chapter 40, without an enabling ordinance or by-law, or by the equivalent of these procedures by a state agency under regulations of the department of public health. The disposition of fines assessed under this section shall be subject to section 188 of chapter 111. Fines assessed by the commonwealth or its agents shall be subject to section 2 of chapter 29. In a city or town having an ordinance or by-law that imposes a fine greater than the fine imposed by this section, the ordinance or by-law shall prevail over this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Any person may register a complaint to initiate an investigation and enforcement with the local board of health, the department of public health, or the local inspection department or the equivalent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     The supreme judicial court or the superior court shall issue appropriate orders to enforce this section and any regulation under it, at the request of any agency mentioned in paragraph (1).
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     A fine or fee collected by the commonwealth under this section shall be used for the enforcement or for educational programs on the harmful effects of tobacco.
        </section>
        <section prefix="n">
    	     Each local board of health, each local inspection department or its equivalent, and the alcoholic beverages control commission shall report annually to the commissioner of public health, beginning January 1, 2006: the number of citations issued; the workplaces which have been issued citations and the number of citations issued to each workplace; the amount that each workplace has been fined; and the total amount collected in fines. The department of public health shall file a copy of the report with the clerks of the house of representatives and the senate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="o">
    	     The department of public health may issue regulations to implement this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>