<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="272" order_by="272" level="3">Crimes Against Chastity, Morality, Decency And Good Order</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>85B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assistance Animals Stolen Or Attacked; Actions For Economic And Non Economic Damages</catch_line>
    <order_by>85B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A physically impaired person who uses an assistance animal or the owner of the assistance animal, may bring an action for economic and non-economic damages against a person who steals or attacks the assistance animal. The action authorized by this subsection may be brought by the physically impaired person or owner notwithstanding that the assistance animal was in the custody or under the supervision of another person when the theft or attack occurred. If any other non-assistance animal should attack an assistance animal, the owner of the assistance animal may seek compensation from the owner or custodian of the non-assistance animal found to have caused harm to the assistance animal.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     If the theft or attack of an assistance animal as described in subsection (a) results in the death of the animal or the animal is not returned or if injuries sustained prevent the assistance animal from returning to service, the measure of economic damages shall include, but are not limited to, the veterinary medical expenses and the replacement cost of an equally trained assistance animal, without any differentiation for the age or the experience of the animal.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     A cause of action shall not arise under this section if the physically impaired individual, owner or the individual having custody or supervision of the assistance animal was engaged in the commission of a crime at the time of injury sustained by the assistance animal.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>