<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="268" order_by="268" level="3">Crimes Against Public Justice</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Tampering With Record, Document Or Other Object For Use In An Official Proceeding</catch_line>
    <order_by>13E</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section the following word shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meaning:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Whoever alters, destroys, mutilates, or conceals a record, document, or other object, or attempts to do so, with the intent to impair the record, document or object’s integrity or availability for use in an official proceeding, whether or not the proceeding is pending at that time, shall be punished, by (i) a fine of not more than $10,000, or by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than 5 years, or in a jail or house of correction for not more than 2 1/2 years, or both, or (ii) if the official proceeding involves a violation of a criminal statute, by a fine of not more than $25,000, or by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than 10 years, or in a jail or house of correction for not more than 2 1/2 years, or both.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The record, document, or other object need not be admissible in evidence or free of a claim of privilege.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     A prosecution under this section may be brought in the county where the official proceeding was or would have been convened or where the alleged conduct constituting an offense occurred.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>