<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="269" order_by="269" level="3">Crimes Against Public Peace</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12F</section_number>
    <catch_line>Airport Secure Areas; Possession Or Placement Of A Cutting Device Or Prohibited Weapon; Punishment</catch_line>
    <order_by>12F</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     For the purposes of this section, the following words shall have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Whoever occupies, or attempts to enter or occupy, a secure area of an airport or the cabin of an airplane, knowingly having in his possession or in his control and knowingly concealing, a cutting device or a prohibited weapon, notwithstanding any license to possess such a weapon or device, shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 21/2 years or by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than 5 years or by a fine of not more than $5,000, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Whoever, with intent to commit a felony, occupies, or attempts to enter or occupy, a secure area of an airport or the cabin of an airplane knowingly having in his possession or in his control a cutting device or a prohibited weapon shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 2 years or by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than 10 years or by a fine of not more than $10,000, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Whoever, with intent to commit a felony, places, attempts to place or attempts to have placed within a secure area of an airport or the cabin of an airplane, a prohibited weapon or cutting device, notwithstanding any license to possess such a weapon or device, shall be punished by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 21/2 years or by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than 10 years or by a fine of not more than $10,000, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Whoever willfully and without regard for the safety of human life, or with reckless disregard for the safety of human life, violates subsection (b), (c) or (d) shall be punished by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than 20 years or by a fine of not more than $20,000, or by both such fine and imprisonment.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     This section shall not apply to:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     any law enforcement officer of a state or political subdivision of a state, an officer or employee of the United States government or United States military personnel authorized to carry prohibited weapons or cutting devices in an official capacity;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     a duly licensed individual transporting an unloaded, lawful weapon or cutting device in baggage not accessible to a passenger in flight and, in the case of a lawful weapon, if the air carrier was informed of the presence of the weapon;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     a cutting device, which is otherwise lawfully possessed, ordinarily used in the course of the holder’s employment, trade or occupation, while the holder is authorized to conduct such employment, trade or occupation within a secure area of an airport or airplane cabin.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>