<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="271" order_by="271" level="3">Crimes Against Public Policy</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8</section_number>
    <catch_line>Permitting Lotteries, Raffles And Games Of Chance In Buildings</catch_line>
    <order_by>8</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 22, 2011. For text effective November 22, 2011, see below.]  Whoever, in a house, shop or building owned or occupied by him or under his control, knowingly permits the setting up, managing or drawing of such lottery, or such disposal or attempt to dispose of property, or the sale of a lottery ticket or share of a ticket, or any other writing, certificate, bill, token or other device purporting or intended to entitle the holder, bearer or any other person to a prize or to a share of or interest in a prize to be drawn in a lottery, or in such disposal of property, and whoever knowingly suffers money or other property to be raffled for in such house, shop or building, or to be won there by throwing or using dice or by any other game of chance, shall be punished by a fine of not more than two thousand dollars or by imprisonment for not more than one year.
Chapter 271: Permitting lotteries, raffles and games of chance in buildings
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 194, Sec. effective November 22, 2011. For text effective until November 22, 2011, see above.]  Whoever owns, occupies or is in control of a house, shop or building and knowingly permits the establishing, managing or drawing of a lottery, or the disposal or attempt to dispose of property, or the sale of a lottery ticket or share of a ticket, or any other writing, certificate, bill, token or other device purporting or intended to entitle the holder, bearer or any other person to a prize or to a share of or an interest in a prize to be drawn in a lottery, or in the disposal of property, and whoever knowingly allows money or other property to be raffled for or won by throwing or using dice or by any other game of chance that is not being conducted in a gaming establishment licensed under chapter 23K, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $2,000 or by imprisonment in the house of correction for not more than 1 year.
    </text>
</law>