<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="266" order_by="266" level="3">Crimes Against Property</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>37A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Misuse Of Credit Cards; Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>37A</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in sections thirty-seven A to thirty-seven C, inclusive, the following words shall have the following meanings, unless the context otherwise requires: 
“Cardholder”, the person named on the face of a credit card to whom or for whose benefit the credit card is issued by an issuer. 
“Credit card”, any instrument or device, whether known as a credit card, credit plate, or by any other name, issued with or without fee by an issuer for the use of the cardholder in obtaining money, goods, services or anything else of value on credit. 
“Expired credit card”, a credit card which is no longer valid because the term shown on its face has elapsed. 
“Falsely embosses”, completion of a credit card, without the authorization of the named issuer, by adding any of the matter, other than the signature of the cardholder, which an issuer requires to appear on the credit card before it can be used by a cardholder. 
“Falsely makes”, making or drawing, in whole or in part, a device or instrument which purports to be the credit card of a named issuer but which is not such a credit card because the issuer did not authorize the making or drawing, or altering a credit card which was validly issued. 
“Incomplete credit card”, a credit card that does not contain all of the matter that must be stamped, embossed, imprinted or written on said card other than the signature, as required by the issuer before it can be used by a cardholder. 
“Issuer”, the business organization or financial institution which issues a credit card or his duly authorized agent. 
“Receives” or “receiving”, acquiring possession or control or accepting as security for a loan. 
“Revoked credit card”, a credit card which is no longer valid because permission to use it has been suspended or terminated by the issuer.
    </text>
</law>