<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="265" order_by="265" level="3">Crimes Against The Person</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>131/2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Punishment For Manslaughter While Operating A Motor Vehicle</catch_line>
    <order_by>131/2</order_by>
    <text>
        Whoever commits manslaughter while operating a motor vehicle in violation of paragraph (a) of subdivision (1) of section 24 of chapter 90 or section 8A of chapter 90B, shall be punished by imprisonment in the state prison for not less than 5 years and not more than 20 years, and by a fine of not more than $25,000. The sentence of imprisonment imposed upon such person shall not be reduced to less than 5 years, nor suspended, nor shall any such person be eligible for probation, parole or furlough or receive a deduction from his sentence for good conduct until he shall have served 5 years of such sentence. The commissioner of correction may, on the recommendation of the warden, superintendent or other person in charge of a correctional institution, or of the administrator of a county correctional institution, grant to an offender committed under this section a temporary release in the custody of an officer of such institution for the following purposes only: to attend the funeral of a relative; to visit a critically ill relative; to obtain emergency medical or psychiatric services unavailable at said institution; or to engage in employment pursuant to a work release program. Upon receipt of notice of a conviction under this section, the registrar may suspend the license or right to operate of such person for any extended period up to life, provided that such suspension be at least a 15 year period. A person aggrieved by a decision of the registrar pursuant to this section may file an appeal in the superior court of the trial court department. If the court determines that the registrar abused his discretion, the court may vacate the suspension or revocation of a license or right to operate and reduce the period of suspension or revocation as ordered by the registrar, but in no event may the reduced period of suspension be for less than 15 years.
    </text>
</law>