<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="4" order_by="4" level="1">Crimes, Punishments And Proceedingsin Criminal Cases</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="2">Crimes And Punishments</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="271" order_by="271" level="3">Crimes Against Public Policy</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Innholders And Others Keeping Or Suffering Implements To Be Used For Gaming</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 22, 2011. For text effective November 22, 2011, see below.]  Every innholder, common victualler or person keeping or suffering to be kept in any place occupied by him implements such as are used in gaming, in order that the same may for hire, gain or reward be used for amusement, who suffers implements of such kind to be used upon any part of such premises for gaming for money or other property, or who suffers a person to play at an unlawful game or sport therein, shall for the first offence forfeit not more than one hundred dollars or be imprisoned for not more than three months; and for a subsequent offence shall be imprisoned for not more than one year. In either case he shall further recognize with sufficient sureties in a reasonable sum for his good behavior, and especially that he will not be guilty of any offence against any of the provisions of sections one to six, inclusive, for three years from the date of the recognizance.
Chapter 271: Innholders and others keeping or suffering implements to be used for gaming
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 194, Sec. 53 effective November 22, 2011. For text effective until November 22, 2011, see above.]  Except as permitted under chapter 23K, every innholder, common victualler or person keeping or suffering to be kept in any place occupied by him implements such as are used in gaming, in order that the same may for hire, gain or reward be used for amusement, who suffers implements of such kind to be used upon any part of such premises for gaming for money or other property, or who suffers a person to play at an unlawful game or sport therein, shall for the first offence forfeit not more than one hundred dollars or be imprisoned for not more than three months; and for a subsequent offence shall be imprisoned for not more than one year. In either case he shall further recognize with sufficient sureties in a reasonable sum for his good behavior, and especially that he will not be guilty of any offence against any of the provisions of sections one to six, inclusive, for three years from the date of the recognizance.
    </text>
</law>