<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="121A" order_by="121A" level="3">Urban Redevelopment Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Notice Of Hearing</catch_line>
    <order_by>6B</order_by>
    <text>
        The planning board shall give notice of each public hearing required by section six by publishing a notice in a newspaper of general circulation in the city or town in which the project is to be located once in each of two successive weeks, the first publication to be at least fourteen days before the day of the hearing, and by posting a notice in a conspicuous place in the city or town for at least the fourteen consecutive days immediately prior to the day of the hearing. 
The planning board at least fourteen days before the day of the hearing shall mail a notice to each owner of land that is within the proposed project, or abuts the proposed project, or is across a public or private street or way from the proposed project, notwithstanding that the land of such owner lies within a city or town other than the city or town in which the project is to be located. The assessors of the city or town in which the land of such owner lies shall certify to the planning board the name and address of such owner as it appears on the tax list, and notice mailed to the name and address certified will be sufficient notice to such owner. 
The planning board at least fourteen days before the day of the hearing, shall mail notices to the applicant and to all persons to whom the applicant requests in writing that notice be sent. 
A notice required by this section shall contain the date, time and place of the hearing, a statement of the purpose of the hearing, a general description of the boundaries of the proposed project, a description of the types of buildings to be constructed in the proposed project, the name and address of the applicant, and a statement that section six C provides that a person aggrieved by the approval or disapproval of a project has sixty days within which to seek judicial review.
    </text>
</law>