<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118I" order_by="118I" level="3">Health Information Technology</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Plan Requirements</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 134 effective November 4, 2012.]  Any plan approved by the executive office and council or the e-Health institute, including every grantee and implementing organization that receives monies funded in whole or in part from the e-Health Institute Fund established in section 6E of chapter 40J or the Massachusetts Health Information Exchange Fund established under section 10, shall:  (1) establish a mechanism to allow patients to opt-in to the health information exchange and to opt-out at any time;  (2) maintain identifiable health information in physically and technologically secure environments by means including, but not limited to: prohibiting the storage or transfer of unencrypted and non-password protected identifiable health information on portable data storage devices; requiring data encryption, unique alpha-numerical identifiers and password protection; and other methods to prevent unauthorized access to identifiable health information;  (3) provide patients the option of, upon request to a provider, obtaining a list of individuals and entities that have accessed their identifiable health information from that provider;  (4) develop and distribute to authorized users of the health information exchange and to prospective exchange participants, written guidelines addressing privacy, confidentiality and security of health information and inform individuals: the information available through the exchange, who may access their information and the purposes for which their information may be accessed; and  (5) ensure compliance with all state and federal privacy requirements, including those imposed by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, P.L. 104-191, the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, P.L. 111-5, 42 C.F.R. §§ 2.11 et seq. and 45 C.F.R. §§ 160, 162 and 164.
    </text>
</law>