<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118E" order_by="118E" level="3">Division Of Medical Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Aliens Or Persons Residing In United States Under Color Of Law;  Benefits</catch_line>
    <order_by>16D</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Eligibility for benefits for aliens pursuant to this chapter shall be determined without regard to the availability of federal funding for such benefits or to the provisions of sections 401, 402 or 403 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     A person who is not a citizen of the United States but who is either a qualified alien within the meaning of section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 or is otherwise permanently residing in the United States under color of law may receive different benefits unless such person: (i) is residing in a nursing facility, as defined by 42 U.S.C. section 1396, as of June 30, 1997; (ii) was receiving services or benefits pursuant to this chapter as of June 30, 1997; (iii) had an application for long-term care services pending on July 1, 1997; or (iv) is eligible for federally reimbursed services or benefits; provided, however, that services or benefits other than emergency services shall not be provided to undocumented aliens unless required by federal law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Benefits for aliens under this section shall not be provided to persons age 19 or older; but the benefits shall not be terminated for persons described in clauses (i), (ii), (iii) and (iv) of subsection (2).
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Before termination of eligibility under the authority of subsection (3), the division shall review eligibility to assure that all federally eligible aliens are identified and their costs of coverage reimbursed by the federal Medicaid program to the greatest extent possible consistent with federal law.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The division shall review all claims for services to aliens to assure that all emergency services are reimbursed by the federal Medicaid program to the greatest extent possible consistent with federal law, including coverage for chronic medical conditions, which, if left untreated, could reasonably be expected to place the persons’ health in serious jeopardy, cause serious impairment to bodily functions or cause serious dysfunction of any bodily organ or part.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     Notwithstanding subsection (3), if appropriations permit, the division shall determine eligibility in accordance with subsection (1) and (2).
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     Notwithstanding subsection (3), a person who is not a citizen of the United States but who is either a qualified alien within the meaning of section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 or is otherwise permanently residing in the United States under color of law shall be eligible to receive benefits under MassHealth Essential if such individual meets the categorical and financial eligibility requirements under MassHealth; provided further that such individual is either age 65 or older, or between age 19 and 64, inclusive, and disabled. Such individual shall not be subject to sponsor income deeming or related restrictions.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>