<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="119" order_by="119" level="3">Protection And Care Of Children, And Proceedings Against Them</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>26</section_number>
    <catch_line>Procedure At Hearing; Order Of Commitment; Petition To Dispense With Parental Consent To Adoption; Reimbursement Of Commonwealth; Petition For Review</catch_line>
    <order_by>26</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     If the child is identified by the court and it appears that the precept and summonses have been duly and legally served, that notice has been issued to the department and the report of the person qualified under section 21A is received, the court may excuse the child from the hearing and shall proceed to hear the evidence.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     If the court finds the allegations in the petition proved within the meaning of this chapter, it may adjudge that the child is in need of care and protection. In making such adjudication, the health and safety of the child shall be of paramount concern. If the child is adjudged to be in need of care and protection, the court may commit the child to the custody of the department until he becomes an adult or until, in the opinion of the department, the object of his commitment has been accomplished, whichever occurs first; and the court shall consider the provisions of section 29C and shall make the written certification and determinations required by said section 29C. The court also may make any other appropriate order, including conditions and limitations, about the care and custody of the child as may be in the child’s best interest including, but not limited to, any 1 or more of the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     It may permit the child to remain with a parent, guardian or other custodian, and may require supervision as directed by the court for the care and protection of the child.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     It may transfer temporary or permanent legal custody to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     any person, including the child’s parent, who, after study by a probation officer or other person or agency designated by the court, is found by the court to be qualified to give care to the child;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     any agency or other private organization licensed or otherwise authorized by law to receive and provide care for the child; or
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     the department of children and families.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     It may order appropriate physical care including medical or dental care.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     It may dispense with the need for consent of any person named in section 2 of chapter 210 to the adoption, custody, guardianship or other disposition of the child named therein.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     The court may order the parents or parent of said child to reimburse the commonwealth or other agency for care in appropriate cases.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     On any petition filed in any court under this section, the department or the parents, person having legal custody, probation officer or guardian of a child or the counsel or guardian ad litem for a child may petition the court not more than once every 6 months for a review and redetermination of the current needs of such child whose case has come before the court, except that any person against whom a decree to dispense with consent to adoption has been entered under clause (4) of subsection (b) shall not have such right of petition for review and redetermination. Unless the court enters written findings setting forth specific extraordinary circumstances that require continued intervention by the court, the court shall enter a final order of adjudication and permanent disposition, not later than 15 months after the date the case was first filed in court. The date by which a final order of adjudication and permanent disposition shall be entered may be extended once for a period not to exceed 3 months and only if the court makes a written finding that the parent has made consistent and goal-oriented progress likely to lead to the child’s return to the parent’s care and custody. Findings in support of such final order of adjudication and permanent disposition shall be made in writing within a reasonable time of the court’s order. The court shall not lose jurisdiction over the petition by reason of its failure to enter a final order and the findings in support thereof within the time set forth in this paragraph.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>