<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="121E" order_by="121E" level="3">Housing Innovations Trust Fund</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        “Alternative forms of rental and ownership housing”, shall include, but not be limited to: single room occupancy units; limited equity cooperative housing; transitional housing for the homeless; battered women’s shelters; mutual housing; housing acquired by nonprofit entities pursuant to Title II of the National Emergency Low Income Housing Preservation Act of 1987 and Title VI of the National Affordable Housing Act of 1990; employer assisted housing; lease-to-purchase housing; housing produced pursuant to a court-approved receivership; innovative forms of housing which seek to mitigate the adverse impact on housing affordability in communities with high concentrations of college or university students; joint projects between municipalities or housing development agencies and institutions of higher education designed to produce or preserve affordable units within those areas; and other innovative forms of housing. 
“Area median income”, income as determined by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development. 
“Authorities”, the Massachusetts Development Finance Agency established in chapter 23G, community development corporations established pursuant to chapter 40F, the Community Economic Development Assistance Corporation established in chapter 40H, operating agencies established pursuant to chapter 121B, the Massachusetts Housing Finance Agency, established in chapter 708 of the acts of 1966 and nonprofit agencies certified by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development as community housing development organizations. 
“Department”, the department of housing and community development. 
“Fund”, the Housing Innovations Trust Fund established in section 2.
    </text>
</law>