<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="120A" order_by="120A" level="3">Interstate Compact On Juveniles</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>15</section_number>
    <catch_line>Penalties Against Compacting State For Default In Performance Of Obligations Or Responsibilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>15</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     If the interstate commission determines that any compacting state has at any time defaulted in the performance of any of its obligations or responsibilities under this compact, or the by-laws or duly adopted rules, the interstate commission may impose any or all of the following penalties:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     remedial training and technical assistance as directed by the interstate commission;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     alternative dispute resolution;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     fines, fees and costs in such amounts as are deemed to be reasonable as fixed by the interstate commission; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     suspension or termination of membership in the compact, which shall be imposed only after all other reasonable means of securing compliance under the by-laws and rules have been exhausted and the interstate commission has therefore determined that the offending state is in default. Immediate notice of suspension shall be given by the interstate commission to the governor, the chief justice or the chief judicial officer of the state, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state’s legislature and the state council. Grounds for default include, but are not limited to, failure of a compacting state to perform such obligations or responsibilities imposed upon it by this compact, the by-laws or duly adopted rules and any other grounds designated in interstate commission by-laws and rules. The interstate commission shall immediately notify the defaulting state, in writing, of the penalty imposed by the interstate commission and of the default, pending a cure of the default. The interstate commission shall stipulate the conditions and the time period within which the defaulting state must cure the default. If the defaulting state fails to cure the default within the time period specified by the interstate commission, the defaulting state shall be terminated from the compact upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the compacting states and all rights, privileges and benefits conferred by this compact shall be terminated from the effective date of termination of membership.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Within 60 days of the effective date of termination of a defaulting state, the commission shall notify the governor, the chief justice or chief judicial officer, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state’s legislature and the state council of such termination.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The defaulting state shall be responsible for all assessments, obligations and liabilities incurred through the effective date of termination including any obligations, the performance of which extends beyond the effective date of termination.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The interstate commission shall not bear any costs relating to the defaulting state unless otherwise mutually agreed upon, in writing, between the interstate commission and the defaulting state.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Reinstatement following termination of any compacting state requires both a reenactment of the compact by the defaulting state and the approval of the interstate commission pursuant to the rules.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>