<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118I" order_by="118I" level="3">Health Information Technology</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Health Information Exchange Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 134 effective November 4, 2012.]  There shall be established and set up on the books of the executive office the Massachusetts Health Information Exchange Fund, referred to in this section as the fund, for the purpose of developing a statewide health information exchange. There shall be credited to the fund any appropriations, proceeds of any bonds or notes of the commonwealth issued for the purpose, or other monies authorized by the general court and designated thereto; any federal grants or loans; any private gifts, grants or donations made available; and any income derived from the investment of amounts credited to the fund. The executive office shall seek, to the greatest extent possible, private gifts, grants and donations to the fund. The executive office shall hold the fund in an account or accounts separate from other funds. The fund shall be administered by the executive office without further appropriation. Amounts credited to the fund shall be available for reasonable expenditure by the executive office, subject to the approval of the council where such approval is required under this chapter, for such purposes as the executive office determines are necessary to support the dissemination and development of the statewide health information exchange. The secretary of administration and finance shall transfer a portion of (i) any money in the E-Health Institute Fund, (ii) any money from the ONC Health Information Exchange Cooperative Agreement, or (iii) the ONC Health Information Exchange Challenge Grant programs that is related to the implementation of the statewide health information exchange.
    </text>
</law>