<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118I" order_by="118I" level="3">Health Information Technology</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 134 effective November 4, 2012.]  As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:  "Commission'', the health policy commission established in section 2 of chapter 6D.  "Council'', the health information technology council established under section 2.  "Electronic health record,'' an electronic record of patient health information generated by llor more encounters in any care delivery setting.  "Executive office'', the executive office of health and human services.  "Health information exchange,'' an electronic platform enabling the transmission of healthcare-related data among providers, payers, personal health records controlled by a patient and government agencies according to national standards, the reliable and secure transfer of data among diverse systems and access to and retrieval of data.  "Longitudinal medical record'', a patient's lifetime electronic health record whether located, maintained or stored on a provider server, at a central storage repository, or distributed in multiple locations but accessible with patient consent.  "Massachusetts eHealth institute'' or "institute'', the Massachusetts e-Health institute established under section 6D of chapter 40J.  "Office of the National Coordinator'' or "ONC'', the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology within the United States Department of Health and Human Services.  "Statewide health information exchange'', a health information exchange established, operated or funded by a governmental entity or entities in the commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>