<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118A" order_by="118A" level="3">Assistance To The Aged And Disabled</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Federal Agreement;  Administration Of Program;  Provisions</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until April 11, 2011. For text effective April 11, 2011, see below.]  The commissioner of transitional assistance, in this chapter called the commissioner, shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of the United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, under which said Secretary shall, on behalf of the commonwealth, administer the program of state supplementary payments authorized by section one. Such agreement shall contain all requirements for and limitations and qualifications on state supplementary payments which title XVI or regulations adopted thereunder make necessary in order to qualify the commonwealth for administration by said Secretary of state supplementary payments. Such agreement may include, but need not be limited to: provision for varying categories of assistance for state supplementation; a maximum of five living arrangements in any one category which may receive differing state supplementary payments; procedures for making payments to said Secretary and limitations on such payments; limits on state supplementary payments for inmates of public institutions or patients in health care facilities; ineligibility for state supplementary payments of certain individuals who are ineligible for supplemental security income; provision for recoupment of overpayments, or payments unlawfully procured, of state supplementary payments and adjustments against future state payments on account of such recoupment, and any other fiscal and quality control provisions deemed advisable by the commissioner; and provision for a hearing before said Secretary or his designee for any person aggrieved by a determination made pursuant to the agreement concerning any state supplementary payment.
Chapter 118A: Federal agreement; administration of program
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 9, Sec. 10 effective April 11, 2011. For text effective until April 11, 2011, see above.]  The commissioner of transitional assistance shall enter into an agreement with the Social Security Administration regarding the administration of the program of state supplementary payments authorized in section 1. This agreement shall contain all of the requirements for, and limitations and qualifications on, state supplementary payments which Title XVI or regulations adopted thereunder make necessary. At the option of the commissioner, this agreement may provide for either state or federal administration of the program. Administration of the program by the commonwealth may be delegated to another governmental entity.
    </text>
</law>