<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="121C" order_by="121C" level="3">Economic Development And Industrial Corporations</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Revenue Bonds; Revenue Refunding Bonds; Requisites; Negotiability</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        The corporation is hereby authorized to provide by resolution, one time or from time to time, for the issuance of revenue bonds of the corporation for the purposes of paying all or any part of the cost of a project or projects. The principal of and interest on such bonds shall be payable solely from the funds herein provided for such payment. The bonds of each issue shall be dated, shall bear interest at such rates, and shall mature at such time or times not exceeding forty years from their date or dates, as may be determined by the corporation, and may be made redeemable before maturity, at the option of the corporation, at such price or prices and under such terms and conditions as may be fixed by the corporation prior to the issuance of the bonds. The corporation shall determine the form of the bonds, including any interest coupons to be attached thereto, and the manner of execution of the bonds, and shall fix the denomination or denominations of the bonds and the place or places of payment of principal and interest, which may be at any bank or trust company within the commonwealth. In case any officer whose signature or a facsimile of whose signature shall appear on any bonds or coupons shall cease to be such officer before the delivery of such bonds, such signature or such facsimile shall nevertheless be valid and sufficient for all purposes the same as if he had remained in office until such delivery. The bonds may be issued in coupon or registered form or both, as the corporation may determine and provision may be made for the registration of any coupon bonds as to principal alone and also as to both principal and interest. The corporation may sell such bonds in such manner, either at public or at private sale, and for such price, as it may determine to be for the best interests of the corporation. 
The proceeds of such bonds shall be used solely for the payment of the cost of the project or projects, and shall be disbursed in such manner and under such restrictions, if any, as the corporations may provide. Prior to the preparation of definitive bonds, the corporation may, under like restrictions, issue interim receipts or temporary bonds, with or without coupons, exchangeable for definitive bonds when such bonds have been executed and are available for delivery. The corporation may also provide for the replacement of any bonds which shall become mutilated or shall be destroyed or lost. Revenue bonds may be issued under the provisions of this act subject only to those proceedings, conditions or things which are specifically required by this act. 
The corporation is hereby authorized to provide by resolution for issuance of revenue refunding bonds of the corporation for the purpose of refunding any revenue bonds then outstanding and issued under the provisions of this act, including the payment of any redemption premium thereon and any interest accrued or to accrue to the date of redemption of such bonds, and, if deemed advisable by the corporation, for the additional purpose of constructing or reconstructing any extensions or improvements of the project. The issue of such bonds, the maturities, and other details thereof, the rights of the holders thereof, and the duties of the corporation in respect of the same may be applicable. 
While any bonds issued by the corporation remain outstanding, the powers, duties or existence of the corporation shall not be diminished or impaired in any way that will affect adversely the interests and rights of the holders of such bonds. 
Revenue and revenue refunding bonds issued under the provisions of this section, unless otherwise authorized by law, shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the commonwealth or of the city, or a pledge of the faith and credit of the commonwealth or of the city, but such bonds shall be payable solely from the funds herein provided therefor from revenues. In the event that the corporation, or municipality or commonwealth is not obliged to pay said revenue and revenue refunding bonds, then, and in that event, all such revenue and revenue refunding bonds shall contain on the face thereof a statement to the effect that neither the corporation nor the commonwealth nor the municipality shall be obliged to pay the same or the interest thereon except from revenues and that neither the faith and credit nor taxing power of the commonwealth or of the municipality is pledged to the payment of the principal of or the interest on such bonds. 
All revenue and revenue refunding bonds issued under the provisions of this chapter shall have and are hereby declared to have all the qualities and incidents of negotiable instruments as defined in section 3-104 of the Uniform Commercial Code of this commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>