<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="118E" order_by="118E" level="3">Division Of Medical Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>64</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions For Secs. 64 Through 69</catch_line>
    <order_by>64</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 131 effective November 4, 2012.]  As used in sections 64 to 69, inclusive, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:  "Acute hospital'', the teaching hospital of the University of Massachusetts medical school and any hospital licensed under section 51 of chapter 111 and which contains a majority of medical-surgical, pediatric, obstetric and maternity beds, as defined by the department of public health.  "Allowable reimbursement'', payment to acute hospitals and community health centers for health services provided to uninsured or underinsured patients of the commonwealth under section 69 and any further regulations promulgated by the health safety net office.  "Ambulatory surgical center'', a distinct entity that operates exclusively to provide surgical services to patients not requiring hospitalization and meets the requirements of the federal Health Care Financing Administration for participation in the Medicare program.  "Ambulatory surgical center services'', services described for purposes of the Medicare program under 42 U.S.C. 1395k(a)(2)(F)(I); provided that "ambulatory surgical center services'' shall include facility services only and shall not include surgical procedures.  "Bad debt'', an account receivable based on services furnished to a patient which: (i) is regarded as uncollectible, following reasonable collection efforts consistent with regulations of the office, which regulations shall allow third party payers to negotiate with hospitals to collect the bad debts of its enrollees; (ii) is charged as a credit loss; (iii) is not the obligation of a governmental unit or the federal government or any agency thereof; and (iv) is not a reimbursable health care service.  "Community health center'', a health center operating in conformance with the requirements of Confinement of a person in a nursing home, hospital or other medical institution shall not in and of itself, suffice to qualify such person as a resident.  "Surcharge payor'', an individual or entity that pays for or arranges for the purchase of health care services provided by acute hospitals and ambulatory surgical center services provided by ambulatory surgical centers, as defined in this section; provided, however, that the term "surcharge payor'' shall include a managed care organization; and provided further, that "surcharge payor'' shall not include Title XVIII and Title XIX programs and their beneficiaries or recipients, other governmental programs of public assistance and their beneficiaries or recipients and the workers' compensation program established under chapter 152.  "Underinsured patient'', a patient whose health insurance plan or self-insurance health plan does not pay, in whole or in part, for health services that are eligible for reimbursement from the health safety net trust fund, provided that such patient meets income eligibility standards set by the office.  "Uninsured patient'', a patient who is a resident of the commonwealth, who is not covered by a health insurance plan or a self-insurance health plan and who is not eligible for a medical assistance program.
    </text>
</law>