<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="17" order_by="17" level="2">Public Welfare</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="119" order_by="119" level="3">Protection And Care Of Children, And Proceedings Against Them</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>36</section_number>
    <catch_line>Bringing Child Into Commonwealth With View To Adoption, Guardianship, Custody Or Care; Permit; Application; Bond</catch_line>
    <order_by>36</order_by>
    <text>
        No person or institution shall bring or cause to be brought into the commonwealth, or receive therein, from any other state, province or country, any child for the purpose of placing or boarding, or of procuring the placing or boarding of such child, in a family or home within the commonwealth, with a view to adoption, guardianship, custody or care by any person other than one related to him by blood or marriage, without first obtaining a permit therefor from the department. Such a permit shall not issue until a written application therefor has been filed with the department on forms by it prepared, containing such information relative to such child as the department may require, accompanied by an individual or blanket bond running to the commonwealth in such penal sum and with such surety or sureties as the department may approve, conditioned on the following:—(1) that all statements contained in such an application are true in substantial particulars; (2) that any such child becoming a public charge during his minority shall be removed from the state not later than thirty days after notice from the department; (3) that such child shall be removed from the state immediately upon his release from any penal or reformatory institution or training school to which he has been committed, within three years of his arrival within the state, for juvenile delinquency or crime; (4) that such child shall be placed or boarded under such agreement as will secure to him a proper home and surroundings, and as will render his custodian responsible for his proper care, education and training, under adequate supervision and subject to annual visitation by an agent; and (5) that such reports relative to the child shall be made to the department as it may require. In case of a breach of any condition of such a bond, the attorney general, upon request of the department, shall put the bond in suit, and the commonwealth or any city or town thereof shall be reimbursed from the proceeds for any expense incurred by reason of a breach of any such condition. Violation of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than one hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or both.
    </text>
</law>