<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6A" order_by="6A" level="3">Executive Offices</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16L</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Committee To The Health Care Quality And Cost Council</catch_line>
    <order_by>16L</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until November 4, 2012. Repealed by 2012, 224, Sec. 7.]  (a) There shall be established an advisory committee to the health care quality and cost council, established by section 16K, to allow the broadest possible involvement of the health care industry and others concerned about health care quality and cost.  (b) The advisory committee shall consist of at least 29 members to be appointed by the governor, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Medical Society, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Hospital Association, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Association of Health Plans, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of Blue Cross Blue Shield of Massachusetts, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts AFL-CIO Council, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts League of Community Health Centers, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of Health Care For All, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Public Health Association, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Association of Behavioral Health Systems, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Extended Care Federation, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Council of Human Service Providers, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Home Care Alliance of Massachusetts, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of Associated Industries of Massachusetts, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Business Roundtable, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Taxpayers Foundation, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts chapter of the National Federation of Independent Business, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Retailers Association of Massachusetts, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Biotechnology Council, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Blue Cross Blue Shield of Massachusetts Foundation, Inc., 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts chapter of the American Association of Retired Persons, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Coalition of Taft-Hartley Trust Funds, Inc., and additional members including, but not limited to, a representative of the mental health field, a representative of pediatric health care, a representative of primary health care, a representative of medical education, a representative of racial or ethnic minority groups concerned with health care, a representative of hospice care, a representative of the nursing profession and a representative of the pharmaceutical field. Members of the advisory committee shall be appointed for terms of 3 years or until a successor is appointed. Members shall be eligible to be reappointed and shall serve without compensation.  (c) The members of the advisory committee shall annually elect a chair, vice chair and secretary and may adopt by-laws governing the affairs of the advisory committee.  (d) The advisory committee shall have the following duties: (i) advise the council on the consumer health information website and health care provider and insurer reports; (ii) advise the council on the annual health care quality improvement and cost containment goals, transparency standards and quality performance benchmarks; and (iii) review and comment on all reports of the council before public release, including the annual reporting plan and any revisions and the annual report to the general court.  (e) A written record of all meetings of the committee shall be maintained by the secretary and a copy filed within 15 days after each meeting with the council.
    </text>
</law>