<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="3">Department Of Environmental Management</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>30A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Grants For Construction Of Collection Systems</catch_line>
    <order_by>30A</order_by>
    <text>
        The division may make grants to public entities for the costs of constructing collection systems. Subject to appropriation, such grants shall be made in accordance with the priority system and list established for this section by regulation of the director, and, in no event, shall exceed fifty per cent of the construction costs of such projects, as determined by the division. No project shall be eligible for a grant under this section unless the abatement facilities to which the project facilities would be added have been constructed or have received a grant for construction under section thirty-three. No project shall be eligible for a grant under this section if the sewage flows to be added by the use of the project facilities would result in or contribute to a condition in violation of this chapter, or any regulation, permit or order issued or adopted thereunder. No grant made under this section shall exceed three million dollars. The division shall not award a grant under this section to a public entity which has accepted another such grant within the previous year, unless the division determines, in accordance with the priority system and list for a given fiscal year, that all other projects which are ready to proceed have been brought to the fundable list for such fiscal year. 
Payments of financial assistance by the commonwealth pursuant to this section shall be made in accordance with a payment schedule established by the division with the approval of the commissioner of administration.
    </text>
</law>