<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23D" order_by="23D" level="3">Employee Ownership Revolving Loan Fund</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19</section_number>
    <catch_line>Start Up Programs; Requests For Grants; Memoranda Of Understanding</catch_line>
    <order_by>19</order_by>
    <text>
        The director may promote and accept requests for grants for start-up employee involvement programs in state agencies, the majority of whose employees are not subject to the provisions of chapter one hundred and fifty E, authorities of the commonwealth, the Massachusetts board of regents of higher education or any institution under its authority, regional and municipal authorities, cities, towns, regional school districts and independent vocational schools. The school committee of a city or town may request such grants for the public school system under its control. Any such grant to cities and towns for such public school systems shall be deposited with the treasurer of such city or town to be expended by the school committee without further appropriation. Such grant requests shall include, but not be limited to, an approved statement of purpose and an implementation plan to which participating labor and employer representatives have committed themselves in writing. Said grants shall be on a matching basis with said participating state agency, the majority of whose employees are not subject to the provisions of chapter one hundred and fifty E, authority of the commonwealth, Massachusetts board of regents of higher education, city, town, regional school district or independent vocational school funding. Said grants shall be used for, but not be limited to, training managers, union leadership and employees in employee involvement strategies and methods. 
Said director is authorized to enter into memoranda of understanding with the state agencies including, but not limited to, the office of employee relations, the human resources division within the executive office for administration and finance and the board of conciliation and arbitration, which are already actively involved in coordinating the commonwealth’s employee involvement program. Such memoranda of understanding shall include, but not be limited to, joint sponsorship of conferences, workshops, and education and outreach materials. 
Said director shall develop memoranda of understanding with state agencies which are or might be involved with employee ownership, including agencies of the commonwealth which are involved with providing capital sources.
    </text>
</law>