<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>30</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing Or Registration Of Persons Employed By A Gaming Licensee</catch_line>
    <order_by>30</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) No person shall be employed by a gaming licensee unless such person has been licensed by or registered with the commission.  (b) Any person seeking a key gaming employee license or a gaming employee license shall file an application with the bureau. Such application shall be on a form prescribed by the commission and shall include, but not be limited to, the following: (i) the name of the applicant; (ii) the address of the applicant; (iii) a detailed employment history of the applicant; (iv) fingerprints; (v) a criminal and arrest record; and (vi) any civil judgments obtained against the applicant pertaining to antitrust or security regulation. The bureau may require such other information as it considers appropriate including, but not limited to, information related to the financial integrity of the applicant, and may require the applicant to submit other documentation it considers appropriate including, but not limited to, bank accounts and records, bank references, business and personal income and disbursement schedules, tax returns and other reports filed by government agencies and business and personal accounting check records and ledgers.  (c) All other employees in a gaming establishment who are not considered to be gaming employees, key gaming employees or who have restricted access to an area of the gaming establishment or knowledge of security procedures, shall be required to register with the bureau as a gaming service employee and shall produce such information as the bureau may require to become registered under this chapter.  (d) Upon receipt of an application for a key gaming employee license and a gaming employee license the bureau shall conduct an investigation of each applicant which shall include obtaining criminal offender record information from the criminal history systems board and exchanging fingerprint data and criminal history with the department of state police and the United States Federal Bureau of Investigation.  (e) Upon petition by a gaming licensee, the commission may issue a temporary license to an applicant for a key gaming employee license or a gaming employee license if: (i) the applicant for a key gaming employee license or gaming employee license has filed a completed application with the commission; and (ii) the gaming licensee certifies, and the commission finds, that the issuance of a temporary license is necessary for the operation of the gaming establishment and is not designed to circumvent the normal licensing procedures. Unless otherwise stated by the commission, a temporary license issued under this section shall expire 6 months from the date of its issuance and may be renewed, at the discretion of the commission, for an additional 6-month period.  (f) The commission may deny an application for a key gaming employee or gaming employee license or the registration of any other employee of a gaming establishment if the commission finds that an applicant or registrant is disqualified under section 16 or may be unsuitable for licensure under any of the criteria set forth in section 12; provided, however, that the commission, in its discretion, may issue a license to an applicant for a gaming employee license or register a gaming service employee who has a prior conviction if the applicant or registrant can affirmatively demonstrate the applicant's rehabilitation. In considering the rehabilitation of an applicant for a license under this section, the commission shall consider the following: (i) the nature and duties of the position of the applicant; (ii) the nature and seriousness of the offense or conduct; (iii) the circumstances under which the offense or conduct occurred; (iv) the date of the offense or conduct; (v) the age of the applicant when the offense or conduct was committed; (vi) whether the offense or conduct was an isolated or repeated incident; (vii) any social conditions which may have contributed to the offense or conduct; and (viii) any evidence of rehabilitation, including recommendations and references of persons supervising the applicant since the offense or conduct was committed.  (g) After completing an investigation of an applicant for a key gaming employee or gaming employee license the bureau shall approve or deny the license. Any orders by the bureau denying an application under this section shall be accompanied by an explanation of the reasons that an applicant did not meet the qualifications for licensure under this chapter. An applicant for a key gaming employee or gaming employee license may request a hearing before the bureau to contest the findings. After the hearing, the applicant may appeal the decision of the bureau to the commission and the commission may hear the appeal on the record. The decision of the commission shall be final and an applicant for a key gaming employee or gaming employee license shall not be entitled to further review.  (h) The commission may condition, suspend or revoke a license or registration under this section if the commission finds that a licensee or registrant has: (i) been arrested or convicted of a crime while employed by a gaming establishment and failed to report the charges or the conviction to the commission; (ii) failed to comply with the requirements of section 14; or (iii) failed to comply with any of the requirements of this chapter pertaining to licensees.  (i) The commission shall establish fees for a key gaming employee and a gaming employee license which shall include costs incurred for conducting a background investigation into an applicant for a license. The commission shall establish the term of a key gaming employee and a gaming employee license. It shall be the responsibility of the key gaming employee or gaming employee to ensure that the employee's license is current.
    </text>
</law>