<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="20" order_by="20" level="3">Department Of Food And Agriculture</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Department; Board; Commissioner</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a department of food and agriculture under the supervision and control of a board of food and agriculture, hereinafter called the board, consisting of seven members each of whom shall be from a different county, to be appointed by the governor. At least four members of the board shall be farmers whose principal vocation is the production of food and fiber. Upon the expiration of the term of office of a member of the board, his successor shall be appointed by the governor for a term of seven years, or until qualification of his successor. 
The board shall meet not less than six times a year or at the call of the chairman and at such times as shall be determined by its rules or at the request of the commissioner or the call of any three members. The chairman shall be annually appointed by a majority of said board present and voting thereon. Board members shall receive fifty dollars for each day or portion thereof spent in the discharge of their official duties not to exceed six hundred dollars per year and shall be reimbursed for the travel to and from official board meetings and other expenses necessary to conduct such meetings. 
There shall be a commissioner of food and agriculture who shall be appointed and may be removed by the secretary of environmental affairs with the approval of the governor. Said commissioner shall have charge of the administration of the department. The department may expend for traveling expenses of its employees incurred in the performance of their official duties and for other necessary expenses of the department, such sums as may be appropriated.
    </text>
</law>