<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21C" order_by="21C" level="3">Massachusetts Hazardous Waste Management Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Hazardous Waste Advisory Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        There is hereby established within the department a hazardous waste advisory committee to provide consultation to the department concerning matters covered by this chapter. The committee shall review the development of standards, rules, and regulations for hazardous waste management, and shall supply recommendations concerning methods by which existing hazardous waste management practices and the laws regulating them may be supplemented and improved and their administration financed. 
The committee shall consist of at least nine members appointed by the governor, one of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Municipal Association, one of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Health Officers Association, one of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Public Health Association, one of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Association of Conservation Commissions, one of whom shall be a representative of the Associated Industries of Massachusetts, one of whom shall be a representative of the Massachusetts Mayors Association, one of whom shall be a representative from a regional planning agency, one of whom shall be a representative of the City Solicitors and Town Counsel’s Association, and at least one of whom shall be a representative of the public knowledgeable in environmental affairs and shall have no financial interest in any of the recommendations or studies of the committee. Such financial interest shall include, but not be limited to, service as a consultant to any person specializing in waste disposal, or as an attorney of a party with a direct financial interest in hazardous waste disposal. Any member shall be eligible for reappointment. In making initial appointments to said committee, the governor shall appoint two members for terms of one year, three members for terms of two years, three members for terms of three years, and one member for a term of four years. Upon the expiration of the term of any such member, his successor shall be appointed for a term of four years. Persons appointed to fill vacancies shall serve for the unexpired term of said vacancy.
    </text>
</law>