<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23L" order_by="23L" level="3">Local Infrastructure Development Program</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Applicability Of Chapter 40 Q Requirements To Bonds Issued By Agency</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 238, Sec. 14 effective August 7, 2012.]  For purposes of this chapter, the agency may issue bonds secured by infrastructure assessments under and according to the terms of chapter 40Q. With the approval of the municipal governing body, the agency may issue its bonds in place of those of the municipality under chapter 40Q provided that the municipality has fulfilled all requirements set forth in said chapter 40Q that would be required of the municipality if it were itself issuing bonds under said chapter 40Q. In addition, the municipality shall include in its invested revenue district development program as defined in said chapter 40Q, a description of the rights and responsibilities of the assessing party, the agency and the municipality with respect to the program. In such case, the municipality may designate the agency as the issuer of bonds under said chapter 40Q for the purpose of financing any of the project costs as defined in said chapter 40Q and that are located in, or functionally serving the needs of, the development zone. The municipality shall determine the percentage of the captured assessed valuation, as defined in said chapter 40Q, of property within the boundaries of the development zone that the municipality is pledging under an invested revenue district development program as defined in said chapter 40Q for the payment of the agency's bonds. With the written agreement of the persons owning specific tax parcels in the development zone, the assessing party may adopt a plan whereby any of the assessing powers described in this chapter are made applicable exclusively to those parcels in order to secure and fund the debt service for the bonds. The project costs as defined in said chapter 40Q shall not be reduced by the amount of the revenues derived under this chapter and the revenues derived from such a plan may be made contingent upon or abated, in whole or in part, by the assessing party upon the receipt of the anticipated revenues generated through the pledged captured assessed valuation. At its option, the municipality may waive any adjustment for the inflation factor as defined in said chapter 40Q in order to increase the captured assessed valuation available to finance improvements benefiting the development zone. The assessing party, the agency and the municipality shall enter into an agreement delineating the rights and responsibilities of each under such district improvement financing.
    </text>
</law>