<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18" level="3">Department Of Transitional Assistance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>3</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commissioner; Appointment; Qualifications; Salary</catch_line>
    <order_by>3</order_by>
    <text>
        The department shall be under the direction, supervision and control of a commissioner of transitional assistance, in this chapter called the commissioner. The secretary of health and human services shall appoint, with the approval of the governor, the commissioner who shall serve at the pleasure of the secretary and may be removed by the secretary at any time, subject to the approval of the governor. At the time of appointment, the commissioner shall be a graduate of an accredited four-year college or university and shall have had not less than ten years of administrative experience; or not less than eight years of administrative experience of which at least three years shall have been in the organization, management or delivery of human services; or a doctorate or other degree beyond the level of the baccalaureate in the field of business, economics, education, government, law, medicine, psychology, public administration, public health, public policy, social work, urban planning, or a field substantially related to one or more of the foregoing, and not less than five years of administrative experience of which at least two years shall have been in the organization, management or delivery of human services. For the purposes of this section, “administrative experience” shall mean service in a management, or supervisory capacity. The position of commissioner shall be classified in accordance with section forty-five of chapter thirty and the salary shall be determined in accordance with section forty-six C of said chapter thirty, and said commissioner shall devote full time during business hours to the duties of the office.
    </text>
</law>