<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="3">State Superintendent Of Buildings, And State House</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Repairs And Improvements;  Requisitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  Subject to the provisions of sections thirty to thirty-eight, inclusive, of chapter six A, whenever the same shall be applicable, he shall direct the making of all repairs and improvements in the state house, the John W. McCormack State Office Building, the Leverett Saltonstall State Office Building, the Springfield Office Building, the Pittsfield Office Building, the Erich Lindemann Building, the Charles F. Hurley Building, and any other state properties as are designated by law to be the responsibility of the superintendent of state office buildings, and on the grounds of the state house and of any such building; and all executive and administrative departments and officers shall make requisition upon him for any such repairs or improvements.
Chapter 8: Repairs and improvements; requisitions
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 14 effective October 31, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 219. For text effective until October 31, see above.]  The superintendent of the state house shall direct the making of all repairs and improvements in the state house, on the grounds of the state house and to any buildings thereof and all tenants, offices or occupants located in the state house shall make requisition upon the superintendent for any such repairs or improvements.
    </text>
</law>