<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21I" order_by="21I" level="3">Massachusetts Toxics Use Reduction Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16</section_number>
    <catch_line>Improved Enforcement Of Toxics Laws</catch_line>
    <order_by>16</order_by>
    <text>
        Except where otherwise specifically provided, whenever it appears to the department that there has been a violation of this chapter, or any regulation or approval issued or adopted hereunder, the department may refer the toxics user to the office for technical assistance, issue administrative orders requiring compliance with the applicable requirement, or issue an administrative penalty pursuant to the provisions of section sixteen of chapter twenty-one A. 
Without limiting any other authority available to the department pursuant to any statute, the department may order a toxics user who violates any standard limiting a release of toxic or hazardous substances to the environment, or a threat of such release, to prepare for that production unit at which the violation occurred a toxics use reduction plan certified by a toxics use reduction planner demonstrating maximum toxics use reduction opportunities available to that user, where (i) the violation causes or threatens to cause significant harm to the environment or to public health or safety, or (ii) the toxics user has previously violated any standard limiting a release of toxic or hazardous substances to the environment, or a threat of such release. 
Any toxics user in violation of any requirement of this chapter, or any regulation or approval issued or adopted hereunder, may apply to the department for a toxics use reduction waiver pursuant to section seventeen. 
Nothing in this section shall in any manner diminish or condition any authority conferred on the department by any other statute.
    </text>
</law>