<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Minimum Capital Investment For Category 2 License;  Licensing Fee;  Continuing Assessment Of Capitalization Of Licensee</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) The commission shall set the minimum capital investment for a category 2 license; provided, however, that the gaming licensee shall make a capital investment of not less than $125,000,000 into the gaming establishment, which shall include, but not be limited to, a gaming area or other amenities as proposed in the application for a category 2 license; and provided further, that the commission shall determine whether it will include the purchase or lease price of the land where the gaming establishment will be located or any infrastructure designed to support the site, including, but not limited to, drainage, utility support, roadways, interchanges, fill and soil or groundwater or surface water contamination issues, whether or not the applicant is an eligible owner or operator under chapter 21E and has suitable capital to finance its operations and the proposed capital investment. The investment required under this section shall be made within 2 years after receiving a gaming license; provided, however, that any infrastructure improvements necessary to increase visitor capacity and account for traffic mitigation shall not be considered part of the required capital investment and, as determined by the commission, shall be completed before the category 2 licensee shall be authorized to operate a slot machine at the gaming establishment.  (b) The commission shall determine the minimum licensing fee for a category 2 licensee, which shall not be less than $25,000,000 to be paid within 30 days after the award of the license.  (c) Upon award of a category 2 license, the commission shall continue to assess the capitalization of a licensee for the duration of construction of the proposed gaming establishment and the term of the gaming license.
    </text>
</law>