<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21E" order_by="21E" level="3">Massachusetts Oil And Hazardous Material Release Prevention And Response Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Violations; Penalties; Actions To Recover Costs</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        Any violation of this chapter, or of any regulation adopted or order issued thereunder, shall be presumed to constitute irreparable harm to the public health, safety, welfare or the environment. Such presumption may be rebutted by a preponderance of evidence. 
In addition to liability for costs incurred by the commonwealth for the investigation, assessment, containment and removal of a release or a threat of a release of oil or hazardous material, any person who violates any provision of this chapter, or any order or regulation issued or adopted thereunder: (a) shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $50,000 for each such violation; or (b) shall be punished by a fine of not more than $50,000, or by imprisonment for not more than two years in a house of correction, or both, for each such violation; or (c) a person violating any provision of section seven shall be punished by a fine of not more than one hundred thousand dollars, or by imprisonment in the state prison for not more than twenty years or in a jail or house of correction for not more than two and one-half years, or both, for each such violation. Each day such violation occurs or continues shall be considered a separate violation. 
The superior court department of the trial court shall have jurisdiction to enjoin violations of, or grant such additional relief as it deems necessary or appropriate to secure compliance with, the provisions of this chapter, or any order or regulation issued or adopted thereunder upon the petition of the attorney general or the commissioner. Upon request of the commissioner, the attorney general may bring an action to recover all costs incurred by the commonwealth in the assessment, containment and removal of any release or threat of release of oil or hazardous material.
    </text>
</law>