<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
          As used in this chapter the following words shall unless a contrary intention clearly appears, have the following meanings:--[ Definition of "Commissioner'' effective until January 1, 2013. Deleted by 2012, 165, Sec. 25. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  "Commissioner'', the commissioner of administration, except that in sections 38A1/2 to 43H, inclusive, the word "commissioner'' shall mean the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance.  "Eligibility'', written criteria established before a request for applications that is used to determine if an application for an award of grant program resources is acceptable.[ Definition of "Finance committee'' effective until January 1, 2013. Deleted by 2012, 165, Sec. 25. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  "Finance committee'', the committee of the executive council appointed to consider matters of finance.  "Grant program'', financial or technical assistance provided by a state agency or state authority, as defined in section 1 of chapter 29, available to a city, town or other public or private entity otherwise eligible.  "Grant program fiscal statement'', shall include: (1) a description of the substance of the application; (2) the average expected grant amount; (3) a listing of award recipients, including the award amount, if any, the fiscal year of the award and the date of award; (4) the estimated proportion of monies, in-kind match or other monies to be supplied by the award recipient and any other source from which such match will be required; (5) a description of the allocation formula and matching requirements, including whether the grant is distributed on the basis of a specified formula or at the grantor's discretion; (6) a description of any constraints placed on the use of the grant; and (7) contact information, including the telephone number, postal address and internet email address to facilitate the application process.  "Grant program reference'', a description in electronic format that is retrievable and printable that shall include: (1) the grant program application; (2) the grant program eligibility criteria; (3) the application due date; and (4) the grant program fiscal statement.[ Definition of "Secretary'' added by 2012, 165, Sec. 26 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  "Secretary'', the secretary of administration and finance.
    </text>
</law>