<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>54</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Cultural Council; Hearings; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>54</order_by>
    <text>
        The council may hold public and private hearings; may enter into contracts with individuals, organizations and institutions for services furthering the objectives of the council’s program; may enter into contracts with local or regional associations for cooperative endeavors furthering the council’s programs; may accept gifts, contributions and bequests of funds from individuals, foundations and from federal, state or other governmental bodies for the purpose of furthering the council’s program; may make and sign any agreement and may do and perform any and all acts which may be necessary or desirable to carry out the purposes of sections fifty-two through fifty-eight, inclusive. 
The council shall establish and from time to time issue or revise as necessary, guidelines, rules, rulings or regulations for the use of state arts lottery or other funds allocable to it and for its own and local or regional cultural council operations and procedures, and to interpret or carry out the purposes of sections fifty-two through fifty-eight inclusive, including but not limited to, the power to delegate certain of the council’s decision-making as the council may deem appropriate to a committee of the council’s membership specially knowledgeable in the appropriate discipline or subject matter. The council may request from any department, division, board, bureau, commission or agency of the commonwealth such assistance and data as will enable it properly to carry out its powers and duties.
    </text>
</law>