<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="3">Department Of The State Secretary</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Archives Advisory Commission; Establishment; Members And Alternates, Appointment; Powers And Duties; Receipt And Disposition Of Funds; Expenses</catch_line>
    <order_by>2A</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be in the department of the state secretary an archives advisory commission, hereinafter called the commission. Said commission shall consist of seven members, broadly representative of the public, and of public and private institutions concerned with the custody and use of archival and manuscript materials, two of whom shall be appointed by the governor, and five of whom shall be appointed by the state secretary. For each member, the governor and state secretary shall appoint an alternate. The state secretary shall be chairman of the commission. The commission shall advise the state secretary on archival matters, and shall review and approve, disapprove or modify a comprehensive statewide documentary preservation plan that shall be prepared by the archivist of the commonwealth, and shall assist in its administration. The commission may, acting under the chairmanship of the state secretary, or, in the secretary’s absence, the archivist, acting for him and under his direction, receive grants, gifts and contributions and bequests from individuals, foundations and from federal, state or other governmental bodies for furthering and putting into effect the comprehensive statewide documentary preservation plan. The state treasurer shall be the custodian of funds so received, and such funds shall be expended by the state secretary, or the archivist acting for him, without special appropriation, subject, however, to the prior approval of the house and senate committees on ways and means, on state, local and private projects approved by the commission, which carry out the comprehensive statewide documentary preservation plan. 
The members of the commission shall serve without compensation but shall receive from the commonwealth the necessary travel and other expenses actually incurred in the performance of their duties.
    </text>
</law>