<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="3">Department Of The Attorney General, And The District Attorneys</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Actions Brought Against Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Attorney General, Treasurer, Secretary Of State, Etc.;  Limitations</catch_line>
    <order_by>5G</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  (1) No court shall have jurisdiction over an action brought pursuant to section 5C against the governor, lieutenant governor, the attorney general, the treasurer, secretary of state, the auditor, a member of the general court, the inspector general or a member of the judiciary, if the action is based on evidence or information known to the commonwealth when the action was brought.  (2) An individual may not bring an action pursuant to paragraph (2) of said section 5C that is based upon allegations or transactions which are the subject of a civil suit or an administrative proceeding in which the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof is already a party.  (3) No court shall have jurisdiction over an action pursuant to sections 5B to 5O, inclusive, based upon the public disclosure of allegations or transactions in a criminal, civil or administrative hearing; in a legislative, administrative, auditor's or inspector general's report, hearing, audit or investigation; or from the news media, unless the action is brought by the attorney general, or the relator is an original source of the information. No court shall have jurisdiction over an action pursuant to said sections 5B to 5O, inclusive, brought by a person who knew or had reason to know that the attorney general, the state auditor or the inspector general already had knowledge of the situation.  (4) An individual who is or was employed by the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof as an auditor, investigator, attorney, financial officer, or contracting officer who otherwise performed such functions for the commonwealth or who discovered or learned of the allegations or the underlying facts from such persons, may not bring an action pursuant paragraph (2) of section 5C that is based upon allegations or transactions that the relator discovered or learned of in such capacity. For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "in such capacity'' shall refer to any matter within the scope of such person's duties or job description.
Chapter 12: Actions brought against governor, lieutenant governor, attorney general, treasurer, secretary of state, etc.; jurisdiction
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 29 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (a) No court shall have jurisdiction over an action brought pursuant to section 5C against the governor, the lieutenant governor, the attorney general, the treasurer, the secretary of state, the auditor, a member of the general court, the inspector general or a member of the judiciary, if the action is based on evidence or information known to the commonwealth when the action was brought.  (b) An individual may not bring an action pursuant to paragraph (2) of said section 5C that is based upon allegations or transactions which are the subject of a civil suit or an administrative proceeding in which the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof is already a party.  (c) The court shall dismiss an action pursuant to sections 5B to 5O, inclusive, unless opposed by the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof, if substantially the same allegations or transactions as alleged in the action or claim were publicly disclosed: (1) in a Massachusetts criminal, civil or administrative hearing in which the commonwealth is a party; (2) in a Massachusetts legislative, administrative, auditor's or inspector general's report, hearing, audit or investigation; or (3) from the news media, unless the action is brought by the attorney general, or the relator is an original source of the information.
    </text>
</law>