<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35P</section_number>
    <catch_line>State House Special Event Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35P</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  There shall be established upon the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the State House Special Event Fund. The state superintendent of state office buildings shall establish and charge a fee or service charge to nongovernmental individuals, entities and groups using the state house for meetings, receptions or exhibits, which may be waived at the discretion of the superintendent. The superintendent or his designee shall establish such fee or charge based upon the actual cost of use, including personnel requests for security, preparation, equipment replacement, cleanup, utilities used and compensation for wear on the building. The superintendent or his designee may, in their discretion, require a nongovernmental entity to enter into a written agreement indemnifying the commonwealth against any claims for casualty liability and may require the posting of an insurance bond. All monies received by the superintendent under this section shall be by check made payable to and deposited in said fund; provided, however, that the superintendent may retain an amount not to exceed $200,000 annually to be expended after consultation with the state secretary for equipment replacement and educational and cultural programs at the state house.
Chapter 10: State House Special Event Fund
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Secs. 19 and 20 effective October 31, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 219. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  There shall be established upon the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the State House Special Event Fund. The superintendent of the state house shall establish and charge a fee or service charge to nongovernmental individuals, entities and groups using the state house for meetings, receptions or exhibits, which may be waived at the discretion of the superintendent. The superintendent or his designee shall establish such fee or charge based upon the actual cost of use, including personnel requests for security, preparation, equipment replacement, cleanup, utilities used and compensation for wear on the building. The superintendent or his designee may, in their discretion, require a nongovernmental entity to enter into a written agreement indemnifying the commonwealth against any claims for casualty liability and may require the posting of an insurance bond. All monies received by the superintendent under this section shall be by check made payable to and deposited in the fund; provided, however, that the superintendent may retain funds to be expended after consultation with the committee on rules of the 2 branches, acting concurrently, for restoration, equipment repair and replacement and educational and cultural programs and tours at the state house; and provided further that funds shall be used for the maintenance of the military history museum under section 14 of chapter 8.
    </text>
</law>