<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23D" order_by="23D" level="3">Employee Ownership Revolving Loan Fund</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>17</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employee Involvement And Ownership Program; Powers And Duties Of Director</catch_line>
    <order_by>17</order_by>
    <text>
        There is hereby established in the executive branch, under the supervision of the executive director of the industrial services program, a program of employee involvement and ownership. Said program shall provide education, outreach and promotion efforts to create an overall environment in the commonwealth which will expand and enhance employee involvement and ownership, to publicize and promote the benefits of employee involvement and ownership to policy makers and the general public, to encourage joint collaborative outreach efforts regarding involvement and ownership in the workplace, to research and evaluate employee involvement and employee ownership in the commonwealth, to showcase employee involvement and ownership initiatives in the commonwealth, to facilitate and coordinate the sharing of existing information and resources, and to provide grants pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. 
The director shall have the powers to appoint any specific committee or task force and to contract with consultants, agents or advisors deemed necessary to further the purposes of the program of employee involvement and ownership; provided, however, that said director shall seek the advice of the commission prior to such appointment or such hiring. 
Said director may accept gifts or grants of money or property from any source; provided, however, that any money received shall be deposited with the state treasurer to be kept in a separate fund in the treasury for expenditure without appropriation by the director in accordance with the conditions of such gift or grant. 
The director shall, after consultation with the commission, issue such rules, regulations and procedures governing the application for and delivery of services provided for by sections seventeen to twenty-four, inclusive, which are deemed necessary for the proper performance of the duties of the program of employee involvement and ownership.
    </text>
</law>