<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12C" order_by="12C" level="3">Center For Health Information And Analysis</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Center For Health Information And Analysis;  Executive Director;  Term;  Removal</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 19 effective November 4, 2012.]  There is hereby established a center for health information and analysis. There shall be in the center an executive director, who shall be the administrative head of the center and who shall be appointed by a majority vote of the attorney general, the state auditor and the governor for a term of 5 years. The person so appointed shall be selected without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of expertise in health care policy, expertise in health care finance and such other educational requirements and experience that the attorney general, state auditor and governor determine are necessary.  In the case of a vacancy in the position of executive director, a successor shall be appointed in the same manner as the original appointment for the unexpired term. No person shall be appointed for more than 2 consecutive 5-year terms.  The person so appointed may be removed from office, for cause, by a majority vote of the attorney general, the state auditor and the governor. Such cause may include substantial neglect of duty, gross misconduct or conviction of a crime. The reasons for removal of the executive director shall 1 be stated in writing and shall include the basis for such removal. The writing shall be sent to the clerk of the senate, the clerk of the house of representative and to the governor at the time of the removal and shall be a public record.
    </text>
</law>