<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35LL</section_number>
    <catch_line>Nantasket Beach Reservation Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35LL</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be know as the Nantasket Beach Reservation Trust Fund to be used, without further appropriation, for the preservation, maintenance and safety of Nantasket Beach in the town of Hull. Any balance in the fund at the end of the fiscal year shall not revert to the General Fund, but shall remain available for expenditure in subsequent fiscal years. No expenditure made from the fund shall cause the fund to become deficient at any point during a fiscal year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, the department of conservation and recreation shall impose a surcharge of $4 for non-seniors and $2 for seniors upon each fee charged and collected from admission into parking in the Nantasket Beach Reservation. The additional monies collected from the surcharge shall be deposited into the Nantasket Beach Preservation Trust Fund. Expenditures by the trust for public safety shall first be made available to the town of Hull’s police, fire, ambulance and emergency personnel. No later than November 30 of each year, a representative from the department of conservation and recreation shall meet with the Hull board of selectmen to discuss the maintenance and safety plan for the next calendar year as well as the balance and expenditures from the Nantasket Beach Reservation Trust Fund.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>