<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration In Medicine; Membership; Appointment And Term; Expenses; Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board of registration in medicine, in this section and section eleven called the board, consisting of seven persons appointed by the governor, who shall be residents of the commonwealth, five of whom shall be physicians registered under section two of chapter one hundred and twelve, or corresponding provisions of earlier laws, and two of whom shall be representatives of the public, subject to the provisions of section nine B. Each member of the board shall serve for a term of three years. 
No member shall be appointed to more than two consecutive full terms; provided, however, a member appointed for less than a full term may serve two full terms in addition to such part of a full term, and a former member shall again be eligible for appointment after a lapse of one or more years. Any member of the board may be removed by the governor for neglect of duty, misconduct, malfeasance or misfeasance in office after being given a written statement of the charges against him and sufficient opportunity to be heard thereon. The board shall elect from its members a chairman, vice-chairman and secretary who shall serve for one year and until their successors are appointed and qualified. The board shall meet at least once a month or more often upon the call of the chairman at such times and places as the chairman shall designate. 
Members of the board shall, subject to appropriation, be paid thirty-five dollars for each day or part thereof spent in performing their duties, and shall receive their necessary traveling and other expenses while engaged in the business of the board, provided that the amount for expenses shall not be more than twenty dollars per day, except for traveling expense which shall not be more than eight cents per mile. 
The board shall adopt, amend, and rescind such rules and regulations as it deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter; may appoint legal counsel and such assistants as may be required; may make contracts and arrangements for the performance of administrative and similar services required, or appropriate, in the performance of the duties of the board; and may adopt and publish rules of procedure and other regulations not inconsistent with other provisions of the General Laws.
    </text>
</law>