<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration In Pharmacy; Membership; Qualifications;  Appointment; Term</catch_line>
    <order_by>22</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board of registration in pharmacy, in the 3 following sections called the board, consisting of 11 persons, who shall be residents of the commonwealth. Five of these persons shall be registered pharmacists and shall have had at least 10 consecutive years of practical experience in the compounding and dispensing of physicians’ prescriptions, and shall actually be engaged in the drug business. At the time of appointment to the board, at least 1 of such 5 members shall be an independent pharmacist employed in the independent pharmacy setting and at least 1 of 5 members shall be a chain pharmacist employed in the chain pharmacy setting, but not more than 2 pharmacists in any 1 practice setting may serve on the board at any one time. For the purposes of this section “ independent pharmacist” shall mean a pharmacist actively engaged in the business of retail pharmacy and employed in an organization of 9 or fewer registered retail drugstores in the commonwealth under the provisions of section 39 of chapter 112 and employing not more than 20 full time pharmacists, and “chain pharmacist” shall mean a pharmacist in the employ of a retail drug organization operating 10 or more retail drug stores within the commonwealth under the provisions of said section 39; but an independent pharmacist and a chain pharmacist shall represent two distinct practice settings. One person shall be a registered pharmacist and shall have had at least 10 years of experience in the compounding and dispensing of physicians’ prescriptions, and shall actually be engaged as a pharmacist in a non-profit hospital in the commonwealth. One person shall be a registered pharmacist and shall have had at least 10 years of experience employed in a long-term care pharmacy setting. Two members shall be representatives of the public, subject to the provisions of section 9B. One member shall be a physician registered pursuant to chapter 112 and 1 member shall be a nurse registered pursuant to chapter 112. No more than 1 member shall reside in the same senatorial district. One member shall annually in November be appointed by the governor, for 5 years from December first following.
    </text>
</law>