<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15" level="3">Department Of Elementary And Secondary Education</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1G</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Councils To Board; Membership; Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>1G</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Said program shall be designed to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     increase the participation of low-income children in existing school breakfast programs and secondarily to encourage other schools to start a breakfast program. The target of said program is to bring the participation level of children who qualify for free or reduced price breakfasts under federal income eligibility guidelines to at least eighty-five percent of those eligible;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     increase the number of summer food service programs offered across the state, with particular emphasis on needy communities, and to ensure that at least eighty-five percent of the children eligible under federal income guidelines participate in these programs.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The school breakfast related outreach program activities shall include, but not be limited to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     development of an outreach campaign to promote the link between a nutritious breakfast and the ability to learn; to make the school breakfast program attractive to all children; and to create a positive picture of school as a basic source of breakfast for all income groups. The efforts should be particularly targeted toward communities with the highest need and should include outreach to linguistic minorities;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     technical assistance shall be provided and technical assistance materials shall be produced including, but not be limited to, facts and guidelines on United States Department of Agriculture requirements; ideas for increasing participation; ideas for safeguarding confidentiality; ways to involve parents and other members of the community; and suggestions for creative menus; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     technical assistance shall be provided for the development of new and innovative proposals including a “school breakfast period” during existing school hours in schools in which a majority of children are program eligible, and a universal breakfast program in school systems with eighty percent of the students eligible.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The summer food service related outreach program activities shall include, but not be limited to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     an outreach effort to public schools, public entities and private non-profit agencies which would be eligible to provide the summer food services program. Said outreach shall include information and incentives to encourage eligible organizations to be local sponsors or meal preparation sites for the federal summer food service program;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     ongoing support and technical assistance shall be made available to existing programs year round to ensure that they continue to offer the program and to assist in increasing participation levels;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     reviewing and developing training methods and materials provided however that particular attention be given to providing appropriate training for first time sponsors;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     targeting communities and schools which have the highest percentage of program eligible children and establishing an order of descending priorities based on the percentage of program eligible children; provided, however, that there should be a concerted effort to outreach potential participants who are linguistic minorities; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     establishing start up grants not to exceed two thousand five hundred dollars to encourage the participation of first time summer food service sites.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     In all activities of this school breakfast and summer food service outreach program, local communities shall be encouraged and assisted in maximizing the use of federal resources.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Said school breakfast and summer food service outreach program shall work to ensure that local programs are carried out in a manner which protects the confidentiality of those children receiving subsidized meals.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The commissioner shall submit a report to the clerk of the house of representatives who shall forward the same to the joint committee on education, arts and humanities on or before December thirty-first, nineteen hundred and ninety-four and on December thirty-first of each year thereafter. The report shall include, but not be limited to: the percentage of eligible children participating in school breakfast programs statewide during the previous school year; the amount of additional federal dollars brought into the state by all school breakfast and summer food service outreach program activities; the number of additional school breakfast and summer food service programs started in the preceding year; and the increase in participation in summer food services and school breakfast programs.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The commissioner of education, in consultation with the chairman of the board of higher education, shall direct the global education advisory council to explore international opportunities for learning, exchange programs and the availability of curriculum materials for students, teachers, administrators and educational policy makers. Said global education advisory council shall: (a) investigate and compile information concerning international education programs and opportunities. The council shall make recommendations to the commissioner on the expansion of international education programs and opportunities and shall consider ways to encourage participation in such programs. The council shall advise the department of education and the joint committee on education on international program opportunities and the availability of federal or nonprofit agency grants or other funding sources for such programs. The department shall provide information on international education opportunities to local and regional boards of education and to institutions of higher education; (b) develop guidelines and standards to aid local and regional school districts in the establishment of programs of international studies. Such guidelines and standards shall describe the essential components of a quality educational program incorporating international education concepts. The council shall submit such guidelines and standards to the department of education for review and approval; (c) develop criteria for what constitutes a sister school partnership program between a public school of this state and a foreign school. Such criteria shall provide a process for recognition of such partnership. The council shall submit such criteria to the department of education for review and approval; (d) advise the department of education on possible incentives to encourage the formation of partnerships that meet criteria established in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c). Such incentives may include, but need not be limited to, cooperation between sister partnership schools in teacher certification, student assessment programs and recognition of student course credit, participation in summer programs and in other areas where the state could recognize the value of the sister school partnership relationships with minimal cost; (e) conduct an assessment of current practices regarding international education in elementary and secondary public schools in the commonwealth. The global education advisory council’s assessment of current practices shall include, but not be limited to, information gathering through public hearings.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>