<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>40N</section_number>
    <catch_line>Minority And Women Owned Businesses;  Affirmative Marketing Program;  Capital Facility Projects</catch_line>
    <order_by>40N</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. Repealed by 2012, 165, Sec. 66. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  (a) The general court finds that (1) the Massachusetts commission against discrimination conducted hearings and investigations which documented a history of discrimination against minorities and women in the commonwealth; (2) and in 1994, the executive office of transportation and construction produced a disparity study which documented a history of discrimination against minority and women owned businesses, in which the commonwealth's agencies were participants; (3) this discrimination against minorities and women currently affects the use of minority and women owned businesses in state contracting; (4) the commonwealth has a compelling interest in promoting the use of minority owned business and women owned businesses through the use of the available and qualified pool of minority and women owned businesses; (5) it is the policy of the commonwealth to promote equality in the market and, to that end, to encourage full participation of minority and women owned businesses in all areas of state contracting, including contracts for construction and design services.  (b) As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:--  "Affirmative marketing program'', a program of race and gender conscious goals to promote equality in, and to encourage the participation of, minority-owned businesses and women-owned businesses in contracts for capital facility projects and state assisted building projects;  "Capital facility project'', shall have the same meaning as found in section 39A of chapter 7 when the project is under the control of the division of capital asset management and maintenance;  "Design services'', any of the following services provided by any designer, programmer, or construction manager in connection with any public building project:  (i) preparation of master plans, studies, surveys, soil tests, cost estimates or programs;  (ii) preparation of drawings, plans, or specifications, including, but not limited to, schematic drawings, preliminary plans and specifications, working plans and specifications or other administration of construction contracts documents;  (iii) supervision or administration of a construction contract;  (iv) construction management or scheduling.  "Minority'', a person with a permanent residence in the United States who is American Indian, Black, Cape Verdean, Western Hemisphere Hispanic, Aleut, Eskimo, or Asian.  "Minority-owned business'', any contracting or subcontracting business, or businesses that supply the contractors and subcontractors which is beneficially owned by one or more minority persons as follows:  (i) the business must be at least 51 per cent owned by minority persons; in the case of a corporation having more than one class of stockholders, the ownership requirement must be met as to each class of stock;  (ii) the minority owners shall demonstrate that they have dominant control over management;  (iii) the business has not been established solely for the purpose of taking advantage of a special program which has been developed to assist minority businesses;  (iv) in the case of a joint venture between a minority business meeting the requirements of clauses (i) to (iii), inclusive, and a non-minority business, the joint venture shall be found to be a minority business if the minority business meeting the requirements of said clauses (i) to (iii), inclusive, shall have more than one-half control over management of the project bid upon and shall have the right to receive more than one-half of the profits deriving from that project.  "State assisted building project'', a construction project undertaken by a political subdivision of the commonwealth or 2 or more subdivisions thereof for the planning, acquisition, design, construction, demolition, installation, repair or maintenance of a capital facility and whose costs are paid for, reimbursed, grant funded, or otherwise supported, in whole or in part, by the commonwealth;  "State office of minority and women business assistance'' or "SOMWBA'', shall have the same meaning as found in section 40 of chapter 23A .  "Women-owned business'', any contracting or subcontracting business which is beneficially owned by one or more women meeting the requirements set forth in clauses (1) to (4), inclusive, of the definition of minority business, except that the terms "women'', "women owners'', and "women-owned business'', shall be substituted for the terms "minority'' and "minority persons'', "minority owners'', and "minority business'' appearing in the definition.  (c) The commissioner, in consultation with the director of the state office of minority and women business assistance, may establish an affirmative marketing program to ensure the fair participation of minority-owned and women-owned businesses on capital facility projects and state assisted building projects. The affirmative marketing program shall establish participation goals for minority-owned and women-owned business in the capital facility projects and state assisted building projects. The participation goals for minority-owned business and women-owned business shall be based upon the broadest and most inclusive pool of available minority-owned businesses and women-owned businesses interested in and capable of performing construction work and design services on the capital facility projects, state funded building projects, and state assisted building projects; but, the commissioner may establish both statewide and regional participation goals based upon the availability of minority-owned businesses and women-owned businesses. The state office of minority and women business assistance, or its successor agency, shall create and maintain a current directory of certified minority-owned businesses and women-owned businesses which will serve as one source of information in determining the pool of available minority-owned businesses and women-owned businesses. The commissioner and the director of SOMWBA shall meet on a quarterly basis to determine the status of the implementation of the affirmative marketing program and what further steps both agencies consider necessary to achieve the purpose of this section.  (d) Not later than January 15 of each year, the commissioner, in consultation with the director of state office of minority and women business assistance, shall establish participation goals for minority-owned businesses and women-owned businesses. The participation goals established pursuant to this section shall apply to capital facility projects and state assisted building projects. The participation goals shall be expressed as overall annual program goals which shall be applicable to the total dollar amount of contracts awarded for construction work and design services on capital facility projects and state assisted building projects for the calendar year. The commissioner shall publish in the central register, established under section 20A of chapter 9, the participation goals for minority-owned businesses and for women-owned businesses on capital facility projects and state assisted building projects. The participation goals for minority owned businesses and women owned businesses shall remain in effect until revised participation goals are established and published pursuant to this paragraph. The participation goals for minority owned businesses and women owned businesses, developed before the effective date of this section, under any existing executive order and in effect as of the January preceding the effective date of this section shall remain in effect until January 15 of the following year. The participation goals for minority-owned businesses and women-owned businesses shall be revised as necessary every 2 years thereafter.  (e) The commissioner, in consultation with the director of the state office of minority and women business assistance, shall develop a written procedure by which a public agency may, for an individual capital facility project, adjust the participation goals for minority-owned business and women-owned business based upon the actual availability of minority-owned businesses and women-owned businesses, the geographic location of the project, the scope of work of the capital facility project, or other relevant factors.  (f) The commissioner shall develop a written, good faith efforts waiver procedure by which public agencies may determine, at any time before the award of a contract, that compliance with the goals is not feasible and by which public agencies may reduce or waive the goals for an individual contract.  (g) In connection with the affirmative marketing program, the state office of minority and women business assistance shall regularly review and, where necessary, modify its certification process to ensure that it operates effectively, and shall report annually to the secretary of the executive office of administration and finance regarding these matters.  (h) The commissioner shall be responsible for the overall management, monitoring, and enforcement of the affirmative marketing program, as the program relates to capital facility projects under the control of the division, established pursuant to this section. The commissioner may appoint a program director within the office of the commissioner to assist in program development, coordination and compliance. The program director shall also have responsibility for monitoring contract compliance within the division, addressing potential program violations and coordinating division enforcement activities with the state office of minority and women business assistance and the attorney general.  (i) The commissioner shall by March 15 of each year submit to the joint committee on state administration, the senate committee on ways and means, the house committee on ways and means, the clerk of the house, and the clerk of the senate a report on the performance of the division's affirmative marketing program for the preceding year. The report shall, at a minimum, show the name and address of each such minority owned business and women owned business, its designation as a minority-owned or women-owned business, the contract or subcontract price, a description of the work performed on the contract by class of work, and project type, and shall show separately the total number of contracts awarded to minority-owned and women-owned businesses as a percentage of the total number of contracts awarded and as a percentage of the total contract price.  (j) The commissioner shall promulgate regulations necessary to implement this section.
    </text>
</law>