<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>23</section_number>
    <catch_line>Off Highway Vehicle Advisory Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>23</order_by>
    <text>
        There is hereby established within the executive office of energy and environmental affairs a state off-highway vehicle advisory committee. The committee shall advise the secretary and the department of conservation and recreation, the department of fish and game, the department of environmental protection and the office of environmental law enforcement on matters involving the commonwealth’s regulation of off-highway vehicles, as defined in section 20 of chapter 90B, including the development and enforcement of state regulations and policies, safety and training programs and the distribution of available state funding. The committee shall consist of 13 members to be appointed by the secretary, 3 of whom shall be representatives of off-highway vehicle users, 1 of whom shall be a representative of the New England Trail Rider Association; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Specialty Vehicle Industry Association and the Massachusetts Powersport Dealers Association; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the department of public health; 1 of whom shall be a representative of child safety advocates associated with the safe use of off-highway vehicles; 1 of whom shall be a representative of the Snowmobile Association of Massachusetts, Inc.; 2 of whom shall be representatives of a nonprofit organization that owns and manages land open to the public; 1 of whom shall be a representative of an association or organization of large private land owners; 1 of whom shall be a member of a friends group of the Massachusetts Forest and Parks Network; and 2 of whom shall be representatives of state or local law enforcement authorities. Members shall serve without compensation. Members shall be appointed for terms of 3 years. 
The committee shall select a chair annually by a majority vote of the members. The committee shall meet at least twice each year and shall also meet at the request of the secretary or the committee chair.
    </text>
</law>