<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="3">Department Of Environmental Management</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Commission For Conservation Of Soil, Water And Related Resources;  Powers And Duties.</catch_line>
    <order_by>20</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     To encourage and assist educational work in the conservation and development of renewable natural resources, including soil, water, plant life, woodland, fish and wildlife, and recreation resources, the control and prevention of erosion, floodwater and sediment damages, and the conservation, development, utilization and disposal of water, through co-operation with all federal, state, county, local, public and private resource agencies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     To advise the director in developing policies of the division of conservation services relating to the operation of conservation districts and to carry out policies and programs affecting conservation districts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     To perform the functions hereinafter provided for, relating to the establishment, change of boundaries, or dissolution of conservation districts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     To secure the co-operation and assistance of agencies of the United States, the commonwealth and its political subdivisions in promoting the organization and operation of conservation districts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     To disseminate information concerning the activities and programs of conservation districts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     To allot money appropriated for establishing and maintaining conservation districts and conservation district divisions and for the operation of their projects and programs.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     To develop annual budgets for the operation and maintenance of conservation districts, conservation district divisions, and the state commission for submission to the director.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     To establish program priorities and advise conservation districts and divisions on those programs which contribute to the conservation and best use of the natural resources of the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     To develop a natural resource plan for the commonwealth every five years commencing in January, nineteen hundred and eighty-five.
        </section>
        <section prefix="10">
    	     To accept contributions, gifts or grants of money or property, whether real or personal, from any source, private or public, including but not limited to, the United States or its agencies, in order to promote the purpose of this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="11">
    	     To establish, with the approval of the majority of the chairmen of the conservation districts, six conservation district divisions. In establishing said divisions, the state commission may include one or more conservation districts.
        </section>
        <section prefix="12">
    	     To encourage educational activities which promote the conservation and development of renewable natural resources, including soil, water, plant life, woodland, fish, wildlife, recreation resources, prevention of soil erosion, floodwater and sediment damages and the conservation, development, utilization and disposal of water through cooperation with appropriate federal, state, county, public and private agencies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="13">
    	     To set fees for pamphlets, publications or services which shall not exceed the cost of providing such pamphlets, publications or services and to promote uniform fees set by district supervisors.
        </section>
        <section prefix="14">
    	     To disseminate information regarding amendments to the general and special laws of the commonwealth, proposed changes in laws and rules and regulations which affect or shall affect businesses in the commonwealth; and, to establish educational outreach programs for the purpose of assisting small business to implement required changes in legislation.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>