<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23I" order_by="23I" level="3">The Massachusetts Life Sciences Center</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:— 
“Affiliate”, any business which directly or indirectly controls or is controlled by or is under direct or indirect common control of another business including, but not limited to, any business with which a business is merged or consolidated, or which purchases all or substantially all of the assets of a business. 
“Board”, the board of directors of the Massachusetts Life Sciences Center. 
“Center”, the Massachusetts Life Sciences Center established by section 3. 
“Certification proposal”, a written proposal submitted by a life sciences company for approval as a certified life sciences company pursuant to section 5. 
“Certified life sciences company”, a company that has been certified by the center for participation in the commonwealth life sciences investment program and the life sciences tax incentive program, established by section 5. 
“Company”, a business corporation, partnership, firm, unincorporated association or other entity engaged or proposing to engage in economic activity within the commonwealth, and any affiliate thereof, which is, or the members of which are, subject to taxation under chapter 62, 63, 64H or 64I. 
“Department”, the department of revenue established pursuant to section 1 of chapter 14. 
“Eligible new job”, a new job that shall not replace an existing job in the commonwealth and which may be a retained job; provided, however, that “eligible new job” may be further defined by rules, regulations or guidelines promulgated by the center pursuant to section 5; provided further, that an “eligible new job” shall be deemed to have been created in the commonwealth on the first day for which Massachusetts personal income tax withholding is required in connection with the compensation paid to an employee of a life sciences company or the first day for which Massachusetts estimated tax payments are payable by a partner of a partnership constituting a life sciences company. 
“Enterprise”, a small business, as defined in chapters 23A or 40F, which has its principal place of business in the commonwealth and is, or proposes to be, engaged in research and development or manufacturing in the life sciences industry. 
“Equity investment”, (a) a share in a life sciences company certified pursuant to section 5, whether or not transferable or denominated stock, or similar security; (b) interest of a limited partner in a limited partnership; or (c) warrant or right, other than a right to convert, to purchase, sell or subscribe to a share, security or interest of a kind specified in clauses (a) or (b); provided, however, that when making an equity investment in an enterprise pursuant to section 7, the center shall receive not less than 3 per cent of the equity in said enterprise. 
“Independent research institution”, a nonprofit research organization that holds tax-exempt status granted under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code and shall be organized and operated exclusively for scientific or educational purposes; provided, however, that “independent research institution” shall not mean a hospital, college, university or private foundation. 
“Life sciences”, advanced and applied sciences that expand the understanding of human physiology and have the potential to lead to medical advances or therapeutic applications including, but not limited to, agricultural biotechnology, biogenerics, bioinformatics, biomedical engineering, biopharmaceuticals, biotechnology, chemical synthesis, chemistry technology, diagnostics, genomics, image analysis, marine biology, marine technology, medical devices, nanotechnology, natural product pharmaceuticals, proteomics, regenerative medicine, RNA interference, stem cell research and veterinary science. 
“Life sciences company”, a business corporation, partnership, firm, unincorporated association or other entity engaged in life sciences research, development, manufacturing or commercialization in the commonwealth, and any affiliate thereof, which is, or the members of which are, subject to taxation under chapter 62, 63, 64H or 64I. 
“New state revenue”, revenue derived from a life sciences company by the creation of any eligible new jobs or by new commercial activity that would otherwise not have taken place in the commonwealth or as may be defined by any rules or regulations promulgated by the center pursuant to section 5. 
“Permanent full-time employee”, an individual who: (i) is in an employment relationship which, at its inception, does not have a termination date which is a date certain or which is determined with reference to the completion of some specified scope of work; (ii) works a minimum number of weekly hours as the center may specify by rule, regulation or guideline; and (iii) receives employee benefits at least equal to those provided to other full-time employees of the employer, which shall be a life sciences company. 
“Person”, a natural person, corporation, association, partnership or other legal entity. 
“Program”, the commonwealth life sciences investment program established by section 5. 
“Professional investor”, a bank, bank holding company, savings institution, trust company, insurance company, investment company registered under the federal Investment Company Act of 1940, pension or profit-sharing trust or other financial institution or institutional buyer, licensee under the federal Small Business Investment Act of 1958 or any person, partnership or other entity of whose resources a substantial amount shall be dedicated to investing in securities or debt instruments and whose net worth exceeds $250,000. 
“Qualified security”, a note, stock, treasury stock bond, debenture, evidence of indebtedness, certificate of interest or participation in a profit-sharing agreement, preorganization certificate or subscription, transferable share, investment contract, certificate of deposit for a security, certificate of interest or participation in a patent or application therefor, or in royalty or other payments under such a patent or application; in general, any interest or instrument security, so-called, or any certificate for, receipt for, guarantee of, or option, warrant or right to subscribe to or purchase any of the foregoing; and debt of and partnership interest in, as a general or limited partner, any general or limited liability partnership organized under the laws of the commonwealth, and debt of and membership interest in any limited liability company organized under the laws of the commonwealth. 
“Real estate project”, real property where, after a life sciences company is certified, construction or renovation shall be initiated which, when completed, shall result in an increase in the assessed value of the real property of at least 100 per cent over its assessed value as of the date of certification; provided, however, that if a real estate facility is a business incubator facility and is designated as a certified life sciences company pursuant to section 5, each business which executes a binding lease for space in that facility after the date on which the construction or renovation activity begins shall be eligible for separate designation as a certified life sciences company. 
“Revenue”, receipts, fees, rentals or other payments or income received or to be received on account of obligations to the center including, but not limited to, income on account of the leasing, mortgaging, sale or other disposition of a project or proceeds of a loan made by the center in connection with any project, and amounts in reserves or held in other funds or accounts established in connection with the issuance of bonds and the proceeds of any investments thereof, proceeds of foreclosure and any other fees, charges or other income received or receivable by the center. 
“Seed capital”, financing that is provided for the development, refinement and commercialization of a product or process and other working capital needs. 
“Taxpayer”, a certified life sciences company or person subject to the taxes imposed by chapter 62, 63, 64H or 64I. 
“Vocational technical school”, education institutions established pursuant to sections 14 and 15 of chapter 71, providing vocational-technical education as defined in section 1 of chapter 74.
    </text>
</law>