<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6A" order_by="6A" level="3">Executive Offices</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Structurally Deficient Bridge Improvement Program Coordination And Oversight Council; Members; Powers And Duties; Annual Report; Frequency Of Meetings</catch_line>
    <order_by>8C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be established a structurally deficient bridge improvement program coordination and oversight council. The council shall consist of a chair appointed by the governor, the secretary of administration and finance, the secretary of transportation, the secretary of energy and environmental affairs, the administrator of the division of highways of the Massachusetts Department of Transportation, and the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance, or their designees.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     the council shall coordinate and oversee the accelerated structurally deficient bridge improvement program including, without limitation:— (i) ensuring regular communication and coordination between the department of highways and the department of conservation and recreation as to their bridge development projects, programs and plans and any regulations or guidelines promulgated pursuant thereto; (ii) establishing and implementing project controls to ensure adequate tracking and reporting of program progress, cost and schedules; (iii) establishing an annual structurally deficient bridge improvement plan which shall include the number and location of bridges which shall be replaced or rehabilitated in the preceding year and the cost estimates of said replacement or rehabilitation; provided, however, that the council shall annually submit a report pursuant to this clause (iii) of subsection (b) not later than December 31st to the chairs of the house and senate committees on ways and means, the chairs of the joint committee on bonding, capital expenditures and state assets and the chairs of the joint committee on transportation; (iv) directing appropriate agencies to provide technical assistance as necessary to accomplish the objectives of the structurally deficient bridge improvement program; (v) coordinating and resolving any inconsistencies between capital investments made pursuant to the bridge improvement program and capital improvements made pursuant to the commonwealth’s capital plan; and (vi) establish criteria for project selection relative to funding from the structurally deficient bridge improvement program.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The council shall annually, not later than December 31st, submit a report of its activities to the chairs and ranking members of the house and senate committees on ways and means, the chairs and ranking members of the joint committee on bonding, capital expenditures and state assets and the chairs and ranking members of the joint committee on transportation.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The council shall meet at least quarterly. The secretary of executive office of transportation shall provide personnel necessary to coordinate the activities of the council and to provide administrative support to the council, as requested.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>