<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>167</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions Applicable To Secs. 167 And 168 To 178 L</catch_line>
    <order_by>167</order_by>
    <text>
        [Introductory paragraph effective until May 4, 2012. For text effective May 4, 2012, see below.] 
The following words shall, whenever used in this section or in sections one hundred and sixty-eight to one hundred seventy-eight, inclusive, have the following meanings unless the context otherwise requires: “Criminal justice agencies”, those agencies at all levels of government which perform as their principal function, activities relating to (a) crime prevention, including research or the sponsorship of research; (b) the apprehension, prosecution, adjudication, incarceration, or rehabilitation of criminal offenders; or (c) the collection, storage, dissemination or usage of criminal offender record information. 
[Introductory paragraph as amended by 2010, 256, Sec. 2 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102. For text effective until May 4, 2012, see above.] 
The following words shall, whenever used in this section or in sections 168 to 178L, inclusive, have the following meanings unless the context otherwise requires: 
[Definitions of “All available criminal offender record information” to “Commissioner” inserted preceding definition of “Criminal justice agencies” by 2010, 256, Sec. 3 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102.] 
“All available criminal offender record information”, adult and youthful offender convictions, non-convictions and pending criminal court appearances, but excluding criminal records sealed under section 34 of chapter 94C or sections 100A to 100C, inclusive, of chapter 276 or the existence of such records 
“Board”, the criminal record review board established under section 168. 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of criminal justice information services under section 167A. 
“Criminal justice agencies”, those agencies at all levels of government which perform as their principal function, activities relating to (a) crime prevention, including research or the sponsorship of research; (b) the apprehension, prosecution, adjudication, incarceration, or rehabilitation of criminal offenders; or (c) the collection, storage, dissemination or usage of criminal offender record information. 
[Definitions of “Criminal offender record information” and “Department” inserted following definition of “Criminal justice agencies” by 2010, 256, Sec. 4 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102.] 
“Criminal offender record information”, records and data in any communicable form compiled by a Massachusetts criminal justice agency which concern an identifiable individual and relate to the nature or disposition of a criminal charge, an arrest, a pre-trial proceeding, other judicial proceedings, sentencing, incarceration, rehabilitation, or release. Such information shall be restricted to that recorded as the result of the initiation of criminal proceedings or any consequent proceedings related thereto. Criminal offender record information shall not include evaluative information, statistical and analytical reports and files in which individuals are not directly or indirectly identifiable, or intelligence information. Criminal offender record information shall be limited to information concerning persons who have attained the age of 17 and shall not include any information concerning criminal offenses or acts of delinquency committed by any person before he attained the age of 17; provided, however, that if a person under the age of 17 is adjudicated as an adult, information relating to such criminal offense shall be criminal offender record information. Criminal offender record information shall not include information concerning any offenses which are not punishable by incarceration. 
“Department”, the department of criminal justice information services established pursuant to section 167A. 
“Evaluative information”, records, data, or reports concerning individuals charged with crime and compiled by criminal justice agencies which appraise mental condition, physical condition, extent of social adjustment, rehabilitative progress and the like, and which are primarily used in connection with bail, pre-trial or post-trial release proceedings, sentencing, correctional and rehabilitative planning, probation or parole. 
[Definition of “Executive office” inserted following definition of “Evaluative information” by 2010, 256, Sec. 5 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102.] 
“Executive office”, the executive office of public safety and security. 
“Intelligence information”, records and data compiled by a criminal justice agency for the purpose of criminal investigation, including reports of informants, investigators or other persons, or from any type of surveillance associated with an identifiable individual. Intelligence information shall also include records and data compiled by a criminal justice agency for the purpose of investigating a substantial threat of harm to an individual, or to the order or security of a correctional facility. 
“Interstate systems”, all agreements, arrangements and systems for the interstate transmission and exchange of criminal offender record information. Such systems shall not include recordkeeping systems in the commonwealth maintained or controlled by any state or local agency, or group of such agencies, even if such agencies receive or have received information through, or otherwise participated or have participated in, systems for the interstate exchange of criminal record information. 
[Definition of “Person” inserted following definition of “Interstate systems” by 2010, 256, Sec. 6 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102.] 
“Person”, a natural person, corporation, association, partnership or other legal entity acting as a decision maker on an application or interacting directly with a subject. 
“Purge”, remove from the criminal offender record information system such that there is no trace of information removed and no indication that said information was removed. 
[Definitions of “Requestor” to “Subject” added by 2010, 256, Sec. 7 effective May 4, 2012. See 2010, 256, Sec. 145 as amended by 2010, 359, Sec. 102.] 
“Requestor ”, a person, other than a criminal justice agency, submitting a request for criminal offender record information to the department. 
“Secretary”, the secretary of public safety and security. 
“Self-audit”, an inquiry made by a subject or his legally authorized designee to obtain a log of all queries to the department by any individual or entity, other than a criminal justice agency, for the subject’s criminal offender record information, but excluding any information relative to any query conducted by a criminal justice agency. 
“Subject”, an individual for whom a request for criminal offender record information is submitted.
    </text>
</law>