<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6C" order_by="6C" level="3">Massachusetts Department Of Transportation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Internal Special Audit Unit</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
          (a) There shall be within the department, but not subject to the control of the department, an internal special audit unit. The inspector general council established in section 3 of chapter 12A shall appoint a director of the internal special audit unit for a term of 6 years. The governor may remove the director only for cause, and shall fill any vacancy for the unexpired term. The director shall devote his full time and attention to the duties of this office.  (b) The internal special audit unit shall monitor the quality, efficiency and integrity of the department's operating and capital programs and seek to prevent, detect and correct fraud, waste and abuse in the expenditure of public or private transportation funds.  (c) The director may appoint such persons as he shall deem necessary to perform the functions of the internal special audit unit; provided, however, that section 9A of chapter 30 and chapter 31 shall not apply to any person holding any such appointment. Employees of the internal special audit unit shall have experience with accounting, auditing, financial analysis, applicable law, business management and public administration and shall devote their full-time efforts to the unit and shall not be assigned direct operating responsibilities. Every person so appointed to any position in the internal special audit unit shall have experience and skill in the field of such position.  (d) The director may report and refer his findings to the inspector general for investigation pursuant to chapter 12A and the results of such investigation may be referred to the attorney general for appropriate action.[ Subsection (e) added by 2012, 132, Sec. 1 effective June 29, 2012.]  (e) The director shall submit an annual report of the unit's activities for the preceding calendar year, including, but not limited to, findings referred to the inspector general for investigation, to the joint committee on transportation and the house and senate committees on ways and means on or before March 15 of each year.
    </text>
</law>