<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>125</section_number>
    <catch_line>Health And Welfare Commission; Establishment</catch_line>
    <order_by>125</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a health and welfare commission, in this section and in sections one hundred and twenty-six to one hundred and twenty-nine, inclusive, called the commission, consisting of the commissioner of public health, the commissioner of mental health, the commissioner of transitional assistance, the commissioner of rehabilitation, and three members to be appointed by the governor, not more than two of whom shall be members of the same political party, and one of whom shall represent the Massachusetts Psychological Association. Said commission shall plan, co-ordinate and develop comprehensive programs in health and welfare services and facilities. Upon the expiration of the term of office of an appointive member, his successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of three years, and shall serve until the qualification of his successor. Each appointive member of the commission shall receive the sum of fifty dollars for each day or part thereof of service as a commissioner; provided, that no such member shall receive in any fiscal year a sum in excess of five thousand dollars for his services. 
The chairman and vice chairman of the commission shall be elected biennially by the members; provided, however, that no member may serve as chairman for two consecutive terms. The vice chairman shall assist the chairman and serve as chairman in his absence. The commission shall meet monthly, and at other times at the call of the chairman or as the commission may determine. 
The commission may appoint an executive secretary, research assistants, and legal, clerical, and other assistants as may be necessary to carry out its duties. The executive secretary shall not be subject to chapter thirty-one nor to section nine A of chapter thirty, and shall be paid such compensation as the commission shall from time to time fix. 
Funds received by the commission from the federal government, or from any foundation, corporation or other person shall be deposited with the state treasurer and be accounted for and audited in the usual manner prescribed for all agencies of the commonwealth. The commission shall not interfere with the administrative or policy making decisions of the departments of mental health, public health, or public welfare or of the rehabilitation commission.
    </text>
</law>