<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="3">Department Of The Attorney General, And The District Attorneys</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11L</section_number>
    <catch_line>Unlicensed Mental Health And Unlicensed Health Professionals; Sexual Contact With Patients Or Clients; Temporary Restraining Order, Injunction;  Violation; Penalty</catch_line>
    <order_by>11L</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     As used in this section, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     sexual intercourse, cunnilingus, fellatio, anal intercourse or any intrusion, however slight, into the genital or anal openings of the patient’s or former patient’s body by any object used by the unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional for that purpose, or any intrusion, however slight, into the genital or anal openings of the body of the unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional by any part of the patient’s or former patient’s body or by any object used by the patient or former patient for that purpose, if consented to by the unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     sustained kissing of the mouth or kissing or intentional touching by the unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional of the patient’s or former patient’s genital area, groin, inner thigh, buttocks, or breast or the clothing covering any of these body parts; or sustained kissing of the mouth or kissing or intentional touching by the patient or former patient of the unlicensed mental health professional’s or unlicensed health professional’s genital area, groin, inner thigh, buttocks or breast or the clothing covering any of these body parts if the unlicensed mental health professional or unlicensed health professional consents to the kissing or intentional touching. The term sexual contact, shall not include conduct described in the definition of sexual contact that is in accordance with practices generally recognized as legitimate by the health or mental health professions, casual social contact not intended to be sexual in character, or inadvertent or unintentional touching.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Whenever the attorney general has probable cause to believe that an unlicensed mental health professional or unlicensed health professional is having or has had sexual contact with one or more patients or clients while such health professional or mental health professional was licensed or unlicensed, or former patients or clients, and that said unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional poses a threat to the health, safety, or welfare of members of the public who are or may be patients or clients of the unlicensed health or unlicensed mental health professional, the attorney general may bring an action in the name of the commonwealth against said unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional to restrain by temporary restraining order or preliminary or permanent injunction said unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional from providing, offering to provide, or representing himself as being able to provide health services or mental health services.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The action may be brought either in the superior court for the county in which the conduct complained of occurred or in the superior court for the county in which the unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional resides or has his principal place of business.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     No injunction shall be issued pursuant to this section unless the court finds that the defendant has had an opportunity for an evidentiary hearing as to all contested material issues of fact. Issues decided in a prior evidentiary hearing in a court or in an administrative proceeding may be applied to a proceeding pursuant to this section in compliance with the Massachusetts Civil Rules of Procedure.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Any district attorney or other law enforcement office receiving notice of any alleged violation of this section or violation of an injunction or order issued in an action brought under this section shall immediately forward written notice of the same together with any information that he may have to the office of the attorney general.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     In an action brought pursuant to this section, whenever the court issues a temporary restraining order or a preliminary or permanent injunction, ordering a defendant to refrain from certain conduct or activities, the order issued shall contain the following statement:
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     Nothing contained herein shall prohibit the attorney general in his discretion from beginning an action for civil contempt rather than seeking criminal charges for an alleged violation of an order issued under this section. A court making a finding that an unlicensed health professional or unlicensed mental health professional is in civil contempt by reason of an alleged violation of an injunction or the order entered under this section shall assess a civil penalty of not more than ten thousand dollars for each such violation found.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>