<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>131B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Federal Agreement</catch_line>
    <order_by>131B</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until April 11, 2011. For text effective April 11, 2011, see below.]  The commissioner shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services, under which said Secretary shall, on behalf of the commonwealth, administer the program of state supplementary payments for the blind authorized by section one hundred and thirty-one. Such agreement shall be in the form of and satisfy the requirements for the agreement which, under section three of chapter one hundred and eighteen A, the commissioner of public welfare shall execute for the administration of state supplementary payments for the aged and disabled.
Chapter 6: Federal agreement
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 9, Sec. 3 effective April 11, 2011. For text effective until April 11, 2011, see above.]  At the discretion of the Social Security Administration, the commissioner shall enter into an agreement with the Social Security Administration, under which the commonwealth may administer the program of state supplementary payments authorized in section 1 of chapter 118A, or the Social Security Administration may, on behalf of the commonwealth, administer the program of state supplementary payments for the blind authorized in section 131. This agreement shall satisfy the requirements under section 3 of said chapter 118A which the Social Security Administration shall execute for the administration of state supplementary payments for the aged and disabled.
    </text>
</law>