<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="22C" order_by="22C" level="3">The Department Of State Police</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>70</section_number>
    <catch_line>Gaming Enforcement Unit</catch_line>
    <order_by>70</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 15 effective November 22, 2011.]  The colonel of state police shall establish a gaming enforcement unit the responsibilities of which shall include, but not be limited to, the investigation of criminal violations of chapter 23K or any other general or special law pertaining to gaming.  The gaming enforcement unit shall work in conjunction and cooperation with the investigations and enforcement bureau within the Massachusetts gaming commission to enforce chapter 23K and with the division of gaming enforcement within the department of the attorney general to investigate criminal activity related to gaming. Officers and employees of the unit shall be assigned to the investigations and enforcement bureau and shall report to the deputy director of investigations and enforcement and to the colonel of state police. The colonel shall also assign officers of the unit to the division of gaming enforcement, who shall report to the chief of gaming enforcement and to the colonel of state police. No officer of the unit, other than in the performance of official duties, shall place a wager in a gaming establishment licensed under chapter 23K; provided, however, that the code of ethics established pursuant to subsection (m) of section 3 of chapter 23K shall apply to all officers and employees of the unit. The colonel shall establish a program to rotate officers in and out of the unit.
    </text>
</law>