<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>48</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Racing Commission;  Appointment;  Duties;  Tenure;  Annual Report</catch_line>
    <order_by>48</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until May 20, 2012. Repealed by 2011, 194, Sec. 4. See 2011, 194, Sec. 110.]  There shall be within the division of professional licensure a commission to be known as the state racing commission, in this section and in chapters 128A and 128C inclusive called the commission. The commission shall be deemed a board serving in the division of professional licensure, within the meaning of sections 8, 9, 9A, 9B and 9C of chapter 13.  The commission shall consist of three commissioners, a chairman and two associate commissioners, all to be appointed by the governor and serve coterminous with him. Not more than two of such commissioners shall be of the same political party. The day-to-day operations and general administration of the commission, including all administrative functions of the commission and all actions not expressly required by statute or regulation to be carried out by the commission itself, shall, at the direction and under the control of the director of the division of professional licensure, be under the supervision of an executive director, who shall be appointed by the director of the division of professional licensure with the approval of the director of consumer affairs and business regulation. The executive director shall devote his full time during business hours to his duties hereunder. The director of the division of professional licensure may employ, as employees of the division of professional licensure, such other persons, in addition to the aforementioned executive director, as the director of the division of professional licensure may determine to be necessary to carry out such day-to-day operations and general administration of the commission.  Each commissioner shall hold office until the appointment and qualification of his successor. The governor may remove any commissioner for cause and shall fill any vacancy for the unexpired term. Whenever any action by the commission is required to be in writing, such writing shall be sufficient when signed by the commission chairman.  The commission shall make an annual report in January of each year to the general court. That report shall include the following information with respect to the previous calendar year: statements of monies deposited in the Running Horse Capital Improvements Trust Fund and the Running Horse Promotional Trust Fund, each established under section 11 of chapter 494 of the acts of 1978, the Harness Horse Capital Improvements Trust Fund and the Harness Horse Promotional Trust Fund, each established under section 12 of said chapter 494, together with a detailed account of monies disbursed from the funds, the specific capital improvements and promotions for which the disbursements were intended, and a report on which of the improvements and promotions have been accomplished; a statement of racing dates awarded to licensees, including those awarded in connection with a state or county fair; and a statement of the total amounts wagered at each race track, together with the monies paid to the commonwealth and the commission, purses paid to horse owners and monies retained by each licensee, together with a statement of the net profit of each licensee taken from the financial statements filed under section 6 of chapter 128A. Copies of the report shall be transmitted to the governor, the president of the senate, the speaker of the house of representatives, the chairmen of the house and senate committees on ways and means, the joint committee on government regulations and the joint committee on taxation.
    </text>
</law>