<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23A" order_by="23A" level="3">Department Of Economic Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>62</section_number>
    <catch_line>Interagency Permitting Board;  Members;  Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>62</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  There shall be a 10 person interagency permitting board within the Massachusetts office of business development. The members of the board shall be comprised of the state permit ombudsman who will serve as the chair of the interagency permitting board, the secretary of housing and economic development, the secretary of transportation, the secretary of energy and environmental affairs, the secretary of public safety and security, the director of the department of housing and community development, the director of business development, the director of the department of workforce development, the director of the office of consumer affairs and business regulation, and the executive director of the Massachusetts Development Finance Agency; or their designees. Six members shall be a quorum for the transaction of business. The chair shall communicate with municipal officials responsible for local review procedures to determine the municipal perspective on the proposed project, and to facilitate communication between the municipality and state agencies. The interagency permitting board shall consult with each regional office of the Massachusetts office of business development as well as each regional planning agency and regional economic development organizations with which the Massachusetts office of business development has contracted under this chapter in order to better serve local businesses. At the direction of the chair, the board shall meet no fewer than 8 times a year, and shall monitor the development of priority development sites under chapter 43D and investigate ways in which to expedite priority development site projects. The board shall evaluate state agency permit procedures and recommend changes for improved efficiency. The board shall administer the technical assistance grants program established in subsection (b) of section 3 of chapter 43D. The secretary of housing and economic development shall work with the chair of the interagency permitting board and senior staff members to develop a recommended format for an application form and procedure which shall be used by all executive offices when possible.
Chapter 23A: Interagency permitting board; members; duties
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 54 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  There shall be a 10 person interagency permitting board within the Massachusetts office of business development. The members of the board shall be comprised of the state permit ombudsman who will serve as the chair of the interagency permitting board, the secretary of housing and economic development, the secretary of transportation, the secretary of energy and environmental affairs, the secretary of public safety and security, the director of the department of housing and community development, the director of business development, the secretary of labor and workforce development, the director of the office of consumer affairs and business regulation, and the executive director of the Massachusetts Development Finance Agency; or their designees. Six members shall be a quorum for the transaction of business. The chair shall communicate with municipal officials responsible for local review procedures to determine the municipal perspective on the proposed project, and to facilitate communication between the municipality and state agencies. The interagency permitting board shall consult with each regional office of the Massachusetts office of business development as well as each regional planning agency and regional economic development organizations with which the Massachusetts office of business development has contracted under this chapter in order to better serve local businesses. At the direction of the chair, the board shall meet no fewer than 8 times a year, and shall monitor the development of priority development sites under chapter 43D and investigate ways in which to expedite priority development site projects. The board shall evaluate state agency permit procedures and recommend changes for improved efficiency. The board shall administer the technical assistance grants program established in subsection (b) of section 3 of chapter 43D. The secretary of housing and economic development shall work with the chair of the interagency permitting board and senior staff members to develop a recommended format for an application form and procedure which shall be used by all executive offices when possible.
    </text>
</law>