<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Establishment Of Qualification For Licensure By Clear And Convincing Evidence;  Duty To Cooperate In Inquiry Or Investigation;  Willful Provision Of False Or Misleading Information</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) An applicant for a gaming license, and any person required by the commission to be qualified for licensure, shall establish its individual qualifications for licensure to the commission by clear and convincing evidence.  (b) An applicant, licensee, registrant or any other person who shall be qualified under this chapter shall have the continuing duty to provide any assistance or information required by the commission and to cooperate in any inquiry or investigation conducted by the commission. Refusal to answer or produce information, evidence or testimony by an applicant, licensee, registrant or other person required to be qualified under this chapter may result in denial of the application or suspension or revocation of the license or registration by the commission.  (c) No applicant, licensee, registrant or person required to be qualified under this chapter shall willfully withhold information from, or knowingly give false or misleading information to, the commission. If the commission determines that an applicant, or a close associate of an applicant, has willfully provided false or misleading information, such applicant shall not be eligible to receive a license under this chapter. Any licensee or other person required to be qualified for licensure under this chapter who willfully provides false or misleading information shall have its license conditioned, suspended or revoked by the commission.
    </text>
</law>