<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>34</section_number>
    <catch_line>Appointment Of Conservator To Manage And Operate Business Of Gaming Licensee Upon Revocation, Suspension, Or Failure Or Refusal Of Renewal Of License</catch_line>
    <order_by>34</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) Upon revocation or suspension of a gaming license or upon the failure or refusal to renew a gaming license, the commission may appoint a conservator to temporarily manage and operate the business of the gaming licensee relating to the gaming establishment. Such conservator shall be a person of similar experience in the field of gaming management and, in the case of replacing a gaming licensee, shall have experience operating a gaming establishment of similar caliber in another jurisdiction, and shall be in good standing in all jurisdictions in which the conservator operates a gaming establishment. Upon appointment, a conservator shall agree to all licensing provisions of the former gaming licensee.  (b) A conservator shall, before assuming, managerial or operational duties, execute and file a bond for the faithful performance of its duties payable to the commission with such surety and in such form and amount as the commission shall approve.  (c) The commission shall require that the former or suspended gaming licensee purchase liability insurance, in an amount determined by the commission, to protect a conservator from liability for any acts or omissions of the conservator during the conservator's appointment which are reasonably related to and within the scope of the conservator's duties.  (d) During the period of temporary management of the gaming establishment, the commission shall initiate proceedings under this chapter to award a new gaming license to a qualified applicant whose gaming establishment shall be located at the site of the preexisting gaming establishment.  (e) An applicant for a new gaming license shall be qualified for licensure under this chapter; provided, however, that the commission shall determine an appropriate level of investment by an applicant into the preexisting gaming establishment.  (f) Upon award of a new gaming license, the new gaming licensee shall pay the original licensing fee required under this chapter.
    </text>
</law>