<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23A" order_by="23A" level="3">Department Of Economic Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13L</section_number>
    <catch_line>Foreign Offices For International Trade; Establishment; Location;  Functions; List Of Import Or Export Businesses; Publicity; Technical Assistance; Foreign Trade Information, Publication</catch_line>
    <order_by>13L</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There shall be within the international trade office 1 or more foreign offices for international trade. The foreign offices may be located in any country that the executive director of the international trade office determines to be best suited as a location for the furthering of foreign trade opportunities for the businesses of the commonwealth. The foreign offices shall encourage and further trade between foreign businesses and businesses in the commonwealth. The foreign offices shall also promote investment opportunities in the commonwealth for foreign businesses in order to encourage the location and establishment of such businesses within the commonwealth. For the purposes of furthering foreign trade and investment, the foreign offices, subject to appropriation and approval by the executive director of the trade international office, may contract for such advertising and other communication services as may be necessary. The foreign offices shall maintain an updated list of businesses in the commonwealth and foreign businesses which are or might become active in the import or export of their products and services. The executive director shall consult with the Massachusetts office of business development and the regional economic development organizations designated under section 3K in order to ensure that the businesses and assets of all regions of the commonwealth are included in such lists. The foreign office may also provide additional information and assistance to businesses in the commonwealth that desire to export their goods and services.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The foreign offices shall, on a regular basis, make all foreign trade information available to the executive director of the international trade office, who shall publish and furnish such information to regional economic development organizations designated under section 3K and to businesses and corporations in the commonwealth which might be interested in, or benefit from the utilization of such information. The executive director of the international trade office may charge a fee not to exceed the actual printing costs for such information, except that no fee shall be charged to regional economic development organizations designated under section 3K.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>