<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>180</section_number>
    <catch_line>Powers And Duties In Preserving Underwater Archaeological Resources;  State Title; Definition</catch_line>
    <order_by>180</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     cooperate with all departments, boards, officials and institutions of the commonwealth and its political subdivisions that are concerned with matters under its supervision;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     cooperate and consult with appropriate federal agencies or the agencies of other states;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     determine after a public hearing, if the board deems such a hearing in the public interest, whether certain objects found under the waters of the commonwealth are of historical value.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     enter into agreements relative to the federal administration and enforcement of underwater exploration and removal or salvage of underwater archaeological resources beyond the coastal waters of the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     apply for, receive and expend such federal funds or private grants as may be available therefor and accept gifts, contributions and bequests of funds, equipment and property from individuals, organization, and government entities, in carrying out its duties;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     request assistance from appropriate state and local agencies and private organizations and individuals.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     adopt, after public hearing, such rules and regulations regarding reporting and permit requirements for the removal and salvage of underwater archaeological resources as will insure the protection of their historical and educational value;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     grant permits in accordance with section sixty-three of chapter ninety-one to qualified persons, organizations, or corporations for the orderly salvage or removal of underwater archaeological resources;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     oversee the salvage and recovery operations by said permit holders;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     compile and maintain an inventory of underwater archaeological resources reported and recovered under the provisions of this section and section sixty-three of chapter ninety-one, which shall not be a public record; and.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     designate underwater archaeological preserves to provide special protection to those underwater archaeological resources of substantial historical value reported under the provisions of this section and section sixty-three of chapter ninety-one.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>