<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>116</section_number>
    <catch_line>Municipal Police Training Committee;  Members;  Chairperson;  Executive Director</catch_line>
    <order_by>116</order_by>
    <text>
          There shall be a municipal police training committee within the executive office of public safety. Members of said committee shall be as follows:-- 5 chiefs of police to be appointed by the governor from nominations submitted by the Massachusetts Chiefs of Police Association, 1 of whom shall be from the western Massachusetts region, 1 of whom shall be from the central Massachusetts region, 1 of whom shall be from the southeastern Massachusetts region, 1 of whom shall be from the northeastern Massachusetts region and 1 of whom shall be from the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority, 1 chief of police selected by the Massachusetts Chiefs of Police Association, 1 police officer to be appointed by the governor from nominations submitted by the Massachusetts Police Association executive board and the Massachusetts Police Training Officers Association executive board, the commissioner of police of the city of Boston, the colonel of state police, the attorney general and 1 person to be designated by the secretary of public safety, or their respective designees. All such appointments shall be for terms of 3 years with their successors appointed in a like manner.[ Second paragraph effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  The following persons shall be advisory, nonvoting members of the committee: the personnel administrator, the commissioner of correction, the commissioner of youth services, the commissioner of probation, the chairman of the parole board, the executive director of the committee on criminal justice, the chief administrative justice for the trial court, the chief justice of the district court department, the commissioner of education, the chairman of the criminal law committee of the Massachusetts Bar Association, or their respective designees, and the special agent in charge of the Boston office of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, if consent is given by the director of said bureau, or his designee. The governor shall appoint 5 additional advisory, nonvoting members of the committee, 1 of whom shall be an administrator of a city or town, 1 of whom shall be a clerk of the superior court, 1 of whom shall be a member of the committee for public counsel services, 1 of whom shall be a sheriff of a county or a former county, and 1 of whom shall be a district attorney of a district, or their respective designees.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2011, 93, Sec. 2 effective July 1, 2012. See 2011, 93, Sec. 137. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  The following persons shall be advisory, nonvoting members of the committee: the personnel administrator, the commissioner of correction, the commissioner of youth services, the commissioner of probation, the chairman of the parole board, the executive director of the committee on criminal justice, the chief justice of the trial court, the chief justice of the district court department, the commissioner of education, the chairman of the criminal law committee of the Massachusetts Bar Association, or their respective designees, and the special agent in charge of the Boston office of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, if consent is given by the director of said bureau, or his designee. The governor shall appoint 5 additional advisory, nonvoting members of the committee, 1 of whom shall be an administrator of a city or town, 1 of whom shall be a clerk of the superior court, 1 of whom shall be a member of the committee for public counsel services, 1 of whom shall be a sheriff of a county or a former county, and 1 of whom shall be a district attorney of a district, or their respective designees.  The committee shall elect a chairperson annually and shall, as needed, provide nominations for the selection of an executive director to the secretary of public safety. The secretary shall select an executive director from the nominations submitted by the committee. The position of executive director shall be classified in accordance with section 45 of chapter 30 and the salary shall be determined in accordance with section 46C of said chapter 30.  The committee shall set policies and standards for the training of municipal police officers, candidates for appointment as municipal police officers, environmental law enforcement officers and the University of Massachusetts police officers in accordance with applicable laws and regulations, including the training mandated by sections 116A to 116D, inclusive, of this chapter, section 36B of chapter 40, sections 96B and 97B of chapter 41 and section 24M of chapter 90. The committee shall review and recommend to the secretary an annual appropriation for the administration of the committee, as well as for the operations of a headquarters and regional training centers, and for the delivery of standardized training at the centers.
    </text>
</law>