<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="15C" order_by="15C" level="3">Massachusetts College Student Loan Authority</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Revenue Bonds, Notes, Or Other Obligations; Issuance; Authorization By Resolution; Resolution Provisions; Liability</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     The Authority may from time to time issue revenue bonds for any corporate purpose and all such revenue bonds, notes, bond anticipation notes or other obligations of the Authority issued pursuant to this chapter shall be and are hereby declared to be negotiable for all purposes notwithstanding their payment from a limited source and without regard to any other law or laws subject only to the provisions of revenue bonds or notes for registration. In anticipation of the sale of such revenue bonds, the Authority may issue negotiable bond anticipation notes and may renew the same from time to time, but the maximum maturity of any such note, including renewals thereof, shall not exceed five years from the date of issue of the original note. Such notes shall be paid from any revenues of the Authority available therefor and not otherwise pledged, or from the proceeds of sale of the revenue bonds of the Authority in anticipation of which they were issued. The notes shall be issued in the same manner as the revenue bonds. Such notes and the resolution or resolutions authorizing the same may contain any provisions, conditions or limitations which a bond resolution of the Authority may contain.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     The revenue bonds and notes of every issue shall be payable solely out of the revenues of the Authority, pertaining to the program relating to such bonds or notes including principal and interest on Authority loans and education loans, payments by participating institutions for higher education banks, guarantors, insurance companies or others pursuant to letters of credit or purchase agreements, investment earnings from funds or accounts maintained pursuant to the bond resolution, insurance proceeds, loan funding deposits, proceeds of sales of education loans, proceeds of refunding bonds and fees, charges and other revenues of the Authority from such program but subject only to any agreements with the holders of particular revenue bonds or notes pledging any particular revenues and subject to any agreements with any participating institution for higher education.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     The revenue bonds or notes may be issued as serial bonds or notes or as term bonds or notes, or the Authority, in its discretion, may issue bonds or notes of both types. The revenue bonds or notes shall be authorized by resolution of the members of the Authority and shall bear such date or dates and mature at such time or times not exceeding thirty years from the date of issuance from their respective dates, bear interest at such rate or rates, payable at such time or times, be in such denominations, be in such form either coupon or registered, carry such registration or conversion privileges, be executed with manual or facsimile signatures in such manner, be payable in lawful money of the United States at such place or places, and be subject to such terms of redemption, as such resolution or resolutions may provide. Such resolution or resolutions may delegate to the executive director, assistant executive director or any member of the Authority, or any combination of them, the power to determine any of the matters set forth in this section and the power to award the bonds to a purchaser or purchasers at public sale or to negotiate a sale to a purchaser or purchasers provided in the latter case that the bonds are to be reoffered to the public. The revenue bonds or notes may be sold at public or private sale for such price or prices as the Authority shall determine. Pending preparation of the definitive bonds, the Authority may issue interim receipts or certificates which shall be exchanged for such definitive bonds.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Any resolution or resolutions authorizing any revenue bonds or any issue of revenue bonds may contain provisions, which shall be a part of the contract with the holders of the revenue bonds to be authorized as to:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     pledging all or any part of the authority loans, education loans or revenues derived from the Authority loans and education loans with respect to which such bonds or notes are to be issued; (2) pledging all or any part of the revenues paid to the Authority by any guarantor or insurance company; (3) any revenue producing contract or contracts made by the Authority with any individual, partnership, corporation or association or other body, public or private, or any federally guaranteed security and moneys received therefrom whether such security is acquired by the Authority or a participating institution for higher education to secure the payment of the revenue bonds or notes or of any particular issue of revenue bonds or with, subject to such agreements with bondholders or noteholders as may then exist; (4) the fees and other amounts to be charged, and the sums to be raised in each year thereby, and the use, investment and disposition of such sums; (5) the establishment and setting aside of reserves or sinking funds, the setting aside of loan funding deposits, capitalized interest accounts, and cost of issuance accounts, and the regulation and disposition thereof; (6) limitations on the use of the education loans; (7) limitations on the purpose to which the proceeds of sale of any issue of revenue bonds or notes then or thereafter to be issued may be applied, including as authorized purposes, all costs and expenses necessary or incidental to the issuance of bonds, to the acquisition of or commitment to acquire any federally guaranteed security and pledging such proceeds to secure the payment of the revenue bonds, notes or any issue of the revenue bonds or notes; (8) limitations on the issuance of additional bonds or notes, the terms upon which additional bonds may be issued and secured and the terms on which additional bonds or notes may rank on a parity with, or be subordinate or superior to, other bonds or notes; (9) the refunding of outstanding bonds or notes; (10) the procedure, if any, by which the terms of any contract with bondholders, bonds may be amended; (11) limitations on the amount of moneys derived from the educational program to be expended for operating, administrative or other expenses of the Authority; (12) defining the acts or omissions to act which shall constitute a default in the duties of the Authority to holders of its obligations and providing the rights and remedies of such holders in the event of default; (13) the duties, obligations and liabilities of any trustee or paying agent; and (14) providing for guarantees, pledges of endowments, letters of credit, property or other security for the benefit of the holders of such bonds or notes; and (15) any other matters relating to the bonds or notes which the Authority deems desirable.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Neither the members of the Authority nor any person executing the revenue bonds or notes shall be liable personally on the revenue bonds or notes or be subject to any personal liability or accountability by reason of the issuance thereof.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The Authority shall have power out of any funds available therefor to purchase its bonds or notes. The Authority may hold, pledge, cancel or resell such bonds or notes subject to and in accordance with agreements with bondholders.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>