<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11D</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration Of Dieticians And Nutritionists</catch_line>
    <order_by>11D</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be within the division of professional licensure a board of registration of dietitians and nutritionists to be appointed by the governor, who in his discretion may seek the advice of the Massachusetts nutrition board, as established under section 181 of chapter 6, to consist of nine members who are citizens of the commonwealth, four of whom shall be licensed dietitians/nutritionists who are registered dietitians with the Commission on Dietetic Registration of the American Dietetic Association, one of whom shall be a licensed dietitian/nutritionist with a baccalaureate degree, one of whom shall be a licensed dietitian/nutritionist with a doctoral degree, one of whom shall be an educator from an accredited nutrition program in Massachusetts, and two of whom shall be consumers who are representatives of the general public. Of the first board appointed by the governor non-public members shall be registered dietitians or nutritionists with seven years of paid professional experience in the practice of dietetics. 
Members shall be appointed for a term of three years, except that of the members of the first board, three members shall be appointed for terms of one year, three members shall be appointed for terms of two years, and three members shall be appointed for terms of three years. No member shall be appointed to more than two consecutive full terms; provided, however, that a member appointed for less than a full term may serve two full terms in addition to such part of a full term, and a former member shall again be eligible for appointment after a lapse of one or more years. Any member of the board may be removed by the governor for neglect of duty, misconduct or malfeasance or misfeasance in office after being given a written statement of the charges against him and sufficient opportunity to be heard thereon. 
Said board shall elect its chairperson annually and shall meet at the call of such chairperson or upon the request of four or more members of the board. A quorum shall consist of at least five members present. Said chairperson shall only vote on board matters in the case of a tie. Board members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual and reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. The board shall meet at least four times annually.
    </text>
</law>