<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Creation; Secretary; Acting Secretary; Undersecretary</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be an executive office of energy and environmental affairs, hereinafter called the office, which shall be under the supervision of a secretary of energy and environmental affairs, hereinafter called the secretary. Said secretary shall be appointed by the governor and shall be a person of skill and experience in the field of environmental affairs. Said secretary shall serve at the pleasure of the governor, shall receive such salary as may be determined by law, and shall devote full time to the duties of his office. 
In the case of a vacancy in the office of secretary, or in the case of disability, as determined by the governor, or in his absence, the governor may designate an acting secretary to serve as secretary until the vacancy is filled or the absence, or disability, as determined by the governor, ceases. The acting secretary shall have all the powers and duties of the secretary and shall have similar qualifications as the secretary. 
The secretary shall, with the approval of the governor, appoint and may remove, an undersecretary of the executive office, hereinafter called the undersecretary. Said undersecretary shall be a person of skill and experience in the fields of administration and environmental affairs, and shall perform such duties as may be assigned by the secretary. The position of undersecretary shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter thirty-one or section nine A of chapter thirty. Said undersecretary shall receive such salary as may be determined by law and shall devote full time during business hours to the duties of his office.
    </text>
</law>