<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>First Deputy Commissioner</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The commissioner may, with the consent of the governor, appoint a first deputy commissioner of administration who shall also serve as undersecretary. Said first deputy commissioner shall be a person of ability and experience; shall serve at the pleasure of the commissioner; shall receive such salary as the commissioner, with the approval of the governor, shall determine, and, shall devote his entire time to the duties of his office. He shall exercise such authority and discharge such duties of the commissioner as the commissioner may from time to time delegate to him; and in the absence or incapacity of the commissioner or in the event of a vacancy in the position of the commissioner, the said first deputy commissioner shall act as the commissioner until the absence or incapacity shall have terminated or the vacancy shall have been filled.
Chapter 7: First deputy commissioner of administration
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 43 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The secretary may, with the consent of the governor, appoint a first deputy commissioner of administration who shall also serve as undersecretary. The first deputy commissioner shall be a person of ability and experience; shall serve at the pleasure of the secretary; shall receive such salary as the secretary, with the approval of the governor, shall determine, and, shall devote the first deputy commissioner's entire time to the duties of the first deputy commissioner's office. The first deputy commissioner shall exercise such authority and discharge such duties of the secretary as the secretary may delegate to the first deputy commissioner; and in the absence or incapacity of the secretary or in the event of a vacancy in the position of the secretary, the said first deputy commissioner shall act as the secretary until the absence or incapacity shall have terminated or the vacancy shall have been filled.
    </text>
</law>