<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12A" order_by="12A" level="3">Office Of Inspector General</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Inspection Of Records And Papers; Investigations; Summons</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        The inspector general in carrying out the provisions of this chapter shall have access to all records, reports, audits, reviews, papers, books, documents, recommendations, correspondence, including information relative to the purchase of services or anticipated purchase of services from any contractor by any public body, and any other data and material that is maintained by or available to any public body described in section seven which in any way relate to the programs and operations with respect to which the inspector general has duties and responsibilities except records under the provisions of section eighteen of chapter sixty-six as defined in section three of said chapter sixty-six. 
He may request such information, cooperation and assistance from any state, county or local governmental agency as may be necessary for carrying out his duties and responsibilities. Upon receipt of such request each person in charge of, or the governing body of any public body described in section seven, shall furnish to the inspector general or his authorized agent or representative such information, cooperation and assistance, including information relative to the purchase of services or anticipated purchase of services from any contractor by any public body, except records under the provisions of section eighteen of chapter sixty-six as defined in section three of said chapter sixty-six. 
He may make such investigations, audits and reports relating to the administration of the programs and operations of the applicable public bodies described in section seven, as are in the judgment of the inspector general necessary and may conduct an examination of any public documents. 
He shall have direct and prompt access to the head of any public body described in section seven, when necessary for any purpose pertaining to the performance of his duties and responsibilities under this chapter. 
He may request the production, on a voluntary basis, of testimony or documents from any individual firm or non-governmental entity which relate to his duties and responsibilities. 
The inspector general may require by summons, the production of all records, reports, audits, reviews, papers, books, documents, recommendations, correspondence and any other data and material relevant to any matter under audit or investigation pursuant to the provisions of this chapter except records under the provisions of section eighteen of chapter sixty-six as defined in section three of said chapter sixty-six. 
Such summons shall be served in the same manner as a summons for the production of documents in civil cases issued on behalf of the commonwealth, and all provisions of law relative to said summons shall apply to a summons issued pursuant to this chapter. Any justice of the superior court department in the trial court may, upon application by the inspector general, issue an order to compel the production of records, reports, audits, reviews, papers, books, documents, recommendations, correspondence and any other data and material as aforesaid in the same manner and to the same extent as before said superior court department. Any failure to obey such order may be punished by said court as contempt. 
Any summons issued pursuant to this section shall not be made public by the inspector general or any officer or employee of his department, nor shall any documents provided pursuant to this section be made public until such time as it is necessary for the inspector general to do so in the performance of his duties. The production of such books and papers pursuant to summons shall be governed by the same provisions with reference to secrecy which govern proceedings of a grand jury. Disclosure of such production, attendance, and testimony may be made to such members of the staff of the office of inspector general as is deemed necessary by the inspector general to assist him in the performance of his duties and responsibilities under this chapter and such members of the staff may be present at the production of records.
    </text>
</law>