<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>60</section_number>
    <catch_line>Unified Certification Program Trust Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>60</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 68, Sec. 19 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221.]  (a) There shall be established a separate account to be known as the Unified Certification Program Trust Fund, in this section called the fund. The state purchasing agent shall expend funds, without further appropriation, exclusively for the operation of the unified certification program.  (b) Funds received from the federal government by the following state and regional authorities and municipal and regional airports, in this section collectively referred to as the participants, and any others that take part in the unified certification program, for the purpose of operating the unified certification program, shall be deposited in the fund: the Massachusetts Department of Transportation, the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority, the Massachusetts Port Authority, the Berkshire Regional Transit Authority, the Brockton Area Transit Authority, the Cape Cod Regional Transit Authority, the Greater Attleboro-Taunton Regional Transit Authority, the Lowell Regional Transit Authority, the Merrimack Valley Regional Transit Authority, the Montachusett Regional Transit Authority, the Pioneer Valley Regional Transit Authority, the Southeastern Regional Transit Authority, the Worcester Regional Transit Authority, Barnstable Municipal Airport, Martha's Vineyard Airport, Nantucket Memorial Airport and New Bedford Regional Airport. The methodology used in determining the allocation of payments due from each participant shall be determined pursuant to a formula, subject to modification from time to time, that is established by and between the Massachusetts Department of Transportation, the participants and the United States Department of Transportation, consistent with applicable federal laws and regulations.
    </text>
</law>