<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23E" order_by="23E" level="3">Division Of Industrial Accidents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Fraud Investigations;  Right To Request And Receive Information</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  For the purpose of investigating fraud and collecting data regarding workplace injuries, the department shall have the right to request and receive information from the department of revenue, the division of employment and training, the registry of motor vehicles, the department of welfare, the insurance fraud bureau of Massachusetts, the workers' compensation rating and inspection bureau, and individual insurers, self-insurers and self-insurance groups and shall forward information regarding fraudulent activities to these entities. Such information shall be provided within thirty days unless otherwise authorized by the commissioner. The division of administration shall document evidence of any fraudulent activity and promptly refer such documentation to the office of the attorney general.
Chapter 23E: Fraud investigations; right to request and receive information
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 64 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  For the purpose of investigating fraud and collecting data regarding workplace injuries, the department shall have the right to request and receive information from the department of revenue, the department of unemployment assistance, and the department of career services, the registry of motor vehicles, the department of welfare, the insurance fraud bureau of Massachusetts, the workers' compensation rating and inspection bureau, and individual insurers, self-insurers and self-insurance groups and shall forward information regarding fraudulent activities to these entities. Such information shall be provided within thirty days unless otherwise authorized by the commissioner. The division of administration shall document evidence of any fraudulent activity and promptly refer such documentation to the office of the attorney general.
    </text>
</law>