<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23E" order_by="23E" level="3">Division Of Industrial Accidents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commissioner Of Industrial Accidents;  Appointment;  Term;  Salary</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  There shall be a division of industrial accidents, hereinafter referred to as the department under the supervision and control of a commissioner of industrial accidents, hereinafter in this chapter and in chapter one hundred and fifty-two, called the commissioner. The governor shall appoint the commissioner to serve for a term coterminous with that of the governor. Upon the expiration of the term of office of the commissioner, he may be reappointed by the governor. The position of commissioner shall be classified in accordance with section forty-five of chapter thirty and the salary shall be determined in accordance with section forty-six C of said chapter thirty. The commissioner shall devote his full time to the duties of his office and shall not engage in other employment or business activities during regular business hours.
Chapter 23E: Director of industrial accidents; appointment; term; salary
[ Text of section as amended by 2011, 3, Secs. 56 and 57 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  There shall be a department of industrial accidents, hereinafter referred to as the department under the supervision and control of a director of industrial accidents, hereinafter in this chapter and in chapter one hundred and fifty-two, called the director. The governor shall appoint the director to serve for a term coterminous with that of the governor. Upon the expiration of the term of office of the director, he may be reappointed by the governor. The position of director shall be classified in accordance with section forty-five of chapter thirty and the salary shall be determined in accordance with section forty-six C of said chapter thirty. The director shall devote his full time to the duties of his office and shall not engage in other employment or business activities during regular business hours.
    </text>
</law>