<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>163</section_number>
    <catch_line>Management Engineering Task Force</catch_line>
    <order_by>163</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board to be known as the Management Engineering Task Force to consist of not more than forty-five members, the number of which shall vary from time to time based on the magnitude of the work and number of departments to be surveyed as determined by the governor. Said members shall be representatives of the business and professional community of the commonwealth and shall be appointed annually by the governor for terms of one year. Said board shall make survey reports and recommendations on the operation of those departments, divisions and agencies of the commonwealth as the governor shall designate, shall study the management techniques and procedures used by the commonwealth and recommend any changes which improve the utilization of manpower and eliminate inefficiency and waste and shall make such other studies as it may deem to be in the best interest of the commonwealth. 
Said board shall make its reports and recommendations to the secretary of the executive office which includes the departments, divisions and agencies of the commonwealth surveyed by such board, on or before October the thirtieth of each year. The secretary shall report to the governor on the findings of said task force, together with his recommendations on those findings, by the fourth Wednesday in December, and shall file copies thereof with the clerk of the house of representatives and the clerk of the senate.
    </text>
</law>