<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23" level="3">Executive Office Of Labor And Workforce Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11H</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>11H</order_by>
    <text>
          As used in this chapter the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meaning:--  "Apprentice'', a person at least 16 years of age who has entered an apprentice agreement with an employer, or an association of employers, or an organization of employees, or other apprentice program sponsor.  "Apprentice agreement'', a written agreement between an apprentice and an apprentice program sponsor which is registered with the division and which provides for not less than 2,000 hours of reasonably continuous employment, consistent with training requirements as established by industry practice, in the occupation to which he is apprenticed. The written agreement shall also provide for not less than 150 hours per year of related instruction for a person in the occupation to which he is apprenticed, as well as participation in an approved schedule of work experience throughout a reasonably continuous period of employment.  "Apprenticeable occupation'', a skilled trade which: (1) is customarily learned in a practical way through a structured, systemic program of on-the-job supervised training; (2) is clearly identified and commonly recognized through an industry; (3) involves manual, mechanical or technical skills and knowledge which require a minimum of 2,000 hours of on-the-job work experience; and (4) requires related training to supplement the on-the-job training.  "Apprentice program'', a program which is registered with the division for the recruitment, selection, employment, training and qualification of apprentices.  "Apprentice program sponsor'', a person, association, committee, organization, corporation, partnership, trust or other entity operating an apprentice program and in whose name the program is registered with the division.  "Deputy director'', the deputy director of apprentice training.[ Definition of "Director'' effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  "Director'', the director of workforce development.[ Definition of "Director'' as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 51 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  "Director'', the director of the department of labor standards.[ Definition of "Division'' effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  "Division'', the division of apprentice training in the department of workforce development.[ Definition of "Division'' as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 51 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  "Division'', the division of apprentice training in the department of labor standards.[ Definition of "Proctor'' added by 2010, 468, Sec. 1 effective April 14, 2011.]  "Proctor'', an instructor approved by the division or a person competent in an apprentice's trade or occupation including, but not limited to, a journey worker.
    </text>
</law>