<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>39C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Capital Facility Projects;  Coordination;  Clearinghouse</catch_line>
    <order_by>39C</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. Repealed by 2012, 165, Sec. 66. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  The commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall advise the governor and the commissioner of administration on the means and methods available to coordinate capital facility project plans and programs of all public agencies and the federal government in order to establish relative priorities and to avoid duplication and conflicts. He shall create a central depository for planning documents as they relate to that end, and amendments thereto and revisions thereof prepared by or for public agencies. Effective on the effective date of this act, every public agency shall submit a list and description of such documents as currently exist and as they are promulgated and upon the commissioner's request, submit to him a copy thereof. The commissioner may by rule and regulation identify the documents required to be submitted.  The division of capital asset management and maintenance, if it is not designated as the state clearinghouse as provided for by the federal Intergovernmental Cooperation Act of nineteen hundred and sixty-eight, as amended, and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, shall be notified in a timely manner by the agency designated as the state clearinghouse as to any capital facility projects being reviewed by said agency. The commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall review such projects in light of current long range capital facility plans and other programs and policies of the commonwealth and submit his comments and recommendations to the agency designated as the state clearinghouse.
    </text>
</law>