<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23B" order_by="23B" level="3">Department Of Housing And Community Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Urban Job Incentive Bureau; Programs</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be in the Massachusetts office of business development an urban job incentive bureau. The bureau shall initiate, organize, develop and coordinate a statewide manpower employment assistance and training program designed to enlarge and improve the skills of the work force, especially those within urban areas containing sections of substantial poverty. 
In the development of such a manpower program, the bureau shall coordinate with all existing state agencies including, but not limited to, the division of apprentice training in the department of labor and workforce development, the bureau of vocational education in the department of education and the rehabilitation commission, and with all individual or agency manpower and training programs sponsored, directed or funded by the federal government operating within the commonwealth. The bureau shall keep an inventory of all such programs and make an evaluation of their applicability to persons from sections of substantial poverty and the numbers of persons placed in employment during and immediately after the completion of each respective program. It shall, from time to time, determine and designate eligible sections of substantial poverty and it shall approve and certify the training or assistance programs which are to be utilized or undertaken by an eligible business facility. 
In addition, it shall submit to the governor and the general court on or before the first Wednesday in December, nineteen hundred and seventy-one, and on an annual basis thereafter, a recommended program for improving state manpower development programs, especially in urban areas containing sections of substantial poverty. In developing such a program, it shall consider, but not be limited to, the advisability and feasibility of adopting or assisting in the adoption of new or more practical methods of vocational training and guidance, rehabilitation methods, special transportation opportunities, training allowances, support for special recruitment by existing agencies and other means of further involving private and public employers in employing persons from areas containing sections of substantial poverty.
    </text>
</law>