<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="25" order_by="25" level="3">Department Of Public Utilities</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commonwealth Utilities Commission; Membership; Appointment And Terms;  Chairman; Quorum; Salaries; Annual Report</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        The department shall be under the supervision and control of the commonwealth utilities commission, in this chapter called the commission, which shall consist of 3 members, 2 of whom shall be appointed and may be removed by the secretary of energy and environmental affairs for a term coterminous with that of the governor. The third member shall be appointed and may be removed by the secretary for a term of 4 years. The secretary shall designate one commissioner as chairman, who shall serve as chairman for 2 years, and may be reappointed, unless removed as chairman by the secretary, with the approval of the governor. Commission members shall have background or expertise in electricity or natural gas matters. Any appointment or removal by the secretary under this section shall require the approval of the governor. The commissioners shall devote their full time to the duties of their office. Not more than 2 members of the commission shall be members of the same political party. Any decision made or order issued by the commission may be made by majority vote of a quorum of 2 members. 
The initial base salary of the chairman of the commission shall be $90,000, and the initial base salary of the other members shall be $82,500. Said salaries shall be subject to step increases consistent with the provisions of sections 45 and 46C of chapter 30. The members shall receive necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of their official duties. 
The commission shall make an annual report of its activities in January of each year to the general court.
    </text>
</law>