<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="19A" order_by="19A" level="3">Department Of Elder Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Home Care Program; Needs And Services Of Adult Handicapped; Powers And Duties Of Secretary</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     to provide assistance to communities in solving local problems with regard to elderly persons including, but not limited to, problems in identifying and coordinating local resources to serve the needs of elderly persons;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     to facilitate communications and the free flow of information between communities and the offices, agencies, and employees of the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     to encourage and assist communities to plan, develop and implement home care programs which shall be operated either by agencies organized by the commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof or by nonprofit corporations organized under chapter one hundred and eighty and which shall be designated by the department. Any hospital or nursing home licensed by the department of public health pursuant to the provisions of chapter one hundred and eleven shall not be eligible to operate home care programs under this chapter. A majority of the governing body of the aforesaid home care providers shall be persons sixty years of age or older who reside in the cities or towns served by said provider. A majority of the governing body of the aforesaid home care providers, except those serving the city of Boston, shall be appointed by the councils on aging of the cities and towns served by said provider.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     to provide and act as a clearinghouse for information, data, and other materials relative to elderly persons;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     to initiate and carry out studies and analyses which will aid in solving local, regional, and statewide problems concerning elderly persons;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     to coordinate through advice and counsel those programs of other state agencies designed to assist in the solution of local, regional, and statewide problems concerning elderly persons;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     to advise and inform the governor on the affairs and problems of elderly persons in the commonwealth;
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     to exercise the powers and discharge the duties assigned to him in the fields of health care, housing, nutrition, homemaker services, economic opportunity, local and regional planning, transportation, and education and preretirement programs;
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     to further the cooperation of local, state, and federal and private agencies and institutions providing for services or having responsibility for elderly persons;
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     to represent and act on behalf of the commonwealth in connection with federal grant programs applicable to programs for elderly persons in the functional areas described in this section;
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     to seek, accept, and otherwise take advantage of all federal aid available to the department, and to assist other agencies of the commonwealth, local agencies, and community groups in taking advantage of all federal grants and subventions available for elderly persons;
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     to render advice and assistance to communities and other groups in the preparation and submission of grant applications to state and federal agencies relative to programs for elderly persons;
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     to review and coordinate those activities of agencies of the commonwealth and of any political subdivision of the commonwealth at the request of such subdivision, which affect the full and fair utilization of community resources for programs for elderly persons, and initiate programs that will help assure such utilization;
        </section>
        <section prefix="n">
    	     to encourage the formation of councils on aging and to assist local communities in the development of said councils.
        </section>
        <section prefix="o">
    	     to conduct yearly studies and evaluations pertaining to the quality of care and social services for nursing home patients and report such findings and recommendations to the general court.
        </section>
        <section prefix="p">
    	     to establish a corps of elder volunteers in each planning and service area, as designated by the department pursuant to 42 USC Sec. 3025, the purpose of which shall be to provide visiting services to the residents of nursing homes within such area.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>