<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>27</section_number>
    <catch_line>Issuance Of Credit By Gaming Licensee To Patron Of A Gaming Establishment</catch_line>
    <order_by>27</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) A gaming licensee may issue credit to a patron of a gaming establishment in accordance with regulations promulgated by the commission. Such regulations shall include, but not be limited to: (i) procedures for confirming that a patron has an established credit history and is in good standing; (ii) whether the patron has a good credit history with the gaming establishment; (iii) authorization of any credit instrument; (iv) methods for acknowledging a credit instrument and payment of debt; and (v) information to be provided by the patron to the gaming establishment to be shared with the commission for auditing purposes.  (b) Except as otherwise authorized by the commission through regulations under this chapter, no gaming establishment, nor any person acting on behalf of the gaming establishment, shall cash any check, make any loan or otherwise provide or allow to any person any credit or advance of anything of value, or which represents value, to enable that person to place a wager, or release or discharge any debt, either in whole or in part, or make any loan which represents any losses incurred by a player in gaming or simulcast wagering activity, without maintaining a written record of the release or discharge in accordance with the rules of the commission. Nothing in this section shall prohibit a gaming establishment from accepting credit cards for non-gaming-related purchases or services.  (c) Checks cashed in conformity with this section shall be valid instruments enforceable under the laws of the commonwealth. Any check cashed, transferred, conveyed or given in violation of this section or regulations promulgated hereunder shall be invalid and unenforceable.  (d) The commission shall establish procedures and standards for approving promotional gaming credits; provided, however, that no such credit shall be reported as a promotional gaming credit by an operator of a gaming establishment unless the operator can establish that the credit was issued by the gaming establishment and received from a patron as a wager at a slot machine in the gaming establishment.  (e) No person, other than a gaming licensee, shall issue credit to a patron in a gaming establishment.  (f) The commission shall, in consultation with the department of transitional assistance, the department of labor and workforce development, the department of housing and community development or the applicable administering agency, establish by regulation procedures and standards to prohibit a gaming establishment or any person acting on behalf of a gaming establishment from: (i) cashing a government-issued check; (ii) from operating on its premises any credit card or automated teller machine that would allow a patron to obtain cash from a government-issued electronic benefits transfer card; and (iii) from extending or issuing credit to a patron of a gaming establishment who receives any form of income-based public assistance including, but not limited to, the supplemental nutrition assistance program, temporary assistance for needy families, emergency aid to elders, disabled and children, public housing assistance, MassHealth and unemployment insurance. The procedures and standards established shall ensure the privacy of all patrons receiving public assistance.  (g) A person may petition the commission to place the person's name on a list of persons to whom the extension of credit by a gaming establishment shall be prohibited. Any person filing such petition shall submit to the commission the person's name, address and date of birth. The person shall not be required to provide a reason for the request. The commission shall provide this list to the credit department of each gaming establishment; provided, however, that neither the commission nor the credit department of a gaming establishment shall divulge the names on this list to any person or entity other than those provided for in this subsection. If such a person wishes to have their name removed from the list, the person shall petition the commission in accordance with procedures for removal set forth by the commission. If the commission approves the request, the commission shall so inform the credit department of the gaming establishments not later than 7 days after approving the request.  (h) Debt collections under this section and regulations promulgated thereunder shall be limited to key gaming employees or attorneys acting directly on behalf of gaming licensees; provided, however, that a key gaming employee shall not make any such collections if that employee serves as a junket representative for the gaming licensee.
    </text>
</law>