<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21J" order_by="21J" level="3">Underground Storage Tank Petroleum Product Cleanup Fund</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Cleanup Fund Purpose; Limitations On Use Of Fund Monies; Powers Of Cleanup Fund Administrative Review Board; Grant Amounts</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Reimbursement for the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Reimbursement of costs, expenses, and other obligations incurred by an owner or operator described in clauses (1) or (5) of paragraph (a) of section five of chapter twenty-one E as a result of taking a response action, as that term is defined in chapter twenty-one E, in response to, or otherwise incurring expenses as a result of, a release, as that term is defined in chapter twenty-one E, of petroleum product from an underground storage tank or underground storage tank system.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Reimbursement for any claims for bodily injury, property damage, and damage to natural resources which are assessed against an owner or operator described in clauses (1) or (5) of paragraph (a) of section five of chapter twenty-one E as a result of a release, as that term is defined in chapter twenty-one E, of petroleum product from an underground storage tank or underground storage tank system.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     Administrative expenses, personnel expenses, and miscellaneous expenses incurred by the following agencies in the course implementing this chapter, provided, however, that the amount dispensed for each agency for each year shall not exceed the limits provided for herein.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Subject to appropriation, effective for fiscal years beginning on and after July 1, 1992, the limits shall be either the minimum amounts specified below or those greater amounts as set in the manner described below:
        </section>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     The minimum amounts shall be as follows:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     for the board, $800,000;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     for the department, $200,000; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     for the department of environmental protection and the department of fire services underground storage tank compliance, $450,000.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Subject to appropriation, the board may, by a two-thirds vote of those members present and voting, increase any of the amounts specified in clauses (1) or (2), but only to the extent such increase is necessary to allow the board or the departments in question to do the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     Set standards for the proper construction, maintenance, and testing of underground storage tanks and underground storage tank systems.
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     Collect all the fees, penalties, and interest prescribed pursuant to this chapter, account for all the monies thus collected, and take appropriate action against those who do not pay all that they owe or do not comply with all requirements applicable to them for the payment of such monies.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     Adopt and amend from time to time the rules and regulations specified in section eight.
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     Implement and enforce the rules and regulations specified in section eight.
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     Initiate, defend, and otherwise be parties to judicial proceedings pursuant to this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     Take all other action appropriate to effectuate this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Grants provided pursuant to section thirty-seven A of chapter one hundred and forty-eight, not to exceed, subject to appropriation, two million dollars per year; provided, that the board may establish priorities for the allocation of said amount among the various entities and purposes as provided in said section thirty-seven A, in the event that the aggregate amount of funds requested in qualified applications for such grants exceeds said amount:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Effective for fiscal years beginning on and after July 1, 1992, not more than two million dollars per year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Effective through June 30, 1992, not more than seven percent of the total amount of fees, penalties, and interest collected pursuant to this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     Grants to the department of environmental protection to reimburse said department for the costs it incurs in the course of responding, as that term is defined in chapter twenty-one E, to releases, as that term is defined in chapter twenty-one E, of petroleum product from an underground storage tank or underground storage tank system for which previous payments under
        </section>
    </text>
</law>