<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="25B" order_by="25B" level="3">Massachusetts Appliance Efficiency Standards Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7</section_number>
    <catch_line>Certification Of Compliance; Labeling Products To Connote Compliance With Efficiency Requirements Of Chapter</catch_line>
    <order_by>7</order_by>
    <text>
        Manufacturers of appliances and lamps covered by this chapter shall certify to the commissioner that such appliances and lamps are in compliance with the provisions of this chapter. The commissioner shall promulgate regulations governing the certification of appliances and lamps covered by this chapter and shall publish an annual list of such appliances and lamps. Manufacturers’ certifications shall be based on test results. The commissioner shall coordinate with the certification programs of other states and federal agencies with similar standards to the maximum extent practicable, including investigating whether certification in another state can serve as a substitute for certification in the commonwealth. Single voltage external AC to DC power supplies shall be exempt from the requirements of this section. 
Manufacturers of new products covered by section 3 shall identify each product offered for sale or installed in the state as in compliance with this chapter by means of a mark, label or tag on the product and packaging at the time of sale or installation. The commissioner shall promulgate regulations governing the identification of such products and packaging, which shall be coordinated to the greatest practical extent with the labeling programs of other states and federal agencies with equivalent efficiency standards. The commissioner shall allow the use of existing marks, labels or tags which connote compliance with the efficiency requirements of this chapter. State regulated incandescent reflector lamps and metal halide lamp fixtures shall be exempt from the requirements of this paragraph. The commissioner, in consultation with other states, product manufacturers and other interested parties, shall study and evaluate the usefulness and effectiveness of such markings for incandescent reflector lamps and metal halide lamp fixtures.
    </text>
</law>