<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="15A" order_by="15A" level="3">Public Education</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>16</section_number>
    <catch_line>Scholarship Programs; Guidelines</catch_line>
    <order_by>16</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a general scholarship program administered by the council for the purpose of providing financial assistance to students domiciled in the commonwealth and enrolled in and pursuing a program of higher education in any approved public or independent college, university or school of nursing, or any other approved institution furnishing a program of higher education. Such aid and assistance shall consist of awarding of full or partial scholarships to worthy and qualified students in need of financial assistance. 
The amount of awards to qualified students shall be determined by using an indexing system which shall be included in the guidelines established by the council to govern this program. The council shall file a report of current year general scholarship program expenditures, appropriations needed to fund full need for all students, and projections of general scholarship expenditures for the following year by family contribution ranges and independent student contribution ranges. Said report shall be filed with the clerk of the house and senate no later than the end of each calendar year. 
There shall be a Christian A. Herter Memorial Scholarship Program which authorizes the council to guarantee the payment of full or partial scholarships to no more than twenty-five students annually of extraordinary need and ability selected in tenth or eleventh grades by persons or agencies designated by said council under such regulations as the council shall deem necessary. These awards shall be guaranteed to the student at the time of the student’s selection; provided however, that said student successfully completes high school and is enrolled in and pursuing a program of higher education in any approved public or independent college, scientific or technical institution, or any other approved institution furnishing a program of higher education, and shall be payable from the general scholarship funds at the time of the student’s matriculation. 
There shall be a program, administered by the council, providing for the matching of scholarship grants to participating Massachusetts independent regionally accredited colleges, universities and schools of nursing; provided, that the council shall establish policies and regulations relating to the program, including an audit procedure to insure that institutions are in compliance with such policies and regulations; provided, further, that a participating institution shall be eligible to receive an amount equal to such institution’s expenditure for scholarship aid to needy Massachusetts undergraduate students enrolled in such institutions as full-time matriculating students in a course of study leading to an associate or bachelor degree; provided further, that each participating institution shall agree to expend an amount equal to one hundred percent of the grant awarded hereunder in direct financial assistance to the needy Massachusetts students; provided further, that each participating institution shall agree to comply with the information requests of the council in accordance with this chapter. 
There shall be a Christa McAuliffe Teacher Incentive Program for the purpose of providing financial assistance for undergraduate and graduate students in approved institutions of higher education within the commonwealth who agree to teach on a full time basis within a public education system located in the commonwealth. The council shall institute and maintain learning contracts for all students admitted in the teacher incentive program, which shall include provisions for “payback” service for a period commencing after such students have fulfilled all graduation requirements, or for repayment to the commonwealth of the full amount of such grants on terms established by said council. Said council shall establish guidelines governing said program which shall include but not be limited to eligibility requirements, selection criteria, and period of time which must be spent teaching in the commonwealth. 
There shall be a part-time student grant program to provide assistance to part-time undergraduate students attending approved institutions of higher education within the commonwealth who have demonstrated financial need. The council shall establish guidelines governing said program. 
The council may award full or partial scholarships to worthy and qualified students who have been residents of the commonwealth for a period of four years immediately prior to receiving such award and who are in need of financial assistance in order to pursue graduate studies. The council shall award scholarships and notify all applicants on or before July first in each year. No scholarship may be awarded for more than five years to any one student. The council may expend such sums as may be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this paragraph. The council shall establish guidelines governing said program which shall include but not be limited to eligibility requirements and selection criteria. 
There shall be a Council Grant for Campus-based Assistance Program for adult learners and work study opportunities. Participating approved institutions of higher education within Massachusetts shall receive an allocation from the council to provide grant or work study assistance to eligible students with demonstrated financial need. The council shall establish guidelines to govern this program which shall insure that those students receiving assistance include part-time students, graduate students and adult learners. 
There shall be a Public Service Scholarship Program to provide scholarships to children and widowed spouses of Massachusetts police officers, firefighters and correction officers, who are killed or die from injuries received while in the performance of duties including authorized training duty; to children of prisoners of war or military or service persons missing in action in Southeast Asia whose wartime service is credited to the commonwealth and whose service was between February first, nineteen hundred and fifty-five, and the termination of the Vietnam campaign; and to the children of veterans whose service was credited to the commonwealth and who were killed in action or otherwise died as a result of such service. Such scholarships shall be awarded by the council pursuant to its guidelines established to govern this program and shall go to those persons referenced above who are admitted to an institution of higher education in the commonwealth to pursue undergraduate studies. The guidelines shall include, but not be limited to, a waiver of mandatory fees. 
There shall be a dedicated grant program for undergraduate students enrolled at an approved institution of higher education within the commonwealth. The council shall establish guidelines to govern said program. 
There shall be a consortium scholarship program for undergraduate students to pursue programs that are not currently offered by public institutions of higher education within the commonwealth. The council shall establish guidelines to govern said program. 
Any student receiving financial assistance under any program listed above shall maintain satisfactory academic progress in order to continue to receive such assistance. Each institution which recipients attend shall maintain documentation of each recipient’s academic standing and provide requested documentation to the council in accordance with guidelines promulgated by the council. 
All programs of financial assistance above shall be subject to appropriation. 
Any institution of higher education participating in any of the programs set forth above shall annually execute a participating agreement for each such program and place such contracts on file with the council’s scholarship office. 
When applicable federal law requires, each applicant for assistance under any program established herein shall provide appropriate documentation to verify his compliance with the Military Selective Service Act in effect at the time of such application. 
With the exception of the public service scholarship program grants, all financial assistance provided for in this section shall be based on ability to pay, as provided for in guidelines promulgated by the council. 
Upon adoption by the council of guidelines promulgated pursuant to the provisions of this section, said council shall file a copy thereof with the secretary of administration and finance, and with the clerk of the house of representatives, who shall refer such guidelines to the joint committee on education, arts and humanities, and the house and senate ways and means committees.
    </text>
</law>