<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24</section_number>
    <catch_line>Applicants Holding Live Racing License Under Chapter 128 A;  Number Of Live Racing Days;  Annual Purse Agreements</catch_line>
    <order_by>24</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) An applicant for a gaming license who holds a live racing license under chapter 128A shall maintain an existing racing facility on the premises; provided, however, that the gaming licensee shall increase the number of live racing days to a minimum of 125 days according to the following schedule: (i) in the first calendar year of operation, a gaming licensee shall hold 105 racing days; (ii) in the second calendar year of operation, a gaming licensee shall hold 115 racing days; and (iii) in the third and subsequent calendar years of operation, a gaming licensee shall hold 125 racing days;  (b) A gaming licensee may increase the number of live racing days if the gaming licensee is holding a minimum of 125 racing days within 3 years of receiving a gaming license. If a gaming licensee does not conduct live racing for the minimum number of days set forth in subsection (a), the commission shall suspend the gaming license.  (c) After 3 years of operation of the gaming establishment and in consultation with the parties to the purse agreement, the commission may adjust the amount of required racing days at a gaming establishment based on fields, demand and racing performance.  (d) A gaming licensee with a live racetrack shall have an annual purse agreement in effect by December 31 of each year for the following year's racing; provided, however, that if the parties to a purse agreement at a gaming establishment cannot in good faith negotiate an agreement by December 31, the purse agreement shall be arbitrated by the commission.
    </text>
</law>