<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="25A" order_by="25A" level="3">Division Of Energy Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11I</section_number>
    <catch_line>Energy Management Services Contracts; Request For Qualifications; Regulations; Payments; Performance Bond</catch_line>
    <order_by>11I</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     A state agency, local governmental body or building authority may use this section in the procurement of energy management services as an alternative to the procedures in section 11C. Nothing in this section shall preclude any such agency, body or authority from proceeding under section 11C.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     An agency, local governmental body or building authority may enter into an energy management services contract in order to achieve energy savings at facilities in accordance with this section. All energy savings measures under the contract shall comply with current local, state and federal construction and environmental codes and regulations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     Before entering into an energy management services contract, a state agency, local governmental body or building authority shall issue a request for qualifications. Public notice of the request for qualifications shall conform to the procedures set forth in subsection (1) of section 44J of chapter 149. At least 1 week before soliciting a request for qualifications for an energy management services contract, an agency, body or authority body shall notify the commissioner in writing, in a form and including information as the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall prescribe by regulation, of the entity’s intent to solicit qualifications. The notification, at a minimum, shall include a copy of the request for qualifications. An acknowledgment of receipt, in a form and including information as the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall prescribe by regulation, shall be issued by the commissioner to the agency, body or authority upon compliance with the requirements of this subsection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     references of other energy savings contracts performed by the qualified providers;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     the certificate of eligibility and update statement provided by the qualified providers;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     quality of the products proposed;
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     methodology of determining energy savings;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     general reputation and performance capabilities of the qualified providers;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     substantial conformity with the specifications and other conditions set forth in the request for qualifications;
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     time specified in the qualifications for the performance of the contract; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     any other factors the agency, body, or authority considers reasonable and appropriate, which factors shall be made a matter of record.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The state agency, local governmental body or building authority may cancel a request for qualifications, or may reject in whole or in part any and all proposals when it determines that cancellation or rejection serves its best interests. The agency, body or authority shall state in writing the reason for a cancellation or rejection.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     The state agency, local governmental body or building authority shall negotiate a contract with the most qualified person at compensation which it determines is fair, competitive and reasonable. If the agency, body or authority is unable to negotiate a satisfactory contract with the person considered to be the most qualified at a price the agency, body or authority determines to be fair, competitive and reasonable, negotiations with that person shall be formally terminated. The agency, body or authority shall then undertake negotiations with the second most qualified person. Failing accord with the second most qualified person, the agency, body or authority shall terminate those negotiations and then undertake negotiations with the third most qualified person. Should the agency, body or authority be unable to negotiate a satisfactory contract with any of the selected persons, it may select additional qualified providers who responded to the request for qualifications, in the order of their competence and qualification, and continue negotiations in accordance with this subsection until either an agreement is reached or the agency, body or authority cancels the request for qualifications.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     The decision of the state agency, local governmental body or building authority regarding the selection of a qualified provider shall be final and not subject to appeal except on the grounds of fraud or collusion.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The state agency, local governmental body or building authority shall provide public notice of the meeting at which it proposes to award the energy management services contract, of the name of the parties to the proposed contract and of the purpose of the contract. The public notice shall be made at least 10 days before the meeting. The agency, body or authority shall promptly publish in the central register notice of the award and shall notify the commissioner of the award and provide to him a copy of the energy management services contract.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     The energy management services contract shall include a written guarantee of the qualified provider that either the amount of energy savings guaranteed shall be achieved or the qualified provider shall reimburse the state agency, local governmental body or building authority for the shortfall amount. Methods for measurement and verification of energy savings shall conform to the most recent standards established by the Federal Energy Management Program of the United States Department of Energy.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance, shall adopt regulations for the procurement of energy management services under this section for local government bodies. The commissioner shall enforce the requirements of this section and regulations adopted as they relate to local governmental bodies and shall have all the necessary powers to require compliance. The commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall adopt regulations for services to be procured for state agencies and building authorities. The commissioner of capital asset management and maintenance shall enforce the regulations as they relate to state agencies and building authorities. An order of the commissioner under this subsection shall be effective and may be enforced according to its terms, and enforcement shall not be suspended or stayed by the entry of an appeal. The superior court for Suffolk county shall have jurisdiction over appeals of orders of the commissioner under this subsection, and shall also have jurisdiction upon application of the commissioner to enforce all orders of the commissioner under this subsection. The burden of proof shall be upon the appealing party to show that an order of the commissioner is invalid. An aggrieved person shall not be required to seek and order from the commission as a condition precedent to seeking any other remedy.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     Payments under a contract for energy management services may be based in whole or in part on any cost savings attributable to a reduction in energy and water consumption due to the contractor’s performance or revenues gained due to the contractor’s services which are aimed at energy and water cost savings.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     Unless no other manner of description suffices, and the state agency, local governmental body or building authority so determines in writing, setting forth the basis for the determination, all requirements shall be written in a manner which describes the requirements to be met without having the effect of exclusively requiring a proprietary supply or service, or a procurement from a sole source.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     Before entering into a energy management services contract, the state agency, local governmental body or building authority shall require the qualified provider to file with the agency, body or authority a payment or a performance bond relating to the installation of energy savings measures in an amount equal to 100 per cent of the estimated contract value from a surety company licensed to do business in the commonwealth and whose name appears on United States Treasury Department Circular 570.
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     An energy management services contract may extend beyond the fiscal year in which it became effective.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>