<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>97</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration Of Home Inspectors; Duties; Informational Brochure On Home Inspections</catch_line>
    <order_by>97</order_by>
    <text>
        Said board shall (i) establish the requirements for licensure and for the standards of professional and ethical conduct; (ii) authorize and conduct appropriate examinations to determine the qualifications of applicants; (iii) grant licenses to qualified applicants; (iv) establish standards for continuing education; and (v) set and administer penalties as defined in section 206 of chapter 112 for fraudulent, deceptive or professionally incompetent and unsafe practices and for violations of rules and regulations promulgated by said board. 
Said board shall make available to the public a list of licensed home inspectors and associate home inspectors. 
Said board shall publish a code of ethics. 
The director of consumer affairs and business regulation, after consultation with the board of registration of home inspectors and the board of registration of real estate brokers and salespersons, shall publish an informational brochure on home inspections which shall be issued to home buyers at the signing of the first written contract to purchase. The brochure shall include a definition of a home inspection such that the nature and extent of a home inspection is made clear to a client or prospective client. The brochure shall also include information regarding inspections for lead paint, radon, and termites and other woodboring insects. The joint committee on government regulations and the house and senate committees on post audit and oversight shall receive a copy of the proposed brochure and shall be provided with an opportunity to comment on it 60 days before the brochure is submitted for publication. 
Said board shall administer the provisions of sections 201 to 206, inclusive, of said chapter 112 and shall promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary to implement the same.
    </text>
</law>