<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>192</section_number>
    <catch_line>Commission For The Deaf And Hard Of Hearing; Creation; Financing;  Agreements; Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>192</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a commission for the deaf and hard of hearing to be known as the Massachusetts commission for the deaf and hard of hearing consisting of a commissioner and an advisory board in this section and sections one hundred and ninety-three to one hundred and ninety-nine, inclusive. 
The commission may apply for and accept on behalf of the commonwealth any federal or local grants to aid in the financing of any programs or policies of the commission. Such funds shall be received by the state treasurer on behalf of the commonwealth and deposited in a special account and may be expended, subject to appropriation. The commission may also apply for and accept on behalf of the commonwealth any private grants, bequests, gifts or contributions to further aid in the financing of programs or policies of the commission. Such funds shall be received by the state treasurer on behalf of the commonwealth and deposited in a special trust account for the commission and may be expended, without further appropriation, under the direction of the commissioner. Such special trust account shall be subject to annual audit by the state auditor. 
The commission may make agreements with other departments and agencies of the commonwealth and may contract with other individuals, organizations, corporations, associations or other legal entities including private agencies, or any other departments or agencies of the federal government, the commonwealth or any political subdivisions thereof, to carry out any of its functions and procedures. 
The commissioner, pursuant to the provisions of chapter thirty A shall make, and from time to time revise, such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the functions of said commission including, but not limited to, eligibility requirements for receipt of various services.
    </text>
</law>