<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="15A" order_by="15A" level="3">Public Education</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Teacher Signing Bonus Program; Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>19B</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     On an annual basis, the department of education shall select the best and brightest teaching prospects based on objective measures such as test scores, grade point average or class rank and such other criteria as the department may determine. The department shall establish a system for receiving a limited number of recommendations for outstanding candidates for such bonuses from institutions of higher education across the nation. In selecting bonus recipients, the department shall consider such recommendations.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     In a given year, the department may target awards to attract teachers for those subject matter areas most needed in the commonwealth; provided, however, that such subject matter areas shall be included in the core subjects as described in section 1D of chapter 69.
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     In a given year, the department shall award bonuses only to those deserving candidates rather than providing a set number of bonuses.
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     Recipients shall receive a $20,000 signing bonus over at least three years with at least $8,000 distributed in the first year of the bonus.
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     Such recipients shall be eligible for each year’s bonus payment only if they are certified to teach in the commonwealth and are employed as a teacher by a public school in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     The department shall select and notify bonus recipients by April 1 of each year. Eligible recipients shall receive their annual bonus payments by the subsequent October 1 of each year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="7">
    	     The name of an individual recipient of such bonus shall remain confidential unless recipient waives such confidentiality in writing.
        </section>
        <section prefix="8">
    	     The department shall aggressively market the existence of the program to encourage the best and brightest candidates in the nation to come to the commonwealth to teach. Such marketing shall focus on candidates who would otherwise not consider a career in teaching.
        </section>
        <section prefix="9">
    	     The program shall set forth an outreach plan to attract underrepresented populations to the teaching profession.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>