<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21F" order_by="21F" level="3">Coastal Facilities Improvement</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>2</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>2</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:— 
“Harbor facility”, any existing or proposed public dredged channel, spoil disposal area, bulkheads, ripraps, piers, wharves, fill, docks, floats, beaches or other structures used for fishing, marine industry, or commerce, marine recreations or public access purposes. 
“Harbor plan”, a document which analyses existing harbor and waterfront land uses and delineates future uses. Future land uses may be described through zoning ordinances, capital improvement plans, and building design guidelines and other methods. Planning for the management of the competing uses of harbor waters may include mooring plans, facilities maintenance plans, shellfish management plans or dredging needs assessments. 
“Waterfront facility”, public upland platforms, public buildings containing harbor related facilities or public spaces or structures used for fish or vessel and related equipment handling or storage, and parking facilities and walkways necessary for access to said waterfront facility. 
“Public”, any structure or land owned and maintained by a coastal city or town or by the commonwealth. 
“Improvements”, a project or undertaking involving the planning, engineering, repair, construction or reconstruction of harbor or waterfront facilities. 
“Card program”, the state Commercial Area Revitalization District program established under chapter forty D. 
“Substandard condition”, physical deterioration, faulty arrangement or design, overcrowding, lack of access, or other factors which cause the condition of a harbor or waterfront facility to be detrimental to the public safety, health, morals, welfare or sound growth of a coastal city or town. 
“Designated port area”, any port area suitable for maritime-industrial uses and so designated in accordance with the procedures established by the department of environmental protection under chapter ninety-one. 
“Special assistance development area”, an area identified by the Executive office of environmental affairs under chapter twenty-one A, having special development needs and significant resource areas which have development potential such as in ports, harbors and recreational areas.
    </text>
</law>