<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>179</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Underwater Archaeological Resources; Members; Terms;  Director; Staff</catch_line>
    <order_by>179</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be in the executive office of environmental affairs a board of underwater archaeological resources, hereinafter referred to as the board. The board shall consist of the state archaeologist or his designee, the state archivist or his designee, the director of waterways or his designee, the director of coastal zone management or his designee, the director of environmental law enforcement or his designee, the executive director of the Massachusetts historical commission or his designee and three persons to be appointed by the governor, one of whom shall be a marine archaeologist and two of whom shall be qualified or certified divers, one to be appointed by the governor chosen from a list submitted by recognized diving organizations. The members shall be appointed for terms of three years; provided, however, that of the initial appointments, two shall be for terms of two years and one shall be for a term of three years. The members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. 
The board shall be headed by a director of underwater archaeological resources, appointed by a majority of the members of said board, who shall be responsible for carrying out the work of the board under the supervision of said board. The director shall be qualified by training and experience to carry out the duties of the board. The director may employ such employees, experts and consultants as may be necessary.
    </text>
</law>