<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="22C" order_by="22C" level="3">The Department Of State Police</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>31</section_number>
    <catch_line>Water Resources Authority; Agreement For Police Service; Contents</catch_line>
    <order_by>31</order_by>
    <text>
        The colonel shall enter into an agreement with the Massachusetts water resources authority for police service to be provided by the department to the authority. Said agreement shall fix the legal and fiscal responsibility pertaining to the operation and maintenance of such police service and shall include, but not be limited to, a provision for payments to the commonwealth for the cost of retirement, compensation of injured officers, sick leave, and other employee benefits and for a minimum allowance for departmental supervision. Said agreement shall also require that all terms and conditions of employment established under the applicable collective bargaining agreement pursuant to the provisions of chapter one hundred and fifty E by the commonwealth and the exclusive bargaining representative of any member of the state police providing such police service including, without limitation, the payment by the authority of any benefit or contribution therefor. Said agreement shall also include a provision that all expenses incurred by the department in providing such police service shall, upon proper requisition, be paid by the authority as such expenses are incurred. 
Said agreement shall also provide for the appointment under section ten and assignment of such members of the state police as deemed necessary to meet the requirements of said authority including, but not limited to the provisions of chapter three hundred and seventy-two of the acts of nineteen hundred and eighty-four; provided that such appointment and assignment of any such member of the state police by the colonel shall not be considered a violation of any provisions of chapter twenty-nine.
    </text>
</law>