<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35T</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority State And Local Contribution Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35T</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     There is hereby set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority State and Local Contribution Fund, hereinafter called the Fund. There shall be credited to the Fund (i) the dedicated sales tax revenue amount, provided that in any fiscal year the amount shall be not less the base revenue amount as certified pursuant to subsection (b); and (ii) all assessments received by the commonwealth pursuant to section 9 of chapter 161A. Annual receipts into the fund on account of any fiscal year shall be deemed to meet the full obligation of the commonwealth to the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority, hereinafter called the authority, for such fiscal year. Amounts in the Fund shall be held by the state treasurer or his designee as trustee and not on account of the commonwealth, and the state treasurer is hereby authorized and directed to disburse amounts in the Fund to the authority, without further appropriation, upon the request, from time to time, of the general manager of the authority.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     For purposes of determining the amount to be credited to the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority State and Local Contribution Fund established pursuant to subsection (a), the comptroller shall on March 1 of each year beginning on March 1, 2001 certify the base revenue amount for the following fiscal year. On March 15 of each year beginning on March 15, 2001, the comptroller shall, after consultation with and based on projections of the department of revenue, certify whether the dedicated sales tax revenue amount is projected to exceed the base revenue amount for the upcoming fiscal year. If the comptroller certifies that the projected dedicated sales tax revenue amount will be less than the base revenue amount, then the comptroller shall for the following fiscal year credit to the Fund amounts sufficient to meet the base revenue amount. If the comptroller certifies that the projected dedicated sales tax revenue amount will exceed the base revenue amount, then the comptroller shall for the following fiscal year credit to the Fund the sales tax revenue amount. On November 15 of each year beginning on November 15, 2001, the comptroller shall certify whether the dedicated sales tax revenue amount as of that date is projected to exceed the base revenue amount for the current fiscal year. If the comptroller certifies that the dedicated sales tax revenue amount is projected to be less than the base revenue amount, then the comptroller shall credit to the Fund amounts sufficient to meet the base revenue amount for that fiscal year. If the comptroller certifies that the dedicated sales tax revenue amount is greater than the base revenue amount, then the comptroller shall credit to the Fund the dedicated sales tax revenue amount. On April 1 of each year beginning on April 1, 2002, the comptroller shall repeat the certification process required on November 15 and shall credit the appropriate amount to the Fund.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>