<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6A" order_by="6A" level="3">Executive Offices</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Executive Officer</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  Each secretary shall act as the executive officer of the governor for accomplishing the purposes of his executive office. He shall conduct comprehensive planning with respect to the functions of said office and coordinate the activities and programs of the state agencies therein. He shall conduct studies of the operations of said agencies with a view to effecting improvements in administrative organization, procedures and practices, and to promoting economy, efficiency, and avoiding useless labor and expenses in said agencies. He shall from time to time recommend to the governor such changes as he shall deem desirable in the laws relating to the organization, structure, efficiency or administrative functions, services, procedures and practices of any such agency or agencies. He shall review and act upon budgetary and other financial matters concerning said agencies in accordance with sections two C, three, three A, four, nine B and twenty-nine of chapter twenty-nine.
Chapter 6A: Executive officer
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 20 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  Each secretary shall act as the executive officer of the governor for accomplishing the purposes of his executive office. He shall conduct comprehensive planning with respect to the functions of said office and coordinate the activities and programs of the state agencies therein. He shall conduct studies of the operations of said agencies with a view to effecting improvements in administrative organization, procedures and practices, and to promoting economy, efficiency, and avoiding useless labor and expenses in said agencies. He shall from time to time recommend to the governor such changes as he shall deem desirable in the laws relating to the organization, structure, efficiency or administrative functions, services, procedures and practices of any such agency or agencies. He shall review and act upon budgetary and other financial matters concerning said agencies under chapter 29.
    </text>
</law>