<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="22C" order_by="22C" level="3">The Department Of State Police</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>39</section_number>
    <catch_line>Chemist's Analysis Of Drugs;  Certificate Of Results;  Prima Facie Evidence</catch_line>
    <order_by>39</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until July 1, 2012. For text effective July 1, 2012, see below.]  A certificate by a chemist of the department of the result of an analysis made by him of a drug furnished him by a member of the state police, signed and sworn to by such chemist, shall be prima facie evidence of the composition, quality and when appropriate, net weight of any mixture containing such drug.
Chapter 22C: Chemical analysis of narcotic drug or drug substitute, etc.; certificate of results; prima facie evidence
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 56 effective July 1, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 229. For text effective until July 1, 2012, see above.]  (a) The department shall, free of charge, or the University of Massachusetts Medical School shall, under section 36B of chapter 75, make a chemical analysis of any narcotic drug, any synthetic substitute for the same, any preparation containing the same, or any salt or compound thereof, and of any poison, drug, medicine or chemical submitted to it by police authorities, as the department shall approve for this purpose; provided, however, that neither the department nor the medical school shall conduct such analysis unless it is satisfied that the analysis submitted to it is to be used in connection with the enforcement of law.  (b) A certificate by a chemist or analyst or other designated employee of the department or of the University of Massachusetts medical school of the result of the chemist's or analyst's or other designated employee's analysis, signed and sworn to by that chemist or analyst or other designated employee, shall be prima facie evidence of the composition, quality and, when appropriate, net weight of the substance or any mixture containing the substance.  (c) A signed certificate of drug analysis furnished by an analyst, assistant analyst or other designated employee of the Drug Enforcement Administration of the United States Department of Justice which conforms with the requirements of this section shall be prima facie evidence of the composition, quality and, when appropriate, net weight of the substance or any mixture containing the substance.
    </text>
</law>