<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21H" order_by="21H" level="3">Solid Waste Facilities</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Restrictions On Use And Sale Of Mercury Added Vehicle Switches; Plan For Removal And Recycling Of Mercury Added Components In End Of Life Vehicles</catch_line>
    <order_by>6C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     No person shall sell or offer to sell or distribute a motor vehicle manufactured on or after January 1, 2007, containing 1 or more mercury-added vehicle switches.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     No person shall sell or offer to sell or distribute a mercury-added vehicle switch for new installation in a motor vehicle.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     If a mercury-added vehicle switch in a motor vehicle in commerce requires replacement, it shall be replaced with a non-mercury alternative. If a non-mercury alternative is not commercially available, replacement with a non-mercury alternative shall not be required. If the mercury-added vehicle switch requiring replacement is a component of an anti-lock braking system or an airbag, replacement with a non-mercury alternative shall not be required.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     No person shall crush, cause to be crushed or otherwise arrange for an end-of-life motor vehicle to be crushed without first having removed any mercury-added components, including, but not limited to, mercury-added vehicle switches. A scrap recycling facility may agree to accept an end-of-life motor vehicle that has not been flattened, crushed or baled containing mercury-added components. If accepted, the scrap recycling facility is responsible for proper removal, recycling, transporting, storage and general containment of all mercury-added components in accordance with chapter 21C and the department’s regulations concerning hazardous waste.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     Any person or facility removing a mercury-added component from a vehicle in commerce or from an end-of-life vehicle shall manage the mercury-added component in accordance with chapter 21C and the department’s regulations concerning hazardous waste.
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     No later than August 1, 2007, every automobile manufacturer shall, individually or as a group, develop and file with the department and implement a plan that describes the proper removal, recycling, transportation, storage and general containment of mercury-added switches from end-of-life vehicles in accordance with chapter 21C and the department’s regulations concerning hazardous waste.
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     The plan shall include, at a minimum:-
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     a method of collecting mercury-added vehicle switches after removal from motor vehicles;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     provisions for identifying or establishing and using facilities where mercury-added vehicle switches may be received and accepted from vehicle recyclers, scrap recyclers and all other persons removing mercury-added vehicle switches from vehicles;
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     provisions for transporting mercury-added vehicle switches collected pursuant to clause (1) of subsection (g) to facilities pursuant to clause (2) of said subsection (g);
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     a program to provide information, training and technical assistance to vehicle recyclers, scrap recyclers and all other persons removing mercury-added vehicle switches from motor vehicles;
        </section>
        <section prefix="5">
    	     a program which is designed to achieve a mercury-added vehicle switch capture rate of at least 90 per cent, consistent with the principle that mercury-added vehicle switches shall be recovered unless the mercury-added vehicle switch is inaccessible due to significant damage to the motor vehicle in the area surrounding where the mercury-added vehicle switch is located;
        </section>
        <section prefix="6">
    	     a financing system for the total cost of removal, collection, record keeping and recovery of mercury-added vehicle switches that shall be borne by the automobile manufacturers and that shall include, but not be limited to, $3 for every mercury-added vehicle switch removed by a vehicle recycler or scrap recycling facility as partial compensation for labor and other costs incurred by a vehicle recycler or scrap recycling facility in the removal of the mercury-added vehicle switch.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     In developing a removal, collection, record keeping and recovery system, automobile manufacturers shall, to the extent practicable, use the existing end-of-life vehicle recycling infrastructure. If an automobile manufacturer does not use such infrastructure, the automobile manufacturer shall include in its plan reasons for establishing a separate removal, collection and recovery system.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     After the plan is filed with the department, each automobile manufacturer shall certify to the department, in writing on an annual basis, that it is implementing the plan in accordance with this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     The department shall evaluate the compliance of all persons subject to this section by conducting audits, inspections or implementing other compliance measures it considers appropriate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     Automobile manufacturers shall report annually to the department and joint committee on environment, natural resources and agriculture. The report shall, at a minimum, include the following:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The number of mercury-added vehicle switches removed during the previous year; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Where and how the mercury-added vehicle switches are stored, recycled or otherwise disposed of.
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     Not later than January 1, 2007, automobile manufacturers and vehicle recyclers shall provide the department with the number of end-of-life vehicles with mercury-added vehicle switches in the commonwealth in calendar year 2005 and the projected numbers for end-of-life vehicles in the commonwealth for each calendar year thereafter until 2030.
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     Automobile manufacturers who have never installed mercury-added vehicle switches in their motor vehicles shall be exempt from this section.
        </section>
        <section prefix="n">
    	     (1) An automobile manufacturer may create an alternative plan, organized, managed and financed by the automobile manufacturer, that will be exempt from clauses (5) and (6) of subsection (g) if:-
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     the automobile manufacturer submits a plan, in writing to the department that describes the proper removal, recycling, transportation, storage and general containment of mercury-added switches from end-of-life vehicles in accordance with chapter 21C and the department’s regulations concerning hazardous waste, that meets the requirements of clauses(1) to (4), inclusive, of subsection (g);
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     the alternate plan is implemented no later than January 1, 2007;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     the automobile manufacturer demonstrates that the plan’s capture rate is equal to or greater than 50 per cent by December 31, 2007, as determined by the department; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     the automobile manufacturer demonstrates that the plan’s capture rate is equal to or greater than 90 per cent by December 31, 2008, as determined by the department.
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Nothing in this section shall prohibit an automobile manufacturer from substituting a new plan in accordance with, and subject to the requirements of, subsection (o).
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     If no alternative plan is in effect by January 1, 2007, pursuant to this section, the automobile manufacturer shall comply with subsection (g).
        </section>
        <section prefix="4">
    	     If the department determines that an automobile manufacturer is not in compliance with this subsection, the automobile manufacturer shall comply with subsection (g) within 30 days of the determination by the department.
        </section>
        <section prefix="o">
    	     If an automobile manufacturer’s plan under subsection (g) has been in effect for at least 1 year, the automobile manufacturer may submit an alternate plan to the department for approval. The alternate plan shall meet the following criteria:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     The alternate plan has been in effect for at least 1 year in another state and can be implemented statewide;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     The alternate plan has achieved at least a 90 per cent capture rate in that state; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     The alternate plan, to the extent practicable, uses the existing end-of-life vehicle recycling infrastructure in the commonwealth.
        </section>
        <section prefix="p">
    	     When considering whether to approve an alternate plan pursuant to subsections (n) and (o), the department shall take into consideration the environmental impact in the commonwealth and the economic impact on Massachusetts businesses.
        </section>
        <section prefix="q">
    	     Approval of the alternate plan pursuant to subsections (n) and (o) by the department shall release the automobile manufacturer from its obligations under its original plan, starting on the effective date of the alternate plan.
        </section>
        <section prefix="r">
    	     An alternate plan may include an agreement between automobile manufacturers and automobile dealers to remove switches before the vehicle reaches its end-of-life.
        </section>
        <section prefix="s">
    	     Vehicle recyclers shall, before delivering or selling automobile bodies to scrap recycling facilities, certify in writing, in a form approved by the department, that all mercury-added vehicle switches have been removed.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>