<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="25A" order_by="25A" level="3">Division Of Energy Resources</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>12</section_number>
    <catch_line>Regulations; Submission To General Court</catch_line>
    <order_by>12</order_by>
    <text>
        Except for emergency regulations adopted pursuant to section two of chapter thirty A, and except for actions taken under section eight of this chapter, any regulation, as defined in section one of said chapter thirty A, or any amendment or repeal of any such regulation adopted by the commissioner pursuant to this chapter, shall, after compliance with all applicable provisions of said chapter thirty A, except section five, shall be submitted to the general court. Said commissioner shall file the proposed regulation, amendment or repeal with the clerk of the house of representatives, together with a statement that the pertinent provisions of said chapter thirty A, except section five have been complied with. Such regulations shall be accompanied by a summary of the regulations in layman’s terms. The clerk of the house of representatives, with the approval of the president of the senate and the speaker of the house of representatives, shall refer such regulations to the joint committee on telecommunications, utilities and energy. Within thirty days after such referral, said committee may hold a public hearing on the regulations and shall issue a report to said commissioner. Said commissioner shall review said report and shall adopt final regulations as deemed appropriate in view of said report and shall file with the chairmen of such reporting committee its final regulations. Not earlier than thirty days after the filing of such report with the committee, said commissioner shall file the final regulations with the state secretary as provided in section five of said chapter A and said regulations shall thereupon take effect.
    </text>
</law>