<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Debt Statements</catch_line>
    <order_by>9A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  A debt statement shall be forwarded on a quarterly basis to the state treasurer, comptroller, and the house and senate committees on ways and means by all authorities and agencies of the commonwealth having authority to issue notes or bonds except the Massachusetts Port Authority and the Massachusetts Department of Transportation. Said debt statement shall be certified by an authorized official of said authority or agency. Such debt statement shall include authorized, unissued and outstanding bonds and notes of the authority or agency as of the first day of each quarter. Said debt statement shall include the debt service requirements of both principal and interest for the subsequent twenty-four month period and an estimate of the date and principal amount of bonds and notes to be sold in the subsequent twelve-month period. Said debt statement shall be filed under rules and regulations prescribed by the state treasurer.
Chapter 10: Debt statements
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 93 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  A debt statement shall be forwarded on a quarterly basis to the state treasurer, comptroller and the house and senate committees on ways and means by those agencies of the commonwealth and authorities identified by the comptroller under subsection (c) of section 12 of chapter 7A, having authority to issue notes or bonds. Said debt statement shall be certified by an authorized official of said agency or authority. Such debt statement shall include authorized, unissued and outstanding bonds and notes of the authority or agency as of the first day of each quarter. Said debt statement shall include the debt service requirements of both principal and interest for the subsequent 24-month period and an estimate of the date and principal amount of bonds and notes to be sold in the subsequent 12-month period. Said debt statement shall be filed under rules and regulations prescribed by the state treasurer.
    </text>
</law>