<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23J" order_by="23J" level="3">Massachusetts Clean Energy Technology Center</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter, the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings: 
“Board”, the board of directors of the center. 
“Bonds”, when used in reference to the center, any bonds, notes, debentures, interim certificates or other financial undertakings for the purpose of raising capital, including, but not limited to, lines of credit, forward purchase agreements, investment agreements and other banking or financial arrangements. 
“Center”, the Massachusetts clean energy center established by section 2. 
“Clean energy”, advanced and applied technologies that significantly reduce or eliminate the use of energy from non-renewable sources, including, but not limited to: energy efficiency; demand response; energy conservation and those technologies powered in whole or in part by the sun, wind, water, biomass, alcohol, wood, fuel cells any renewable, non-depletable or recyclable fuel and for purposes of this Act, an alternative energy generating source as defined in clauses (1) to (5), inclusive, of subsection (a) of section 11F1/2 of chapter 25A. 
“Clean energy research”, advanced and applied research in new clean energy technologies including: solar photovoltaic; solar thermal; wind power; geothermal; wave and tidal energy; advanced hydropower; energy storage for automotive applications; energy storage for grid applications; biofuels, including ethanol, biodiesel and advanced biofuels; renewable, biodegradable chemicals; advanced thermal-to-energy conversion; hydrogen; carbon capture and sequestration; energy monitoring; green building materials; energy-efficient lighting; gasification and conversion to liquids fuels; industrial energy efficiency; demand-side management; fuel cells; and other technologies that the board considers to qualify under the definitions herein; provided, however, that “clean energy research” shall not include coal, oil, natural gas except when used in fuel cells or nuclear power. 
“Contribution agreement”, an agreement authorized under this chapter in which a private entity or public entity other than the commonwealth agrees to provide to the center contributions for the purpose of promoting clean energy research. 
“Director”, the director of the Massachusetts Renewable Energy Trust appointed pursuant to section 2. 
“Executive director”, the executive director of the center appointed pursuant to section 2. 
“Federal agency”, an office, agency, division, department, board or commission of the United States government. 
“Fund”, the Massachusetts Alternative and Clean Energy Investment Trust Fund established in subsection (a) of section 35FF of chapter 10. 
“Person”, a natural or corporate person, including bodies politic and corporate, public departments, offices, agencies, authorities and political subdivisions of the commonwealth, corporations, trusts, societies, associations and partnerships and subordinate instrumentalities of any 1 or more political subdivisions of the commonwealth. 
“Public body”, the commonwealth and any body politic and corporate of the commonwealth, including any political subdivision or instrumentality thereof, which is empowered to issue bonds secured by a pledge of revenues or other special funds or assets, including any municipality or district for which the issuance of debt is governed or limited by chapter 44. 
“Revenues”, any receipts, fees, rentals or other payments or income received or to be received on account of obligations to the center including, without limitation: equity ownership in public or private companies; income on account of the leasing, mortgaging, sale or other disposition of a project or proceeds of a loan made by the center in connection with any project; and amounts in reserves or held in other funds or accounts established in connection with the issuance of bonds and the proceeds of any investments thereof; proceeds of foreclosure; and any other fees, charges or other income received or receivable by the center. 
“Trust fund”, the Massachusetts Renewable Energy Trust Fund established pursuant to section 9.
    </text>
</law>