<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35J</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Tourism Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35J</order_by>
    <text>
        [ See 2012, 139, Sec. 166.]  There is hereby established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund known as the Massachusetts Tourism Fund, into which shall be deposited thirty-five percent of the revenues received from the tax imposed by section three of chapter sixty-four G, and section twenty-two of chapter five hundred and forty-six of the acts of nineteen hundred and sixty-nine. Monies in said fund shall be applied subject to appropriation by the General Court as follows:  (a) forty percent to the office of travel and tourism for tourism promotion programs;  (b) thirty-eight percent to the Massachusetts Convention Center Authority established under the provisions of chapter one hundred and ninety of the acts of nineteen hundred and eighty-two;  (c) nineteen percent for financial assistance to tourist promotion agencies under the provisions of section fourteen of chapter twenty-three A; and  (d) three percent for the expenses of the Massachusetts international trade office.  (e) notwithstanding the provisions of the preceding paragraphs or any other general or special law to the contrary, for any fiscal year in which revenues deposited into the Massachusetts Tourism Fund exceed the amounts deposited into said fund in the previous fiscal year, 50 per cent of the increase in said revenues shall be applied, subject to appropriation, to the Massachusetts Cultural Facilities Fund, established pursuant to subsection (b) of section 42 of chapter 23G.
    </text>
</law>