<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18C" order_by="18C" level="3">Office Of The Child Advocate</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        As used in this chapter, the following words shall have the following meanings, unless the context clearly requires otherwise:— 
“Advisory board”, the child advocate advisory board established by section 4. 
“Child advocate”, the child advocate appointed under section 3. 
“Critical incident”, (a) a fatality, near fatality, or serious bodily injury of a child who is in the custody of or receiving services from the executive office of health and human services or 1 of its constituent agencies; or (b) circumstances which result in a reasonable belief that the executive office of health and human services or 1 of its constituent agencies failed in its duty to protect a child and, as a result, the child was at imminent risk of, or suffered, serious bodily injury. 
“Department”, the department of children and families. 
“Executive agency”, a state agency within the office of the governor that includes the executive office of education, the executive office of public safety and security, executive office of health and human services, the Massachusetts interagency council on homelessness and housing established by Executive Order No. 492 and the executive office of housing and economic development. 
“Office”, the office of the child advocate. 
“Serious bodily injury”, bodily injury which involves a substantial risk of death, extreme physical pain, protracted and obvious disfigurement or protracted loss or impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ or mental faculty.
    </text>
</law>