<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6C" order_by="6C" level="3">Massachusetts Department Of Transportation</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>56</section_number>
    <catch_line>Registry Of Motor Vehicles; Administrator</catch_line>
    <order_by>56</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be within the department a registry of motor vehicles, which shall perform such functions as the secretary may determine in relation to the administration, implementation and enforcement of the department’s authority over motor vehicles. The registry shall be under the supervision and control of the administrator, who shall be known as the registrar of motor vehicles. The administrator shall be the executive and administrative head of the registry and shall be responsible for administering and enforcing the provisions of law relative to the registry and to each administrative unit thereof. The duties given to the administrator in this chapter and in any other general or special law shall be exercised and discharged subject to the direction, control and supervision of the secretary. The administrator shall appoint a deputy registrar, assistant to the registrar, hearings officers and supervising inspectors and may appoint such other officers and employees as may be necessary to carry out the work of the registry. In the event of a vacancy in the office of registrar, his powers and duties shall be exercised and performed by the deputy registrar until a registrar is duly qualified. 
The administrator shall be exempt from chapter 31 and the position of administrator shall be classified in accordance with section 45 of chapter 30 and the salary shall be determined in accordance with section 46C of said chapter 30. The administrator shall be appointed with due regard to his fitness, by reason of his experience in matters relating to transportation infrastructure, including roads and bridges, such as the construction, operations or financing thereof or other relevant experience relative to the efficient exercise of his powers and duties. The administrator shall administer this section and the General Laws, rules and regulations that grant powers to or impose duties upon the division, subject to the supervision of the secretary.
    </text>
</law>