<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="3">State Superintendent Of Buildings, And State House</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Superintendent Of State Office Buildings</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  There shall be within the executive office for administration and finance a bureau of state office buildings, headed by a state superintendent of state office buildings. The superintendent shall be appointed by the commissioner of administration and may be removed in like manner. The superintendent shall be a person of ability and experience and shall devote his entire time to the duties of his office. Said office shall not be classified under chapter 31.
Chapter 8: Bureau of the state house; superintendent of the state house
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 12 effective October 31, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 219. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  There shall be within the executive office for administration and finance a bureau of the state house, headed by a superintendent of the state house. The bureau of the state house shall be located in the state house. The superintendent shall be selected by the chairs of the committee on rules of the 2 branches from a list of 3 candidates submitted to the committee on rules of the 2 branches by the secretary of administration and finance. The superintendent shall be a person of ability and experience with a background in finance and operations and may have a background in engineering. The entire time of the superintendent shall be devoted to the duties of the office. The office shall not be classified under chapter 31.
    </text>
</law>