<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="26" order_by="26" level="3">Department Of Banking And Insurance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Appeal On Motor Vehicle Liability Policies And Bonds</catch_line>
    <order_by>8A</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board of appeal on motor vehicle liability policies and bonds serving in the division of insurance and consisting of the commissioner of insurance or his representative, the registrar of motor vehicles or a representative, and two assistant attorneys general to be designated from time to time by the attorney general. The commissioner of insurance may by a writing, in such form as he may prescribe, filed in his office, designate from time to time a representative to act in his place and the registrar of motor vehicles may in like manner designate from time to time a representative to act in his place. Any such designation may be revoked at any time and may run for such period as the designating officer may prescribe. The compensation of such a representative, if not an employee of the commonwealth, shall be fixed by the board, subject to the approval of the governor and council. The commissioner of insurance or his representative shall be the chairman of the board. With the approval of the governor and council, the board may appoint and remove a secretary and such clerical and other assistants as its work may require. The secretary so appointed shall be eligible to serve also as the representative of the commissioner of insurance, if designated as aforesaid. All expenditures incurred under this section shall be paid from the highway fund. The secretary shall keep a record of all proceedings before the board, and he and such clerical and other assistants shall perform such duties as the board may direct. Any member of the board shall have power to summon and compel the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, records and documents and may administer oaths. Sections nine and eleven of chapter two hundred and thirty-three shall apply to the board and witnesses summoned before it. The fees of witnesses before the board for attendance and travel shall be the same as for witnesses before a court in civil cases and need not be paid nor tendered to them prior to their attendance, and shall be paid by the commonwealth upon the certificate of the board or a member thereof filed with the comptroller. An office and a room for hearings shall be provided by the commonwealth, to be assigned by the governor and council. The board may hold hearings at any place within the commonwealth and the members and secretary thereof shall be allowed their necessary traveling and other expenses in holding hearings outside the city of Boston. The board, with the approval of the governor and council, may make and amend reasonable rules and regulations to expedite and regulate hearings and the procedure before it.
    </text>
</law>