<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>22C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Procurement By State Of Goods Or Services From Persons With An Office Or Facility In Northern Ireland; Certification; Bids</catch_line>
    <order_by>22C</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     Except as otherwise provided in this section, a state agency, a state authority, the house of representatives or the state senate may not procure goods or services from any person employing ten or more employees in an office or other facility located in Northern Ireland, who fails to certify that:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     he does not discriminate in employment, compensation, or the terms, conditions and privileges of employment on account of religious or political belief; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     he promotes religious tolerance within the work place, and the eradication of any manifestations of religious and other illegal discrimination.
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     A state agency, a state authority, or the house of representatives or the senate may procure goods or services from a person who employs ten or more employees in an office or other facility located in Northern Ireland and fails to provide the certification required by subsection (c) only after certifying, in writing, to the secretary or, in the case of a state authority, to the chief operating officer that:
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     the procurement is essential; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     compliance with this section would eliminate the only bid or offer or would result in inadequate competition.
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     In any solicitation, a state agency, a state authority, the house of representatives or the senate shall provide notice of the requirements of this section. Prior to reviewing responses to bid documents for any procurements or, if there are none, prior to entering into any contractual arrangement, the awarding authority shall obtain from such person seeking a contract a statement under pains and penalties of perjury from an authorized representative, on a form to be provided by the awarding authority, that he does not employ ten or more employees in an office or other facility located in Northern Ireland or, if he does, certifying compliance with the principles listed in subsection (a) or declaring that he does not so certify.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     In any procurement that includes bidders or offerors who employ ten or more employees in an office or other facility located in Northern Ireland and do not certify compliance with the principles listed in subsection (a), the awarding authority may award the contract to a person who does not certify compliance with the principles listed in subsection (a) only if there is no comparable low bid or offer by a person who does so certify or who does not employ ten or more employees in an office or other facility located in Northern Ireland.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     A person who employs persons in Northern Ireland for the sole purpose of reporting the news, or solely for the purpose of providing goods or services for the provision of international telecommunications shall not be subject to the provisions of sections twenty-two C to twenty-two D, inclusive.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>