<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="22" order_by="22" level="3">Department Of Public Safety</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Elevator Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>11</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be in the department a board to be known as the board of elevator regulations, which shall consist of eight members, to be appointed by the governor, with the advice and consent of the council, for terms of four years each. One of such members shall be the chief of inspections in said department, with power to designate from time to time an inspector in said department to act temporarily as a member of such board, with the same powers and duties as other members of the board, one shall be a consulting engineer, one the building commissioner of Boston or his designee, one the inspector of buildings of some city or town other than Boston, one a representative of a liability insurance company licensed to write elevator insurance in the commonwealth, one a representative of elevator manufacturers, one an experienced elevator constructor, and one representative of owners of buildings subject to chapter one hundred and forty-three and one representative of the department of fire services. The governor, with the advice and consent of the council, shall from time to time designate one member of said board as chairman. 
No member shall act as a member of the board, or vote as such, in connection with any matter as to which his private right, distinct from the public interest, is immediately concerned. 
A majority of said board, constituted as above provided, may transact business, but a lesser number may adjourn from time to time. 
Each member of the board shall be paid not less than $50 for each day while in the actual performance of his duties as such, but not exceeding $2,000 in a fiscal year, and shall also receive from the commonwealth all expenses necessarily incurred by him in connection with his official duties. 
Such clerical, technical and other assistants as may be required by the board shall be assigned to it by the commissioner.
    </text>
</law>