<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>58</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions Applicable To Secs. 59 To 61</catch_line>
    <order_by>58</order_by>
    <text>
          As used in sections 59 to 61 of this chapter, the following words shall have the following meanings, unless a contrary intent is clearly indicated:--  "Certified business enterprise'' and "certified business'', a business certified pursuant to section 61.  "Director'', the director of the supplier diversity office.[ Definition of "Disadvantaged business enterprise'' inserted following definition of "Director'' by 2011, 68, Sec. 17 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221.]  "Disadvantaged business enterprise", a disadvantaged business enterprise as defined by the United States Department of Transportation in 49 C.F.R. &sect 26 et seq.  "Minority business enterprise'' or "MBE'', for the purpose of receipt of services from SDO, means a business enterprise that is owned and controlled by one or more socially or economically disadvantaged persons. Such disadvantage may arise from cultural, racial, chronic economic circumstances or background or other similar cause. Such persons include, but are not limited to, African Americans, Cape Verdeans, Western Hemisphere Hispanics, Asians, American Indians, Eskimos, and Aleuts. For purposes of section 61 and of section 40N of chapter 7, the term "minority owned business'' shall have the same meaning as "minority business enterprise''.  "Office'', the supplier diversity office as established by section 61.  "SDO'', the supplier diversity office as designated by section 61. The office shall be the successor to the office of minority and women business assistance.  "Secretary'', the secretary of the executive office for administration and finance.  "State purchasing agent'', the head of the operational services division of the executive office for administration and finance.[ Definition of "Unified certification program'' inserted following definition of "State purchasing agent'' by 2011, 68, Sec. 18 effective July 1, 2011. See 2011, 68, Sec. 221.]  ''Unified certification program'', the program, whereby the supplier diversity office certifies disadvantaged business enterprises, as required by regulations of the United States Department of Transportation in 49 C.F.R. &sect 26 et seq.  "Veteran business enterprise'' or "VBE'', a business enterprise that is both owned and controlled by 1 or more veterans, as defined in section 7 of chapter 4, who has invested in an ongoing business free of conversion rights.  "Women business enterprise'' or "WBE'', for the purpose of receipt of services from SDO means a business enterprise that is both owned and controlled, by one or more women who have invested in an ongoing business free of conversion rights. For purposes of section 61 and of section 40N of chapter 7, the term "women owned business'' shall have the same meaning as "women business enterprise.''
    </text>
</law>