<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>8A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Water Resources Commission; Members; Terms</catch_line>
    <order_by>8A</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be established within the executive office of environmental affairs the water resources commission hereinafter in this section and in sections eight B to eight F, inclusive, called the commission, which shall consist of the secretary of the executive office of environmental affairs, the commissioner of the department of environmental protection, the commissioner of the department of conservation and recreation, the commissioner of the department of fish and game, the commissioner of the department of food and agriculture, and the director of housing and community development, all of whom shall serve ex officio, and 5 persons to be appointed by the governor. 
The 5 members appointed by the governor for a term of three years shall each represent a major type of water user, have a demonstrated knowledge in at least one area of water resource management, have a demonstrated interest in statewide water resource issues, and an ability to address all issues at a level of expertise commensurate with the commission’s mandate; provided, however, that one member so appointed shall be a member of the groundwater industry. The governor’s appointments shall be made with appropriate consideration being given to a list of candidates provided by the secretary of environmental affairs. 
In his initial appointments the governor shall designate two members to serve for one year, two for a term of two years and two for a term of three years and their successors shall serve for terms of three years.
    </text>
</law>