<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="8" order_by="8" level="3">State Superintendent Of Buildings, And State House</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Care And Operation Of State House</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until October 31, 2012. For text effective October 31, 2012, see below.]  The superintendent shall have charge of the care and operation of the state house, subject to rules as the committee on rules of the 2 branches acting concurrently may adopt, the John W. McCormack state office building, the Leverett Saltonstall state office building, the Springfield office building, the Pittsfield office building, the Erich Lindemann building, the Charles F. Hurley building and all state parking areas related thereto, and any other state properties designated by law, to be the responsibility of the superintendent of state office buildings, and shall see that the chambers and lobbies of the general court and of its committees are kept clean and in good order; shall superintend all ordinary repairs thereof and shall have charge of the current expenses for the care and preservation of the state house, and for the ordinary repairs of the furniture and fixtures therein. He shall take proper precautions against damage thereto, or to the furniture, fixtures or other public property therein; provided, however, that security in the state house shall be the responsibility of the director of the state parks and recreation in consultation and coordination with the speaker of the house of representatives and the president of the senate. The director shall utilize the members of the urban park rangers program, established pursuant to section 34B of chapter 92, to maintain security; provided, however, that the commissioner shall carry out the responsibility subject to rules as the committee on rules of the 2 branches acting concurrently may adopt and shall not be subject to the authority of the superintendent. There shall be maintained an adequate passageway for foot passengers from north to south through the east wing or extension of the state house, to be kept open during the hours as the superintendent shall fix. The state house and all facilities located therein, including hearing rooms, shall be accessible to, functional for and safe for use by physically handicapped persons; provided further that the state shall make available a certain number of designated handicapped parking spaces for the general public; provided, however, that no construction required for the accessibility, functionality and safety shall commence until the superintendent of state buildings has completed the study required in section 2.
Chapter 8: Operation and maintenance of state house
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 139, Sec. 15 effective October 31, 2012. See 2012, 139, Sec. 219. For text effective until October 31, 2012, see above.]  The superintendent shall have charge of the operation and maintenance of the state house, subject to such rules as the committee on rules of the 2 branches, acting concurrently, may adopt and all state parking areas related thereto. The superintendent shall see that the chambers and lobbies of the general court and its committees are kept clean and in good order, shall superintend all ordinary repairs thereof and shall have charge of the current expenses for the care and preservation of the state house and for the ordinary repairs of the furniture and fixtures therein. The superintendent shall take proper precautions against damage thereto or to the furniture, fixtures or other public property therein; provided, however, that security in the state house shall be the responsibility of the commissioner of conservation and recreation in consultation and coordination with the speaker of the house of representatives and the president of the senate. The commissioner of conservation and recreation shall utilize the members of the urban park rangers program, established under section 34B of chapter 92, to maintain security; provided, however, that the commissioner shall carry out the responsibility subject to such rules as the committee on rules of the 2 branches, acting concurrently, may adopt and shall not be subject to the authority of the superintendent. There shall be maintained an adequate passageway for foot passengers from north to south through the east wing or extension of the state house, to be kept open during such hours as the superintendent shall fix. The state house and most facilities used by the public, including hearing rooms, shall be accessible to, functional for and safe for use by persons with physical disabilities; and provided further, that the commonwealth shall make available a certain number of designated handicapped parking spaces for the general public. The superintendent may adopt rules, regulations and orders necessary for the operation and maintenance of the state house.
    </text>
</law>