<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23A" order_by="23A" level="3">Department Of Economic Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>64</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Creative Economy Network</catch_line>
    <order_by>64</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 238, Sec. 11 effective August 7, 2012.]  (a) There shall be established within the executive office of housing and economic development a Massachusetts creative economy network, hereinafter referred to as the network, which shall be directed by a state creative economy director. The network shall consist of private, public and non-profit organizations and cultural districts, designated as such under section58A of chapter 10, engaged in cross-industry collaboration between many interlocking industry sectors that provide creative services including, but not limited to, advertising, architecture, or intellectual property products such as arts, films, electronic media, video games, interactive digital media, multimedia, or design. The creative economy director, in consultation with the creative economy council, established under chapter 354 of the acts of 2008, shall establish criteria for participation in the network.  (b) The duties of the network, under the leadership of the creative economy director, shall include: quantifying the creative economy sector and measuring its impact on the commonwealth's economy; creating a mentorship network within the creative economy sector; developing strategies to increase access to traditional market sectors and within state government; developing a certification for Massachusetts creative economy businesses; increasing opportunities to attract private investment to creative economy businesses through venture capital, microlending and other means; and marketing and branding the creative economy sector.  (c) The network may accept gifts or grants of money or property from any public, private or non-profit source, which shall be held in trust and used for the purpose of promoting the growth and development of the creative economy sector in the commonwealth.  (d) The creative economy director shall file an annual report with the clerks of the house of representatives and senate; the house and senate chairs of the committees on ways and means; the house and senate chairs of the joint committee on economic development and emerging technologies; the house and senate chairs of the joint committee on tourism, arts and cultural development; and the house and senate chairs of the joint committee on community development and small business on or before January 1. The report shall include an overview of the activities of the network, and an update on the number of creative economy businesses in the commonwealth and their impact on the state economy, and an accounting of gifts or grants held in trust by the network and the uses of any funds expended by the trust.
    </text>
</law>