<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18B" order_by="18B" level="3">Department Of Social Services</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>13</section_number>
    <catch_line>Area Boards; Members; Appointment; Terms</catch_line>
    <order_by>13</order_by>
    <text>
        In each area established under section 3, there shall be a children and families area board, in this chapter called the area board, which shall be an agency of the commonwealth and shall serve in the department. The area board shall consist of 23 members, who shall be appointed by the commissioner for terms of 3 years. 
No member shall be an employee of the department. Two-thirds of the members shall be persons other than employees of the commonwealth or its political subdivisions. 
The commissioner shall seek to provide proper geographical representation in the membership of the board. Two-thirds of the members shall live within the area for which they are appointed, and the remaining members shall either live or work in the area. At least 1 member from each city and, if practicable, each town in the area shall be included. 
At least 6 members shall be consumers of services provided by the department. Not more than 2 members shall be selected from nominations submitted by the president of the collective bargaining unit representing the social workers who work for the department in the area. Not more than 2 members shall be selected from private providers within the area. One member at the time of appointment shall be a member of the community mental health area board established under section 14 of chapter 19, 1 member at the time of appointment shall be a person knowledgeable in the field of intellectual disabilities, 2 members at the time of their appointment shall be members of the financial or business professions with special fiscal or budgetary skills, and 2 members shall at the time of their appointment be members of the community service area boards established under section 7 of chapter 18. 
Upon the expiration of the term of any member, his successor shall be appointed, in like manner, for a term of 3 years. In the event of a vacancy, the commissioner may, in like manner, appoint a member who shall serve for the remainder of the unexpired term. Members shall serve without compensation and shall be sworn to the faithful performance of their duties. The area board shall suggest for consideration by the commissioner 1 or more names for each such expiring term or vacancy. No member shall be appointed for more than 3 consecutive 3-year terms.
    </text>
</law>