<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Registration Of Physician Assistants; Membership;  Appointment; Term</catch_line>
    <order_by>11C</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board of registration of physician assistants, herein called the board, to consist of nine members who are residents of the commonwealth, who shall be appointed by the governor, two of whom shall be licensed physicians who shall have been actively engaged in the practice of medicine for at least three years and at least one of whom shall be a member of the Massachusetts Medical Society; one of whom shall be an educator of physician assistants on the faculty or staff of an accredited physician assistant training program; four of whom shall be physician assistants duly certified in the commonwealth who may be selected from a list of names submitted by the Massachusetts Association of Physician Assistants or comparable organization representing physician assistants and two of whom shall be representatives of the general public. 
Members shall be appointed for a term of three years. No member shall be appointed to more than two consecutive full terms; provided, however, that a member appointed for less than a full term may serve two full terms in addition to such part of a full term and a former member shall again be eligible for appointment after a lapse of one or more years. Any member of the board may be removed by the governor for neglect of duty, misconduct or malfeasance or misfeasance in office after being given a written statement of the charges against him and sufficient opportunity to be heard thereon. 
Said board shall elect its chairperson annually and shall meet at the call of such chairperson or upon the request of two or more members of the board. A quorum shall consist of at least five members present. Board members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual and reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. The board shall meet at least four times annually.
    </text>
</law>