<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21C" order_by="21C" level="3">Massachusetts Hazardous Waste Management Act</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Property Subject To Seizure And Forfeiture</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     All conveyances, including motor vehicles, trailers, vessels, or other containers, used or intended for use to transport hazardous wastes in violation of this chapter or of any regulation, order, license, or approval issued or adopted under this chapter;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     All books, records, or other materials which are or contain any evidence of a violation of this chapter or of any regulation, order, license, or approval issued or adopted under this chapter; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     All hazardous wastes collected, transported, stored, used, treated, disposed of, or otherwise handled in violation of this chapter or of any regulation, order, license, or approval issued or adopted under this chapter.
        </section>
        <section prefix="1">
    	     Use by a law enforcement or other public agency;
        </section>
        <section prefix="2">
    	     Sale at a public auction. The proceeds from the sale of the property shall be used to pay for reasonable expenses incurred in the seizure, storage and maintenance, and proceedings for the forfeiture of the property. Any balance shall be forwarded to the department for use in the enforcement of this chapter; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="3">
    	     Disposal of hazardous wastes seized pursuant to this section.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>