<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13" level="3">Division And Boards Of Registration</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11B</section_number>
    <catch_line>Board Of Respiratory Care; Membership; Qualifications; Term</catch_line>
    <order_by>11B</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a board of respiratory care, hereinafter called the board, which shall consist of 7 members to be appointed by the governor and the appointments may be from among a list of nominations submitted by the Massachusetts Society for Respiratory Therapy or its successor. Members of the board shall be residents of the commonwealth and citizens of the United States. Two of such members shall be respiratory therapists licensed in accordance with section 23S of chapter 112 except that such members constituting the first board shall be persons eligible for licensing as practitioners of respiratory care; 2 of such members shall be physicians with pulmonary related specialties licensed in accordance with the provisions of section 2 of said chapter 112, 1 such member shall be a nurse with pulmonary related experience licensed in accordance with said chapter 112, and 2 of such members shall be consumers of respiratory care services selected from and representing the general public. 
Each member of the board shall serve for a term of three years except that immediately following the enactment of this section, the initial terms of two of the members shall be for a term of three years, two of the members shall be for a term of two years, and two of the members shall be for a term of one year. No member shall be appointed to more than two consecutive full terms; provided, however, that a member appointed for less than a full term may serve two full terms in addition to such part of a full term and a former member shall again be eligible for appointment after a lapse of one or more years.
    </text>
</law>