<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21A" order_by="21A" level="3">Executive Office Of Energy And Environmental Affairs</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Licensing</catch_line>
    <order_by>19C</order_by>
    <text>
        The board may license individuals to be hazardous waste site cleanup professionals. Each application for an initial license or license renewal shall be accompanied by a fee established by the board that shall be set to cover all costs of processing the application, and each licensee whose license is valid for one year or more shall pay an annual fee that shall be set to cover all costs of administering and enforcing sections nineteen through nineteen J, inclusive, and shall otherwise be set in accordance with the provisions of section three B of chapter seven. The board may deny an application for an initial license or for a license renewal, or suspend or revoke a license, at any time for cause. The board may grant an application for an initial license or for a license renewal, and may allow a license to remain in effect, only if and while the board is persuaded that the applicant for or holder of the license is in compliance, and will be in compliance routinely and on a continuing basis, with all standards and requirements applicable to hazardous waste site cleanup professionals. Each license issued pursuant to sections nineteen through nineteen J, inclusive, shall be issued only to an individual, shall be valid only for the individual to whom it is issued, and may not be transferred. Each license issued pursuant to sections nineteen through nineteen J, inclusive, shall be for a period not to exceed five years, unless a shorter term is specified therein, or unless sooner suspended or revoked. Any individual whose application for an initial license or for a license renewal is denied, or whose license is revoked, may be barred by the board from applying for a license for a period of not more than five years. The term during which reapplication is barred shall be established as part of the determination or decision of the board in the proceedings concerning the denial or revocation. 
The board shall cause notice of each license application, approval, denial, suspension, or revocation, or the lifting or termination of each license suspension, and of each public censure and private censure, and of the results of all adjudicatory proceedings thereon, to be given to the department promptly and in whatever ways are necessary in order to enable the department to promptly and properly exercise its powers and perform its duties pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, chapter twenty-one E, and all other applicable laws. The board shall not approve an application for an initial license or for a license renewal until at least thirty days after the department has received said notice, or until the department has notified the board in writing that it has no objection to the approval of the application, whichever occurs first.
    </text>
</law>