<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>43A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Office Of Facilities Management;  Director;  Staff;  Building Inventory</catch_line>
    <order_by>43A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. Repealed by 2012, 165, Sec. 66. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  There shall be located within the division of capital asset management and maintenance an office of facilities management, headed by a director of facilities management. The director shall be appointed by the commissioner, with the approval of the commissioner of administration, and may be removed in like manner. Said office shall not be subject to section nine A of chapter thirty or chapter thirty-one. No person shall be appointed director of said office unless at the time thereof he shall be registered by the commonwealth as an architect or professional engineer pursuant to the provisions of chapter one hundred and twelve and shall have proven ability and extensive experience in the management and oversight of operation, maintenance and repair of buildings.  The director may appoint such deputies and other supervisory staff as the work of the office may require, subject to appropriation and the commissioner's approval. Such staff shall serve at the pleasure of the director and shall not be subject to chapter thirty-one or to section nine A of chapter thirty. The director shall appoint, subject to the commissioner's approval, all other officers and employees of said office.  The director shall develop, in cooperation with the commissioner and using agencies, an inventory of buildings owned or otherwise occupied by state agencies and building authorities. Said inventory may detail the age, condition, type of construction, and physical life expectancy of each building and its major structural components. The inventory shall be updated as repairs, replacements and alterations are performed. Said inventory shall be filed by the commissioner by February fifteenth yearly with the clerks of the house of representatives and senate, and with the joint committee on state administration, and shall be a public document available for general distribution. The director shall recommend to the commissioner standards and guidelines governing the type of information to be included in said inventory, which shall be properly coordinated with the real property inventory established and maintained pursuant to section forty J.
    </text>
</law>