<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12A" order_by="12A" level="3">Office Of Inspector General</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Rules And Regulations</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        The office shall, pursuant to the provisions of chapter thirty A, promulgate rules and regulations which shall govern its proceedings. 
The state secretary shall not accept for filing any such regulations unless such regulation has, in addition to compliance with all applicable provisions of chapter thirty A, been approved by the general court and the governor. 
Any such regulations, adopted by the office, after compliance with all applicable provisions of said chapter thirty A, be filed with the house of representatives under the provisions of this section and shall be accompanied by a summary of said regulations. Such regulation shall be referred to the appropriate joint standing committee within five days of the filing thereof. The said committee shall consider the proposed regulations and shall report to the general court within forty-five days whether or not such regulations should be adopted. 
The clerk of the senate shall cause any such regulations approved by both branches of the general court within seventy-five days from the time of filing of the same with the house of representatives, to be forwarded to the governor for his approval; provided, that any such regulations which are not approved by the general court and the governor within ninety days of such filing shall be deemed to have been disapproved. 
If the governor approves any such regulations so submitted he shall forward the same to the state secretary who shall publish the same in accordance with section five of chapter thirty A. 
Emergency regulations may be adopted by the office after the prorogation of the general court in the manner provided by said section five of chapter thirty A; provided, that such regulations shall be filed with the house of representatives for submission to the next session of the general court for approval as hereinbefore provided; and provided, further, that such regulations shall not remain in force for more than ninety days after the general court has convened for such session.
    </text>
</law>