<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7" level="3">Executive Office For Administration And Finance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Requested Special Examination On Matters Of Management Or Finances;  Pilot Studies Of Proposed Statewide Programs</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  On request of either branch of the general court or of the ways and means committee of either branch, or of the governor, or of the finance committee, the secretary of administration and finance shall make a special examination of, and give to them any information in his possession relative to, any matter affecting the management or finances of any department, officer, commission or undertaking which receives an annual appropriation of money from the commonwealth, including annual appropriations to be met by assessments.  On request of either branch of the general court or of the ways and means committee of either branch, the secretary may assist in the undertaking of a pilot study of any proposed statewide program with an estimated cost of one million dollars of state appropriated funds or revenues of the commonwealth, to determine the cost and impact on the tax structure of the commonwealth or its political subdivisions. Said secretary shall notify the appropriate legislative body if he is unable to make such pilot study.
Chapter 7: Requested special examination on matters of management or finances
[ Text of section as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 50 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  On request of either branch of the general court or of the ways and means committee of either branch or of the governor, the secretary shall make a special examination of, and give to them any information in the secretary's possession relative to, any matter affecting the management or finances of any department, officer, commission or undertaking which receives an annual appropriation of money from the commonwealth, including annual appropriations to be met by assessments.
    </text>
</law>