<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7C" order_by="7C" level="3">Capital Asset Management And Maintenance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>28</section_number>
    <catch_line>Duties And Responsibilities Of Director Of Facilities Management</catch_line>
    <order_by>28</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 165, Sec. 82 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  As used in this section, "using agencies'' shall mean state agencies and building authorities.  The director of facilities management shall: (1) develop, in cooperation with individual state agencies and building authorities, policies, standards, programs and schedules governing the performance of preventive maintenance; (2) develop preventive maintenance training programs for state agency and building authority personnel; (3) evaluate the status of preventive maintenance programs at each state agency and building authority; (4) review using agency maintenance operating budget requests together with maintenance reports submitted pursuant to section 3 of chapter 29 for the purpose of evaluating the priority, necessity, feasibility and appropriateness of said requests; (5) review using agency capital budget requests for repair projects and make recommendations to the commissioner as to those projects of each using agency that should be given funding priority; (6) recommend to the commissioner standards and guidelines for the control and supervision of repair projects controlled and supervised by using agencies; (7) advise the commissioner as to those methods available for the repair of deteriorating buildings, including the costs and benefits of continuing minor repairs versus the costs and benefits of major renovation or rehabilitation; (8) advise the commissioner as to maintenance and repair difficulties encountered in using agency buildings that may be due to faulty design or construction of new facilities; (9) advise the commissioner as to the feasibility and costs of renovating or rehabilitating for state use structures that have been certified historic landmarks, as provided by sections 26 to 27C of chapter 9, that have been listed in the National Register of Historic Places, as provided by 16 U.S.C. 470a, or that have been designated landmarks by the local governing authority; (10) advise the commissioner as to changes in operations and maintenance costs and operational and repair difficulties that may result from using agency proposals for alteration or conversion of existing facilities; and (11) assist using agencies in evaluating maintenance and repair problems and devising and implementing solutions.
    </text>
</law>