<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6A" order_by="6A" level="3">Executive Offices</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>7A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Performance Of Core Information Technology Functions By Executive Office Or Designated State Agencies</catch_line>
    <order_by>7A</order_by>
    <text>
        Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, each secretary may, identify information technology related activities and related supporting financial functions common to the state agencies within the executive office and may designate such functions as core information technology functions. To improve administrative efficiency and preserve fiscal resources, the secretary may direct that core information technology functions be performed by the executive office or by state agencies designated by the secretary to perform those functions. The secretary may delegate the secretary’s signature authority for such functions to an officer or employee of an agency within the executive office. Nothing in this section shall waive the responsibility of each agency head to certify obligations and expenditures for appropriations and other legally available funds of the agency pursuant to section 3 of chapter 7A, the responsibilities of an agency head pursuant to state finance law, including but not limited to, sections 19, 20, 24, 26 and 27 of chapter 29, and the responsibility of an agency head to certify work by employees of the agency pursuant to section 31 of said chapter 29. The executive office or any state agencies designated to perform core information technology functions may charge the state agencies that receive such services for the reasonable costs of providing the services. Any employee transfers that occur in connection with the consolidation of core information technology functions within the executive office or state agencies shall not: (a) impair the civil service status of any such transferred employee who immediately before the effective date of that transfer either holds a permanent appointment in a position classified under chapter 31 or has tenure in a position by reason of section 9A of chapter 30; or (b) impair or change an employee’s status, rights or benefits under chapter 150E.
    </text>
</law>