<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12" level="3">Department Of The Attorney General, And The District Attorneys</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>11M</section_number>
    <catch_line>Division Of Gaming Enforcement</catch_line>
    <order_by>11M</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 9 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) As used in this section the following words shall, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, have the following meanings:  "Commission'', the Massachusetts gaming commission established in chapter 23K.  "Division'', the division of gaming enforcement established in subsection (b).  "Gaming establishment'', as defined in section 1 of chapter 23K.  (b) There shall be in the department of the attorney general a division of gaming enforcement. The attorney general shall designate an assistant attorney general as the director of gaming enforcement. The director may appoint and remove, subject to the approval of the attorney general, such expert, clerical or other assistants as the work of the division may require.  (c) The division shall enforce criminal violations of chapter 23K which shall include, but not be limited to: (1) investigating and prosecuting allegations of criminal activity related to or impacting the operation of gaming establishments or games; (2) receiving and taking appropriate action on referrals for criminal prosecution from the commission or any other law enforcement body; (3) providing assistance, upon request, to the commission in the consideration and promulgation of rules and regulations; (4) ensuring that there shall be no duplication of duties and responsibilities between the division and the commission; and (5) recommending persons to be placed on a list of excluded persons to be maintained by the commission.  No employee of the division and no person engaged by the division in the course of an investigation, other than in the performance of their official duties, shall place a wager in a gaming establishment licensed under chapter 23K during the period of their employment or assignment with the division. The attorney general shall establish a code of ethics for all division employees which shall be more restrictive than chapters 268A and 268B. A copy of the code of ethics shall be filed with the state ethics commission. The code shall include provisions reasonably necessary to carry out this section including, but not limited to: (i) prohibiting the receipt of gifts by a division employee from a gaming licensee, applicant, close associate, affiliate or other person or entity subject to the jurisdiction of the commission established in chapter 23K; and (ii) prohibiting the participation by a division employee in a particular matter as defined in section 1 of said chapter 268A that affects the financial interest of a relative within the third degree of consanguinity or any other person with whom such employee has a significant relationship as defined in the code of ethics.  Officers and employees of the gaming enforcement unit in the department of state police who are assigned to the division shall record their time and submit their total hours to the director of gaming enforcement. The division shall submit a request for reimbursement to the commission and the commission shall reimburse the department of state police.  The division shall submit quarterly requests to the commission for expenses associated with the operation of the division and the commission shall reimburse the division for such expenses; provided, however, that the commission shall not approve such a request if the request would exceed an annual reimbursement of $3,000,000.
    </text>
</law>