<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23E" order_by="23E" level="3">Division Of Industrial Accidents</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>6</section_number>
    <catch_line>Senior Judges; Powers And Duties; Selection</catch_line>
    <order_by>6</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     no less than two years of experience as an administrative judge or administrative law judge at the industrial accident board;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     proven knowledge of chapter one hundred and fifty-two, its regulations and other relevant laws;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     demonstrable administrative and management ability; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     superior writing skills as may be shown by hearing or review board decisions, law review articles or any other appropriate written materials.
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     the initial training of newly appointed administrative judges and administrative law judges as to their responsibilities and powers including, but not limited to, the conduct of conferences and hearings, the prompt, clear, and concise writing of orders and decisions and the management of claims to assist workers in their return to work;
        </section>
        <section prefix="ii">
    	     the establishment of an annual workers’ compensation judicial training program to instruct all administrative judges or administrative law judges in matters related to their professional development;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iii">
    	     the establishment of criteria, in conjunction with the commissioner, upon which to perform an annual review of each administrative judge and administrative law judge;
        </section>
        <section prefix="iv">
    	     the fair allocation of all claims and complaints to ensure each administrative judge receives a balanced and equitable case load during the calendar year;
        </section>
        <section prefix="v">
    	     the establishment of criteria under which a claimant may claim a hardship and request a conference on the first available date;
        </section>
        <section prefix="vi">
    	     the training, supervision and review of conciliators, and the association, where feasible, of particular conciliators to particular judges for the purpose of fostering more effective conciliation of disputes.
        </section>
        <section prefix="vii">
    	     the senior judge shall accept motions for expedited conferences relating to fraudulent behavior, illegal discontinuance of compensation, catastrophic injuries, medical emergencies, or denials pursuant to section fifteen A of chapter one hundred and fifty-two. Such session shall be held on a weekly basis if necessary. The motions and the procedure at the sessions shall conform to requirements set forth by the senior judge. The motion sessions shall be presided over by an administrative law judge or conciliator selected by the senior judge. If the administrative law judge, administrative judge or conciliator grants the motion for an expedited conference, said conference shall be held within fourteen days.
        </section>
        <section prefix="viii">
    	     the development of a standard form for pre-conference memoranda to be prepared by the parties.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>