<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>189</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Council; Membership; Duties</catch_line>
    <order_by>189</order_by>
    <text>
        The advisory council shall consist of the commissioner of mental health, the commissioner of rehabilitation, the commissioner for the blind, the director of the office of deafness, the chairperson of the commission on the employment of people with disabilities, the chairman of the architectural barriers board, the commissioner of children and families, the commissioner of public welfare, the commissioner of public health, the chairman of the Massachusetts commission against discrimination, the director of housing and community development, the secretary of transportation and construction, the director of consumer affairs and business regulation and the secretary of elder affairs, ex officiis, or their respective representatives, and thirty-three persons qualified by training, experience, or demonstrated interest in the affairs of persons with disabilities, and representing the broad range of disabilities present in the commonwealth, to be appointed by the governor as follows:— eleven for a term of three years, eleven for a term of two years, and eleven for a term of one year. Upon expiration of the term of any appointive member, his successor shall be appointed in like manner for a term of three years. The governor shall in like manner fill any vacancy for the remainder of the unexpired term. Said members of the advisory council shall elect their chairman and shall meet at least quarterly. They shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties. If any member is absent from two regularly scheduled quarterly meetings in any one calendar year, his office as a member of said council shall be deemed vacant. The chairman of the council shall forthwith notify the governor that such vacancy exists. 
Said advisory council shall advise the director on policy, planning, and needs in the commonwealth for programs and services for persons with disabilities; assist the director in establishing priorities for office activities; and annually review the programs, budgets and policies of the office.
    </text>
</law>