<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12A" order_by="12A" level="3">Office Of Inspector General</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>4</section_number>
    <catch_line>Employees; Appointment And Removal, Salaries, Qualifications</catch_line>
    <order_by>4</order_by>
    <text>
        The inspector general may, subject to appropriation, appoint and may remove such employees, as he deems necessary to perform the duties of his office, including but not limited to assistant inspectors general, chief and deputy counsels, clerks, paralegals, accountants, auditors, financial management analysts and investigators and may determine their salaries and duties; provided, however, that the total amount of all such salaries shall not exceed the sum appropriated therefor by the general court. The provisions of sections nine A and forty-five of chapter thirty, chapter thirty-one and chapter one hundred and fifty E shall not apply to officers and employees within the office. 
The inspector general may establish personnel regulations for the officers and employees of the office. He shall file an annual personnel report not later than the first Wednesday in February with the senate and house committees on ways and means containing the job classifications, duties and salary of each officer and employee within the department together with personnel regulations applicable to said officers and employees. He shall file amendments to such report with the senate and house committees on ways and means whenever any changes become effective. The inspector general may establish motor vehicle regulations for the officers and employees of the office of the inspector general and the provisions of section thirty-six of chapter thirty shall not apply to officers and employees with the office. 
With the exception of the attorney general, the state auditor, the secretary of public safety, and the state comptroller, no member of the inspector general council or officer or employee of the office of inspector general shall hold, or be a candidate for, any elective public office while an officer or employee, or for three years thereafter, nor shall he hold office in any political party or political committee, or participate in any political campaign of any candidate for public office while an officer or employee. 
The estimate of the amount required for the maintenance of the office required to be filed under section three of chapter twenty-nine shall be submitted by the inspector general with the advice and consent of the inspector general council. 
The inspector general, with the advice and consent of the inspector general council may apply for and receive federal funds in order to fulfill the duties and responsibilities of the office.
    </text>
</law>