<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="9" order_by="9" level="3">Department Of The State Secretary</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>19</section_number>
    <catch_line>Destruction Or Sale Of Documents Of No Value;  Reproduction Of Records Of Corporations.</catch_line>
    <order_by>19</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The state secretary, having first obtained authority from the governor and council, may destroy or sell such documents, records and papers as in his judgment are of no value; and if sold, the proceeds thereof shall be paid to the commonwealth.[ First paragraph as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 86 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The state secretary may destroy or sell such documents, records and papers as in his judgment are of no value; and if sold, the proceeds thereof shall be paid to the commonwealth.  Notwithstanding the foregoing or any provision of section forty-two of chapter thirty, if the secretary has caused any record relative to corporations, voluntary associations, limited partnerships or trusts which he is required to keep, to be recorded, copied or reproduced by any photographic, photostatic, microfilm, microcard, miniature photographic or other process which accurately reproduces or forms a durable medium for so reproducing the original, he may, at any time after two years from the date when the original was deposited with him, destroy such original. Such record, copy or reproduction shall be attested by the secretary, when required, as a true copy of the original.
    </text>
</law>