<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23H" order_by="23H" level="3">Workforce Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Department Of Career Services</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Subsection (a) effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  (a) Within the executive office of labor and workforce development, there shall be a department of workforce development, in this chapter called the department.[ Subsection (a) as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 70 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  (a) Within the executive office of labor and workforce development, there shall be a department of career services, in this chapter called the department.  (b) The mission of the department shall be to develop, coordinate, and maintain a coherent workforce development system that fills the needs of employers for a skilled workforce and promotes lifelong learning among employees. The department shall cooperate with all federal, state, and local agencies active in the field of workforce development to achieve this goal.[ Subsection (c) effective until March 27, 2011. Deleted by 2011, 3, Sec. 71.]  (c) Subject to appropriation, the department shall be provided with such offices in Boston and elsewhere in the commonwealth as may be approved by the governor and may expend sums for other necessary expenses of said department. Said department may accept gifts or grants of money or property, whether real or personal, from any source, public or private, including, but not limited to, the United States of America or its agencies, for the purpose of assisting the departments in the discharge of their duties.[ Subsection (d) effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  (d) The following state agencies and funds shall be in the department of workforce development: the one stop career centers, the state workforce investment board, the division of apprentice training, the commonwealth corporation, the workforce training fund, and the division of unemployment assistance. The division of unemployment assistance shall include the medical security trust fund and the unemployment insurance trust fund.[ Subsection (d) as amended by 2011, 3, Secs. 70 and 72 to 74 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  (d) The following state agencies and funds shall be in the department of career services: the one stop career centers, the state workforce investment board, the commonwealth corporation, and the workforce training fund. The division of unemployment assistance shall include the medical security trust fund and the unemployment insurance trust fund.
    </text>
</law>