<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23G" order_by="23G" level="3">The Massachusetts Development Finance Agency</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>43</section_number>
    <catch_line>Cultural Facilities Fund Advisory Committee; Members; Review Of Applications For Grant And Loans</catch_line>
    <order_by>43</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be a cultural facilities fund advisory committee, the function of which shall be strictly advisory to the agency in connection with the management and operation of the Massachusetts Cultural Facilities Fund. The committee shall consist of the following members: the director of the Massachusetts cultural council or his designee; the director of the office of travel and tourism or his designee; the director of the agency or his designee; and 6 members to be appointed by the governor, 1 of whom shall have expertise in fundraising, 1 of whom shall have expertise in finance and 1 of whom shall have expertise in construction. In appointing members, the governor shall ensure that each of the following geographic regions of the commonwealth is represented: the central area, the greater Boston area, the metro-west area, the northeast area, the southeast area and the western area. All members shall be appointed for a term of 5 years, may be reappointed, and shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed from the Fund for ordinary and reasonable in-state travel expenses. The committee may meet as often as the members may determine, but shall meet at least bi-annually, or at such other intervals as may be established by the agency in order to review recommendations made by the Massachusetts cultural council, or such other qualified organization with which the agency contracts, with respect to the Fund and to make any advisory recommendations with respect thereto to the agency. Subsection (d), and subsections (f) to (i), inclusive, and subsection (l) of section 2 shall apply to the members and affairs of the committee. All applications for grants or loans recommended by the Massachusetts cultural council or other such organization with whom the agency may contract shall be reviewed by the committee. The committee shall then issue findings and recommendations to the agency as to which applications should be approved. Only those applications that are recommended by the committee for approval shall be considered by the agency’s board of directors for final approval. If the agency’s board of directors votes to deny any recommended approval, the agency shall, within 30 days of such action, provide the applicant with a written explanation for such denial.
    </text>
</law>