<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="15D" order_by="15D" level="3">Department Of Early Education And Care</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Suspension, Revocation, Etc. Of License Or Approval; Annual Report</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
        Subject to the requirements of chapter 30A, the department may suspend, revoke, make probationary, refuse to issue or renew the license of any person, assess a civil fine within the limits prescribed by this section, or impose any other sanctions it considers appropriate, in accordance with rules and regulations promulgated by the board. This action may be taken if the person: fails to comply with applicable rules and regulations, furnishes or makes any misleading or false statements relative to any submission required under the rules and regulations, refuses to submit any reports or make available any records required by the rules and regulations or refuses to admit representatives of the department at any reasonable time for purposes of investigation or inspection. The department may temporarily suspend a license in an emergency situation without a prior hearing. Upon request of an aggrieved party, a hearing shall be held as soon after the license is suspended as is reasonably possible. Any party aggrieved by a final decision of the department in any adjudicatory proceeding under this section may petition for judicial review under section 14 of chapter 30A. 
The board shall include in its annual report rules and regulations promulgated by the board relative to the use of civil fines and sanctions, the types of sanctions, and the amount of those fines.
    </text>
</law>