<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5C</section_number>
    <catch_line>Investment Division;  Responsibilities</catch_line>
    <order_by>5C</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The state treasurer shall establish with the advice of the council an investment division, under the direction of a deputy state treasurer, for investments, who shall be responsible for the investment of all state funds under the custody of the state treasurer, including without limitation temporary cash investment.[ First paragraph as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 89 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The state treasurer shall establish an investment division, under the direction of a deputy state treasurer, for investments, who shall be responsible for the investment of all state funds under the custody of the state treasurer, including without limitation temporary cash investment.[ Second paragraph effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  The state treasurer may, with the advice of the council, retain such professional investment counsel or other counsel to evaluate and recommend policies for cash and investment management for the commonwealth or its subdivisions.[ Second paragraph as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 90 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  The state treasurer may retain such professional investment counsel or other counsel to evaluate and recommend policies for cash and investment management for the commonwealth or its subdivisions.
    </text>
</law>