<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>190</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts Industrial Advisory Board</catch_line>
    <order_by>190</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section effective until March 27, 2011. Repealed by 2011, 3, Sec. 10.]  There shall be a Massachusetts Industrial Advisory Board, hereinafter called the board, to consist of the director of economic development and the director of labor and workforce development, or their designees, acting as co-chairmen. In addition, the governor shall appoint two members from labor, two members from business, one member who is a professional economist, one member having expertise in finance, and one member representing local communities. The members appointed by the governor shall serve for a term of four years. Upon expiration of the term of a member, a successor shall be appointed, in the same manner, for a like term. Any member shall be eligible for reappointment. Vacancies shall be filled in a like manner for the remainder of the unexpired term. The members appointed by the governor shall be compensated for reasonable expenses only.  The board shall advise the governor from time to time on issues and policy matters pertaining to the well-being of industry in the commonwealth, including, but not limited to, overseeing the development of the Massachusetts industrial service program, as governed by chapter twenty-three D, and making recommendations to improve the performance of said program, monitoring the implementation of the social compact governing private and public actions to cushion the impact of plant closings, and providing advice on industry-wide assistance programs. The board shall also advise the deputy director of employment and training in analysis of plant closings in accordance with the provisions of section seventy-one C of chapter one hundred and fifty-one A.  The board shall annually submit a report to the governor, clerk of the house of representatives, and clerk of the senate within ninety days of the end of each fiscal year. The report shall include: (1) a description of the activities of the industrial service program, including the number of businesses assisted, jobs maintained, and efforts to assist workers and communities affected by plant closings; (2) any recommendations to improve the performance of said program; (3) an account of the marketing, acceptance of and adherence to said social compact; and (4) a description and evaluation of any industry assistance programs undertaken by the Commonwealth.
    </text>
</law>