<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23K" order_by="23K" level="3">The Massachusetts Gaming Commission</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>49</section_number>
    <catch_line>Applicability Of Others Laws To Gaming Establishments;  Exclusion Of Gaming Establishment And Businesses Located Within Gaming Establishments From And From Eligibility For Certain Credits Or Deductions Listed In Chapters 62 Or 63</catch_line>
    <order_by>49</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2011, 194, Sec. 16 effective November 22, 2011.]  (a) A gaming establishment, including any business located within a gaming establishment, shall not be a certified project within the meaning of section 3F of chapter 23A. Gaming establishments shall not be designated as economic opportunity areas within the meaning of section 3E of said chapter 23A. Gaming establishments shall not be eligible for tax increment financing under section 59 of chapter 40 or special tax assessments set forth in section 3E of said chapter 23A. Gaming establishments shall not be classified and taxed as recreational land under chapter 61B. Gaming establishments shall not be designated as development districts within the meaning of chapter 40Q.  (b) Unless otherwise provided, a gaming establishment or a business located or to be located within a gaming establishment shall not be eligible for the following credits or deductions listed in chapter 62 or chapter 63: the investment tax credit under section 31A of chapter 63, the employment credit under section 31C of said chapter 63, the van pool credit under section 31E of said chapter 63, the deduction for expenditures for industrial waste treatment or air pollution control under section 38D of said chapter 63, the deduction for compensation paid to an eligible business facility's employees domiciled in a section of substantial poverty under section 38F of said chapter 63, the film tax credit under subsection (l) of section 6 of chapter 62 and section 38X of said chapter 63, the alternative energy sources deduction under section 38H of said chapter 63, the research expense credit under section 38M of said chapter 63, the economic opportunity area credit under subsection (g) of said section 6 of said chapter 62 and section 38N of said chapter 63, the abandoned building deduction under subparagraph (10) of subsection (a) of Part B of section 3 of said chapter 62 and section 38O of said chapter 63, the harbor maintenance tax credit under section 38P of said chapter 63, the brownfields credit under subsection (j) of said section 6 of said chapter 62 and section 38Q of said chapter 63, the historic rehabilitation tax credit under section 6J of said chapter 62 and section 38R of said chapter 63 and the automatic sprinkler system depreciation deduction under section 38S of said chapter 63.
    </text>
</law>