<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35E</section_number>
    <catch_line>Organ Transplant Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35E</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund to be known as the Organ Transplant Fund, to assist residents of the commonwealth in paying all or part of any costs associated with a medically required organ transplant. Said fund shall consist of all revenues received by the commonwealth: (1) under the provisions of section six E of chapter sixty-two; (2) from public and private sources as gifts, grants, and donations to further such human organ transplant programs; and (3) from the federal government as reimbursements, grants-in-aid or other receipts on account of such transplant operations. 
All revenues credited under this section shall remain in said Organ Transplant Fund, not subject to appropriation, to assist residents of the commonwealth in paying all or part of any costs associated with a medically required organ transplant. The state treasurer shall not deposit said revenues in or transfer said revenues to the General Fund or any other fund other than the Organ Transplant Fund. 
The state treasurer shall deposit the fund in accordance with the provisions of sections thirty-four and thirty-four A of chapter twenty-nine in such manner as will secure the highest interest rate available consistent with safety of the fund and with the requirement that all amounts on deposit be available for immediate withdrawal at any time. The fund shall be expended only for the purposes stated above at the direction of the commissioner of public health and any unexpended balances shall be redeposited, as herein provided, for future use consistent with this section.
    </text>
</law>