<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23H" order_by="23H" level="3">Workforce Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>10</section_number>
    <catch_line>Performance Standards For Workforce Development And Job Training Programs</catch_line>
    <order_by>10</order_by>
    <text>
          By April 1, 2004, the state workforce investment board shall develop performance standards for workforce development and job training programs receiving state funding. The standards may vary across program types. The state workforce investment board may contract with a consultant to develop the performance standards. The state workforce investment board shall consult with stakeholder advocacy groups, community-based nonprofit service providers, and local workforce investment boards in the development of both performance standards and reporting requirements. The standards must at a minimum measure: the employability levels of individuals as defined by basic skill level, the amount of work experience, and barriers to employment prior to program entry; the individual's annual income and employability level for the 12 months prior to entering the program, the starting annual income upon placement after completing the program, employability level and annual income one year after completion of the program, and the individual's reported satisfaction; the program completion rate, placement rate, employability level upon placement, and one-year retention rate; and the cost per placement and per job retained at one year and the percentage of program funding coming from the state and other levels of government.  Commencing April 1, 2005, all workforce development services and job skills training programs receiving state funds must submit an annual performance report to the state workforce investment board. The state workforce investment board may develop a uniform format for the report and prescribe the manner in which the report is required to be submitted.[ Third paragraph effective until March 27, 2011. For text effective March 27, 2011, see below.]  By December 31 of each odd-numbered year and commencing December 31, 2005, the director of the department of workforce development, in consultation with the state workforce investment board, shall submit recommendations to the house and senate clerks regarding modifications to, including the elimination of, existing statutory requirements with respect to workforce development and job training programs. The recommendations shall include recommendations regarding funding levels required to meet worker and employer skill development needs, with a particular focus on low income and low wage workers.[ Third paragraph as amended by 2011, 3, Sec. 90 effective March 27, 2011. For text effective until March 27, 2011, see above.]  By December 31 of each odd-numbered year and commencing December 31, 2005, the director of the department of career services, in consultation with the state workforce investment board, shall submit recommendations to the house and senate clerks regarding modifications to, including the elimination of, existing statutory requirements with respect to workforce development and job training programs. The recommendations shall include recommendations regarding funding levels required to meet worker and employer skill development needs, with a particular focus on low income and low wage workers.
    </text>
</law>