<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="15C" order_by="15C" level="3">Massachusetts College Student Loan Authority</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>5</section_number>
    <catch_line>Purposes Of Authority; Powers</catch_line>
    <order_by>5</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     to adopt by-laws for the regulation of its affairs and the conduct of its business;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     to adopt an official seal and alter the same at pleasure;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     to maintain an office at such place or places in the commonwealth as it may designate;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     to sue and be sued in its own name, plead and be impleaded;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     to determine criteria and guidelines encompassing the type of and qualifications for education loan financing programs. The criteria and guidelines established by the Authority for its education loan financing programs shall include such eligibility standards for borrowers as the Authority shall determine are necessary or desirable in order to effectuate the purposes of the chapter, including the following:—(i) each student shall have a certificate of admission or enrollment at a participating institution for higher education, (ii) each student or his or her parents shall satisfy such financial qualifications as the Authority shall establish to effectuate the purposes of the chapter, and (iii) each student and his parents shall submit such information as may be required by the Authority to his or her institution of higher education;
        </section>
        <section prefix="f">
    	     to establish specific criteria governing the eligibility of institutions for higher education to participate in its programs, and for the making of Authority loans and education loans, provisions for default, the establishment of default reserve funds, the purchase of default insurance, the provision by such institutions of prudent debt service reserves, and the furnishing by participating institutions for higher education and others of such additional guarantees of the education loans, Authority loans or the bonds as the Authority shall determine, all of such criteria to be established to assure the marketability of the bonds and the adequacy of the security for the bonds. The criteria governing the eligibility of institutions for higher learning shall include limitations upon the principal amounts and the terms of education loans, criteria regarding the qualifications and characteristics of borrowers and procedures for allocating authority loans among institutions of higher education eligible for its program in order to effectuate the purposes of the chapter;
        </section>
        <section prefix="g">
    	     to establish rules and regulations with respect to Authority loans, educational loans, savings programs and tuition agreements.
        </section>
        <section prefix="h">
    	     to receive and accept from any source loans, contributions or grants for or in aid of an Authority education loan financing program or savings program or any portion thereof and, when desirable, to use such funds, property or labor only for the purposes for which it was loaned, contributed or granted;
        </section>
        <section prefix="i">
    	     to contract with guarantors, financial institutions or other qualified loan origination and servicing organizations, which shall assist in prequalifying borrowers for education loans and which shall service and administer each education loan. The Authority may require that each borrower be charged a fee to defray the costs of origination, servicing and administration of education loans. The amount and method of collection of such fee shall be determined by the Authority. Participating institutions for higher education may perform these acts if authorized by the Authority;
        </section>
        <section prefix="j">
    	     to contract with a guarantor to provide security for the payment of education loans through the issuance of default insurance or letters of credit or other credit arrangements or to provide a guarantee of payment covering all or a portion of each education loan made by or on behalf of the Authority or by or on behalf of an institution for higher education from the proceeds of an Authority loan.
        </section>
        <section prefix="k">
    	     to employ attorneys, accountants, consultants, financial experts, loan processors, banks, managers, and such other employees and agents as may be necessary in its judgment, and to fix their compensation;
        </section>
        <section prefix="l">
    	     to make direct education loans or to purchase education loans from or to make Authority loans to participating institutions for higher education or financial institutions and require that the proceeds of such Authority loans be used for making education loans, funding reserves, providing for capitalized interest and paying other costs and fees involved in making education loan or issuing bonds.
        </section>
        <section prefix="m">
    	     to charge and equitably apportion among participating institutions for higher education its administrative costs and expenses incurred in the exercise of the powers and duties granted by this chapter;
        </section>
        <section prefix="n">
    	     to borrow working capital funds and other funds as may be necessary for start-up and continuing operations, as long as such funds are borrowed in the name of the Authority only. Such borrowings shall be limited obligations of the character described in section twelve and shall be payable solely from revenues of the Authority or the proceeds of bonds pledged for that purpose;
        </section>
        <section prefix="o">
    	     notwithstanding any other provisions in this chapter, to commingle and pledge as security for one or more series or issues of bonds, only with the consent of all of the institutions of higher education which are participating in such series or issues, (a) the education loan series portfolios and some or all future education loan series portfolios of such institutions of higher education; and (b) the loan funding deposits of such institutions. Bonds may be issued in series under one or more resolutions or trust agreements in the discretion of the Authority.
        </section>
        <section prefix="p">
    	     to examine records and financial reports of participating institutions for higher education, and to examine records and financial reports of any person, organization or institution retained under clauses (i), (j) or (k) of this section;
        </section>
        <section prefix="q">
    	     to do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of this chapter.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>