<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="14" order_by="14" level="3">Department Of Revenue</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Division Of Child Support Enforcement</catch_line>
    <order_by>1A</order_by>
    <text>
        [ First paragraph effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  There shall be within the department of revenue a division of child support enforcement headed by a deputy commissioner, and such other administrative units as may be established in or assigned to said division from time to time by the commissioner. Said deputy commissioner shall be appointed by the commissioner with the approval of the secretary of administration, and may be removed in like manner, shall be a person of ability and experience and shall devote his entire time to the duties of his office. Said position shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter thirty-one or section nine A of chapter thirty. Said division shall be a separate administrative unit within the department, operating independent of and apart from the operational state and local tax or finance units therein. Said division shall be provided with such resources as may be necessary to implement the provisions of chapter one hundred and nineteen A. The commissioner of revenue shall have authority to delegate any child support enforcement powers or duties assigned to him under any provision of law to the IV-D agency.[ First paragraph as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 110 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  There shall be within the department of revenue a division of child support enforcement headed by a deputy commissioner, and such other administrative units as may be established in or assigned to said division from time to time by the commissioner. Said deputy commissioner shall be appointed by the commissioner with the approval of the secretary of administration and finance, and may be removed in like manner, shall be a person of ability and experience and shall devote his entire time to the duties of his office. Said position shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter thirty-one or section nine A of chapter thirty. Said division shall be a separate administrative unit within the department, operating independent of and apart from the operational state and local tax or finance units therein. Said division shall be provided with such resources as may be necessary to implement the provisions of chapter one hundred and nineteen A. The commissioner of revenue shall have authority to delegate any child support enforcement powers or duties assigned to him under any provision of law to the IV-D agency.  The commissioner may appoint and remove such additional assistants, technical consultants, contractors and other persons, may engage such other technical, contractual and other assistants as the work of said division may, from time to time, require and may develop and maintain a data processing installation exclusively for the automated collection, disbursement and data systems of said division.
    </text>
</law>