<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="12C" order_by="12C" level="3">Center For Health Information And Analysis</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>14</section_number>
    <catch_line>Standard Quality Measure Set</catch_line>
    <order_by>14</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 224, Sec. 19 effective November 4, 2012.]  (a) The center shall develop the uniform reporting of a standard set of health care quality measures for each health care provider facility, medical group, or provider group in the commonwealth hereinafter referred to as the "standard quality measure set.''  (b) The center shall convene a statewide advisory committee which shall recommend to the center a standard quality measure set. The statewide advisory committee shall consist of the executive director of the center or designee, who shall serve as the chairperson; the executive director of the group insurance commission or designee, the Medicaid director or designee; and 7 representatives of organizations to be appointed by the governor, 1 of whom shall be a representative from an acute care hospital or hospital association, 1 of whom shall be a representative from a provider group or medical association or provider association, 1 of whom shall be a representative from a medical group, 2 of whom shall be representatives of private health plans, 1 of whom shall be a representative from an employer association and 1 of whom shall be a representative from a health care consumer group.  (c) In developing its recommendation of the standard quality measure set, the advisory committee shall, after consulting with state and national organizations that monitor and develop quality and safety measures, select from existing quality measures and shall not select quality measures that are still in development or develop its own quality measures. The committee shall annually recommend to the center any updates to the standard quality measure set on or before November 1. The committee may solicit for consideration and recommend other nationally recognized quality measures, including, but not limited to, recommendations from medical or provider specialty groups as to appropriate quality measures for that group's specialty. At a minimum, the standard quality measure set shall consist of the following quality measures: (1) the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services hospital process measures for acute myocardial infarction, congestive heart failure, pneumonia and surgical infection prevention; (2) the Hospital Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems survey; (3) the Healthcare Effectiveness Data and Information Set reported as individual measures and as a weighted aggregate of the individual measures by medical or provider group; and (4) the Ambulatory Care Experiences Survey. The standard quality measure set shall include outcome measures. The committee shall review additional appropriate outcome measures as they are developed.
    </text>
</law>