<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23B" order_by="23B" level="3">Department Of Housing And Community Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>1</section_number>
    <catch_line>Department Of Housing And Community Development; Appointment, Duties And Salary Of Director</catch_line>
    <order_by>1</order_by>
    <text>
        In the executive office of housing and economic development, there shall be a department of housing and community development, in this chapter called the department, which shall be under the supervision and control of an undersecretary for housing and community development, in this chapter called the undersecretary or the director. The undersecretary shall be appointed by the secretary of housing and economic development, with the approval of the governor, for a term coterminous with that of the governor, shall serve at the pleasure of the secretary, and shall not be subject to section 9A of chapter 30 or chapter 31. Upon expiration of the term of office of the director or in the event of a vacancy, a successor shall be appointed by the governor for a term coterminous with that of the governor. The director shall devote his full time during business hours to the duties of his office. The director shall be the executive and administrative head of the department and shall be responsible for administering and enforcing the provisions of law relative to the department and to each administrative unit thereof, except as provided in subsection (b) of section 2; provided, however, that the director may authorize any officer of the department to exercise in his name any power or to discharge any duty assigned to him by law, and may at any time revoke such authority. The director shall receive such salary as the governor shall determine, provided, however, that such salary is equivalent to the salary received by the director of labor and workforce development, the director of economic development and the director of consumer affairs and business regulation.
    </text>
</law>