<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="7C" order_by="7C" level="3">Capital Asset Management And Maintenance</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>71</section_number>
    <catch_line>Review And Study By Commissioner Of All Requests And Recommendations For Appropriations Or Authorizations For Expenditures Pertaining To Capital Facility Projects;  Review By Commissioner Of Petition, Motion Or Amendment Introduced By General Court Relating To Capital Facility Project</catch_line>
    <order_by>71</order_by>
    <text>
        [ Text of section added by 2012, 165, Sec. 82 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137.]  All requests and recommendations for appropriations or authorizations for expenditures by the commonwealth that pertain to capital facility projects shall be studied by the commissioner with reference to any current long range capital facility development plans proposed in accordance with the requirements of sections 64, 65, 66 and 67. The commissioner shall consider the effects upon the policies, programs, and priorities with regard to which the commissioner is required to report in accordance with section 73 and with reference to any other matters which the commissioner requires to be reported to him in his review and evaluation of capital facility budget requests by public agencies under sections 64, 65, 66, 67 and 68. After such review and study, the commissioner shall promptly prepare and submit his recommendations to the general court.  The commissioner shall promptly review any petition, motion or amendment introduced in either chamber of the general court which makes a provision for a capital facility project. During such review the commissioner shall study the necessity, desirability, and relative priority of such capital facility project by reference to any current long range capital facilities development plans proposed in accordance with the requirements of sections 64, 65, 66, 67 and 68. The commissioner shall consider the effects upon the policies, programs, and priorities with regard to which the commissioner is required to report in accordance with section 73, and with reference to any other matters which the commissioner requires to be reported to him in his review and evaluation of capital facility budget requests by public agencies in accordance with the provisions of sections 64, 65, 66, 67 and 68. After such review and study the commissioner shall promptly prepare and forward his recommendation on the petition, motion, or amendment to the chamber in which it was introduced and where it is pending.
    </text>
</law>