<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21" level="3">Department Of Environmental Management</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>26A</section_number>
    <catch_line>Definitions Applicable To Secs. 26 To 53</catch_line>
    <order_by>26A</order_by>
    <text>
        Unless the context otherwise requires, when used in sections twenty-six to fifty-three, inclusive, the following words shall have the following meanings: 
“Abatement facilities”, facilities for the purpose of treating, neutralizing, or stabilizing sewage and such industrial and other wastes as are disposed of by means of the facilities, including treatment or disposal plants, the necessary intercepting, outfall and outlet sewers, pumping stations integral to such facilities and sewers, equipment and furnishings thereof and their appurtenances. 
“Board”, the board of certification of operators of wastewater treatment facilities. 
“Collection system”, each and all of the common lateral sewers and appurtenances of publicly owned treatment works which are primarily installed to receive wastewaters from individual structures or from private property, and which include service connection “Y” fittings and service connections within the boundary of the public way or easement. 
“Commissioner”, the commissioner of the department of environmental protection, or his authorized designee. 
“Director”, the director of the division of water pollution control, or his authorized delegate or representative. 
“District”, a district created pursuant to section twenty-eight. 
“District commission”, the governing body of a district. 
“Effluent limitation”, a requirement, established under state or federal law, specifying the maximum permissible quantity or concentration of any pollutant that may be present in discharges, or their maximum permissible hydraulic flow, over designated periods of time, to waters of the commonwealth or to a public sewerage system. 
“FWPCA”, the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, 33 U.S.C. §§ 1251 et sequens, as amended. 
“Person”, any agency or political subdivision of the commonwealth, public or private corporation or authority, individual, partnership or association, or other entity, including any officer of a public or private agency or organization, upon whom a duty may be imposed by or pursuant to any provision of sections twenty-six to fifty-three, inclusive. 
“Pollutant”, any element or property of sewage, agricultural, industrial or commercial waste, runoff, leachate, heated effluent, or other matter, in whatever form and whether originating at a point or major nonpoint source, which is or may be discharged, drained or otherwise introduced into any sewerage system, treatment works or waters of the commonwealth. 
“Priority list”, the ranking, in terms of priority, of projects eligible for funding during a given planning period, which has been established pursuant to the priority system. 
“Priority system”, the methodology for rating and ranking projects eligible for grant assistance under sections thirty A and thirty-three of this chapter and for establishing priority lists for those projects. 
“Public entity”, any city, town, special district, or other existing governmental unit eligible to receive a grant for the construction of treatment works from the United States Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to Title II of the FWPCA, as amended. 
“Treatment works” and “facilities”, any and all devices, processes and properties, real or personal, used in the collection, pumping, transmission, storage, treatment, disposal, recycling, reclamation or reuse of waterborne pollutants. 
“Waters” and “waters of the commonwealth”, all waters within the jurisdiction of the commonwealth, including, without limitation, rivers, streams, lakes, ponds, springs, impoundments, estuaries, coastal waters and groundwaters.
    </text>
</law>