<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="23B" order_by="23B" level="3">Department Of Housing And Community Development</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>30</section_number>
    <catch_line>Emergency Housing Assistance Program</catch_line>
    <order_by>30</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="A">
    	     The department shall promulgate rules and regulations to establish the levels of benefits available under the program and to ensure simplicity of administration in the best interest of needy recipients. Such benefits shall include, but not be limited to, the following:—
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     for the prevention of the loss of housing, the actual liability up to three times the monthly rental or mortgage liability;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     for the prevention of utility shutoffs or for the resumption of utility services, up to three months of the actual service liabilities;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     for the provision of home heating assistance, up to three months of the actual fuel liabilities.
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     The department shall promulgate regulations which would authorize the department to make payments for a fourth month of rent, utility or fuel arrearages if the director certifies in writing that the family would otherwise become homeless, or be without utilities or fuel.
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     for the prevention of homelessness, temporary shelter as necessary to alleviate homelessness when such family has no feasible alternative housing available, storage of furniture for up to thirty days; moving expenses; advance rent payments of one month’s rent; and security deposit not to exceed one month’s rent.
        </section>
        <section prefix="B">
    	     The department shall promulgate rules and regulations to establish the requirements and standards for eligibility. Subject to appropriation, such regulations shall provide that a needy family shall be eligible for assistance under the emergency assistance program if its income is within the income limits for the program of aid to families with dependent children established pursuant to chapter one hundred and eighteen.
        </section>
        <section prefix="a">
    	     the collection and analysis of data regarding utilization patterns;
        </section>
        <section prefix="b">
    	     the recording and tracking of use of this program by individual recipients, including, but not limited to, the utilization of a year to year cross check of recipients to determine if a person or persons has received similar benefits in the previous year or years;
        </section>
        <section prefix="c">
    	     the utilization by the department of mechanisms, such as payment of all or part of a regular assistance grant directly to vendors, to prevent the misuse of this program, provided, however, that such mechanisms are authorized under federal or state law;
        </section>
        <section prefix="d">
    	     the utilization of wage reporting and bank matching systems, provided, however, that the provision of assistance shall not be delayed by such utilization;
        </section>
        <section prefix="e">
    	     the verification of all elements of eligibility. Such verification requirements, including home visits by workers assigned to recipients, shall be reasonable and in accordance with federal law and regulations, where applicable. The department shall determine which verification requirements can be reasonably met by third party affidavits and shall provide notification to recipients and applicants of the circumstances when third party affidavits may be used. The department shall establish reasonable procedures for the verification of continuing eligibility, including monthly reporting and retrospective budgeting where appropriate.
        </section>
        <section prefix="C">
    	     Subject to federal approval of any necessary waivers, the department shall use the warrant management system established pursuant to section twenty-three A of chapter two hundred and seventy-six; and, in accordance with section 11 of chapter 14 and the rules and regulations of the fraudulent claims commission, the department shall forward the name of any applicant or beneficiary of emergency housing assistance who, according to said warrant management system, has an outstanding default or arrest warrant issued against him; and the department shall comply with existing state and federal law applicable to time standards for review and determination of eligibility, and all notice and hearing requirements afforded to applicants and beneficiaries under its emergency housing assistance programs; and
        </section>
        <section prefix="D">
    	     Any person or institution which knowingly makes a false representation or, contrary to a legal duty to do so, knowingly fails to disclose any material fact affecting eligibility or level of benefits to the department or its agents, for the purpose of causing any person, including the person making such representations, to be eligible for emergency housing assistance, shall be punished by a fine of not less than two hundred nor more than five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not more than one year.
        </section>
        <section prefix="E">
    	     Any vendor under the emergency housing assistance program administered by the department shall submit to the department, within six months of the last day of the month in which such service was rendered, a bill for the same. For the purposes of this chapter a vendor shall be any person or institution providing services in connection with any assistance program administered by the department. All vouchers submitted by a vendor shall be signed under the penalties of perjury.
        </section>
        <section prefix="F">
    	     There shall be within the office of the chief counsel a division of hearings for the purpose of holding the hearings referred to herein and rendering decisions. Said division shall be under the supervision of a hearings manager appointed by the director and shall be independent of all other divisions and personnel of the department.
        </section>
    </text>
</law>