<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="25" order_by="25" level="3">Department Of Public Utilities</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18</section_number>
    <catch_line>Assessments Upon Energy Companies Based On Intrastate Revenues;  Rates;  Suspension Of Rates</catch_line>
    <order_by>18</order_by>
    <text>
          The commission may make an assessment against each electric and gas company under the jurisdictional control of the department and each generation company and supplier licensed by the department to do business in the commonwealth, based upon the intrastate operating revenues subject to the jurisdiction of the department of each such company derived from sales within the commonwealth of electric and gas service, respectively, as shown in the annual report of each such company to the department. Said assessments shall be made at a rate not exceeding 0.2 per cent of such intrastate operating revenues, as shall be determined and certified annually by the commission as sufficient to reimburse the commonwealth for funds appropriated by the general court for the operation and general administration of the department, exclusive of funds appropriated by the general court for the transportation division and for the cost of fringe benefits as established by the commissioner of administration pursuant to section 5D of chapter 29, including group life and health insurance, retirement benefits, paid vacations, holidays and sick leave. The funds may be used to compensate consultants in hearings on petitions filed by companies subject to assessment under this section. Assessments made under this section may be credited to the normal operating cost of each company. Each company shall pay the amount assessed against it within 30 days after the date of the notice of assessment from the department. Such assessments shall be collected by the department and credited to the General Fund. Any funds unexpended in any fiscal year for the purposes for which such assessments were made shall be credited against the assessment to be made in the following fiscal year and the assessment in the following fiscal year shall be reduced by any such unexpended amount.  For the purpose of providing the department with additional operating funds for the regulation of electric companies, the commission may make a separate assessment proportionally against each electric company under the jurisdictional control of the department and each generation company and supplier licensed by the department to do business in the commonwealth, based upon the intrastate operating revenues subject to the jurisdiction of the department of each of such companies derived from sales within the commonwealth of electric service, as shown in the annual report of each of such companies to the department. Such assessment shall be made at a rate as shall be determined and certified annually by the commission as sufficient to produce an annual amount of not less than $2,438,000 commencing in fiscal year 1998 and in each fiscal year thereafter, plus the costs of fringe benefits and indirect costs as established by the commissioner of administration pursuant to section 5D of chapter 29, including group life and health insurance, retirement benefits, paid vacations, holidays and sick leave. The amount of such assessment may be increased by the commission annually by a rate not to exceed the most recent annual consumer price index as calculated for the northeast region for all urban consumers. Assessments made under this section may be credited to the normal operating cost of each company. Each company shall pay the amount assessed against it within 30 days after the date of the notice of assessment from the department. Such assessments shall be collected by the department, and credited to the Department of Telecommunications and Energy Trust Fund established by section 12O.[ Paragraph inserted following the second paragraph by 2012, 216, Sec. 2 effective August 6, 2012.]  For the purpose of providing the department with additional operating funds for activities of the department in investigating the preparation for and responses to storm and other emergency events by the electric companies doing business in the commonwealth, the commission may make a separate assessment proportionally against each electric company under the jurisdictional control of the department, based upon the intrastate operating revenues subject to the jurisdiction of the department of each of the companies derived from sales within the commonwealth of electric service, as shown in the annual report of each of the companies to the department. This assessment shall be made at a rate that shall be determined and certified annually by the commission as sufficient to produce an annual amount of not less than $165,000, plus the costs of fringe benefits and indirect costs as established by the secretary of administration and finance under section 5D of chapter 29, including group life and health insurance, retirement benefits, paid vacations, holidays and sick leave. The amount of the assessment may be increased by the commission annually by a rate not to exceed the most recent annual consumer price index as calculated for the northeast region for all urban consumers. Notwithstanding any general or special law to the contrary, no electric company may seek recovery of any assessments made under this paragraph in any rate proceeding before the department. Each company shall pay the amount assessed against it within 30 days after the date of the notice of assessment from the department. Such assessments shall be collected by the department and credited to the Department of Public Utilities Storm Trust Fund established in section 12P.  A schedule of filing fees shall be determined annually by the commissioner of administration under the provisions of section 3B of chapter 7 for the following: (i) petitions for certificates of environmental impact and public need, provided, however, that such filing fee for any municipal corporation empowered to operate a municipal lighting plant under the provisions of section 35 or 36 of chapter 164 shall not exceed a maximum amount; and (ii) notices of intention to construct an oil facility, with a maximum amount per oil facility to be graduated in accordance with the expected capital investment in the facility.[ Fourth paragraph effective until November 1, 2012. Deleted by 2012, 209, Sec. 4.]  Notwithstanding the provisions of section 20 of chapter 159 and section 94 of chapter 164, during any fiscal year in which such assessment is made, the department shall have no authority to suspend the effective date of any rate, price or charge set forth in any schedule filed subsequent to January 1, 1977 by a gas or electric company under the provisions of said section 94 of said chapter 164 for a period longer than six months; provided, however, that in the event that such six-month period expires on a Sunday or legal holiday, any rate, price or charge suspended under this section shall remain suspended until the day following the next day which is not a Sunday or legal holiday.
    </text>
</law>