<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="18A" order_by="18A" level="3">Department Of Youth Services</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>9</section_number>
    <catch_line>Advisory Committee</catch_line>
    <order_by>9</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be in the department an advisory committee consisting of the commissioner of youth services, the commissioner of welfare, the commissioner of the department of early education and care, the commissioner of mental health, the commissioner of education, the chairman of the parole board, the commissioner of correction, the commissioner of probation, the commissioner of rehabilitation, the chairman of the Massachusetts commission against discrimination, the executive secretary of the Massachusetts Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, and the executive secretary of the Massachusetts Committee on Children and Youth, all of whom shall serve ex officiis, and nine other persons to be appointed by the secretary of health and human services, with the approval of the governor. Such persons shall have demonstrated professional involvement and expertise in the area of delinquency prevention, rehabilitation, and treatment. Upon the expiration of the term of office of any appointed member, his successor shall be appointed for a term of three years. Any vacancy shall be filled by the secretary of health and human services for the remainder of the unexpired term. The secretary of health and human services shall appoint from the members of said committee a chairman and a vice chairman. The committee may appoint a full time executive secretary. Members of said committee shall serve without compensation, but each member shall be reimbursed by the commonwealth for all reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of his official duties. 
Said advisory committee shall have the following duties: (a) It shall advise the commissioner on policy, program development and priorities of need in developing a comprehensive program (1) for the treatment, rehabilitation and custody of juvenile offenders and (2) for integration of the juvenile offender into constructive community life. (b) It shall review the annual plan and the proposed annual budget for the department, and shall make recommendations to the commissioner relative thereto. (c) It shall advise on the recruitment policies of the schools in the department. (d) It shall submit an annual report in which it may propose legislation and present material for the education of the public. (e) It shall visit, at its discretion, every institution and facility within the jurisdiction of the department. It shall meet at least four times a year and shall convene special meetings at the call of the chairman of the committee, a majority of the committee, or the commissioner. For the purposes of holding meetings and conducting official business, a majority of the membership shall constitute a quorum. A written record of all meetings of the committee shall be maintained by the executive secretary and a copy filed within fifteen days after each meeting by said secretary with the commissioner of administration and finance.
    </text>
</law>