<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35</section_number>
    <catch_line>State Lottery And Gaming Fund;  Expenditures</catch_line>
    <order_by>35</order_by>
    <text>
          There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund, to be known as the State Lottery and Gaming Fund. Said fund shall consist of all revenues received from the sale of lottery tickets or shares, and all other monies credited or transferred thereto from any other fund or source pursuant to law.  In order to provide local property tax relief and continue services at the local level, revenues of the lottery commission from whatever source shall be expended only for the following purposes:  (a) For the payment of prizes to the holders of winning lottery tickets or shares;  (b) For the expenses of the commission in administering and operating the lottery, as certified by the secretary of administration and finance, provided that the state treasurer shall transfer the certified amount to the General Fund for said purposes;[ Clause (c) of the second paragraph effective until January 1, 2013. For text effective January 1, 2013, see below.]  (c) For the purposes of the Local Aid Fund, the net balance of the State Lottery and Gaming Fund, as determined by the comptroller on every September thirtieth, December thirty-first, March thirty-first and June thirtieth of each fiscal year; and[ Clause (c) of the second paragraph as amended by 2012, 165, Sec. 103 effective January 1, 2013. See 2012, 165, Sec. 137. For text effective until January 1, 2013, see above.]  (c) For budgeted aid to cities and towns as provided in section 18C of chapter 58, subject to appropriation; and  (d) For the purposes of accommodating discrepancies between the receipt of revenues and related expenditures, the commission may incur expenses and the comptroller may certify for payment expenses incurred in anticipation of revenues.
    </text>
</law>