<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="10" order_by="10" level="3">Department Of The State Treasurer</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>35O</section_number>
    <catch_line>Massachusetts United States Olympic Fund</catch_line>
    <order_by>35O</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be established and set up on the books of the commonwealth a separate fund, to be known as the Massachusetts United States Olympic Fund to assist residents of the commonwealth in paying all or part of any costs associated with the development, maintenance, and operation of the United States Olympic team participating in the Olympics and the United States Paralympic team participating in the Paralympics. 
Said fund shall consist of all revenues received by the commonwealth: (1) under the provisions of law authorizing the purchase of distinctive motor vehicle registration plates for the Massachusetts United States olympic committee, pursuant to section two of chapter ninety; (2) the provisions of law authorizing the voluntary check-off donation indicated on the department of revenue’s annual individual income tax return, pursuant to section six H of chapter sixty-two, and (3) from public and private sources as gifts, grants, and donations to further the development, maintenance, and operation of the United States olympic team. 
The state treasurer shall deposit monies in said fund in accordance with the provisions of sections thirty-four and thirty-four A of chapter twenty-nine in such manner as will secure the highest interest rate available consistent with safety of the fund and with the requirement that all amounts on deposit be available for immediate withdrawal at any time by the authorized representative of the United States olympic committee.
    </text>
</law>