<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="2" order_by="2" level="2">Executive And Administrative Officers Of The Commonwealth</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="3">The Governor, Lieutenant Governor And Council, Certain Officers Under The Governor And Council, And State Library</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>20</section_number>
    <catch_line>Powers And Duties Of Art Commission</catch_line>
    <order_by>20</order_by>
    <text>
        There shall be submitted to the art commission for its approval in an advisory capacity any plan relative to the creation, acquisition, construction, erection or remodeling by the commonwealth of any work of art, accompanied by designs, descriptions, specifications, drawings or models sufficient to enable the commission to determine the artistic character of such work of art. The commission shall file with the governor, within thirty days after such submission, its opinion of such proposed work of art together with such suggestions and recommendations as it may deem proper. The term “work of art”, as used in this section, shall include any painting, portrait, mural decoration, stained glass, statue, bas-relief, ornament, fountain or any other article or structure of a permanent character intended for decoration or commemoration. 
Upon request of the governor, the commission shall act in an advisory capacity relative to the artistic character of any building constructed, erected or remodeled by the commonwealth, or upon land owned by the commonwealth, and when, upon request of the governor, there shall be submitted to said commission any plan relating to such construction, erection or remodeling of any such building, accompanied by designs, descriptions, specifications, drawings or models sufficient to enable the commission to determine the artistic character of such building, the commission shall file with the governor, within thirty days after such submission, its opinion of such proposed building together with such suggestions and recommendations as it may deem proper. The term “building”, as used in this section, shall include structures intended for human occupation and use, and also bridges, arches, gates, walls or other permanent structures of any character. 
Said commission shall have the custody and care of all historical relics in the state house, and of all works of art, as herein defined, erected or maintained therein including portraits or other memorials procured under the provisions of section nineteen or nineteen A of chapter eight; provided, however, that said commission shall not place in or remove from any space in the state house assigned to the general court any such historical relic or work of art without the approval of the committees on rules of the two branches, acting concurrently.
    </text>
</law>