<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="part" identifier="1" order_by="1" level="1">Administration Of The Government</unit>
        <unit label="title" identifier="5" order_by="5" level="2">Militia</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="33" order_by="33" level="3">Militia</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>24</section_number>
    <catch_line>Oaths; Form</catch_line>
    <order_by>24</order_by>
    <text>
        Every commissioned officer, before entering upon the performance of his official duties or exercising any command, shall take and subscribe the following oaths and declarations: 
I, ____________, do solemnly swear that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the commonwealth of Massachusetts, and will support the constitution thereof. So help me, God. 
I, ____________, do solemnly swear that I will obey the lawful orders of all my superior officers. So help me, God. 
I, ____________, do solemnly swear that I will faithfully and impartially discharge and perform all the duties incumbent on me as ____________ according to the best of my ability and understanding, agreeably to the rules and regulations of the constitution and the laws of the commonwealth. So help me, God. 
I, ____________, do solemnly swear that I will support the constitution of the United States. So help me, God. 
All officers shall take and subscribe the said oaths before any competent authority or an officer qualified under section eighty-one to administer oaths, except retired officers and aides-de-camp of the commander-in-chief who may take said oaths before any competent authority; and the following certificate shall be printed on every commission and shall be signed by the person before whom the officer is qualified: 
This may certify that ____________, commissioned as within on this ______ day of ____________, A.D., ___ personally appeared and took and subscribed the oaths required by the constitution and laws of this commonwealth and by a law of the United States, to qualify him to discharge the duties of his office. 
Before me,
    </text>
</law>